<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/synesthesia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/synesthesia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>assisted synesthesia as augmented reality</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-11-assisted-synesthesia-as-augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-11-assisted-synesthesia-as-augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A comment I wrote on Ethan Hein&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ethanhein.com/wp/2009/in-the-sequencer-the-notation-is-the-performance&#34;&gt;account of color-coding sequencer tracks:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;When you say “&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffdf;&#34;&gt;color coding improved your ears&lt;/span&gt;”, the first thing that comes to mind is that you are doing some kind of machine-assisted &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffff80;&#34;&gt;synesthesia&lt;/span&gt;. very cool, that.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another enticing pice from &lt;a href=&#34;http://oblong.com/article/085zBpRSY9JeLv2z.html&#34;&gt;oblong industries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It&amp;#39;s true that one of the elements is a blue ball that bounces in time to the music and touches down on the notes that are playing just then. Also true: a ball like that can never be entirely serious, but it can be entirely effective. What works is assisted &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;synaesthesia&lt;/span&gt;, making sound seem like sight and looking seem like hearing. The time in which music happens is turned into the space of the animated score.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then pretty quickly we hit this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b6YTQJVzwlI&#34;&gt;video of John Underkoffler at TED&lt;/a&gt; on the future of the user interface.  Not quite what I was after, very lovely in its own Minority Report style but not for the perspective I was after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaicoxkiod.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;an interesting perspective from a &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffdf;&#34;&gt;synaesthete&lt;/span&gt;, but I won&amp;#39;t quote&lt;/a&gt; based on the copyright:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;PLEASE DO NOT LIFT CONTENT FROM THESE PAGES WITHOUT FIRST OBTAINING PERMISSION. ONCE PERMISSION HAS BEEN OBTAINED, YOU ARE OBLIGED TO INCLUDE A LINK FROM THE CONTENT BACK TO THIS SITE. You are welcome to post content on this site, provided you include a link back to its hosting origin. Many thanks.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An, finally, aha, wikipedia yields a reference:  Plouznikoff, N., Plouznikoff, A. &amp;amp; Robert, J.-M. (2005), &amp;quot;Artificial &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffbfff;&#34;&gt;Grapheme-Color Synesthesia&lt;/span&gt; for Wearable Task Support&amp;quot;, Ninth IEEE International Symposium on Wearable Computers, pp. 108-113&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;This paper presents the benefits of generating an artificial &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffbfdf;&#34;&gt;visual synesthesia&lt;/span&gt; through a wearable computer. Following a short introduction to remind the need for seamless human-wearable computer interactions, this paper makes the case for drawing upon synesthesia, a combination of the senses naturally occurring in a small portion of the population, to augment everyday entities and more precisely to enrich written graphemes. We present the rationale behind our research and summarize the functionality, architecture and implementation of our current prototype. Preliminary results suggest that this kind of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;artificial synesthesia improves short term memory recall and visual information search times&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1124772.1124828&#34;&gt;the followup paper&lt;/a&gt; crucially gives the link to augmented reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;This paper studies a novel approach advocating the virtual alteration of real-world interfaces through a form of augmented reality. Following an introduction reminding the need for easy to use and more consistent interfaces across our many day to day devices, this paper makes the case for using wearable computers to enhance the interactions between humans and conventional appliances. We present the rationale behind our research and summarize our current prototype&amp;#39;s functionalities, architecture and implementation. Preliminary results suggest that &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;virtually altering the interface of real world devices improves execution times for simple tasks using these devices.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>