<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper Notebooks on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/paper-notebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper Notebooks on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 15:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/paper-notebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing things down</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-writing-things-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-writing-things-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a series of paper notebooks that I keep meeting notes in. I&amp;rsquo;ve settled
on the Roaring Spring 100pp 5 to 1&amp;rdquo; quad ruled book, which I can get for $2.68
at the Barnes and Noble in the U of Michigan Union. The book goes with me
everywhere, and I treat it like a classic lab notebook - date and time stamp
all the pages, write things down when you possibly can, never tear a page out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that writing things down makes a huge difference in how I remember them.
The a2b3 lunch non-summary that I posted earlier today was written in a first
draft in the notebook. The practice is informed a lot by writing things into
Twitter - you don&amp;rsquo;t have much space so you have to be crisp and concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Twitter, I also get to do little sketches and drawings in the notebooks.
I miss that ability to do freehand drawings in a quad ruled environment where
it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a shape that makes sense. My hand-drawing skills are much
better than my computer drawing skills, and that means that some part of things
I want to capture have to be written down with ink on paper first (and maybe
later or maybe never digitized).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>