<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neurotypical on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/neurotypical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neurotypical on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 14:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/neurotypical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurodiversity and the advantages of autism-spectrum disorders in network building</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-20-neurodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-20-neurodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurodiversity means accepting those whose various nervous system components behave as generally expected (neurotypical), as well as those whose nervous systems don&amp;#39;t (autism, migraines, scotopic sensitivity, sensory hyperacuity, parkinson&amp;#39;s, ALS, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges in building an effective team and a useful network of people to work with is to reach out widely enough to reach some people who have a &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;diversity&lt;/span&gt; of background and experience. Seek representation from all corners including people from large and small cities, from a variety of ethnic and racial backgrounds, and with diverse religious, cultural, and economic backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A parallel set of diversity-seeking looks to build connections with people who have diverse ways of perceiving the world. The &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffbfff;&#34;&gt;neurotypical&lt;/span&gt; view of the world is best balanced with views from people who don&amp;#39;t have nervous systems and sensory systems that perceive the world or act on those perceptions in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffdf;&#34;&gt;Neurodiversity&lt;/span&gt; is a word with some specific meaning within a community of people with autism-spectrum disorders, a community which I know only at the edges and can&amp;#39;t count myself a core part of. In some ways I can only hope to approximate that perspective, e.g. in the occasional bits of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #dfbfff;&#34;&gt;assisted synesthesia&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;that I try to sneak into my writing. If you are living in a neurotypical world, the insight from someone with diverse sensory perception can trigger the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #dfbfff;&#34;&gt;great weird ideas&lt;/span&gt; that you find when worlds that were once foreign to each other gain a bridge that helps pull good thoughts from one side to the other. Or, perhaps, I&amp;#39;m a&amp;#0160;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #e6ebd5;&#34;&gt;neurodiverse&lt;/span&gt; individual in this collection, and you are neurotypical by comparison; it&amp;#39;s so hard to tell sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://holisticwisdom.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Linda Diane Feldt&lt;/a&gt; for the idea, and credit goes to Patricia Anderson for the source for the quote, attributed to the &amp;quot;Autism Liberation Front&amp;quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>