<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Hampel on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/matt-hampel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matt Hampel on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:14:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/matt-hampel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning polygons in R and Shapely</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:14:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</guid>
      <description>The project of the week has been an effort to generate a set of maps - 2935 of them, in fact. The source data is from the Department of Energy, listing a set of utility companies and the counties they cover; the goal is to have a boundary map generated for each utility company. I know it won&amp;rsquo;t be a perfect boundary (most utility companies have at least one county that they only provide service to part of), but as a start it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge the Ann Arbor Community Television Network with the Ann Arbor District Library&#39;s video services?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-31-ann-arbors-community-television-network-a-study-by-matt-hampel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 15:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-31-ann-arbors-community-television-network-a-study-by-matt-hampel/</guid>
      <description>Matt Hampel has released a study of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Community Television Network.&amp;#0160; He writes about an organization that was innovative and forward-looking in the 1970s that is now running with little public oversight and with only the most tentative ways of engaging with the public through networks other than cable television.
Most notable in the whole discussion is a comparison of CTN&amp;#39;s video archiving and online access system with a similar setup at the Ann Arbor District Library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>