<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links Marginalia on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/links-marginalia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links Marginalia on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 23:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/links-marginalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 9 april 2008 (by hand this time)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 23:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the usual deliciousing of links has paused for a while, but things still need to be linked; here&#39;s a brief narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://relish.myraklarman.com/festifools-2008&#34;&gt;Festifools 2008&lt;/a&gt; photos are up (thanks to Myra Klarman) - quite a few awesome puppet pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed Festifools this year for a memorial service for &lt;a href=&#34;http://mblog.lib.umich.edu/alumniauthors/archives/2007/12/wilfred_kaplan.html&#34;&gt;Wilfred Kaplan&lt;/a&gt;, University of Michigan math professor emeritus and long time friend.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a Mac with no passwords, you can still get in by booting to single user.&amp;nbsp; These &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=75459&#34;&gt;Mac OS X Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; detail many &amp;quot;special&amp;quot; commands you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A query on Twitter (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/awd&#34;&gt;@awd)&lt;/a&gt; led me to the MELCAT collection of books and materials with the catalog subject &lt;a href=&#34;https://elibrary.mel.org/search~S15?/dtelegraph+-+history/dtelegraph+history/1%2C3%2C50%2CE/2exact&amp;amp;FF=dtelegraph+history&amp;amp;1%2C48%2C/indexsort=-&#34;&gt;Telegraph - History&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The AADL only has 4 titles with that topic, but state-wide there&#39;s lots more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, Twitter is awesome for reference questions, esp. when you manage to collect reference librarians as friends who are working desk shifts.&amp;nbsp; With the Twitter mobile interface and the right people on the other end of the line it&#39;s way better than Google (since at worst people Google for you and sort through the results).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spinroot.com/gerard/hist.html&#34;&gt;The Early History of Data Networks&lt;/a&gt; tells a story of the (optical) telegraphs that went through Sweden and France starting as early as 1794.&amp;nbsp; The Swedish system of Edelcrantz was a 10-shutter system connected by telescopes, capable of sending coded messages a distance of 10 km between stations whose operator would then set up the same configuration for the next station in line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burnsparkrun.org/&#34;&gt;2008 Burns Park Run&lt;/a&gt; is Sunday, May 4.&amp;nbsp; If all goes according to plan I&#39;ll be walking the 5k.&amp;nbsp; There&#39;s nothing better than walking briskly past a runner who has slowed down to catch their breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The last lecture in the &amp;quot;Wikipedia and Academia&amp;quot; series is scheduled for
this Thursday night. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiowa.edu/~history/People/poe.html&#34;&gt;Marshall Poe&lt;/a&gt; will be doing the honors with a talk called
&amp;quot;Please Listen to Me: Wikipedia, Web 2.0 and Human Nature.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp; Thursday, April 10th, 7:00 p.m., 201 Pray-Harrold Hall, EMU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trampolinesystems.com/products/metascope/&#34;&gt;Metascope&lt;/a&gt; is a new tool for visualizing and analyzing networks of up to 10000 nodes.&amp;nbsp; There are versions for Windows and for Mac, and the download includes a dataset based on network data extracted from the Enron corpus of 200000 emails.&amp;nbsp; (via ona-prac)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everythingscool.org/&#34;&gt;Everything&#39;s Cool &lt;/a&gt;is a documentary on the impact of the media on the public perception of climate change.&amp;nbsp; (Sent to me by my cousin who has a PhD in clouds.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thus ends the emptying of the inbox into the blog&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>