<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Little Bird on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/little-bird/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Little Bird on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/little-bird/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Coworking notes at Elixir Vitae</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 16:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A productive afternoon with Mohan Kartha in which I opened a great
many tabs in Chrome. This bit of writing to close those out. Elixir
Vitae is a great spot for writing - lots of quiet noise from the coolers
to keep a background hum, and close to the bus station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sorting out the simplest task that I&amp;rsquo;d like to do with Node-RED,
now that I have a Raspberry Pi 2 running it under Docker in a configuration
that&amp;rsquo;s reliable enough that it seems like it&amp;rsquo;s stable. The easiest
network test in the world is the ping test, and so my first stab at
a try for &amp;ldquo;run always&amp;rdquo; is a simple configuration to notice when the
network looks like it&amp;rsquo;s down and when it is to collect some more
detailed information and log it to a file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for that is this simple configuration from an idea
by Nathan Chantrell, implemented by Martin Harizanov in 2014.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://harizanov.com/2014/03/presence-detection-using-phones-wifi-and-node-red/&#34;&gt;Presence detection using phone’s WiFi and Node-RED&lt;/a&gt; relies on static
IP address assignments from DHCP, plus &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo;, to notice if
someone&amp;rsquo;s device is in the building, turned on, and listening to
wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough phones drain their battery to know that absence
of a wifi signal is not an unambiguous marker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantelope is doing a beta product launch at the final AFC Ann Arbor minor
league soccer game of the year, Saturday, July 25 at 6 PM at Hollway
Field (Pioneer High School, 601 W. Stadium, Ann Arbor). See
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fantelope.com/afc-ann-arbor-fantelope-beta-launch/&#34;&gt;the Fantelope web site&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at writing code to send postcards from Lob.com is
working. The note to self is that if you have a square bracket in
a URL, that you have to turn off curl&amp;rsquo;s globbing function, e.g.
with -g or &amp;ndash;globoff. &amp;ldquo;When you set this option, you can specify
URLs that contain the letters {}[] without having them being
interpreted by curl itself. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every card has a tracking code, so the next bit of reporting to write
is to see which cards are awaiting printing, which ones are in transit,
where they are going to and whether they have been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AAATA moved the endpoint URL for its old-school &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo;
mobile RideTrak application. To go to a particular route like
the 5, see e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&lt;/a&gt; .
The main &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org&lt;/a&gt; has a newer interface, but
alas my Windows Phone 8.1 with its Internet Explorer browser
doesn&amp;rsquo;t do that page justice. (That, and I prefer the old interface
because I managed to figure it out for the stop I&amp;rsquo;m always catching
the bus from.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getlittlebird.com/&#34;&gt;Little Bird&lt;/a&gt; promises to
&amp;ldquo;help businesses unlock the valuable information in structured social data&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve asked for a trial to see what they have in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wondering what the best approach is to the task of
&amp;ldquo;download all of my email from Gmail&amp;rdquo;, since the storage I
now have available on my laptop would make it straightforward
to have an 18 GB personal mail spool and because I really actually
would love to search through it so that I can mark some messages
for permanent deletion. One possibility is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enkive.org&#34;&gt;Enkive&lt;/a&gt;
from The Linux Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am reminded that I want to carry around a set of headphones with me
that plug into my Nokia 635 so that I can use the phone as a radio,
and also reminded that I want to try to construct a headphone dipole
as an antenna for my NooElec DVB-T tuner. The challenge will be remembering
those desires at the right time so that when I see the parts I need
in the junk pile at home that I can grab what I need for my every
day carry bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I need to track down an 8 GB USB stick to load a boot ISO on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a trial of Little Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Little Bird is a system that helps you discover influencers
and experts in any topic. I&amp;rsquo;m at the very start of a 7 day trial.
Marshall Kirkpatrick is CEO of Little Bird, and he has been
active on Twitter posting interesting ideas about influence
marketing - and given that it seemed prudent to give the product a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing is aimed at agencies, not individuals, so I&amp;rsquo;m going
to look at this product through the eyes of people doing
&amp;ldquo;social listening&amp;rdquo; for a living, tracking the messages that
appear on a topic and either quietly making sense of what
is happening or actively engaging with those people to try
to influence their opinions. The single user price is out of
my reach for an annual commitment, though I might keep it up
for another month if I can find a specific task that warrants
the extra tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first test with any social software is to point it at a domain
that I know (Ann Arbor) and see what it unearths. Little Bird
found for me 1000 influential accounts having to do with Ann Arbor,
and in a boost to my ego it puts me in the top 50. Without understanding
how the algorithms work it seems that it biases towards identifying
busy accounts that post a lot of news, vs. the clever individual
whose every post is good but who doesn&amp;rsquo;t post that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a style of posting which I would have to describe as
&amp;ldquo;thinkfluential&amp;rdquo; which Little Bird has a nose for. The thinkfluencer
will post frequently on a given topic, and a lot of people will
retweet them and they will retweet a lot of people. Every message
is relentlessly on message and you won&amp;rsquo;t find cat pictures or
meeting banter mixed in. More often than not you&amp;rsquo;ll see the
thinkfluence augmented by robots that post newsy things day and
night, even when the thinkfluencer is away from the keyboard.
There doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be any interaction at all with this
&amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo;, just a never-ending confluence of thinkfluence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wish that Little Bird had another round of filters, to help me
understand the question at scale &amp;ldquo;is this person really a bot&amp;rdquo;.
The real utility for me of identifying expertise is not to pick
out the high-frequency posting bot, but to suss out who on a topic
is good at engaging on the things they know about. Bot identification
is the Turing Test at work, and maybe just maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a set of
computable metrics that you can build across a corpus of Twitter
users to pull that out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>