<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Little Bird on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/little-bird/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Little Bird on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/little-bird/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a trial of Little Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Little Bird is a system that helps you discover influencers
and experts in any topic. I&amp;rsquo;m at the very start of a 7 day trial.
Marshall Kirkpatrick is CEO of Little Bird, and he has been
active on Twitter posting interesting ideas about influence
marketing - and given that it seemed prudent to give the product a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing is aimed at agencies, not individuals, so I&amp;rsquo;m going
to look at this product through the eyes of people doing
&amp;ldquo;social listening&amp;rdquo; for a living, tracking the messages that
appear on a topic and either quietly making sense of what
is happening or actively engaging with those people to try
to influence their opinions. The single user price is out of
my reach for an annual commitment, though I might keep it up
for another month if I can find a specific task that warrants
the extra tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first test with any social software is to point it at a domain
that I know (Ann Arbor) and see what it unearths. Little Bird
found for me 1000 influential accounts having to do with Ann Arbor,
and in a boost to my ego it puts me in the top 50. Without understanding
how the algorithms work it seems that it biases towards identifying
busy accounts that post a lot of news, vs. the clever individual
whose every post is good but who doesn&amp;rsquo;t post that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a style of posting which I would have to describe as
&amp;ldquo;thinkfluential&amp;rdquo; which Little Bird has a nose for. The thinkfluencer
will post frequently on a given topic, and a lot of people will
retweet them and they will retweet a lot of people. Every message
is relentlessly on message and you won&amp;rsquo;t find cat pictures or
meeting banter mixed in. More often than not you&amp;rsquo;ll see the
thinkfluence augmented by robots that post newsy things day and
night, even when the thinkfluencer is away from the keyboard.
There doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be any interaction at all with this
&amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo;, just a never-ending confluence of thinkfluence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wish that Little Bird had another round of filters, to help me
understand the question at scale &amp;ldquo;is this person really a bot&amp;rdquo;.
The real utility for me of identifying expertise is not to pick
out the high-frequency posting bot, but to suss out who on a topic
is good at engaging on the things they know about. Bot identification
is the Turing Test at work, and maybe just maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a set of
computable metrics that you can build across a corpus of Twitter
users to pull that out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>