<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android Radio on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/android-radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android Radio on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:45:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/android-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TuneIn: listen to broadcast radio from all over the world</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Tunein-appicon-free&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Tunein-appicon-free&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&amp;#39;m fond of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunein.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;TuneIn&lt;/a&gt;, a free service that lets you tune in to radio broadcasts from all over the world. I used it last night to listen to Pacific Coast League AAA baseball, and I&amp;#39;ve previously tuned in hockey games, news stations from far-away places when there&amp;#39;s breaking news, and the occasional music channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the remarkable things about TuneIn is that they have program schedules for the stations they are following, and so you can get real time updates for what&amp;#39;s playing now and who&amp;#39;s playing whom. The front page rotates new songs that if you&amp;#39;re a quick click you can hear more or less in their entirety as they are being broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particularly useful part of TuneIn is its &amp;quot;trending&amp;quot; tab, where it gives you real time feedback on which channels have the most activity. When people are listening primarily to music, it&amp;#39;s a slow news day; when the top station is an all-news local channel, there&amp;#39;s breaking news.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=tunein.player&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;TuneIn Android app&lt;/a&gt; has nearly all of the features of the web site, and it takes advantage of knowing where you are to offer up local stations. In addition there&amp;#39;s a &amp;quot;TuneIn Radio Pro&amp;quot;, which gives you record and rewind for $4.99. There has to be a monetization strategy in there somewhere; they also serve up ads as you connect to some channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended. For public safety scanner monitoring, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broadcastify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Broadcastify&lt;/a&gt; is a good complement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>