<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-public-schools/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-public-schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAFT POLICY 5060 - STUDENT PARTICIPATION IN ASSESSMENT PROGRAMS</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-10-draft-policy-5060-student-participation-in-assessment-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 23:20:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-10-draft-policy-5060-student-participation-in-assessment-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: this is part of the discussion at the Ann Arbor School Board meeting of June 10, 2015. You can see a &lt;a href=&#34;https://annarbivore.wordpress.com/2015/06/10/aaps-board-meeting-15-june-2015/&#34;&gt;full live blog of the meeting at Ann Arbivore&lt;/a&gt; which is written by former Ann Arbor Chronicle writer Monet Tiedemann.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DRAFT POLICY 5060 - STUDENT PARTICIPATION IN ASSESSMENT PROGRAMS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Board of Education believes that assessing student progress provides important data by which the district can measure the effectiveness of curriculum and instruction and the impact of our educational programs on student achievement.  Participation in assessment programs by all students ensures accurate information is provided to parents, educators and other stakeholders and is necessary to improve educational outcomes for our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft Amended Policy 5060&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Board of Education believes that assessing student progress provides important data by which the district can measure the effectiveness of curriculum and instruction and the impact of our educational programs on student achievement.  Participation in assessment programs by all students ensures accurate information is provided to parents, educators and other stakeholders and is necessary to improve educational outcomes for our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students enrolled in the Ann Arbor Public Schools are required to participate in any and all assessments mandated by State and Federal law.  Therefore, full participation in these required assessments is mandatory for all students who are enrolled in the Ann Arbor Public Schools.   There is no mechanism or policy that allows for districts, or their students, to “opt out” of mandated state or federal assessments.  Failure by the district to test the required number of students in each school and/or district-wide may result in educational, financial or reporting sanctions or other negative consequences, and could lead to changes in district policies or procedures to ensure adequate and/or uniform participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Superintendent or designee shall administer student assessments in content areas and grade levels as required by state and federal laws, and shall work with district administrators, principals and the parent and student community to ensure adequate education about and participation in state and federal mandated testing .    Failure  to participate in all state and federal assessments will result in the Board taking any additional actions deemed appropriate to protect the district. Therefore, full participation in state assessments is mandatory for all students who are enrolled in the Ann Arbor Public Schools.  Failure to participate in all state assessments may result in exclusion and/or removal from any application-based school or program.  Special exceptions to individual student participation may be granted by the Superintendent or designee upon a showing of extraordinary circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Superintendent or designee shall provide regular updates of student progress to students, parents, educators and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Superintendent or designee shall administer student assessments in content areas and grade levels as required by state and federal laws. Therefore, full participation in state assessments is mandatory for all students who are enrolled in the Ann Arbor Public Schools.  Failure to participate in all state assessments may result in exclusion and/or removal from any application-based school or program.  Special exceptions may be granted by the superintendent or designee upon a showing of extraordinary circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Superintendent or designee shall provide regular updates of student progress to students, parents, educators and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tamber Woodworth to replace Cindy Leaman as Pioneer HS Principal</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-25-tamber-woodworth-to-replace-cindy-leaman-as-pioneer-hs-principal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 07:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-25-tamber-woodworth-to-replace-cindy-leaman-as-pioneer-hs-principal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This letter went out Friday night, but there was no discussion or announcement on the a2schools.org official school website as late as early Monday morning. I first saw the full text of this letter on the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/2013/11/principal-principles-perspectives-and.html&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Schools Musings&lt;/a&gt; weblog where there&#39;s a good discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
Dear Pioneer Families,

I have notified the Pioneer community today that Ms. Cindy Leaman has agreed
to serve as Principal of Ann Arbor&#39;s A2 Virtual+ Academy beginning 
January 6, 2014.

Ms. Tamber Woodworth will serve as Principal for the remainder of the 
school year. Ms. Woodworth has agreed to return to Pioneer where 
she served previously as both a class principal and principal prior 
to her retirement.

I know we will all work together to support our students at Pioneer.

Thank you,

Jeanice Swift

Superintendent.
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Former Ann Arbor Public Schools principal accused of plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll start with a confession: I don&#39;t think that plagiarism is as big a deal as some people do, especially when you are recycling your own words. (&#34;Self-plagiarism is style.&#34;) The best writers have a set of phrases that they love to use, and it&#39;s not unusual for them to pull something they&#39;ve done before and rework it a bit to suit the new occasion. This is especially true when you&#39;re writing formulaic work that&#39;s short. How many different very short birthday greetings can you send?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, educators are usually held to higher standards of writing than their students, and writing is expected to be something that they are good enough at that they don&#39;t need to crib from someone else&#39;s words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that as a preface, here&#39;s someone else&#39;s words about someone else using someone else&#39;s words, in this case a former AAPS principal (Sulura Jackson) who is now in Chapel Hill, NC. The reporting is from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indyweek.com/indyweek/chapel-hill-high-school-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/Content?oid=3770001&#34;&gt;Indy Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What they found is startling: Multiple documents obtained by the INDY that show Jackson—before and after her arrival at Chapel Hill High—lifted entire passages and letters from books, online articles and teaching resource guides. She used those passages without citation in staff memos, letters to students and even recommendation letters for colleagues, frequently passing them off as her words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the world of education is full of web sites that are full of reusable forms and letters for communicating with students and teachers, like this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationworld.com/tools_templates/index.shtml&#34;&gt;Education World&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Communicate with parents by snail mail or e-mail with these editable and/or printable forms and letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or the business world in general, with this set of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4hb.com/letters/index.html&#34;&gt;662 business letters&lt;/a&gt; - catchy titles like &#34;Apology to receiver of NSF check&#34; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I received your letter of (date) with my check
  attached marked &#34;insufficient funds&#34;, I called my bank
  immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The gentleman I spoke with, (name) , discovered
  that the bank had failed to credit my account with a
  substantial deposit I had made several days prior.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The bank has assured me that they will be sending you a
  formal letter of apology for their error. Attached is my
  check in the amount of $ to replace the dishonored
  one you have returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications from authorities are often ritualistic, formulaic, and repetitious. Hopefully, though, they are not careless. Jackson was tripped up by this mistake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Looking back, the alleged plagiarism might have gone unnoticed were it not for one careless sentence the Chapel Hill High School principal wrote in an October condolence letter to a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;Everyone at Skyline is saddened to learn of the death of your mother,&#34; the letter said.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It seemed Sulura Jackson, who arrived in Chapel Hill this summer with a sparkling, lengthy résumé, had failed to remove the name of her former school, Skyline High, in Ann Arbor, Mich., from the text.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Teachers who spoke to the INDY on the condition that their names not be used for fear of retribution say the incident prompted them to dig deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re going to use a form letter, for goodness sake read the whole form and fill in all the blanks before sending it !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indyweek.com/triangulator/archives/2013/11/21/whats-next-for-chhs-principal-accused-of-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Again from Indy Week&lt;/a&gt;: &#34;More evidence of Chapel Hill High plagiarism?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Members of the Chapel Hill-Carrboro City Schools Board of Education were already scheduled to meet tonight at the Lincoln Center in Chapel Hill. The board&#39;s agenda says members will discuss a personnel matter in closed session starting at 6 p.m. The public portion of the meeting begins at 7 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools superintendent Patricia Green resigns</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patricia Green, superintendent of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, has resigned effective 90 days from April 10, 2013. Her letter of resignation, which was distributed by electronic mail to AAPS parents, follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/2013/04/part-iv-my-commentary-on-superintendent.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ruth from A2 Schools Muse has insightful commentary.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 11, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues and AAPS Families:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last evening, I gave President Deb Mexicotte a letter in which I asked her to 
accept my resignation as Superintendent of Schools of the Ann Arbor Public 
Schools, effective 90 days from yesterday. I shared with her that I plan to 
retire during the summer after 43 years as a professional educator in public 
education. I have been blessed to have truly enjoyed my 43-year career and I 
thanked her and the Board for the opportunity to serve the Ann Arbor 
community during these past two years.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all my colleagues in Ann Arbor Public Schools, it has been a privilege to 
work with you and I wish you well as you continue to maintain the highest 
of standards for all of our children in the future. Ann Arbor is truly an 
outstanding school district with so many dedicated staff members who care 
enormously about children. Your commitment and dedication are beyond 
compare! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I retire, I hope to do some reflective writing about my many experiences 
in education, do some traveling, and reconnect with family and friends who I 
have neglected over the years!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to you all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patricia P. Green, Ph.D.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superintendent of Schools
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second day of school (no photos)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-second-day-of-school-no-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 09:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-second-day-of-school-no-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Facebook stream is full of pictures of kids on their first day of school. (That&amp;#39;s great!) Sorry that I don&amp;#39;t have a first day, or even a second day, photo to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second day at our house featured a last-minute lunch prep (mac and cheese) and then two bicycle rides, one each for the 7th grader and for the 2d grader. The Burns Park school grounds were busy with a stream of parents and kids coming for dropoff; I haven&amp;#39;t seen the new Summers-Knoll morning rush yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By all guesses it&amp;#39;s going to be a good year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Elementary school closed December 7, 2011 due to power outage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-burns-park-elementary-school-closed-december-7-2011-due-to-power-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 07:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-burns-park-elementary-school-closed-december-7-2011-due-to-power-outage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We got word via telephone this morning before school started that a power outage at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2schools.org/burnspark.home/home&#34;&gt;Burns Park Elementary School&lt;/a&gt; (see map below, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dteenergy.com/map/outage.html&#34;&gt;the DTE outage map&lt;/a&gt;) has cancelled school for the day. The outage affects over 1400 customers in Burns Park, Lower Burns Park, and along South State Street. I can&#39;t tell from the map whether University of Michigan facilities are also affected, but the report from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/news/power-outage-affecting-traffic-signals-along-stadium-and-packard/?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&#34;&gt;the dotcom&lt;/a&gt; is that traffic signals are also affected along Packard and on East Stadium near the Stadium Bridges project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details from the DTE outage information page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Job ID: W11120700007
  Estimated Restoration: Wed Dec 07 2011, 12 00 - Wed Dec 07 2011, 14 00
  Off Since: Wed Dec 07 2011, 06 00
  Last Update: Wed Dec 07 2011, 07 50
  Cause: Area outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef015437f8d9ed970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef015437f8d9ed970c&#34; alt=&#34;Picture 24&#34; title=&#34;Picture 24&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef015437f8d9ed970c-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From: Liz Margolis, Ann Arbor Public Schools
To: Burns Park Staff and Families&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burns Park is closed today. There is no power to the building and in the area. DTE is unable to give us an accurate time when the power will be restored. No school for staff or students, today, Wednesday, December 7. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize for this late notice. The power went down at 6:40 this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liz Margolis, Director of Communications, AAPS&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning damage closes Ann Arbor Northside Elementary School on May 26, no one injured</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-may-storm-northside-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 01:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-may-storm-northside-lightning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lightning hit a brick chimney at Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Northside Elementary School on Wednesday at about 4:15 p.m., sending bricks flying 100 feet through the school pickup area. Fortunately, no one was hurt, as the area was vacant except for a staff member&amp;#39;s vehicle which was damaged by flying brick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was aware of this when it happened because the lightning strike was powerful enough to cause the power grid to bounce, prompting &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/billmerrill/status/73488487357218817&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;comments on Twitter and speculating on the exact location&lt;/a&gt;. Phil Proefrock&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10150192189429285&amp;amp;set=a.97532604284.91608.619364284&amp;amp;type=1&amp;amp;theater&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;photo published to Facebook&lt;/a&gt; tells the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northside will be closed on Thursday for building repairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaps.k12.mi.us/aaps/news&amp;amp;mode=single&amp;amp;recordID=393642&amp;amp;nextMode=list&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools news release&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com/news/ann-arbors-northside-elementary-school-to-close-thursday-after-lightning-strikes-building/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AnnArbor.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2011/05/25/northside-elementary-closed-thursday/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;, reporting on the civic news ticker that the chimney &amp;quot;crumbled&amp;quot; based on the school board report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strikestarus.com/index.aspx?id=14&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;24 hour lightning summary from Strikestar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo from Phil Proefrock pending permission to include here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eb9d0e5970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Image_gen&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eb9d0e5970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eb9d0e5970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Image_gen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Elementary School calendar and lost and found</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-burns-park-elementary-school-calendar-and-lost-and-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 01:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-burns-park-elementary-school-calendar-and-lost-and-found/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A convenient calendar for the end of the school year, which is to say that I&amp;rsquo;m doing this for next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been making a point when I visit the school to pick up or drop off J. to make a pass past the lost and found and put anything on a hanger that could possibly go onto a hanger. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know if that makes an immediate difference, but it&amp;rsquo;s satisfying to find a 5 minute volunteer opportunity that I can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?mode=AGENDA&amp;amp;height=500&amp;amp;wkst=1&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23FFFFFF&amp;amp;src=5guqck62nnck6is8t1qucgu17o%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;color=%23AB8B00&amp;amp;ctz=America%2FNew_York&#34; style=&#34; border-width:0 &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Kim, former third grade teacher at Burns Park Elementary School, passed away on Sunday, Sept. 20, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-26-alice-kim-former-third-grade-teacher-at-burns-park-elementary-school-passed-away-on-sunday-sept-20-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-26-alice-kim-former-third-grade-teacher-at-burns-park-elementary-school-passed-away-on-sunday-sept-20-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block;&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=133485801&#34;&gt;from the AnnArbor.com obituaries:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a59e94ec970b-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;09262009_0003444054_1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a59e94ec970b &#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a59e94ec970b-800wi&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px solid black; margin: 3px;&#34; title=&#34;09262009_0003444054_1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;asset asset-image&#34;&gt;Mrs. &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Alice_Kim&#34;&gt;Alice Kim&lt;/a&gt; passed away on Sunday September 20, 2009. She was a
third grade teacher at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Burns_Park_Elementary_School&#34;&gt;Burns Park Elementary School&lt;/a&gt; in Ann Arbor, MI
for many years. She dedicated her life to her profession because she
loved children and teaching. She is survived by her daughters and
husband. She will be greatly missed by all of the people she taught,
worked with, and loved. A private family funeral is planned. In lieu of
flowers, a donation to the following would be preferred: &amp;quot;The
University of Michigan&amp;quot; -Address: Department of Internal Medicine
Development. 301 E. Liberty, Suite 400, Ann Arbor, MI 48104. Memo:
Swartz Professorship in honor of Alice Kim.
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block; width: 615px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=133485801&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block; width: 615px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block; width: 615px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block; width: 615px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools 2009 budget forums March 3 and March 5</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-18-ann-arbor-public-schools-2009-budget-forums-march-3-and-march-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 22:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-18-ann-arbor-public-schools-2009-budget-forums-march-3-and-march-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;from an AAPS press release&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Superintendent &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Todd%20Roberts&#34;&gt;Todd Roberts&lt;/a&gt; and Deputy Superintendent &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Robert%20Allen&#34;&gt;Robert Allen&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting two sessions to give staff, parents, students and community members an overview of the
district’s budget planning for the 2009/2010 school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Tuesday, March 3 , 7-9pm at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Scarlett%20Middle%20School&#34;&gt;Scarlett Middle School&lt;/a&gt;, 3300 Lorraine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Thursday, March 5 at 7-9pm &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Forsythe%20Middle%20School&#34;&gt;Forsythe Middle School&lt;/a&gt;, 1655 Newport&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to review how the schools got to this point, you can go back to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/04/robert_allen_an.html&#34;&gt;2007 AAPS budget crisis meeting&lt;/a&gt; with a presentation by Robert Allen on the financial challenges visible then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more comments at the blogs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miparentsforschools.org/&#34;&gt;Michigan Parents for Schools&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Schools Musings&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; (and if you find other people blogging specifically about schools around here let me know).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New weblog: Ann Arbor Schools Musings</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-12-new-weblog-ann-arbor-schools-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 22:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-12-new-weblog-ann-arbor-schools-musings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruth is writing about the Ann Arbor Public Schools in a new blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Schools Musings. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/2009/01/why-im-writing-about-schools.html&#34;&gt;Her introductory post spells out the reasons for blogging about school:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Sometimes I find the schools satisfactory, and sometimes not, but in general I have a lot of questions. Questions about &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;why&lt;/span&gt; things run the way they do. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/span&gt; about whether things could run better. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Critiques&lt;/span&gt; about the schools. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Ideas&lt;/span&gt;
to improve them. And--in general--I believe that most of the staff
wants the schools to work. But for whom? Are we teaching to the masses?
To the top 10%? The bottom 10%? And are we succeeding? Anyway, what
does it mean to succeed?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In addition, as the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor News&lt;/span&gt; shrinks its coverage of everything (except maybe sports--which are important too), &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;we are not getting the news we need about the schools&lt;/span&gt;. I believe that &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;these are our schools&lt;/span&gt;--yes,
the taxpayers--and we need to know what is going on. These are our
schools--yes, the parents--and we need to be able to make decisions for
our kids. These are our schools--yes, the staff--who often don&amp;#39;t have a
voice in decisions. These are our schools--yes, the students--and what
students think also matters.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaps.k12.mi.us/boe.home/boe_home&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools are run by an elected Board of Education; their web site&lt;/a&gt; has some information about how that public body operates.&amp;#0160; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaps.k12.mi.us/boe.0809/home&#34;&gt;board calendar&lt;/a&gt; for 2008-2009 has a schedule of public meetings, and includes links to the packets of information that have been assembled for the board to review for each meeting.&amp;#0160; You may find them dry reading; you may find them hard to get through; you might find them slow to download, because the one I picked up with 64 pages and 4.4 megabytes, mostly of newspaper clippings from the Ann Arbor News.&amp;#0160; If you have comments, there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaps.k12.mi.us/boe.home/rules_for_public_commentary&#34;&gt;rules for public commentary at the board meetings&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be well elaborated to deal with any number of issues that arise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Elementary - Kindergarten Roundup 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-burns-park-elementary-kindergarten-roundup-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-burns-park-elementary-kindergarten-roundup-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;from the PTO newsletter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindergarten Round-Up&lt;/strong&gt; - Kindergarten Parent Orientation is &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 17th at 7:00 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;#0160;This is for &lt;em&gt;parents only&lt;/em&gt;
to talk about our Kindergarten program and answer any questions you may
have, visit the classrooms and obtain enrollment forms. &amp;#0160;Free childcare
will be provided by the PTO, but you must call the school (734-994-1919) to
pre-register. &amp;#0160;The following &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, February 19th&lt;/strong&gt;
prospective Kindergartners will be divided into small groups and will
then have the opportunity to spend an hour with one of the Kindergarten
teachers doing Kindergarten activities. &amp;#0160;If you know of any families
with children to enroll in Kindergarten for the fall, please let them
know about these two dates for Kindergarten Round Up and encourage them
to call the school office.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burnsparkpto.org/&#34;&gt;more burns park pto news etc at their web site.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>