<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 02:52:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>early review: MedHelper for Android, a pill tracker application</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-29-early-review-medhelper-for-android-a-pill-tracker-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 02:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-29-early-review-medhelper-for-android-a-pill-tracker-application/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m starting to use MedHelper for Android as a tool to keep track of my medicine. As you get older, it&#39;s more and more likely that you&#39;ll be on some medication, and since I&#39;ve had side effects from previous meds I&#39;m happy to find something that helps me track things.
It&#39;s a relatively complicated program compared to some simple pill reminder apps on the market, but my use is relatively simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mobile-only internet</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-29-the-mobile-only-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 23:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-29-the-mobile-only-internet/</guid>
      <description>I was away from my laptop for a few days, but still had use of a mobile phone to view the internet through. (I also had a beach nearby and a room full of relatives). Here&amp;#39;s some observations from the mobile-only internet.
First and foremost, it&amp;#39;s a lot harder to type on a tiny screen with one finger poking at the glass. My online composition is sufficiently slow that I can&amp;#39;t come anywhere near close to keeping up with my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy - bookmarks and apps for your mobile phone</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-26-hurricane-sandy-bookmarks-for-your-mobile-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-26-hurricane-sandy-bookmarks-for-your-mobile-phone/</guid>
      <description>My twitter feed is blowing up with people discussing Hurricane Sandy and its likely impact on the East Coast. In the interests of having somewhere useful to drop things that come up along the way, here&amp;#39;s a live blog of sorts of the event. I&amp;#39;ll put all of my Sandy stuff here, rather than have it go over multiple other entries. The top of this is collected info; the bottom is the blog collecting things without much sorting except chronological.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to post photos from a blackberry to the net</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-how-to-post-photos-from-a-blackberry-to-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 18:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-how-to-post-photos-from-a-blackberry-to-the-net/</guid>
      <description>So, I have a new Blackberry replacing my old Blackberry.&amp;#0160; The new device has a camera in it, which I never had before in a phone.&amp;#0160; So therefore I need to figure out how to get pictures from the phone to the various places I put pictures now and understand the path.
Facebook: My phone has a Facebook app - it was even pre-installed.&amp;#0160; So the camera has a &amp;quot;Send to Facebook&amp;quot; menu entry, which sends it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>android on your netbook, or making a really big mobile phone</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-02-android-on-your-netbook-or-making-a-really-big-mobile-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 16:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-02-android-on-your-netbook-or-making-a-really-big-mobile-phone/</guid>
      <description>Some smart people have ported Google&amp;#39;s Android operating system to an Asus netbook.
Here&amp;#39;s the view of the logical extension of what this merger between mobile phone operating systems and notebook computers will be: shoe phone 2.0


Lots more courtesy of Techmeme:
Matt Warman / Telegraph: &amp;#0160; Google Android on a netbookGreg Sterling / Search Engine Land: &amp;#0160; Report: Android OS Coming To NetbooksGoogle Watch: &amp;#0160; Programmers Run Google Android on Asus EEEPC 1000H NetbookNathania Johnson / Search Engine Watch: &amp;#0160; Apple Should Buy Yahoo: Why I&amp;#39;m Now ConvincedDana Blankenhorn / Open Source: &amp;#0160; Android will be more than a phone&amp;#0160; —&amp;#0160; The obvious can make anyone seem like a genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>typepad mobile, some missing useful features</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-typepad-mobile-some-missing-useful-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 15:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-typepad-mobile-some-missing-useful-features/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m writing this from my mobile phone, using typepad mobile to post with. As a blog post interface it works pretty well.  There is one key piece that is missing to make it more helpful: a search function. I don&amp;#39;t see a way to easily search through my past posts from the phone to go back and update and edit one of them. It is easy to get to the last 5 posts but the next option is to list all 1900 entries, no thanks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>