<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan Elections on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-elections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan Elections on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 13:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Election 2008 and the internet: lessons learned</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-06-election-2008-and-the-internet-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-06-election-2008-and-the-internet-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>Two days after the election, and enough of the aftermath and peak traffic of the day has settled so that we can learn a few lessons from what happened.
0. Party in the streets!
Shawn Smith captured this moment in Ann Arbor. 

 1.&amp;#0160; Design for infinite traffic.
Election reporting is perhaps the best reason to look at cloud computing as a system for dealing with peak load needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-04-votereport---ann-arbor-voting-reports-via-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 08:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-04-votereport---ann-arbor-voting-reports-via-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is using an octothorpetag #votereport to mark voting reports today.&amp;#0160; There&amp;#39;s several systems downstream processing and mapping that data.&amp;#0160; See e.g. votereport.us (simple log), twittervotereport.com (map), and the Twitter vote report wiki (details for media and developers).
You can also get a pretty good point of view via Twitter just searching for the string Ann Arbor.
Here&amp;#39;s reports as I&amp;#39;ve seen them so far this morning, times approx:
730am @mollyali: Couple hundred people in line @ pioneer high, ann arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>free on election day: a sample</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-02-free-on-election-day-a-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 00:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-02-free-on-election-day-a-sample/</guid>
      <description>sticker image from electionstickers.com There is no way on earth this is going to be complete, but here&amp;#39;s something like a list.&amp;#0160; comments welcomed.&amp;#0160; here is an NPR story and interview with some background; some places require indication of voting, others will go on the honor system.
Local:
(didn&amp;#39;t find anything special yet for Ann Arbor, but I&amp;#39;m sure there&amp;#39;s something)
National:
Krispy Kreme: free donut (via Budget Travel / Newsweek / New York)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automark problems - how to test, anticipate, and fix</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-automark-proble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 11:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-automark-proble/</guid>
      <description>Every year when I vote I use the Automark machines, which are designed for voters needing assistive voting technology at the polls.&amp;nbsp; At my polling place I seem to be the only person who ever uses them, so this is some way to do my bit of public service.
The last few times I have gone through this there have been problems.&amp;nbsp; The first time, I gave up and voted on a regular machine; the second time, I figured things out in time to vote with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Election Results for 2008 August primary election</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-05-michigan-electi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 20:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-05-michigan-electi/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Michigan election results for the November 2008 general election, if you came here from a search.
The polls have closed, and results are just starting to trickle in at 8:30pm. Here&#39;s some places to look for data. (update: it&#39;s the next day and the votes are tallied)
The Michigan Secretary of State has 2008 Unofficial Michigan Primary Election Results for all state-wide races, state senators and representatives, and judicial races.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Sample Ballot for 2008 August 5 primary election; AutoMARK problems redux</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-michigan-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 16:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-michigan-sample/</guid>
      <description>The primaries in Michigan are tomorrow, August 5 2008.
If you want a sample ballot, go to the Michigan Voter Information Center run by the Michigan Secretary of State. You&#39;ll put in your voter information, and it will come up with a list of elections on the ballot. Publius also generates Michigan sample ballots, as does the MLive Voter Guide.
The list of Washtenaw County precinct locations is kept by the County Clerk and Register of Deeds, Larry Kestenbaum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor May 6 2008 election results and AutoMARK voting issues</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-ann-arbor-may-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 21:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-ann-arbor-may-6/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll link to election results when they go online here. The Washtenaw County site has the official results. The Ann Arbor News has coverage on the blog, but, true to form, they don&#39;t link to the official results site in their coverage.
Early returns (63% counted at 9:30pm) have both Ann Arbor millage proposals passing 3-1, and incumbent school board member Helen Gates-Bryant leading 2-1. Voter turnout looks like it&#39;s going to be less than 10% county wide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>