<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/ocr/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/ocr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Optical Character Recognition with parallel computing?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-optical-character-recognition-with-parallel-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 01:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-optical-character-recognition-with-parallel-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some references to collect here on the use of general-purpose graphic processors in OCR.&amp;#0160; Nominally, you run some kind of MapReduce based algorithm with a GPGPU over some image, and out spits text much faster than any ordinary processor of any speed; of course, there are lots of details to attend to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/Research/Projects/Data/102604.html&#34;&gt;From Berkeley EECS: Algorithms and Frameworks for OCR and Content-based Image Retrieval&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Jike Chong, Bryan Christopher Catanzaro, Narayanan Sundaram, Fares Hedayati and Kurt Keutzer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;A new breed of general-purpose manycore computing platform is
emerging. Exemplary examples include the Niagara from Sun Microsystems,
the G80 from Nvidia, the Cell from IBM, and the up-coming Larrabee from
Intel. These manycore processors each pack 8-32 relatively simple cores
on a chip, capable of supporting up to 100s of threads, and boast
tremendous potential peak single-chip performances up to the range of
Tera-FLOPS. However, traditional algorithms and applications in many
domains cannot take advantage of much of the parallelism provided by
these platforms. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The ParLab at Berkeley was recently founded in part to help
meet this acute need for novel algorithmic approaches to unleash the
performance potentials of emerging manycore platforms for a wide range
of application domains. It proposes to concentrate on analyzing the
communication and computation patterns (or Dwarfs) of important classes
of algorithms underlying modern application domains, and develop
techniques to efficiently parallelize them for the general purpose
manycore platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We concentrate on the domain of image recognition and
retrieval, leveraging the Intel PIRO content-based image retrieval
framework as a motivating application. Specifically, we study the
parallelization of classification algorithms for machine learning, and
develop parallelization techniques to improve the performance of these
algorithms and applications on the emerging manycore platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bv2.co.uk/?p=281&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a discussion of an OCR system that uses the CUDA libraries called cocr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The cuda implementation allows for exceptionally fast image
manipulation, cleaning and segmentation before being presented to the
template based ocr system.&amp;#0160; Traditional cpu based ocr systems are very
slow, especially in the image rotation, cleaning etc departments and
although cocr is by no means a complete ocr package it is orders of
magnitude faster than the various cpu based ones I’ve tried. With a bit
more work and an additional of a neural network ocr it could easily
become a system able to do greater than realtime ocr’ing.&amp;#0160; Neural
networks are extremely well suited to GPU implementations due to their
inherit parallelism. I will post more snippets and modules of the
system here over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;#39;t able to find any evidence that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/ocropus/&#34;&gt;ocropus &lt;/a&gt;OCR system that Google has used and released is using any parallel computing mechanisms, so this still looks like &amp;quot;gee, it should work for someone, if you can throw a PhD student or two at it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>