<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Security on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/information-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information Security on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 01:48:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/information-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor network takedown by the Nazgûl</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-10-tor-network-takedown-by-the-nazg%C3%BBl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 01:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-10-tor-network-takedown-by-the-nazg%C3%BBl/</guid>
      <description>I would liken Tor to putting on Sauron&amp;#39;s ring. The wearer is invisible to ordinary beings, like Men, but highly visible to the Nazgûl.
&amp;mdash; Matthew Green (@matthew_d_green) October 24, 2014 
Ars Technica writes (November 9, 2014) about the takedown of many sites on the Tor network. An excerpt:
 The theory posited by “the kid who started Doxbin“ to nachash was that the attack was an attempt to force connections to the site’s various .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shellshock, the logo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-25-shellshock-the-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-25-shellshock-the-logo/</guid>
      <description>No security vulnerability disclosure is complete without a logo. #ShellShock pic.twitter.com/yZFDj745Po
&amp;mdash; Paul M. Gerhardt (@pmg) September 24, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Obamacare registration: denial of service attack, or self-inflicted injury?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-06-slow-obamacare-registration-denial-of-service-attack-or-self-inflicted-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 23:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-06-slow-obamacare-registration-denial-of-service-attack-or-self-inflicted-injury/</guid>
      <description>The new healthcare marketplace for the Affordable Care Act, Healthcare.GOV, has been operating slowly under the weight of open enrollment for &#34;Obamacare&#34; plans. The question then comes up: is this some kind of coordinated denial of service attack on the system, or is the system architecture simply slow under heavy load?

Reuters took a look at the issue, and found some problems with the healthcare marketplace&#39;s systems design.
 Five outside technology experts interviewed by Reuters, however, say they believe flaws in system architecture, not traffic alone, contributed to the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need: A login and registration system for a free WiFi network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-26-need-a-login-and-registration-system-for-a-free-wifi-network-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 11:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-26-need-a-login-and-registration-system-for-a-free-wifi-network-/</guid>
      <description>A note from Steve Pierce regarding a request for ideas and code to help people log into a free WiFi mesh network. Contact him for details at bottom.
 HDL.com and volunteers have deployed a free WiFi network in SE Michigan over the last 5 years. With over 1,000 access points deployed and 650,000 unique devices connected, Wireless Ypsi and companion networks such as Detroit Enabled are averaging over 2,500 users per day, making it one of the largest free WiFi networks in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOR network anonymity compromised by Javascript exploit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-05-tor-network-anonymity-compromised-by-javascript-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 07:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-05-tor-network-anonymity-compromised-by-javascript-exploit/</guid>
      <description>TOR is an anonymous network set up originally by the US Navy in order to support cloaked access by the US Government to the Internet. Users access the network through a computer or browser set up to point traffic towards a network of &amp;quot;onion routers&amp;quot;, which scramble the path that the packet takes to eventually reach the Internet. There are also provisions for &amp;quot;dark&amp;quot; web sites or hidden service operators to exist within the TOR network, which should in theory be reachable anonymously by TOR users but not the great outside Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collected Articles on Code Reconstruction, Katharine Swift, 1976, as announced in CRYPTOLOG</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-29-collected-articles-on-code-reconstruction-katharine-swift-1976-as-announced-in-cryptolog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-29-collected-articles-on-code-reconstruction-katharine-swift-1976-as-announced-in-cryptolog/</guid>
      <description>The National Security Agency has declassified a number of issues of CRYPTOLOG, their in-house magazine. Here&amp;#39;s an example from 1977, announcing the publication (for anyone with a Top Secret Codeword clearance) of Katharine Swift&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Collected Articles on Code Reconstruction&amp;quot;. &amp;#0160;&amp;quot;It is hoped that managers as well as book-breakers and programmers, and senior analysts as well as neophytes, will find material that will help each in making his individual contribution on the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More computer security problems in more systems; &#34;not only hashed and salted, but pan-seared and dusted with a saffron quince reduction&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-08-more-computer-security-problems-in-more-systems-not-only-hashed-and-salted-but-pan-seared-and-dusted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-08-more-computer-security-problems-in-more-systems-not-only-hashed-and-salted-but-pan-seared-and-dusted/</guid>
      <description>When you notice a big LinkedIn password breach one day, and then several other sites also announce problems in subsequent days, there seems to be a pattern worth noticing. Here&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ve noticed of late.
&amp;#0160;
Ars Technica reports that the Flame virus uses a previously undiscovered attack on the MD5 cryptographic hash in order to carry out some of its devious work.&amp;#0160;
 Flame is the first known example of an MD5 collision attack being used maliciously in a real-world environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn has had a password leak. How to repair it.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-linkedin-has-had-a-password-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-linkedin-has-had-a-password-leak/</guid>
      <description>Change your LinkedIn password.
News emerged on Wednesday, June 6, 2012 that LinkedIn had a leak of its password database. This was confirmed as a number of security researchers identified their own password hashes in the file, as well as a number of cracked passwords from that file that had the string &amp;quot;LinkedIn&amp;quot; or some variant in the text. You can protect yourself by changing your LinkedIn password, and by also changing any other passwords that you use which are the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>that image of the spreadsheet in the PDF you sent me is not the public record you are required to share</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-04-that-image-of-the-spreadsheet-in-the-pdf-you-sent-me-is-not-the-public-record-you-are-required-to-sh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 16:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-04-that-image-of-the-spreadsheet-in-the-pdf-you-sent-me-is-not-the-public-record-you-are-required-to-sh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve become one of those people who requests and then reads the &amp;quot;board packets&amp;quot; for meetings of public bodies.&amp;#0160; These are fascinating things, generally 50-150 page tomes of memos, spreadsheets, graphs, charts, and news clippings that the staff of a public body will prepare for its board to go into a public meeting.
The fascinating thing from a technical point of view is just how many of these board packets include spreadsheets, and how many of the spreadsheets are presented either as bitmapped images or as text-only documents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>