<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/reciprocity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/reciprocity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Grant, Give and Take; on being &#34;otherish&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief review of Give and Take, which I checked out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1427997&#34;&gt;from the Ann Arbor District Library.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant writes about a number of people he calls givers, who are generous to a fault when sharing their time and expertise, even when there is not a sure bet that the generosity will be repaid. He contrasts this with the matchers, who always keep track of favors, and the takers who seek to exploit every circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant likes givers, but recognizes that sometimes people give too much and never manage to get things in return. These selfless people tend to burn out when too many things go opposite to their interests. He opens up the opportunity to recognize a newly coined word &#34;otherish&#34; - an opposite of selfish where you consider both your interests and the others interests simultaneously. &#34;Otherish&#34; people are looking for win-win situations, as opposed to selfless people who end up in win-lose setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#34;Givers are overrepresented at the top, as well as at the bottom, of most success measures.&#34; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/printer_friendly.cfm?articleid=3224&#34;&gt;interview with Adam Grant&lt;/a&gt; about the book is a 25 minute version which touches on several more high points of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocity, give and take a little bit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 16:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.giveandtake.com/Home/AdamGrant&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Adam Grant&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; book&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1427997&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Give and Take&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(aadl). &amp;#0160;Look in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/magazine/is-giving-the-secret-to-getting-ahead.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;March 31 NY Times Magazine for a preview&lt;/a&gt;, featuring a quote from the U of Michigan&amp;#39;s Jerry Davis. At the moment I&amp;#39;m&amp;#0160;33d on a list of 53 holds at the library for the book; if you&amp;#39;re generous, and have finished your copy, please lend it to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table of contents and blurb, from the AADL catalog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good returns: the dangers and rewards of giving more than you get -- The peacock and the panda: how givers, takers, and matchers build networks -- The ripple effect: collaboration and the dynamics of giving and taking credit -- Finding the diamond in the rough: the fact and fiction of recognizing potential -- The power of powerless communication: how to be modest and influence people -- The art of motivation maintenance: why some givers burn out but others are on fire -- Chump change: overcoming the doormat effect -- The scrooge shift: why a soccer team, a fingerprint, and a name can tilt us in the other direction -- Out of the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using his own cutting-edge research as a professor at Wharton Business School, Adam Grant shows how helping others can lead to greater personal success. He demonstrates how smart givers avoid becoming doormats, and why this kind of success has the power to transform not just individuals and groups, but entire organisations and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m particularly intrigued by the notion that there&amp;#39;s a distinction that creates &amp;quot;smart givers&amp;quot; that win some unspecified game through a generous strategy that pays off for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes from a lunchtime talk on social media</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-04-some-notes-from-a-lunchtime-talk-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 10:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-04-some-notes-from-a-lunchtime-talk-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few highlights, not the whole talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes for the talk were the four words: novelty, reciprocity, frequency, mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For novelty I spoke to the notion that people are on a perpetual search for the next new thing, and that any solution to any problem has to be revisited periodically in the light of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reciprocity is the notion that people will respond in kind if you act generously to them, and I spoke to how this plays out in social media with &amp;quot;friends&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;followers&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;likes&amp;quot; as the actions often reciprocated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding frequency, the notion is that communications media have a natural rhythm, and that you need to be aware of how often you post or comment so that you don&amp;#39;t either overrun the medium or be so quiet as to be unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally mobility is the observation that more and more people are coming to the net primarily through mobile devices and if you want to serve them you need to have a solution for your web and net presence that looks good on the small screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was greeted with a fair degree of skepticism about the value of social media for business, especially from someone who cancelled his Facebook account and never has been on Twitter. There was good discussion of how hard it is to simultaneously be brand-conscious and be aware of a professional persona vs. sharing details of a personal life. I think it&amp;#39;s harder for people in an agency role whose job it is to make the client look good but who don&amp;#39;t have to have a personal public identity in order to do their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some day when I retire I&amp;#39;ll give up on social media entirely and just send postcards to people - they are novel compared to the communciations that people mostly get, they&amp;#39;re quite portable and mobile, no one expects a frequency of a postcard more than once in a long while, and if you send postcards you&amp;#39;re likely to get postcards in return.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>