<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geojson on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/geojson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geojson on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:14:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/geojson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning polygons in R and Shapely</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:14:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</guid>
      <description>The project of the week has been an effort to generate a set of maps - 2935 of them, in fact. The source data is from the Department of Energy, listing a set of utility companies and the counties they cover; the goal is to have a boundary map generated for each utility company. I know it won&amp;rsquo;t be a perfect boundary (most utility companies have at least one county that they only provide service to part of), but as a start it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps with Leaflet and LeafletR</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-02-maps-with-leaflet-and-leafletr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 01:09:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-02-maps-with-leaflet-and-leafletr/</guid>
      <description>style leaflet(data=&#34;/Users/emv/tmp/N.geojson&#34;,dest=tempdir(),popup=&#34;*&#34;,style=style)  So, progress.
One process, written in python, takes an Excel file provided by the county and creates a GeoJSON file from it. Addresses in the file are geocoded. The original file has a set of restaurant inspection reports and three kinds of inspection problems found; I add a fourth &#34;score&#34; variable that&#39;s derived in some way from those three.
A second process (code above) is in R using the LeafletR graphing package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using &#34;jq&#34; for command line web applications for civic data</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-using-jq-for-command-line-web-applications-for-civic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 09:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-using-jq-for-command-line-web-applications-for-civic-data/</guid>
      <description>One of the tools that I rediscovered and have been really happy for having done so is &amp;ldquo;jq&amp;rdquo;, a command line tool that bills itself as &amp;ldquo;awk for json&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing awk code since 1985, and some limited subset of it is something that I know really, really well. awk, however, is from the punchcard era, and as such it likes to deal with records that are all on one line each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on building the Marquette Park Cemetery finder app for Code Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 01:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working on a tool or a set of tools to assist people in finding grave sites in the Park Cemetery in Marquette, Michigan as a part of a project for Code Michigan. I&#39;m working with a team that&#39;s based in the U.P. to do this, and we&#39;re collaborating over Google Hangouts. Code Michigan is a hackathon, so this project timeline is compressed to a single weekend. The team is Edward Vielmetti, Jim Argeropoulos, Chris Marr, and Lynn Czarnecki Makela.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>