<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yesterbox on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/yesterbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yesterbox on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:28:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/yesterbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Still answering yesterday&#39;s email; also doing yesterday&#39;s todos</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-still-answering-yesterdays-email-also-doing-yesterdays-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-still-answering-yesterdays-email-also-doing-yesterdays-todos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a big fan of finite lists of things to do. It&#39;s hard to keep up with things that require an answer, and sometimes you need to let things slide until the next day. When you combine those two, you get &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/yesterbox-answer-yesterdays-email-today.html&#34;&gt;yesterbox&lt;/a&gt;. The basic idea is that you answer today&#39;s email tomorrow, so that you know when you get to the bottom of yesterday&#39;s mail you are really done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slight complication for this system for me is that I&#39;m also using a todo list which is supposed to capture everything I need to do. Alas, things go onto this list and stay there forever. How to reconcile the two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;m going to try, as best I can, is to deal with today&#39;s bright ideas about what I need to do but don&#39;t have time to do right now tomorrow. There will be a finite number of things to look at, and I can probably deal with some of them right away. I don&#39;t mean to kick the can down the road, but I also don&#39;t want to try to tackle everything I&#39;ve ever thought of doing all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired in part by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wallofvoodoo.net/&#34;&gt;Wall of Voodoo&lt;/a&gt; song &#34;Tomorrow&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll do it tomorrow / that seems like a pretty good idea to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/-eEfAGzgv18?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>