<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/farmers-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:32:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Westside Farmers Market on hold due to zoning restrictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>If you can figure out the City of Ann Arbor zoning, you&amp;#39;re better than me.
The Westside Farmers Market, which has been holding court in the parking lot of Zingerman&amp;#39;s Roadhouse, has put off its 2009 season until zoning issues get resolved.&amp;#0160; Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Westside Farmers&amp;#39; Market is currently &amp;quot;on hold&amp;quot; due to zoning restrictions from the city of Ann Arbor.
The Ann Arbor News story by Judy McGovern reads</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday: menu plan, Used Cars, 1880s ann arbor panorama</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</guid>
      <description>The menu plan for tonight for the late supper for the resident scholar: spring salad w/asparagus, oyster mushrooms from Alpena, eggs from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen, spinach from Brines Farm, savory tofu from the coop, and a curry dressing. The boys will probably get something a lot simpler.
I wish I had rhubarb to have made stewed rhubarb but I got there to market too late.&amp;#0160; A stewed rhubarb is a compote, which is not to say a compost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where and when to find pea greens or pea tips?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</guid>
      <description>Every year I look forward to finding pea greens, so that I can stir fry them up.&amp;#0160; And every year at the farmer&amp;#39;s market I don&amp;#39;t find them.&amp;#0160; I hope this year can be different, but I have some questions.
If I wanted to grow pea greens on my own, what variety of peas would I use?
Are pea vines usually sprayed, and would you want to look out for no-spray vendors?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.
March 21, 2009!&amp;#0160;
  Apples  Baked goods  Beef  Beet greens  Beets  Bison  Biscotti  Cider  Cupcakes  Delicious chocolate cookies  Cultivated mushrooms  Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)  Dulce du leche  Eggs  Honey  Jams &amp;amp; jellies  Kale  Lamb  Maple Syrup  Onions  Popcorn  Potatoes  Delicate salad greens  Radishes  Spinach  Tamales  Winter squash   +&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>