<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Farmers Market on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/farmers-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Farmers Market on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 12:58:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report for June 27, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 12:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;mostly pulled from twitter, but also from some field reporting from your fearless market reporter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/farmersmarketer/status/2353422343&#34;&gt;The Farmer&amp;#39;s Marketer (Kim Bayer) notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;status-body&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;msgtxt en&#34; id=&#34;msgtxt2353422343&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Committee forming to determine if year round indoor &lt;strong&gt;farmers&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;market&lt;/strong&gt; viable in downtown &lt;strong&gt;Ann&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Arbor&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;quot; Open House 7.8.09. 3:30-7pm. Eaton Bldg.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have a URL to point to for this one for more details but you could ask Kim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeff McCabe is on a misson to create &amp;quot;as many hoop houses in our area as these efforts can muster&amp;quot;; he has resources to support two of them to be built this fall, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.repastspresentandfuture.org/about/our-mission/small-farms-small-farmers-initiative/&#34;&gt;contact him for the application due July 10.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the market this week: cherries (tart and sweet), gooseberries from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Wasem%27s&#34;&gt;Wasem&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; (we got there too late, they were sold out), pea shoots from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Gardenworks&#34;&gt;Gardenworks&lt;/a&gt; (again we got there too late), squash blossoms, some very wonderful radishes, little potatoes, several kinds of kale, peas in the shell, peas where you eat the shell, peas out of the shell, strawberries, eggs, horseradish, coffee from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Roos%20Roast&#34;&gt;Roos Roast&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; It was a very busy summer market day with every stall full or nearly so.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What to do with all of this bounty?&amp;#0160; Erica (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/erksnerks/statuses/2360136303&#34;&gt;erksnerks&lt;/a&gt;) says&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;span class=&#34;status-body&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;entry-content&#34;&gt;pitting tart cherries right this minute got 3 quarts pie for dinner!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;mmm, pie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Westside Farmers Market on hold due to zoning restrictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you can figure out the City of Ann Arbor zoning, you&amp;#39;re better than me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.westsidefarmersmarket.com/&#34;&gt;Westside Farmers Market&lt;/a&gt;, which has been holding court in the parking lot of Zingerman&amp;#39;s Roadhouse, has put off its 2009 season until zoning issues get resolved.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Westside Farmers&amp;#39; Market is currently &amp;quot;on hold&amp;quot; due to zoning restrictions from the city of Ann Arbor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2009/05/zoning_violation_shuts_down_an.html&#34;&gt;The Ann Arbor News story by Judy McGovern reads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The property&amp;#39;s C3 zoning is the most relaxed of the three commercial categories, but it doesn&amp;#39;t allow the kind of &amp;quot;special use&amp;quot; permits that can be issued to properties in the more restrictive C1 and C2 categories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That appears to be an oversight in the regulations, and city officials are working to change the code, said City Council Member Carsten Hohnke, whose 5th Ward includes the property.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/City_Clerk/Ordinances/Pages/Online%20City%20Code.aspx&#34;&gt;city code&lt;/a&gt;; it appears that C3 zoning (5:10.23) for the properly in question is preferential to properties where automotive access is the characteristic function:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;Normal-Level&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote l0&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;(1)&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal; font-style: italic; text-decoration: none; display: inline;&#34;&gt;Intent.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;
            &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal; font-style: normal; text-decoration: none; display: inline;&#34;&gt;The
design and regulations of this district are set up to provide for
certain types of commercial activities which have characteristics in
common. In this district, the customer usually comes directly to the
particular establishment by automobile, making a separate stop for each
errand. Comparison shopping activity is less than in the central
business district. Since there is little essential interdependence of
activities, establishments can be dispersed over considerable areas
with each establishment having its own automobile parking. Good
automobile accessibility is essential to these districts. The uses
permitted, because of their lack of intense pedestrian activity and
their required contact with auto access, would be incompatible in the
central business district.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The get-out-of-jail-free card is this language on special use permits, as described in the C-1 Local Business District language (5.10.15):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;Normal-Level&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;l1 blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;(h)&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;The City Council may, by resolution, designate
certain dates and locations as special events temporary outdoor sales
areas. Said resolution shall include conditions and standards of
conduct to be in force for outdoor sales and displays on private
property. A property owner who wishes to conduct outdoor sales and
displays on his or her private property, as provided for in the council
resolution, shall first apply for and receive a Zoning Compliance
Permit by the date designated in the resolution. The conditions and
standards contained in the resolution shall be conditions of the Zoning
Compliance Permit issued to a property owner. Failure to comply with
the conditions set in the resolution shall be a violation of this
ordinance section and shall be grounds to revoke all permits granted to
the property owner for the duration of the special event identified in
the resolution.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The question, is appears, is whether the C-1 &amp;quot;special events&amp;quot; language applies to C-3 zoning, or whether there is no permit possible for someone in the automotive, big box, strip mall and huge parking lot district to ever do a temporary outdoor sales area.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given that Zingerman&amp;#39;s had a previous permit for this use I suspect there&amp;#39;s some other story not yet being told.&amp;#0160; Your guess is as good as mine what prompted this whole snafu.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2009/04/development_dirt_dda_drug_stor.html&#34;&gt;Zingerman&amp;#39;s has had disputes with the city about their 322 E Kingsley property&amp;#39;s zoning&lt;/a&gt; , which have come to council recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday: menu plan, Used Cars, 1880s ann arbor panorama</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The menu plan for tonight for the late supper for the resident scholar: spring salad w/asparagus, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.williamsfamilyfungi.com/&#34;&gt;oyster mushrooms from Alpena&lt;/a&gt;, eggs from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen, spinach from Brines Farm, savory tofu from the coop, and a curry dressing. The boys will probably get something a lot simpler.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I had rhubarb to have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tonytantillo.com/vegetables/rhubarb.html&#34;&gt;stewed rhubarb&lt;/a&gt; but I got there to market too late.&amp;#0160; A stewed rhubarb is a compote, which is not to say a compost.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rhubarbinfo.com/rhubarb-poison.html&#34;&gt;Don&amp;#39;t eat the leaves&lt;/a&gt;, they have oxalic acid which is toxic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/teacherpatti&#34;&gt;teacherpatti&lt;/a&gt; for the Farmers Market heads-up, to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/suchpretty&#34;&gt;suchpretty&lt;/a&gt; for the pretty things to look at at market, and to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/roosroast&#34;&gt;roosroast&lt;/a&gt; and crew resplendent in ties selling coffee with a movie recommendation (here&amp;#39;s a scene from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQiTRQTiMGY&#34;&gt;Used Cars&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;You ought to buy it right now.&lt;br /&gt;This Buick is you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing that came up along the way was a mention of the Arborwiki stickers; here&amp;#39;s the art that I have&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/ArborWiki_Stickers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/images/2/2f/ArborWiki-3x4.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current market location is just to the north of the old location, which was the grounds of the county courthouse visible upper right in this 1880s panorama view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where and when to find pea greens or pea tips?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year I look forward to finding pea greens, so that I can stir fry them up.&amp;#0160; And every year at the farmer&amp;#39;s market I don&amp;#39;t find them.&amp;#0160; I hope this year can be different, but I have some questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to grow pea greens on my own, what variety of peas would I use?&lt;br /&gt;Are pea vines usually sprayed, and would you want to look out for no-spray vendors?&lt;br /&gt;When is the best time to pick?&lt;br /&gt;Do you lose all of the pod harvest or can you have both?&lt;br /&gt;If I harvested a bushel of vines from a U-Pick operation would they look at me funny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our traditional pea-picking weekend here is Father&amp;#39;s Day, when we go to Rawsonville for peas and strawberries and we make sure to take sunblock and water (note to future self).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ms-rteCustom-ArticleByline&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 21, 2009!&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Apples&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Baked goods&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beef&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beet greens&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Biscotti&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cider&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cupcakes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delicious chocolate cookies&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cultivated mushrooms&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dulce du leche&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Eggs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Honey&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jams &amp;amp; jellies&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kale&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lamb&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Maple Syrup&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Onions&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Popcorn&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Potatoes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delicate salad greens&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Radishes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Spinach&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tamales&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Winter squash &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ms-rteCustom-ArticleHeadLine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;+&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Michigan fruit crop estimates, early reports</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 17:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A place to collect fruit crop damage reports for 2008.  Today is the 53rd Annual Fruit Crop Guesstimate, sponsored by the Michigan Frozen Food Packers Association, will be June 18, at 2 p.m. at the Amway Grand Hotel, in Grand Rapids; when those reports come in for real I&#39;ll post them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Guesstimate results are in - details here, too long to post, at &lt;a href=&#34;http://fruitgrowersnews.com/pages/news.php?ns=1614&#34;&gt;Fruit Growers News&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Poor Weather Has Cut Size of Most U.S. Fruit Crops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 19, 2008 - By Dick Lehnert &lt;br /&gt;
Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crummy spring weather coast to coast has reduced the production for most fruit crops. The word “record” was used only once – for blueberries – during the 53rd annual Fruit Crop Guesstimate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Guesstimate, sponsored by the Michigan Frozen Food Packers Association and attended by more than 150 people from across North America, was held June 18 in Grand Rapids, Mich. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the presenters adjusted their PowerPoint presentations as they were making them, reflecting continuing poor weather. New York has hit by a hail storm of “epic proportions” on June 16, and the June drop, delayed and prolonged by cool weather that slowed crop development, was still taking apples and peaches from trees across the northern states. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 18: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.record-eagle.com/local/local_story_170094110.html&#34;&gt;Traverse City cherry crop damage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just completely trashed,&amp;rdquo; Williams said of the small tract of cherry trees along Bright Road south of Maple City. &amp;ldquo;You can see how it took the leaves down and everything &amp;hellip; it stripped (the cherries) right off the trees.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hail that pelted Williams&#39; fruit trees marked the latest episode in a series of nature-related setbacks blamed for damaging the region&#39;s cherry crop. This year&#39;s harvest is shaping up as the worst since the nearly cherry-less summer of 2002, experts said.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 10: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leelanaunews.com/blog/2008/06/10/southern-leelanau-hardest-hit-by-frost/&#34;&gt;Southern Leelenau apple crop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Orchards were damaged last week when temperatures dropped as low as the mid-20s, but farms in the northern half of the county – above the 45th Parallel – weren’t hit quite so hard, said Nikki Rothwell, director of the Northwest Michigan Horticultural Resource Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think there is significant damage out there. We can’t put a number on it but we’ve got poor pollination on top of a freeze event,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apples were hit hardest by early morning cold May 28, followed by sweet cherries and then tarts and other crops growing in moderate to poor sites, or in a valley or pocket more susceptible to cold weather, she said.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>