<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum Cleaners on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/vacuum-cleaners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vacuum Cleaners on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 16:09:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/vacuum-cleaners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vacuum Cleaners for sale, Ann Arbor area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-16-vintage-vacuum-cleaners-for-sale-ann-arbor-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 16:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-16-vintage-vacuum-cleaners-for-sale-ann-arbor-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are interested, please contact Rusty at rra359@gmail.com . He writes on April 16, 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to belong to the Vacuum Cleaners Collector Club a few years back.  I live in Ann Arbor on the west side, and am interested in selling off my Vacuum collection.  I am hoping you may know of some people who may be interested, since I am no longer in the club. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have about 60 vacuums, dating back to the “coffee can Hoovers.”  I donated a couple to the Hoover Museum when I went to the Hoover 100th anniversary a few years back.  I have mostly Hoovers (60, 61, 62, etc), and an Electrolux G that is in practically showroom condition with all of the attachments including the power head and turbo floor scrubber.  I also have a 1205 that works well.  I’ve got a Rainbow (around 1993) and some older Kirbys (D-50, D-80, Classic III 2C and Legend).  I also have some newer Miele’s that work very well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for me selling is that I need the space in the basement, and need some $$ for home repair.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>