<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>V. V. Mayakovsky on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/v.-v/index.-mayakovsky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in V. V. Mayakovsky on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 12:40:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/v.-v.-mayakovsky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>the flying proletarian / Mayakovsky</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-the-flying-prol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 12:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-the-flying-prol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sovlit.com/bios/mayakovsky.html&#34;&gt;V. V. Mayakovsky bio in the Encyclopedia of Soviet Authors&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1925 Mayakovsky also made one of his few forays into the sphere of utopian science fiction with his poem Letaiushchi Proletarii (&#34;The Flying Proletarian&#34;). As described by Victor Tarras in his biography of Mayakovsky, The Flying Proletarian was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;...set in the year 2125 and features a giant air battle, with death rays and such, between the Soviet proletarian and the American bourgeois air forces. The latter prevails until an uprising of New York workers against their government turns the tide. Mayakovsky&#39;s communist future is all comfort and electric ease: electric razors, electric toothbrushes, everybody with his own private airplane (Moscow no longer has any streets, just airports). Labor is wholly mechanized, so that a worker merely operates a keyboard. Altogether, Mayakovsky&#39;s utopia is written from the viewpoint of a laborer who is tired of backbreaking, dirty work. . . . There are no kitchens, no housework. People eat in aerocafeterias and amuse themselves with cosmic cinemas, cosmic dances, and such--all nonalcoholic (alcohol is served by prescription only). The sport of the future is avio-polo--football has long since been abandoned as crude and boring.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a new work on Mayakovsky out: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/cat/seek/record=1310503&#34;&gt;Night wraps the sky : writings by and about Mayakovsky / edited by Michael Almereyda&lt;/a&gt; (AADL link).  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Night-Wraps-Sky-Writings-Mayakovsky/dp/0374281351&#34;&gt;(amazon link)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>