<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Field Guide To Blueberries on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/books/a-field-guide-to-blueberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Field Guide To Blueberries on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:44:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/books/a-field-guide-to-blueberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim Johnson, poet laureate of Duluth, MN; In The Blueberry Bucket</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-03-jim-johnson-poe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-03-jim-johnson-poe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Johnson is the 2008-2010 poet laureate of Duluth, Minnesota.  From a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mnartists.org/article.do?rid=189603&#34;&gt;profile of Jim Johnson&lt;/a&gt; by writer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mnartists.org/artistHome.do?rid=11865&#34;&gt;Cheryl Reitan&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mnartists.org&#34;&gt;mnartists.org&lt;/a&gt; site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
JIM JOHNSON, THE RECENTLY CHOSEN 2008-2010 DULUTH POET LAUREATE, writes poetry that is cut from the cloth of his Finnish roots. While much of his work recalls the lives of Finnish settlers in northern Minnesota, the message is universal. It is the quintessentially American story of the immigrant experience and of families, hunger, nature, and hard work.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In The Blueberry Bucket (from A Field Guide to Blueberries)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A man picks blueberries all day. In the bucket&lt;br /&gt;
small green and withered sifting down,&lt;br /&gt;
too old and squashed against the sides,&lt;br /&gt;
twigs leave spruce needles settled to the bottom&lt;br /&gt;
while the large ripe rise up to the top.&lt;br /&gt;
So full of flesh, so ordinary?&lt;br /&gt;
a woman, at sunset&lt;br /&gt;
a blond woman leading a reindeer&lt;br /&gt;
across the horizon. You are that woman. I am that man.&lt;br /&gt;
And this I give to you&lt;br /&gt;
is, if not the history of the world&lt;br /&gt;
at the end of the day, but&lt;br /&gt;
a bucketful of blueberries.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In blueberry picking news, we were at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Dexter_Blueberry_Farm&#34;&gt;the Dexter Blueberry Farm&lt;/a&gt; yesterday (August 2 2008) and picked a good quantity of berries - the big commercial high bush berries which are easier to fill buckets with, even if you are the only one picking and your traveling companions are mostly eating.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>