<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trenary Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/trenary-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trenary Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 23:17:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/trenary-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trenary Outhouse Races 2009 - &#34;Haul Your Arse to the Sweetest 16th Ever&#34; - Feb 28, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-trenary-outhouse-races-2009-haul-your-arse-to-the-sweetest-16th-ever-feb-28-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 23:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-trenary-outhouse-races-2009-haul-your-arse-to-the-sweetest-16th-ever-feb-28-2009/</guid>
      <description>In Trenary, MI each year, when it&amp;#39;s cold and snowy, they hold a race to see who can push an outhouse on skis (suitably decorated) the fastest down Main Street.
The official web site has many more details.
Past year&amp;#39;s coverage:
2008:&amp;#0160;Trenary Outhouse Classic - Races show Yooper spirit&amp;#0160;from the Mining Journal&amp;#39;s Winter Visitor&amp;#39;s Guide has an interview with athlete Tom Felty
Tom said he built the outhouse in his yard back home and described it as a “conversation piece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trenary Outhouse Classic - 15th Annual - Feb 23 2008 - Trenary, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-trenary-outhous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 22:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-trenary-outhous/</guid>
      <description>For the past 15 years, intrepid outdoorspeople in Trenary, MI have been pushing outhouses down a racetrack in February. Here&amp;rsquo;s some details and coverage of this year&amp;rsquo;s event, and reports from previous years. Phone for more detail (906) 228-7749 or the Marquette County Convention and Visitors Bureau.  Autoweek Magazine on the 2007 Trenary Outhouse Classic:  From the towering dunes of Dakar to the thrill rides beside Suzuka to most of the highlights in between, we have witnessed no racing sillier than the Trenary Outhouse Classic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-01-26</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-26-links-for-20-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 03:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-26-links-for-20-17/</guid>
      <description> Trenary Outhouse Races say ya to da UP, eh? Trenary, home of Trenary Toast and the annual Outhouse Races. Photos from Da Yoopers Tourist Trap. wish there was a downstate port-a-potty race to go with it. (tags: trenary michigan yooper outhouse race pictures awesome party-like-its-49891)   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>