<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-brandt/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-brandt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiresome telegraphy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-19-tiresome-telegraphy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-19-tiresome-telegraphy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really should stop writing words for Twitter Inc. and start again writing essays or book chapters. So much telegraphy is tiresome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy the cadence of a well-formed 140 character sentence. It&amp;rsquo;s a good width to set your typewriter to for composition.
Set it to 132 for writing, leaving 8 characters free as a sequence number in case you drop your card deck and need to sort.
&amp;ldquo;Twitter like COBOL&amp;rdquo;, writes Tom Brandt; I was thinking more of FORTRAN dusty decks that are too precious to scramble.
Draw a diagonal line across the deck so that if it does get scrambled, you can put it back together. Use a monospace font.
&amp;ldquo;Wrap your deck in the greenbar output&amp;rdquo;, writes Bob Allen, &amp;ldquo;and rubberband it tightly.&amp;rdquo; Jef Poskanzer illustrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;und&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/uwuBoKkwdU&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uwuBoKkwdU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jef Poskanzer (@jef_poskanzer) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jef_poskanzer/status/810511409666736128&#34;&gt;December 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instant nature of telegraphy is its appeal. You type, and the listeners on the wire get a galvanic jolt an instant later.
If you are fortunate, they respond in turn, and you have what feels like electric heart-to-heart communications. Zap! Magic!
It feels spontaneous, but beware: the insistent response that you considered heartfelt is but a zero point fluctuation.
Someone else is hoping for a response to their tweet, and you bounce a spark back and forth until the spark is spent.
Then silence again, and the wire goes quiet except for sparkless bots, one-way news drips and sports scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We mistake an instant response as deep attention, and pay less attention to the carefully worded replies that come later.
Long-delayed responses are indistinguishable from failure to communicate, and quick replies are self-evident signs of life.
&amp;ldquo;Watson, come quickly&amp;rdquo;, and the test is the speed of the reaction, not the thoughtfulness of the response.
How do you revisit that urge for instant speed and replace it with something that allows contemplation? Not in Twitter, I fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a lot of words into the tweetstream - more than plenty enough words to compose an entire novel.
The question is whether there&amp;rsquo;s a novel has already been written, and just needs to be edited to bring it to market.
The raw materials are already there, so what matters is only some level of diligence and digging and sorting to make it whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Dickens syndicated his novels through magazines, one chapter written after another and posted as it was fresh.
He had a full month to produce each installment, and at times was working on two works simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dickens on the telegraph, 1850, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bl.uk/collection-items/wings-of-wire-from-household-words&#34;&gt;Wings of Wire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to think of it as a syndicated essay, sent in fragments over the wire one line at a time.
It&amp;rsquo;s up to the recipient to reassemble the fragments and to call out when there&amp;rsquo;s a missing piece.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>