<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marginalia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marginalia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marginalia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marginalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</guid>
      <description>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.

Bright idea? Write it down, photograph it, transcribe it, then (and only then) post to the network.
It&#39;s OK to wait quite a long time between initial idea and eventual posting. This also works for blog postings, or at least it should. Twitter happens to make it easy to do in one step for short posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⑳⑩</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-01-01-unicode-twenty-ten/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 09:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-01-01-unicode-twenty-ten/</guid>
      <description>Two unicode characters to start the new year right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on leadership, direction, conflict and change</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-02-thoughts-on-leadership-direction-conflict-and-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 12:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-02-thoughts-on-leadership-direction-conflict-and-change/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;I am a leader by default, because nature abhors a vacuum.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160; Desmond Tutu, quoted in the Christian Science Monitor, Dec 20 1984.
&amp;quot;The real leader has no need to lead - he is content to point the way.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160; Henry Miller, from his essay The Wisdom of the Heart, 1947.
&amp;quot;Only in the frictionless vacuum of a nonexistent abstract world can movement or change occur without that abrasive friction of conflict.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160; Saul Alinsky, 1971</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 9 april 2008 (by hand this time)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 23:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</guid>
      <description>the usual deliciousing of links has paused for a while, but things still need to be linked; here&#39;s a brief narrative.
Festifools 2008 photos are up (thanks to Myra Klarman) - quite a few awesome puppet pictures.
I missed Festifools this year for a memorial service for Wilfred Kaplan, University of Michigan math professor emeritus and long time friend.&amp;nbsp; If you have a Mac with no passwords, you can still get in by booting to single user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>note to self: are windmills prohibited by my city zoning?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-25-note-to-self-ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 02:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-25-note-to-self-ar/</guid>
      <description>Would it be OK to put a windmill on my chimney to replace the television antenna, and if so are there any restrictions on size, weight, or anything else in the Ann Arbor city code?  The Half Bakery has a lovely collection of great weird ideas about a windmill powered friction oven, which concludes roughly that chimneys don&amp;rsquo;t have the sort of structural integrity to be whipped around in the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>buy local, sell global</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-24-buy-local-sell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-24-buy-local-sell/</guid>
      <description>note to self: buy local, sell global is a good strategy.
buy local, sell local is also a good strategy.
buy global, sell local is also a good strategy.
buy global, sell global can also be a good strategy.
so at some point it&#39;s about how well you do any of these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>note to self: only brush the ones you want to keep</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-23-note-to-self-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 23:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-23-note-to-self-on/</guid>
      <description>time to make a dental appointment. Technorati Tags: dentist, note-to-self</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>