<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jerry Michalski on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jerry-michalski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jerry Michalski on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jerry-michalski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and
incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down
everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s
no internal inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough
that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is
always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is
demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under
them. Even if you have an iron-clad commitment to keeping the
memory bank narrowly scoped and revisiting every element of it to
refresh it periodically, the nature of written memory is to grow more and more
out of date or to consume more and more resources to keep fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map is not the territory - and even if by some miracle the map
at one time was perfectly matched with the world - the world changes
fast enough that we can&amp;rsquo;t know any more than a small part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the impossible task of keeping a Localwiki fresh in
the face of reflecting changes in a city, by Brian Eno&amp;rsquo;s quote
&amp;ldquo;Forgetting is as important as remembering&amp;rdquo;, and by
Jerry Michalski&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Brain&amp;rdquo; magnum opus. Of course I forget where I
read the Eno quote, and a search for it turns up William James saying
the same thing in 1892, but Eno is easier to remember as a source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>