<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 23:53:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;d like to illustrate this blog more, but I&#39;m cautious about appropriating artwork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-25-id-like-to-illustrate-this-blog-more-but-im-cautious-about-appropriating-artwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 23:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-25-id-like-to-illustrate-this-blog-more-but-im-cautious-about-appropriating-artwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fca83bdc970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fca83bdc970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 350px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Johns-jasper-zero-nine-1958-59-9913541&#34; title=&#34;Johns-jasper-zero-nine-1958-59-9913541&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fca83bdc970b-350wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are lots of reasons to want to use more art on this weblog. It&#39;s attractive, for one; it displays good taste to have interesting artwork to illustrate your points; and the reader who is tuned to the visual image has a lot more likelihood to appreciate a crisp image than they will a wall of text. That&#39;s all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also am very aware that in most cases the works that I&#39;d like to share references to are copyrighted, and in some cases (looking at you, Getty Images) the copyright holders have been aggressive in pursuing their digital rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sigh in amazement at the companies set up to do wholesale copyright infringement, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinterest.com/jklfa/jasper-johns-crosshatch/&#34;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=google+image+search+jasper+johns&amp;amp;espv=210&amp;amp;es_sm=119&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=_ZPkUsy9JZDaoATuzICwCQ&amp;amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1174&amp;amp;bih=662#q=jasper%20johns%20numbers&amp;amp;revid=321734900&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;imgdii=_&#34;&gt;Google Image Search&lt;/a&gt; and the like of this world that scoop up imagery wholesale and are not shy about reusing it for their own purposes. The hope is that the worst case is a DMCA takedown, and the best case is an artist who I&#39;d ask permission of who would be thrilled to have a low resolution version of their illustration, photo, or artwork adorn this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artwork in question is from Jasper Johns; it&#39;s entitled 0-9 and, if the title of the image is to be believed, dates from 1958-1959. I don&#39;t know precisely which museum or collector owns this piece. If I can figure out exact credit, I&#39;ll share it. The image is used with the belief that a low resolution version of the original artwork is fair use. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>