<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 23:53:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;d like to illustrate this blog more, but I&#39;m cautious about appropriating artwork</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-25-id-like-to-illustrate-this-blog-more-but-im-cautious-about-appropriating-artwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 23:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-25-id-like-to-illustrate-this-blog-more-but-im-cautious-about-appropriating-artwork/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of reasons to want to use more art on this weblog. It&#39;s attractive, for one; it displays good taste to have interesting artwork to illustrate your points; and the reader who is tuned to the visual image has a lot more likelihood to appreciate a crisp image than they will a wall of text. That&#39;s all good.
I also am very aware that in most cases the works that I&#39;d like to share references to are copyrighted, and in some cases (looking at you, Getty Images) the copyright holders have been aggressive in pursuing their digital rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging is easy.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 01:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</guid>
      <description>Blogging is easy. All you have to do is write twice a day without any direction and stay on target until you find out what the target was.
Everyone who writes a blog struggles with the tension between staying on focus and writing whatever you damn well please. Without an editor to nix your worst impulses, you can easily go far, far astray from whatever initial impulse brought you to writing and whatever attractive topic led you to have readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stadium Bridges art survey</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-19-stadium-bridges-art-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 12:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-19-stadium-bridges-art-survey/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor is conducting a survey to get public input on several proposals for monumental public art to accompany the newly build Stadium Bridges. There are four proposals in all. The Ann Arbor dotcom has a review of the works.&amp;#0160;The City of Ann Arbor project page includes links to full proposals from artists.
Fill out the survey!
The artists, and their works, are
Sheila Klein, &amp;quot;Untitled&amp;quot;. Maize and blue striped poles, trees in planters on the bridge, a sculpture of cheerleaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIA free weekend for Ann Arbor residents April 20-21, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-16-dia-free-weekend-for-ann-arbor-residents-april-20-21-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 10:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-16-dia-free-weekend-for-ann-arbor-residents-april-20-21-2013/</guid>
      <description>The Detroit Institute of Arts is offering free admission to Ann Arbor residents for the weekend of April 20 and 21, 2013 as part of their Inside|Out program. Details from the DIA web site:
“Community weekends” are another new component of this year’s program. Residents of participating communities will enjoy a designated Saturday and Sunday to visit the museum free and see the actual art work installed in their cities’ works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self show at the Gallery Project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-quantified-self-show-at-the-gallery-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-quantified-self-show-at-the-gallery-project/</guid>
      <description>From the news release:
The&amp;#0160;Gallery Project presents&amp;#0160;Quantified Self, a multimedia exhibit in which 34 local, regional, and national artists examine how individuals collect and often project information about themselves and others in the digital world. Artists examine the quantified self from two unique perspectives: one, how information about individuals is collected, stored, processed, and used by these individuals and communicated to others; and two how entities collect information about individuals and groups for commercial and other purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QR codes made from sugar cubes at the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-05-nqrt-a2mmf-qrcode-sugar-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 09:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-05-nqrt-a2mmf-qrcode-sugar-cubes/</guid>
      <description>The NQRT project had its first sighting in the wild at the 2011 Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire. Ryan Burns organized a group of passers by to our booth to assemble a pound of sugar cubes into a scannable QR code, and Jamie Lausch and I took over mid-way and explained what we had done and helped people make &amp;quot;cootie catchers&amp;quot; with the &amp;quot;Save the date&amp;quot; message for the October 2011 event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>