<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom Of Information Act on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/freedom-of-information-act/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom Of Information Act on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 09:47:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/freedom-of-information-act/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MuckRock News interview: &#34;Sometimes the documents aren&#39;t the most important outcome&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-27-muckrock-news-interview-sometimes-the-documents-arent-the-most-important-outcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 09:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-27-muckrock-news-interview-sometimes-the-documents-arent-the-most-important-outcome/</guid>
      <description>MuckRock&#39;s George Levine did an interview with me for MuckRock News. Here&#39;s the start:
 In this week’s Requester’s Voice MuckRock goes hyperlocal with Ann Arbor’s Edward Vielmetti. From parking garages to sidewalks, Vielmetti is plugged in to the home of the Wolverines. He shows us how working with public documents should extend beyond federal fiddlings and can really have an impact on a local community. Formerly of AnnArbor.com, Vielmetti currently writes a weekly FOIA post for Damn Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iFOIA, a FOIA letter generator and request tracker from the Reporters Committee for the Freedom of the Press</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-17-ifoia-a-foia-letter-generator-and-request-tracker-from-the-reporters-committee-for-the-freedom-of-th/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 11:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-17-ifoia-a-foia-letter-generator-and-request-tracker-from-the-reporters-committee-for-the-freedom-of-th/</guid>
      <description>The Reporters Committee for the Freedom of the Press (RCFP) announced a new FOIA generator and FOIA request tracker, &#34;iFOIA&#34;, at the ONA &#39;13 conference. From their press release:
 The iFOIA resource, which is online at www.ifoia.org, is an extension of the Reporters Committee’s popular FOIA Letter Generator, which has been a feature of the organization’s website since 1996. iFOIA can be used on a desktop or mobile device, and allows users to choose whether to keep their correspondence chains with government agencies confidential or share them with designated colleagues, such as editors and lawyers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association a public body under Michigan FOIA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</guid>
      <description>The question from a story in the Marquette Mining Journal:
 MARQUETTE - Marquette County Circuit Court Judge Thomas Solka heard oral arguments Thursday on a case involving whether the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association is a public body subject to producing financial information under the Freedom of Information Act.
The association is important to plaintiffs in the case because it was created under state law requirements by the Michigan Department of Environmental Quality, which makes it a public body by extension, the plaintiffs contend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA Machine kickstarter is rolling right along</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-21-foia-machine-kickstarter-is-rolling-right-along/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-21-foia-machine-kickstarter-is-rolling-right-along/</guid>
      <description>With 25 days to go, the FOIA Machine kickstarter is almost 2x overfunded. They are looking to build a system for automatically tracking and managing FOIA requests.
I am not clear how this effort differs from the already existing MuckRock News system, but there&amp;#39;s room for innovation in the space because FOIA can be the world&amp;#39;s worst search engine and any help is welcomed.
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to search the Michigan legislature for pending legislation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-04-how-to-search-the-michigan-legislature-for-pending-legislation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 23:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-04-how-to-search-the-michigan-legislature-for-pending-legislation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m trying my best to track every bill that affects Freedom of Information Act laws in Michigan.
The method runs as follows:
1. Go to the Michigan Legislative Website, where bills and their status are shown.
2. Search bill text for &amp;quot;Freedom of information&amp;quot;.
3. Note with (dismay? amazement?) that 14 bills are found, 4 on the Senate side, 10 on the House side. Realize that this includes legislation that refers to FOIA laws but does not change them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>foia, the world&#39;s worst possible search engine</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-foia-the-worlds-worst-possible-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 22:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-foia-the-worlds-worst-possible-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>In celebration of Sunshine Week, my AnnArbor.com story on just how awful the FOIA process is. &amp;#0160;It would be easier and more profitable to lurk in hallways and root around in dumpsters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a new freedom of information blog starting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-a-new-freedom-of-information-blog-starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 13:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-a-new-freedom-of-information-blog-starting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve been writing a &amp;quot;FOIA Friday&amp;quot; series at AnnArbor.com, and the thought has started to occur to me that it would be a lot easier to write it if I had another blog to use to cut and paste clippings into so that I had more material to work from.
So, prepare for a new FOIA blog at http://vielmetti.typepad.com/foia which doesn&amp;#39;t have a clever name yet but will serve as a place to collect stuff that&amp;#39;s relevant and interesting to open government issues, yet out of scope for the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not an &#34;information activist&#34; or a &#34;civic minded data freak&#34;, thank you very much</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-07-i-am-not-an-information-activist-or-a-civic-minded-data-freak-thank-you-very-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-07-i-am-not-an-information-activist-or-a-civic-minded-data-freak-thank-you-very-much/</guid>
      <description>Let me explain to you why those terms don&amp;#39;t explain things very well.
I learned about public accounting from studying the works of Henry Carter Adams at the Interstate Commerce Commission by going through his correspondence and notebooks as stored at the Bentley Library.&amp;#0160; Adams was an economist who left Ann Arbor to go to DC to help regulate the railroads, and in particular to help deduce by careful study of required safety records which of several kinds of rail technology in use were most prone to accidents that would injure, cripple, or kill railroad workers and passengers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA letter generators: how to ask for public records in Michigan, courteously and efficiently</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-foia-letter-generators-how-to-ask-for-public-records-in-michigan-courteously-and-efficiently/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 11:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-foia-letter-generators-how-to-ask-for-public-records-in-michigan-courteously-and-efficiently/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a set of simple applications that people have put together to create letter that request public records through the Freedom of Information Act.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a collection of those sites, with a little commentary on each in part as they apply to requesting public records in Michigan.
FOI Letter Generator from the Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press.
This page generates letters for both federal and state agencies.&amp;#0160; On the federal side, it has separate forms for each of several dozen agencies; on the state side, it gives detailed instructions and references to state statutes for each of the 50 states plus DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Obama on the Freedom of Information Act</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-26-president-obama-on-the-freedom-of-information-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 16:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-26-president-obama-on-the-freedom-of-information-act/</guid>
      <description>From President Obama in his memo to the heads of federal agencies: A democracy requires accountability, and accountability requires transparency.&amp;#0160; As Justice Louis Brandeis wrote, “sunlight is said to be the best of disinfectants.”&amp;#0160; In our democracy, the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), which encourages accountability through transparency, is the most prominent expression of a profound national commitment to ensuring an open Government.&amp;#0160; At the heart of that commitment is the idea that accountability is in the interest of the Government and the citizenry alike.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>