<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave Winer on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dave-winer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dave Winer on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 10:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dave-winer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The business model is hamsters generating less money with each turn of the wheel.&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-30-the-business-model-is-hamsters-generating-less-money-with-each-turn-of-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 10:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-30-the-business-model-is-hamsters-generating-less-money-with-each-turn-of-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/stories/2012/05/26/newYorkTech.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The phrase is from Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;, noting the path of Web 2.0 company growth and the difference between what the systems are worth to the owners vs. what they are worth to the early adopters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APIs are corporate APIs, the CMSes are silos, the business model is hamsters generating less money with each turn of the wheel.&amp;#0160;&lt;a name=&#34;isNewYorkTechDifferentFromCaliforniaTechThereMightBeSomeSlightDifferencesButYouCouldTakeATechConferenceFromCaliforniaPlopItDownInNycAndNotOnlyWouldTheSameIdeasBeDiscussedFromTheSamePerspectiveButMostOfThePeopleWouldBeTheSameTheApisAreCorporateApisTheCmsesAreSilosTheBusinessModelIsHamstersGeneratingLessMoneyWithEachTurnOfTheWheel&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/stories/2012/05/26/newYorkTech.html#isNewYorkTechDifferentFromCaliforniaTechThereMightBeSomeSlightDifferencesButYouCouldTakeATechConferenceFromCaliforniaPlopItDownInNycAndNotOnlyWouldTheSameIdeasBeDiscussedFromTheSamePerspectiveButMostOfThePeopleWouldBeTheSameTheApisAreCorporateApisTheCmsesAreSilosTheBusinessModelIsHamstersGeneratingLessMoneyWithEachTurnOfTheWheel&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;permalink&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;9&#34; src=&#34;http://scripting.com/images/2001/09/20/sharpPermaLink3.gif&#34; width=&#34;6&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t say this is wrong, but it brings some regret for the time spent being the early hamster on the wheel and seeing whatever value I added to the likes of brand new systems being captured completely by those systems. It makes me want to start something brand new of my own - but then - you end up being captured by all of the tools you have to learn to bring it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best thing to think through this is that all new shiny online services have a lifespan. Some of them grow quickly and then die (remember Pownce? I thought not), some of them grow slowly and still live on somehow (remember Plurk?), others never get off the ground (a dozen tiny spam-overrun Twitter clones), and a tiny handful make it to Twitter size. You generally don&amp;#39;t know when you&amp;#39;re starting to talk to people through some new online system whether you are going to treat it as a long-term commitment to learning a complex system, or just some hands-on experimentation in something to be ignored and forgotten in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you are a hamster, and you see a wheel. Do you get on to try it out, give yourself some exercise, or do you go to your workshop and build a better wheel?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>