<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Argus Farm Stop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/argus-farm-stop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Argus Farm Stop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/argus-farm-stop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomatillo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</guid>
      <description>I bought a little box of tomatillos from Argus Farm Stop. The question now is what to do with them.
Suggestions so far include:
 fried like green tomatoes, slice thin, coat with a thin batter roasted them with onions and jalapenos and make into a salsa raw tomatillo salsa a la Rick Bayless fried with onions and then add to scrambled eggs for tortillas baked shrimp with tomatillos, feta, and cilantro carne en su jugo, a la La Fiesta Mexicana in Ypsilanti in pastel de Montezuma  What I ended up making was a very simplified version of Tomatillo Breakfast Tacos, reducing the recipe to just onions, tomatillos, and eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.
 The news of the day is a death on State Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>A nice lunch at Argus Farm Stop. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from Harnois Farm, and we had 9 at the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily telegraph: A new routine with the Argus Farm Stop and the Ann Arbor Y</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</guid>
      <description>Last week was spring break, so my routines were completely upended. The boys didn&#39;t have school and so I didn&#39;t actually have to be anywhere in the morning. Yet I was up and out of bed and awake by 7:00 a.m. and the weather was nice. Perfect weather to try out a new spring routine.
The first piece of the new routine is getting to the Ann Arbor YMCA. If the weather is nice and I don&#39;t have anything else going on, it&#39;s a nice bike ride; if I&#39;m making a car trip into town for school, it&#39;s close enough to be a good next stop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>