<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Argus Farm Stop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/argus-farm-stop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Argus Farm Stop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/argus-farm-stop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine
under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old
olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction
site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building
that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the day is a death on State Street. A young man was
climbing over the skylights at the Nickels Arcade and fell to his
death when the skylight glass gave way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 1915, the SS Eastland was packed with employees from
the Western Electric Hawthorne Works when it rolled over in
the Chicago River. 844 passengers and crew lost their lives, making
the Eastland disaster the worst shipwreck on the Great Lakes.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastlanddisaster.org/&#34;&gt;Eastland Disaster Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;
for extensive notes on and photos of the scene and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2civictech/&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt;
is coming up on Monday, July 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literatibookstore.com/&#34;&gt;Literati Bookstore&lt;/a&gt; is open
again after a water leak caused them to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote a tiny R script that generates maps. The challenge
today is to find a portable environment so that I can deploy this script
on shared infrastructure. The project took 30 minutes of MacBook Air processor
time running full blast parallel, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t care about wall clock time
to complete the effort I do care about building something that I can hand
off to someone else to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocker-org/ropensci&#34;&gt;ropensci&lt;/a&gt; Docker
package from the Rocker project is the answer, or most of the answer, for this.
Rocker has built R images where lots of useful packages have been installed,
including systems where the install directions are a little bit complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all complicated software environments the biggest challenge is dealing
with dependencies. If you want to use the latest and greatest fast algorithms,
you have to be prepared to spin up on what the cool kids are doing in the
rest of their environment. If somehow you can jump to the edge of the development
in the algorithm world without being tripped up by the hairy dependency graph
that got you there, it can be a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So; install Docker on the Mac with &amp;lsquo;boot2docker&amp;rsquo;; then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;docker pull rocker/ropensci
docker run -it rocker/ropensci R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and poof, you have an environment current to this month&amp;rsquo;s desktop of leading
R developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily telegraph: A new routine with the Argus Farm Stop and the Ann Arbor Y</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was spring break, so my routines were completely upended. The boys didn&#39;t have school and so I didn&#39;t actually have to be anywhere in the morning. Yet I was up and out of bed and awake by 7:00 a.m. and the weather was nice. Perfect weather to try out a new spring routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first piece of the new routine is getting to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarborymca.org/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor YMCA&lt;/a&gt;. If the weather is nice and I don&#39;t have anything else going on, it&#39;s a nice bike ride; if I&#39;m making a car trip into town for school, it&#39;s close enough to be a good next stop. The only slight problem with the Y during the day is parking, not that I&#39;d spend money on parking, but that everyone knows to park on West Washington St. There&#39;s nothing quite like a sauna in the morning to get you going, and there&#39;s a lovely little library by the pool with a very fast wifi and good power outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second piece of the new routine is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.argusfarmstop.com/&#34;&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/a&gt;. I had been in here when it first opened, but now the routine has settled down a bit, and after the 8:00 a.m - 9:00 a.m. coffee rush it&#39;s a pretty reasonable spot to sit and type. There&#39;s delicious day-old bread to be had at reasonable prices and they will lop off an end for you to chew on while you drink your coffee. As a bonus the parking on Second St usually has a free space on one side or another at 8:00 a.m. so I can walk to the Y, do my thing, walk back, sit for a bit and type some more, and be good to go by 10:00 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation at the Farm Stop is sparkling - talked to a fellow named Granger who&#39;s moving here from Colorado about food, where to get a good bi bim bap, and his plans with his friends to open up a glass shop in town. 
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Kathy Sample&lt;/span&gt;
was behind the counter sorting out the morning flow and talking about the farmers bringing in their produce and their meats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between those two changes I now can pretty much count on being bathed, fed, watered, and have a little bit of shopping done by 10:00 a.m. If the weather is nice, I get a bike ride in to start the day, and I haven&#39;t spent any pennies on parking, and it also works to take the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomatillo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a little box of
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;tomatillos&lt;/span&gt;
from Argus Farm Stop. The question now is what to do with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions so far include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fried like green tomatoes, slice thin, coat with a thin batter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roasted them with onions and jalapenos and make into a salsa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rickbayless.com/recipe/raw-tomatillo-salsa/&#34;&gt;raw tomatillo salsa&lt;/a&gt; a la Rick Bayless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fried with onions and then add to scrambled eggs for tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;baked shrimp with tomatillos, feta, and cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carne en su jugo, a la La Fiesta Mexicana in Ypsilanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in pastel de Montezuma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I ended up making was a very simplified version of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eatingwell.com/recipes/tomatillo_breakfast_tacos.html&#34;&gt;Tomatillo Breakfast Tacos&lt;/a&gt;,
reducing the recipe to just onions, tomatillos, and eggs.
Cook chopped onions and chopped tomatillos over medium
heat (6 of 10) until the tomatillos are soft and the
onions are browned, about 12 minutes. Crack some eggs over the top of the
mixture and cover. Cook without stirring until the eggs are
set to your desired doneness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More discussion and commentary on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/edward.vielmetti/posts/10105504923525943&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Note that Twitter did not
supply a good stream of answers, but it did unearth
the one recipe I actually used, so there&amp;rsquo;s that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Eby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julie Weatherbee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patricia Anderson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kate Remen-Wait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cendra Lynn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joanna Hastings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathie Kroll Weinmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Trudeau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Diane Feldt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruth Scodel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feral Foods, the grower of said tomatillos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://argusfarmstop.com&#34;&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/a&gt;. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Harnois_Farm&#34;&gt;Harnois Farm&lt;/a&gt;, and we had 9 at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>