<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Johnny Cash on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/johnny-cash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Johnny Cash on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/johnny-cash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Biggby Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a warm but pleasant mid-summer late Monday morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m
visiting the first cafe inbound on a walk to town. Biggby Packard
is where I end up when the inbound bus schedule timing is just so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summertime cafes near campus are odd. There&amp;rsquo;s not really enough here
to motivate someone to drive here for coffee, so it draws people
from the surrounding neighborhood and from the athletic campus.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been in here before when I was the only patron for more than
an hour but this morning there&amp;rsquo;s a few more people sitting typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first ran into the &amp;ldquo;pocketmod&amp;rdquo; planning technique in 2005, and
here it is 10 years later and there&amp;rsquo;s one in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pocketmod is a cleverly folded piece of paper with preprinted
templates for things like a mini calendar, todo list, quadrille
paper, checklist etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the smallest instance of a PDA that I
have seen yet, requiring nothing more than a blank piece of paper
and a pair of scissors to execute. You could even bypass the scissors
if you had good paper and a crisp straightedge to do a rip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astoundingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketmod.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pocketmod.com/&lt;/a&gt; is still online, in all of
its 2005-2007 glory. That system does an 8-up PDF from a set of templates,
so that you can print a lovingly detailed mini booklet. My own use
has long since devolved into scrap paper plus rip down the center.
When it fills up, invert the fold, and you have a brand new organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now playing, Johnny Cash&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;One Piece at a Time&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;GM wouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss just
one little piece.&amp;rdquo; Look for the promo photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Menu plan: green beans with walnuts and miso sauce, plus a few green beans
uncooked on the side for J who likes to eat the raw. A recipe of sorts is
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/recipe-review-green-beans-with-49874&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;,
which refers to a 2005 New York Times Dining article about Yumiko
Kano and her brand of Japanese cooking.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://justbento.com/handbook/bento-basics/review-saisai-lunch-vegan-bento-by-yumiko-kano&#34;&gt;Just Bento&lt;/a&gt; has some reviews of books by Yumiko Kano (aka Yumiko Kanoh or
Kanou Kumiko). &lt;a href=&#34;http://theunbearablelightnessofbeinghungry.com/2009/10/vegetarian-ramen/&#34;&gt;The Unbearable Lightness of Being Hungry&lt;/a&gt; has a 2009 vegetarian ramen recipe
from the same author. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://metropolis.co.jp/dining/table-talk/yumiko-kano/&#34;&gt;profile of Yumiko Kano&lt;/a&gt; in Metropolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some
very yummy new potatoes from Farmers Market that I cooked up last night,
which were 1000x more wonderful than storebought old potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exit Biggby heading north to North Campus to Mujo&amp;rsquo;s, for some
time spent writing. Close all of the windows, save all of the
documents, publish locally all of the works in progress. North
Campus has the virute of frequent free bus service from Central
Campus, and it&amp;rsquo;s far enough away to completely flush all of
the thoughts of what I had been doing so I can work on another project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>