<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future Self on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/future-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Future Self on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/future-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to future self: on planning ahead and making sense</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-note-to-self-on-organizing-communicating-and-noting-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-note-to-self-on-organizing-communicating-and-noting-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog serves a couple of functions, not all of which are sensibly
part of the same easy to define train of thought.  It&amp;rsquo;s
&amp;ldquo;note to self&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;note to future self&amp;rdquo;, for the sorts of things
that I want to publicly remember so that I can find them again.
It&amp;rsquo;s notes about places I&amp;rsquo;d aspire to be and events I&amp;rsquo;d like to go
to. And some of it is research in progress, in which I get
interested enough in something to write down what I find out about
it and then wait for searchers to come up with good questions that
find it (and more) so I can learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was described by someone as &amp;ldquo;it looks like part of a
bigger project, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me describe the bigger project in words that I used in 1998
when I launched some earlier version of this project as the Vacuum
mailing list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can people organize in their minds and personal interactions
information about a network so large that strains the limits of the
imagination? Vacuum tries to provide insight, tools, and clues to find
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was 1998, about 10 years ago - the net was a lot smaller
then. I marvel at its complexity now.&amp;nbsp; But for the most
part I don&amp;rsquo;t try to do anything other than help answer this continuing
question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to take &lt;a
href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/secret&#34;&gt;a systematic approach
to self-instruction at my new blog called The Bloggers&amp;rsquo;s Secret&lt;/a&gt;,
but as always understanding what you already know in a format that
lets you tell others about it is a continuous work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More
reading: Karl Weick on Sensemaking in Organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe
src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=080397177X&amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_blank&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34;
style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;
marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder systems, a survey and overview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-reminder-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 16:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-reminder-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of what I hope will be a series of posts, and with that I hope some publishable output at the end; my guess is that if I write about this a dozen times I&#39;ll have 1800 publishable words on the topic when I&#39;m done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminder systems are tools - paper, electronic, physical, or some mix of all of them - which prompt you to do something in the future.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The quick word check on the search engine shows up 400000+ uses of the term, and a handful of ads, which suggests that&#39;s a common phrase; you&#39;ll also see &amp;quot;reminder services&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;appointments reminder&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;meetings reminder&amp;quot;, and a zillion others.&amp;nbsp; So this is not new ground, not by any means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular chunk of this space I am interested in is the &amp;quot;note to future self&amp;quot;; the message that you send to yourself in the future to do or think of something, which comes to you as a message in some way.&amp;nbsp; Think of it as a time capsule that you open, or a package that you had forgotten and then reopened; some part of it will hopefully be novel and trigger some &amp;quot;that&#39;s easy&amp;quot; reaction rather than the &amp;quot;oh blah I still can&#39;t figure out how to do that&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My future self is a lot more capable than I am, as witnessed by all of the promises that my current self makes for my future self to do.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes these are things which sound easy in the instant but actually prove hard in the future; others are things which my current self has figured out in essence but just hasn&#39;t worked through in detail, and thus it needs a little nudge to push it back to that memory of how to solve it.&amp;nbsp; It always helps to have some sleep on problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we remind ourselves.&amp;nbsp; We put notes on the door, post things on the fridge, leave out the shoes on the steps so that they go to the shoemakers, paste sticky notes on our laptops.&amp;nbsp; Elaborate tickler systems send us to the stores to buy forty three color coded folders, which get cut up and used by our children for craft projects.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Facebook tells us about our friends birthdays, but not quite in enough time to send them postcards; our dentist and insurance agent seem to be the most regular, if boring correspondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll collect the various systems I&#39;ve used, am using, or gave up on in this category; there are some in the previous &amp;quot;Calendars&amp;quot; section which I&#39;ll mine for ideas.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogger&#39;s secret: note to future self</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-06-bloggers-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 14:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-06-bloggers-secret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of an occasional &amp;quot;blogger&#39;s secret&amp;quot; series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write for yourself. Really, you are best off with an audience of one
to start, and use your time and effort to write down things that you
will want to read in a week or a month or a year. If you are
interesting to your audience of one, you have some hope of being
interesting to some other person somewhere else on the planet who is
interested in you. Tip: If you have already writtten something
somewhere on the net that you&#39;re proud of, repurpose it or reprint it
in your blog; that can get you off to a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an adjunct to this, you can use scheduled reminder services to nudge you in the right direction and remind you about things you might want to remember in the future.&amp;nbsp; So write that note to your future self, and then publish a pointer to in in the future, so that you&#39;ll see it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>