<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plainview Texas on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/plainview-texas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plainview Texas on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:38:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/plainview-texas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA Texas peanut factory - the former Jimmy Dean Meat sausage factory - in Plainview, TX closed</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-16-pca-texas-peanut-factory-the-former-jimmy-dean-meat-sausage-factory-in-plainview-tx-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-16-pca-texas-peanut-factory-the-former-jimmy-dean-meat-sausage-factory-in-plainview-tx-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a kid who eats peanut butter, you&amp;#39;ve been listening to news of the peanut recalls.&amp;#0160; And when your eight year old furrows his brow when you go shopping together and is concerned about salmonella in his peanuts, you&amp;#39;re concerned too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest bit of this story is the closing of the PCA plant in Plainview, TX.&amp;#0160; I was able to grab some old news stories about the opening of the plant, and to compare those with the stories that are running now.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s something like a narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 1969, Jimmy Dean opened a sausage factory in Plainview, TX.&amp;#0160; It closed in 1974, sat idle for 30 years, and then was reopened as a peanut processing plant in 2004.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; The best local source for news coverage is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myplainview.com/&#34;&gt;Plainview Daily Herald&lt;/a&gt;, and these clippings are from their online site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the Plainview Daily Herald, 4/15/2004:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Jim Booher, who has been involved in food processing for 20 years, is working on opening his third plant and is highly complimentary of the cooperation he´s received here as manager of the Peanut Corporation of America plant. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Renovation work is under way on the old Jimmy Dean Meat Co. plant on &lt;br /&gt;the west service road of North I-27, adjacent to United Parcel Service. &lt;br /&gt;The community landed PCA in December, offering an incentive package &lt;br /&gt;which included $390,000 over 10 years with the Plainview-Hale County &lt;br /&gt;Industrial Foundation, the City of Plainview and Hale County each &lt;br /&gt;putting up $13,000 a year. In-kind work by each entity will be done as &lt;br /&gt;well. The package does not include tax abatement. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;High Plains Millwright of Plainview is handling the demolition work, &lt;br /&gt;tearing down some walls, taking out concrete tiers and doing other &lt;br /&gt;work before renovation begins. A metal building will be erected on an &lt;br /&gt;existing concrete slab and will be connected to the main building. &lt;br /&gt;“We hope to be open sometime in August or September, depending on &lt;br /&gt;when we get our equipment installed,” said Booher, who is moving here &lt;br /&gt;from Grand Prairie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;KCBD, Ch. 11, has a similar story from 4/21/04:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Plainview Peanut Plant to Open this Summer &lt;br /&gt;Peanut production in West Texas is growing and &lt;br /&gt;that&amp;#39;s why local farmers are excited about the &lt;br /&gt;new plant. The plant is undergoing a facelift to &lt;br /&gt;make way for 80,000 square feet of peanut &lt;br /&gt;processing machinery. &amp;quot;We&amp;#39;re looking at &lt;br /&gt;probably within the next three months of &lt;br /&gt;putting equipment in and painting and getting &lt;br /&gt;ready for operation,&amp;quot; says plant manager, Jim &lt;br /&gt;Booher. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The cached copy of the PCA site (since removed) has this to say about the Texas plant:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We&amp;#39;re Ready NOW, not later! &lt;br /&gt;Beginning with the first load of &lt;br /&gt;peanuts ever processed at Peanut &lt;br /&gt;Corporation&amp;#39;s new Texas plant, our &lt;br /&gt;most&amp;#0160; important&amp;#0160; task has been &lt;br /&gt;quality.&amp;#0160; We don&amp;#39;t&amp;#0160; request&amp;#0160; your &lt;br /&gt;patience while we figure out how to &lt;br /&gt;do this. &lt;br /&gt;Instead, we request that you hold us &lt;br /&gt;to the high standards you&amp;#39;ve always &lt;br /&gt;expected from a Peanut Corporation &lt;br /&gt;of America plant. We&amp;#39;re ready.&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;Pride in Our Newest Plant. Pride in Texas! &lt;br /&gt;There couldn&amp;#39;t be a more perfect location than Plainview, &lt;br /&gt;Texas for the newest addition to Peanut Corporation&amp;#39;s list of &lt;br /&gt;plants! Just off North Interstate 27 in Plainview, we connect &lt;br /&gt;the Western and Central&amp;#0160; United States with the Texas &lt;br /&gt;Peanut Industry. Texas really is the best state, y&amp;#39;all! &lt;br /&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;Blanchers &lt;br /&gt;Product Listing &lt;br /&gt;Coming soon to this spot: a comprehensive &lt;br /&gt;listing of products and services brought to &lt;br /&gt;you by Peanut Corporation of America in &lt;br /&gt;Plainview, Texas. &lt;br /&gt;Until the list is posted, please feel free to &lt;br /&gt;contact Jim Booher, our Texas plant&amp;#39;s &lt;br /&gt;operations manager for a complete discussion &lt;br /&gt;of how we can serve you. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How did Plainview get the plant?&amp;#0160; More from the Daily Herald, Feb 25 2007:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;One day,&amp;#0160;Peanut Corporation of America President Stewart Parnell
from Lynchburg, Va., flew&amp;#0160;in for fuel and a visit and happened to
mention that&amp;#0160;he was looking to locate a peanut processing plant in this
area, and Miller directed him to Hale County State Bank President Brian
Pohlmeier, who&amp;#0160;was on the board of the Plainview-Hale County&amp;#0160;Industrial
Board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;“As it turned out,” said Miller, “Brian had
been&amp;#0160;Parnell’s&amp;#0160;loan officer&amp;#0160;for several of the planes he had bought and
it wound up with the peanut plant locating in the old Jimmy Dean plant.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sept 1, 2008 Daily Herald has a brief story about the rehab of the plant:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The IDC has issued millions of dollars in revenue bonds to help
businesses in the area, including three bonds in Hale County and four
in Castro County — mainly for dairies, IDC legal representative Malcolm
Tisdel said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The city and county work hand-in-hand with the IDC and Plainview/Hale County Industrial Foundation to bring in new industry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jesus
Garrocho, operations manager at Peanut Corporation of America, said the
IDC was instrumental in bringing the company to Plainview.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The
(Peanut Corp.) facility had been empty for 30 years,” Brian Pohlmeier,
president of the IDC, said. “Now it has a business that employees
30-some people.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together, the Industrial Foundation and IDC
have contributed substantial economic impact to the area. The IDC helps
not only Hale County but surrounding counties as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;#39;s more from the 10/29/2003 Daily Herald:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt; The inducement package being offered Peanut Corp. calls for the
city, county and Plainview-Hale County Industrial Foundation to
contribute $100,000 each in $10,000 increments over a 10-year span. It
also calls for paving the parking lot of the plant and installing a
special water line for firefighting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt; The county approved the proposal Monday and the industrial foundation board was expected to do so today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;
In return for the incentives, the plant ­ which will process shelled
and cleaned peanuts into candy and food products ­ is expected to hire
an initial batch of 35 employees, process 256,000 pounds of nuts daily
and ultimately invest $1 million in the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt; “If they pull
out, we don´t pay the ($10,000) installments,” industrial foundation
Executive Director Grady Elder said in outlining the proposal at
Monday´s Commissioners Court meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt; The plant closed in 1974. The building is owned by Ronald Thompson of Lubbock. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know what a sausage factory that has been idle for 30 years looks like, and how much it takes to rehab it to the point where it&amp;#39;s ready to clean peanuts for use in candy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>