<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apples December Food And Drink How To Recipes on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/apples-december-food-and-drink-how-to-recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apples December Food And Drink How To Recipes on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 08:29:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/apples-december-food-and-drink-how-to-recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato pancakes (Latkes) recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-potato-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 08:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-potato-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the family latke recipe, perfected over time. Ten pounds of potatoes serves one neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: the following recipe may be bad for your health and completely &lt;br /&gt;destructive of your kitchen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a newspaper clipping in my recipe book, much amended by me over the &lt;br /&gt;years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;POTATO PANCAKES &lt;br /&gt;Time: 20 minutes (More like two hours, unless you have multiple griddles)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 large eggs &lt;br /&gt;3 cups grated drained, all-purpose potatoes (see below) &lt;br /&gt;1/4 cup grated onion (see below) &lt;br /&gt;1 teaspoon salt, more to taste (less) &lt;br /&gt;2 to 4 tablespoons matzo meal, or as needed (I used whole wheat flour; &lt;br /&gt;you could also use breadcrumbs) &lt;br /&gt;Canola oil, for frying &lt;br /&gt;Applesauce and sour cream for serving, optional (mandatory!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0. Peel the potatoes. If you are peeling a lot of potatoes, put the peeled ones in a bowl of water before you process them so that they don&amp;#39;t get brown while you&amp;#39;re waiting for step 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Put the potatoes through the food processor, using the shredding blade. Take them out, change to the regular grinding blade, and put them through again, adding the onion in big chunks (no need to grate!), eggs, salt and flour. Adjust the flour to make a thick, wet batter that is neither &lt;br /&gt;watery nor dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Place a large skillet (we have better luck using an ancient, well-seasoned griddle) over medium-high heat and add 2 tablespoons oil (more!). When oil is hot drop in heaping 1/8 cups (more!) of batter, flattening them gently to make thick pancakes. When bottoms have browned, after 2 or 3 minutes (more!), flip and brown on other side. Add oil as needed. Drain on paper towels. If necessary (!), work in batches, keeping cooked pancakes warm. Servef hot with applesauce and sour cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yield: 4 servings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APPLESAUCE &lt;br /&gt;Quarter and core many apples; do not peel. Cover bottom of pot with water, put in the apples, half (or a whole) orange (pref. organic, with seeds removed), one (or two) cinnamon sticks. Cook over gentle heat for at least 20 minutes, up to several hours, until apples break down. Cool. Remove cinnamon stick, scrape flesh from orange and return to pot; discard peel. Put apple mixture through food processor; grind well, so that no large pieces of peel remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; font-size: 10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/recipe&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/latke&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;latke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>