<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forgetting on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/forgetting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forgetting on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/forgetting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and
incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down
everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s
no internal inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough
that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is
always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is
demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under
them. Even if you have an iron-clad commitment to keeping the
memory bank narrowly scoped and revisiting every element of it to
refresh it periodically, the nature of written memory is to grow more and more
out of date or to consume more and more resources to keep fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map is not the territory - and even if by some miracle the map
at one time was perfectly matched with the world - the world changes
fast enough that we can&amp;rsquo;t know any more than a small part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the impossible task of keeping a Localwiki fresh in
the face of reflecting changes in a city, by Brian Eno&amp;rsquo;s quote
&amp;ldquo;Forgetting is as important as remembering&amp;rdquo;, and by
Jerry Michalski&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Brain&amp;rdquo; magnum opus. Of course I forget where I
read the Eno quote, and a search for it turns up William James saying
the same thing in 1892, but Eno is easier to remember as a source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing to remember, writing to forget</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 17:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910333faa8970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hotel-California&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910333faa8970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910333faa8970c-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Hotel-California&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This weblog is an unpolished open notebook. It&amp;#39;s primarily full of two things: things I want to remember, and things I want to forget. Let me explain.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weblog is an augmented memory for those fleeting moments of life where you really wish you had some record of, and where you know that if you don&amp;#39;t write it down now it&amp;#39;ll be gone forever. It&amp;#39;s the capture place for that initial review of a piece of software you might or might not grow fond of, the record of what was talked about at a particularly interesting lunch meeting, or the color of a late spring sky (grey, with low clouds; good strawberry picking weather if the rain holds off, but not good for ripening the strawberries). When you go back to reread what&amp;#39;s been written down, some part of the memories come back. If you&amp;#39;re lucky and captured some particularly salient point, the entire memory - the entire conversation - can return and you&amp;#39;ll be transported back to another time and place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weblog is also a place for the things that you figure out through dogged attention to some terribly inconvenient detail of something that&amp;#39;s not working. When you figure it out, you want to write it up so that you can repeat the process if it ever happens to you again. You&amp;#39;d really rather never have to go through the ordeal again but just in case someone else happens on it you&amp;#39;ll have that capsule of hard-won knowlege written down. You&amp;#39;ll write it down so that you can forget it except when you need to refer to it again, when you&amp;#39;ll relearn it as from new based on your old notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll cheat from time to time, going through old posts and updating them with new information or with recollections that match the time. Every so often I&amp;#39;ll unpublish a piece that sounds like it doesn&amp;#39;t want to be something that I want to remember and that isn&amp;#39;t forgotten yet, or that has such atrocious grammar that I don&amp;#39;t want to be remembered by it. My drafts folder has over 200 such articles, ones that neither qualified for remembering or for forgetting, but that I can&amp;#39;t easily bring myself to completely deleting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some blog to remember, some blog to forget (apologies to the Eagles).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging, memory and forgetting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;750 words on blogging, memory and forgetting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been blogging for a long time, and writing online for longer than that - 27 years of typing. In the process, a lot of it has been saved, and a lot of it has been discarded. I&amp;#39;m luckier than most to have a complete set of my writing since 2003 all in Typepad. Heaven help anyone who wrote seriously on Prodigy or Compuserve or Facebook and tried to save any of it permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 2,000 posts in this Typepad installation I started to try to do an index. My writing here was ranged from recipes for semolina pudding to weather maps of Australia to accounts of a peanut processing plant in Texas. No single index is going to make any sense for all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I&amp;#39;ve read a lot, and written a lot, I&amp;#39;ve most likely forgetten most of what I&amp;#39;ve ever written down. The temporary focus on a temporary enthusiasm carries through for a while and then gets discarded, saved but not readily at hand. After years of cumulative writing, what&amp;#39;s there is not a single coherent whole ready to be sculpted into a neat linear narrative, but instead the sometimes interesting and sometimes fragmentary open notebook of a life lived near the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does writing help the memory? Certainly by writing things down you can cause them to be pinned down into a single tangible format that can be referred to later, and if you refer back to them often enough the transient interest becomes something concrete. There&amp;#39;s a lot to be said for putting words down on paper so that they can be edited and refined so that there&amp;#39;s something very particular that they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is our memory these days? With the ubiquity of the Google and its all-seeing maw fed with the writings of our time, the strategy to memorize something may simply be to write it down in a place where it can be Googled and then search to refer back to it when it&amp;#39;s needed.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Google’s maw is infinite and it will undoubtedly attempt someday to put every book ever written in every language into its digital coffers. - &lt;a href=&#34;http://warrenadler.blogspot.com/2009/10/google-to-rescue.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Warren Adler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeding Google is hardly a part-time task, and I feel a need to feed Twitter which is equally hungry to capture the short form version of contemporary accounts of our existence. Twitter is threatening to disgorge for our own personal use the collected record of our Twitter stream - every sandwich you ever ate, every time you complained about squeaky brakes on the bus, every poorly edited grumpy text mashed into the input box - and somehow certainly that will enter our personal memory space as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Forgetting is as important as remembering&amp;quot; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~emv/project/vacuum/vacuum-0.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Brian Eno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process of accumulating digital reminders of what we once experienced is occasionally punctuated by digital loss. There&amp;#39;s the sudden catastrophic loss of the online system that dies with your words left stranded on it, or the hard drive that craters before all of the backups are done. There&amp;#39;s also the slow loss of unfindability where the words or pictures still are somewhere, but you&amp;#39;ve forgotten the magic incantation that will bring them onto the screen. I&amp;#39;ve stranded some text of my own creation, hidden in the grand archives of the University, inaccessible to me or to anyone else because they are student records and thus off limits because of FERPA. No matter, I have remembered a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;Pop tarts and auto parts. - Michael Joyce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a long time, the words that you wrote long ago resurface. I wrote to Tim Berners-Lee in 1991 asking about home page design, and our correspondence was recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/12/home-page-design-advice-from-october-1991-3-months-after-the-webs-public-debut/266380/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;quoted in The Atlantic online.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;Aside from proving that I was there way back when, it reminded me that finding things online is an ongoing struggle, and that our puny screens and keyboards routinely fail us when looking for the answer to a complicated problem or to give us access to what we know is not very far away. The particular question was on home page design, and I know little more about it now than I did 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By writing I remember, and I throw a few more words into the big soup that try to draw on from time to time to recall what I am and what I know. I&amp;#39;ve forgetten more than I&amp;#39;ve ever remembered, and it&amp;#39;s good to go rummaging through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/12/word_hoard.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;word hoard&lt;/a&gt; to see what can be unearthed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forgetting as a feature, not a bug&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;[New] technologies are currently being viewed as either substitutes for, or possible augmentations of, human faculties. I argue that the proffered scenarios of computerized ‘help’ for human activities evident in the ubiquitous computing world tends to focus on augmentation of human remembering, with sensors and computer networks archiving vast amounts of data, but neglects to consider what augmentation might mean when it comes to that other human activity, namely, forgetting. (5)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemplativecomputing.org/2011/12/forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug.html&#34;&gt;www.contemplativecomputing.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Soojung-Kim Pang is reading an article by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.idc.ul.ie/people/liam-bannon&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Liam Bannon&lt;/a&gt;, director of the Interaction Design Centre at the University of Limerick, on forgetting as a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started down the path of thinking about how computers currently handle the process of forgetting, and as part of that better understand what kind of metaphors are missing for the task of augmenting forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s the notion of &amp;quot;garbage collection&amp;quot;, when unwanted memory is reclaimed. That process relies on a way of marking unwanted (computer) memory as forgettable. Every so often the garbage collection process runs, slowing down the system as it does, and cleaning up the mess left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers also have the notion and defect of a &amp;quot;memory leak&amp;quot;, where unwanted memory accumulates in a state where it&amp;#39;s taking up space but not really doing anything. A slow memory leak in a long running process will eventually bring a system down as more and more system resources are absorbed and never freed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When memory does go bad in a computer world, it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;bitrot&amp;quot; - think about old tapes that have glitch errors, or more importantly old computer programs that have a hard time digesting new formats of data. This often happens when a new and improved technology foregoes compatibility with old formats, with the clean slate being easier to build from rather than re-encrufting some old system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing has its own feature of forgetting, in the &amp;quot;sunset&amp;quot; phase of an online service where unpopular, unprofitable, or unendearing features or services get deliberately turned off. If you had relied on that system for your external memory you are in for a rude surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worrisome aspect of computer memory is its binary nature, where a single transient glitch can render mass storage unreadable, and so rather than the healthy forgetting of the human brain you get sudden unrecoverable failure. Your carefully pickled up thoughts or rolodex full of context vanishes, and suddenly you have to rely on your mental rolodex rather than the paper or electronic one to recall details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Filed under Discardia.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Edited March 2013 to expand and add section on sunsetting internet services.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the end of the notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 22:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tasks to take on at the end of filling up a paper notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read through the whole thing, copying out the good parts. There are bound to be enough good parts that you want to save and remember some of them, and scanning them in is one way to preserve the rough qualities. Retyping a clean copy with additional notes inspired by the original is another way to manage that same task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider shredding the bad parts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~emv/project/vacuum/vacuum-0.html&#34;&gt;Forgetting is as important as remembering&lt;/a&gt;, and you can channel &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/03/note-to-self-15.html&#34;&gt;15 minutes of Discardia&lt;/a&gt; by getting rid of junk that is just taking up space. Of course this is a horror if it&#39;s a true laboratory notebook, but I&#39;m not going to make that assumption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compile an index of names. Figuring out who you were thinking of along the way is at least as interesting to methodically review as what you were thinking about, since the review process may be as simple as reconnecting with someone who sparked a great idea but with whom you haven&#39;t had that conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identify a suitable visual design for a new notebook. Figure out how to be inspired by the blank page again, and use a design that matches something that causes you to start the page full of ideas. A blank page can be more constraining than one that has some structure already filled in, and a great page layout can be inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure out what it is that you will be carrying with you every day. The only way to fill a notebook is to have it handy. Don&#39;t allow it to go unused simply because it isn&#39;t there, or because you don&#39;t have a pen or pencil always within reach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original of this was 5 short lines, and it got longer in the process of writing for the net. It also made me want to discard things in order to leave room for more conversation. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>