<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forgetting on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/forgetting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forgetting on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/forgetting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.
One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s no internal inconsistencies.
The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing to remember, writing to forget</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 17:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</guid>
      <description>This weblog is an unpolished open notebook. It&amp;#39;s primarily full of two things: things I want to remember, and things I want to forget. Let me explain. A weblog is an augmented memory for those fleeting moments of life where you really wish you had some record of, and where you know that if you don&amp;#39;t write it down now it&amp;#39;ll be gone forever. It&amp;#39;s the capture place for that initial review of a piece of software you might or might not grow fond of, the record of what was talked about at a particularly interesting lunch meeting, or the color of a late spring sky (grey, with low clouds; good strawberry picking weather if the rain holds off, but not good for ripening the strawberries).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging, memory and forgetting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</guid>
      <description>750 words on blogging, memory and forgetting
I&amp;#39;ve been blogging for a long time, and writing online for longer than that - 27 years of typing. In the process, a lot of it has been saved, and a lot of it has been discarded. I&amp;#39;m luckier than most to have a complete set of my writing since 2003 all in Typepad. Heaven help anyone who wrote seriously on Prodigy or Compuserve or Facebook and tried to save any of it permanently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forgetting as a feature, not a bug&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</guid>
      <description>[New] technologies are currently being viewed as either substitutes for, or possible augmentations of, human faculties. I argue that the proffered scenarios of computerized ‘help’ for human activities evident in the ubiquitous computing world tends to focus on augmentation of human remembering, with sensors and computer networks archiving vast amounts of data, but neglects to consider what augmentation might mean when it comes to that other human activity, namely, forgetting. (5) via www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the end of the notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 22:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Tasks to take on at the end of filling up a paper notebook.
 Read through the whole thing, copying out the good parts. There are bound to be enough good parts that you want to save and remember some of them, and scanning them in is one way to preserve the rough qualities. Retyping a clean copy with additional notes inspired by the original is another way to manage that same task.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>