<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 16:17:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft launch: day 16</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-20-soft-launch-day-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 16:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-20-soft-launch-day-16/</guid>
      <description>Notes from day 16 of the new job at AnnArbor.com
Here is the &amp;quot;soft launch&amp;quot; definition from Wikipedia; of course you don&amp;#39;t completely trust Wikipedia, but it&amp;#39;s a first start, especially when you credit it.
Soft launching&amp;#0160;is the method of launching a missile (such as an&amp;#0160;anti-tank guided missile) in such a way that the&amp;#0160;rocket motor&amp;#0160;ignites outside of the launch tube; the missile is ejected non-explosively. The point is to minimize the risk of damage to the launcher by maintaining a safe distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam analytics: how effective are spam campaigns?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-12-spam-analytics-how-effective-are-spam-campaigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-12-spam-analytics-how-effective-are-spam-campaigns/</guid>
      <description>Just how good do you have to be in direct marketing to have a successful campaign when all of your messages are being delivered as spam?
http://voices.washingtonpost.com/securityfix/2008/11/study_spam_still_profitable_at.html?hpid=sec-tech
 Researchers Hijack Storm Worm to Track Profits
A single response from 12 million e-mails is all it takes for spammers to turn annual profits of millions of dollars promoting knockoff pharmaceuticals, according to an unprecedented new study on the economics of spam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA2M - Lunch Ann Arbor Marketing - Wednesday at Eastern Flame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-la2m---lunch-an/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 00:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-la2m---lunch-an/</guid>
      <description>Derek Mehraban organized the first weekly Wednesday downtown Ann Arbor lunch for people in the marketing world at Eastern Flame on Ashley next to the Fleetwood Diner. He&amp;rsquo;s calling it LA2M.  You can see what a QSL card for LA2M looks like from the 1920s. Derek, if you want to print a sticker, you have a design ready-made.
 There were 12 for lunch for the first event, and the restaurant obliged with a soup and sandwich for $5 special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Marketing Trends 2007</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-07-internet-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-07-internet-market/</guid>
      <description>Slides from the Marketing Roundtable presentation - this has had 2000+ views on Slideshare already!
 | View | Upload your own Technorati Tags: marketing, trends, roundtable</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>