<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postcard on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/postcard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Postcard on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/postcard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away. I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).
The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch a postcard from the command line of my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First round of postcards</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-first-round-of-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-first-round-of-postcards/</guid>
      <description>A first round of postcards sent via Lob.com have arrived or are nearly arrived at their destinations. The initial experience of sending them made it clear that I need to do some simple user interface improvements. I think I can cope with the current situation on producing the card back photo, but again there&amp;rsquo;s more work to be done making the text on the page wonderful.
A reasonable question is, why do you send them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lob a postcard: printer sends cards via API</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:05:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</guid>
      <description>Lob.com has an API to send postcards-as-a-service ($0.70 per each, full custom both sides). Details at https://lob.com/services/postcards . It works, but all of the user interface is up to you; if you know a good service for delivering a single full-custom postcard with postage that actually has a user interface and not an API for less than $1.00 each, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll update here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started checking in a few tiny utility programs that exercise the Lob API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>postcard thoughts</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-09-23-postcard-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 01:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-09-23-postcard-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>If I were to hive off another blog from this one, today I&amp;#39;d do the postcard blog; one that somehow every single post in the blog had the word postcard in the title and postcard in the first paragraph. All postcards all the time, and a design that looked like it was made for postcards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stuck on a postcard / postful / curl problem</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-stuck-on-a-postcard-postful-curl-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-stuck-on-a-postcard-postful-curl-problem/</guid>
      <description>FIXED, see the bottom.&amp;#0160; 12/31
rather than give up in total frustration, here&amp;#39;s what I am trying to implement, using &amp;quot;curl&amp;quot; to drive the system.&amp;#0160; This is from the &amp;quot;postful&amp;quot; API docs.
1. Upload the document. To uploading a document, submit a POST to:
http://www.postful.com/service/upload Be sure to include the Content-Type and Content-Length headers and the document itself as the body of the request.
POST /upload HTTP/1.0
Content-Type: application/octet-stream
Content-Length: 301456</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten secrets to success (or, ten things that I aspire to doing regularly)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-29-ten-secrets-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-29-ten-secrets-to/</guid>
      <description>1. Send a postcard.  2. Go for a walk.  3. Use the library.  4. Keep your inbox at zero.  5. Find a group to go to lunch with regularly.  6. Say thank you.  7. Keep track of what you do.  8. Keep track of what you promise to do.  9. Always carry something to write with.  10. Get enough sleep.  I wish I could say that I do all this, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s something to aim for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of the hand-written note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 09:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</guid>
      <description>I used to send a lot more postcards, back in the day when I was on airplanes all the time.
 Jason Womack sends this out in his newsletter recently, about holiday cards and card writing in general:  Chances are however you celebrate the closing of one year and the opening of another, you will connect with more people in your network during the holiday season. People wonder how I have time for it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>