<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grue on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/grue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grue on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 22:25:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/grue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>You are likely to be eaten by a grue.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-21-you-are-likely-to-be-eaten-by-a-grue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 22:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-21-you-are-likely-to-be-eaten-by-a-grue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The video, entitled &#34;It is pitch dark&#34;, from nerdcore hip-hop grandmaster &lt;a href=&#34;http://frontalot.com/&#34;&gt;MC Frontalot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;345&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/4nigRT2KmCE?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://frontalot.com/index.php/?page=lyrics&amp;amp;lyricid=47&#34;&gt;lyrics&lt;/a&gt;, in part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;You are likely to be eaten by a grue. If this predicament seems particularly cruel, consider whose fault it could be: not a torch or a match in your inventory.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a grue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The grue is a sinister, lurking presence in the dark places of the earth. Its favorite diet is adventurers, but its insatiable appetite is tempered by its fear of light. No grue has ever been seen by the light of day, and few have survived its fearsome jaws to tell the tale.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/pss/2183381&#34;&gt;More on &#34;Grue&#34; and Grue&lt;/a&gt;, The Philosophical Review © 1961 Duke University Press.  
&lt;blockquote&gt;Mr. Grue believes that grass is grue, taken here to mean that it is green until the year 2000 and blue afterward.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Grue is the color of the y2k problem - green (providing riches) until the year 2000, and blue (providing sadness) afterwards.  Noted here, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commercialventvac.com/y2k.html&#34;&gt;The Year 2000 Crisis: One software engineers&#39; perspective&#34;&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is not a new problem.  There is a paradox, called &#34;Goodman&#39;s Grue-Bleen paradox&#34;, which describes what we&#39;re facing.  See The fall 1983 issue of the Bulletin of the Santayana Society, &#34;on Grue and Bleen&#34;, by  Angus Kerr-Lawson.  See also Goodman&#39;s Paradox.  In the paradox, an object is &#34;grue&#34; if it is green between a certain time, T, and blue after T.  An object is &#34;bleen&#34; if it is blue before T, and green after T.  The paradox is how to tell the difference between something which is green and something which is grue.  At the moment, it is impossible to know.  After T, it will be easy.  Similarly, it is easy to tell the difference between something which is green and something which is bleen.  But after T, it might not be.  Further, any system built on distingushing between green and blue will work properly now with green, blue, and bleen objects, but will fail after time T. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Is there a relationship between the &#34;grue&#34; of Zork and the &#34;grue&#34; of the color paradox?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>