<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ypsilanti Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ypsilanti-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ypsilanti Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ypsilanti-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I voted, summer 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor is one of three peculiar communities in the state of Michigan to have partisan City Council elections; the other two are Ypsilanti and Ionia. This has in recent years meant that the races that decide the makeup of City Council happen in the summer when students are gone and when voter turnout is very low.
I did vote, and I do plan to go to at least one of the parties celebrating victory or acknowledging defeat by the candidates who have the remaining funds from their campaign to put out a nice spread for supporters, hangers-on, or the perpetually politically curious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department does a round of restaurant inspections. Wayne Eaker built an importer that pulls in data from the site that hosts the official county inspections, and is storing the inspection data on Github to make it easier for the next person who wants to build a nice interface to all the data.
Wayne was good enough to find a spot to host an interface to this data that lets you browse through it; you can find it at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area closings for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>High winds took down trees and knocked out power to thousands in Washtenaw County the night of 17 November 2013, and the next morning a number of schools and government offices closed because of lack of power.
From various sources including email and twitter; this is surely incomplete.
Ann Arbor Public Schools: Tappan and King are closed today due to power outages at both schools. Tonight&#39;s Listen and Learn at Tappan will be rescheduled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hit and run in Ypsilanti - seeking driver of early 90s Chevy Corsica - Motorcycle accident Friday August 9, 2013 Downtown Ypsilanti (W. Forest Ave at N. Hamilton St. Ypsi)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-12-hit-and-run-in-ypsilanti-seeking-driver-of-early-90s-chevy-corsica-motorcycle-accident-friday-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-12-hit-and-run-in-ypsilanti-seeking-driver-of-early-90s-chevy-corsica-motorcycle-accident-friday-august/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine was in a motorcycle accident in Ypsilanti on Friday, August 9, 2013. Here&amp;#39;s her posting to Craigslist about it - there is a reward offered for identification of the driver that caused the crash. Contact her through this email address:&amp;#0160;ttrfq-3993561879@comm.craigslist.org
&amp;#0160;Motorcycle accident 08/09/13 Downtown Ypsilanti (W. Forest Ave at N. Hamilton St. Ypsi)  *Possible Reward, if vehicle driver identified*
My partner and I were involved in a motorcycle accident around&amp;#0160;8:20pm&amp;#0160;at the corner of W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer with Bloggers, organized by Mark Maynard. Corner Brewery, Ypsilanti, Tuesday April 9 2013 7-9pm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-06-beer-with-bloggers-organized-by-mark-maynard-corner-brewery-ypsilanti-tuesday-april-9-2013-7-9pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-06-beer-with-bloggers-organized-by-mark-maynard-corner-brewery-ypsilanti-tuesday-april-9-2013-7-9pm/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m planning to go to Beer with Bloggers, a get-together organized by Mark Maynard.
 An event for Michigan bloggers of all stripes, and the people who love them... No formal agenda. Just lots of talking over beer about blogs, politics, food, culture and the state of independent media.
 Hope to see you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit to Chicago via Amtrak, 1988 - Super 8 video</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</guid>
      <description>Please enjoy this video from Youtube user &#34;trainluvr&#34; in glorious Super 8 showing the trip from Detroit to Chicago on Amtrak. The whole journey takes just 8 minutes, 16 seconds in time lapse. For a detailed log of every location in the trip, see this Trainsim thread, Amtrak Cab Ride Timelapse. Ypsilanti is at 0:58, Ann Arbor is at 1:06, Battle Creek at 2:49, Niles at 5:40 and Chicago at 7:34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ypsilanti, Michigan to adopt more stringent Open Meetings Act rules</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-10-ypsilanti-michigan-to-adopt-more-stringent-open-meetings-act-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-10-ypsilanti-michigan-to-adopt-more-stringent-open-meetings-act-rules/</guid>
      <description>YPSILANTI - A very straightforward yet revolutionary approach to open meetings in Ypsilanti says that every subcommittee of City Council must abide by the Michigan Open Meetings Act - including providing advance notice of meetings - just in case enough council members show up to form a quorum.Ypsilanti Citizen story:
The OMA resolution, which was added to council’s agenda at 5 p.m. on Oct. 20, was discussed in relation to the approval of the Ypsilanti Downtown Development Authority bylaws - a separate agenda item at the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granholm, Dingell to present check for Ypsi Freighthouse rehab</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-09-granholm-dingell-to-present-check-for-ypsi-freighthouse-rehab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-09-granholm-dingell-to-present-check-for-ypsi-freighthouse-rehab/</guid>
      <description>via Mark Maynard
all links go back to Ypsiwiki
Washtenaw County
The city of Ypsilanti will restore the historic Ypsilanti Freighthouse located in Depot Town. The project will include major structural improvements to the foundation, floor, walls, pilasters, roof and interior mechanical systems. These items, outlined in a Conditional Assessment Report, are required to re-open the 1878 facility, which is planned to serve as a community center, farmers market, café and education center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put a local coupon in your weblog: November 2008 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-13-put-a-local-coupon-in-your-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-13-put-a-local-coupon-in-your-weblog/</guid>
      <description>Mark Maynard, Ypsilanti, November 2008: Cafe Luwak
This month, the MM.com special can be found at&amp;#0160;Cafe Luwak, where, if you buy one sandwich, you’ll get one free… And the same goes for those urban elitist coffee drinks known as lattes… Seriously, how better to celebrate an Obama win in Michigan than with the official drink of the liberal elite?
 Todd Waller, Team366, morgan and york, $5 off on $50 w/coupon (PDF)).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>