<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/blueberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 21:21:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/blueberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SE Michigan U-Pick blueberry season is here starting July 5-7 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-03-se-michigan-u-pick-blueberry-season-is-here-starting-july-5-7-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 21:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-03-se-michigan-u-pick-blueberry-season-is-here-starting-july-5-7-2012/</guid>
      <description>From the Dexter Blueberry Farm&amp;#39;s email notice:
 Dexter Blueberry farm is Opening Thursday July 5 2012 for you to pick blueberries.   The early berries are ready, Blue-Ray and Blue-Crop varieties. These berries tend to be larger, slightly tart and delicious. The picking will be good to excellent. By July 16&amp;#0160;the Jersey will be ready (need rain)&amp;#0160;and they are delicious and sweet.&amp;#0160;The crop this year is huge.&amp;#0160;We expect picking to be Fantastic by the third&amp;#0160;week of July and&amp;#0160;through the season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dexter Blueberry Farm opens July 19, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-17-dexter-blueberry-farm-opens-july-19-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 21:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-17-dexter-blueberry-farm-opens-july-19-2011/</guid>
      <description>From their email; their web site shows the July 20 date.
 We will open a day earlier on Tuesday July 19. The early berries are ready and the Jersey expected in August.
 The blueberry crop that I&amp;#39;m watching is the Upper Peninsula wild blueberries; the report from my source (i.e. my mom) is that they need rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early July berry picking report, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-05-early-july-berry-picking-report-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 10:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-05-early-july-berry-picking-report-2011/</guid>
      <description>U-Pick Strawberry season in the Ann Arbor area is over; it ended June 29 at Rowe&amp;#39;s, and June 26 at Whittaker&amp;#39;s.
Juneberries are still on the trees, but they are overripe and best left for the birds.
Mulberries are out in full force on the trees and on the sidewalks. Look down for black blotches, then look up for ripe berries.
Blackberries and black raspberries can be found in parks or in the yards of helpful neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basil and blueberry recipes, theme and variations</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-04-basil-and-blueberry-recipes-theme-and-variations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 17:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-04-basil-and-blueberry-recipes-theme-and-variations/</guid>
      <description>According to the search logs, it&#39;s season for both. Here&#39;s a bunch of recipes that use both. The common third ingredient is citrus, either lime or lemon, either in the recipe or served as the with.
Lemon cupcakes with blueberry basil filling. &amp;nbsp;from the blog A Good Appetite:
 Blueberry Basil Sauce 1/3 cup frozen or fresh blueberries 1 T water 1/2 t lemon juice 1 1/2 T granulated sugar 6 large basil leaves, chopped  Blueberry, basil and rum cocktail, Art of Drink:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry growers facing price pressures</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-25-blueberry-growers-facing-price-pressures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-25-blueberry-growers-facing-price-pressures/</guid>
      <description>The Capital Press is an agricultural journal for the Western US.&amp;#0160; I search it from time to time to get blueberry crop information.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a latest Oregon blueberry assessment cap altered downward
Mitch Lies
Capital Press
SALEM - Faced with downward pressure on price from increased blueberry acreage, the Oregon Blueberry Commission has opted to lower the cap on blueberry assessments.
Oregon blueberry growers, beginning this summer, will pay no more than 1 percent of the value of their crop in assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen blueberry price report &#43; Eastern Washington Blueberry Workshop March 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-26-frozen-blueberry-price-report-eastern-washinton-blueberry-workshop-march-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 10:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-26-frozen-blueberry-price-report-eastern-washinton-blueberry-workshop-march-2009/</guid>
      <description>As ever I am tracking the blueberry markets in anticipation of summer.
This from the Capital Press: Blueberry stocks in cold storage outpace past years; Berry dealers see bright side in large stocks of fruit
Frozen blueberries are selling at a steady clip, but carryover stocks from 2008&amp;rsquo;s crop are still huge, according to industry experts.
Sales seem to have picked up speed late last year, with warehouse stocks falling by 4 percent in October, 6 percent in November and 7 percent in December 2008, according to the USDA&amp;rsquo;s National Agricultural Statistics Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry muffins with cardamom; some recipes, in the hopes that summer will arrive</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-20-blueberry-muffins-with-cardamom-some-recipes-in-the-hopes-that-summer-will-arrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 01:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-20-blueberry-muffins-with-cardamom-some-recipes-in-the-hopes-that-summer-will-arrive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m just going to keep posting about blueberries until I&amp;#39;m sure it&amp;#39;s going to be summer again; I think we have a few tubs still in the freezer.
The search is for a blueberry muffin recipe with cardamom, and here&amp;#39;s some sample of same, to see what the variety is in the recipes so that perhaps some meta-recipe will emerge.&amp;#0160; Do be sure to read the first one through; it&amp;#39;s a moving memorial and a story of how we celebrate the end of someone&amp;#39;s life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 cultivated blueberries crop report; 2009 Maine wild blueberry meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-18-2008-cultivated-blueberries-crop-report-2009-maine-wild-blueberry-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 09:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-18-2008-cultivated-blueberries-crop-report-2009-maine-wild-blueberry-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Pulled from the University of Maine Wild Blueberry Newsletter, January 2009:
Cultivated Blueberries
Total reported cultivated production in the United States reported by the USDA was 191.86 million pounds fresh and 156.8 million pounds processed for a total crop of 348.9 million pounds. In addition British Columbia, Canada had an average estimated cultivated crop of 70 million pounds despite the increase in the acreage. &amp;#0160;Michigan/Indiana had 113.8 million pounds which represents a bumper crop and greatly exceeds the 94.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter 2009 blueberry crop - price report from Frog Holler, Chilean blueberry marketing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-08-winter-2009-blueberry-crop-price-report-from-frog-holler-chilean-blueberry-marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 10:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-08-winter-2009-blueberry-crop-price-report-from-frog-holler-chilean-blueberry-marketing/</guid>
      <description>From the Frog Blog: Cold weather leads to price hikes (1/9/2009)
Blueberries--now for some good news. Blueberry prices hit rock bottom this weekend. I can&amp;#39;t imagine they could get this cheap in the winter. Prices could be as low as $15 per case. 
I&amp;#39;ll be following the twitter stream of EuroFruit to get more details as well; country of origin might be Chile?
Chilean blueberry campaign expands Steven Maxwell | 08 January 2009 | Print | Download | Comment | Share The Chilean Fresh Fruit Association is to expand its blueberry marketing campaign to Germany, Austria and Italy for the first time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy Michigan blueberries - retail, wholesale, photography and u-pick</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-24-buy-michigan-bl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 01:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-24-buy-michigan-bl/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s blueberry season, and so one of the things you want to do is buy some berries. Here&#39;s how.
For stock photography, Featurepix has a photo of fresh Michigan blueberries on a bush; the original photo is $4. Another wild blueberries on the bush photo from istockphoto is 10 credits (quatloos? rubles? I don&#39;t know the exchange rate).
At retail, Busch&#39;s in Ann Arbor is currently selling them for $14.99 for a 5 pound box, or $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Michigan Blueberries - a photo album (w/many comments)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-wild-michigan-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 15:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-wild-michigan-b/</guid>
      <description>Webshots contributor &#34;candistackable&#34; has a photo album of Michigan wild blueberry picking from 2004.  In our part of Michigan (Topinabee) the woods are thick with wild blueberries toward the end of July and the beginning of August. I hope you enjoy my images.  There&#39;s lots of pictures, and lots of comments on the pictures, including this one from &#34;jrgoflo&#34;:
 I loved these pictures. There&#39;s really nothing better than Wild Michigan blueberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist blueberries in Vancouver, BC: &#34;Plenty&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-buddhist-bluebe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 15:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-buddhist-bluebe/</guid>
      <description>Geri Larkin writes in Crosscut Seattle:
 The book Plenty is about a young Vancouver couple, Alisa Smith and J.B. Mackinnon. The two decide to live on locally grown foods for a year. I&#39;ve just read to the section on blueberries where they find a patch of beautiful, fat juicy ones only to discover that they are being grown for a local Buddhist temple and are not for sale. I don&#39;t know, yet, if they talk their way into a sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry summers / John Clark / Wolf Moon Journal</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-blueberry-summe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-blueberry-summe/</guid>
      <description>BLUEBERRY SUMMERS
By John Clark
My wife Beth waited while I looked around the new room, hunting for the Shedd’s peanut butter pail. The room and the pail are both nearly fifty years old, but names, like memories don’t fade easily. When we reached the blueberry field, I paused. “Expect to see a deer.” After dropping the first few berries from a height sufficient to create the time-honored “Kuplink, kuplank, kuplunk,” we smiled at each other, sharing separate, but still entwined memories of Robert McCloskey’s Blueberries For Sal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>