<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bob Frost on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bob-frost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bob Frost on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bob-frost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Bob Frost (1952-2011), U of Michigan School of Information professor and great-grandson of poet Robert Frost</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-obituary-bob-frost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-obituary-bob-frost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robert L. &amp;quot;Bob&amp;quot; Frost&lt;/strong&gt; (1952 - March 2011) was a professor at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.si.umich.edu&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;University of Michigan School of Information&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#0160;received his Ph.D. in history from the University of Wisconsin in 1983 and joined the University of Michigan faculty in 2000. Frost was the great-grandson of poet &lt;a href=&#34;http://rfrost.people.si.umich.edu/misc/poet.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/a&gt;, and established the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umich.info/about-SI/news-detail.htm?NewsItemID=571&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Frost Open Access Fund&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;with royalties from his great-grandfather&amp;#39;s works to&amp;#0160;support faculty and student projects related to open access to information. He is survived by his wife&amp;#0160;Margaret Hedstrom; relations, colleagues, current and former students and many friends. Donations may go to the American Cancer Society via &lt;a href=&#34;http://main.acsevents.org/goto/teamfrost&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Team Frost&lt;/a&gt;. Additional details are pending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a memorial service for Bob Frost held on &lt;strong&gt;Friday, April 15 at 3:00 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt; at the Michigan Union Ballroom in Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frost was interviewed for Michigan Today in Winter of 1996, in a story published under the title &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigantoday.umich.edu/96/Win96/mta4w96.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Robert Frost&amp;#39;s great-grandson is not a big fan of the poetry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of Bob&amp;#39;s friends, colleagues and students have written in memoriam, collected in small part here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Matienzo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://thesecretmirror.com/blog/2011/03/27/in-memoriam-bob-frost/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;In memoriam&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Most importantly, he was a faculty member in a huge and ever-growing graduate program who seemed to enjoy nearly every interaction he had with a student, and encouraged us to reach out to him to send him links to &amp;quot;cool stuff&amp;quot; on the Web that might interest him.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Michigan School of Information Dean Jeffrey Mackie-Mason announced his death with this message, which was circulated widely and is reproduced here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Date: Sat, Mar 26, 2011 at 11:49 PM&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Dear friends, students, colleagues&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It is with deep personal sadness that I write to tell you that Bob Frost has passed away. He expired while resting at home, with his wife &amp;ndash; our colleague Margaret Hedstrom &amp;ndash; and family members by his side. &amp;#0160;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;As many of you know, because Bob was a delightfully transparent and honest person, he has been fighting cancer for nearly two-and-a-half years. &amp;#0160;He had remarkable courage, and fortitude (the initial prognosis was that he had less than a year to live). Bob was passionate about teaching, about his students, and about our School. &amp;#0160;He insisted on continuing to teach a full load, and even developed new courses during his illness. &amp;#0160;Remarkably, he was still in the classroom teaching SI 500 less than three weeks ago. &amp;#0160;Many generations of undergraduate and graduate students have been touched by Bob; many of them say that he had a transformative impact on their choice of major and career. &amp;#0160;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bob was born in 1952, and received his Ph.D. in history from the University of Wisconsin in 1983. He came to Michigan as a visiting associate professor of history in 1995, and joined the SI faculty in 2000. For more information about his many publications, his teaching and his other interests, see&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~rfrost/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~rfrost/&#34;&gt;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~rfrost/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Bob was passionate about many things, including a passion for sharing information for the good of all. &amp;#0160;Bob and Margaret established the Frost Open Access Fund by donating the royalties that Bob receives from the works of his great-grandfather, poet Robert Frost. &amp;#0160;The fund was also named to honor Bob&amp;#39;s friend and colleague Olivia Frost, SI&amp;#39;s former interim dean and professor emerita. &amp;#0160;The Frost Fund supports innovative projects that utilize open source software, or that study or promote the open access movement.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I have known Bob since shortly after he arrived in Ann Arbor, and over the years was proud to become his friend. &amp;#0160;His death is a great loss to me, and I know it is to many of you as well; I share my sympathy with all of you.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A number of activities are planned to help us address our grief, and to remember Bob. &amp;#0160;One is a fundraiser for cancer research that his students started a week ago in honor of Bob&amp;#39;s battle: if you wish, you may contribute through the American Cancer Society at&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://main.acsevents.org/goto/teamfrost&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://main.acsevents.org/goto/teamfrost&#34;&gt;http://main.acsevents.org/goto/teamfrost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;We will announce details of other activities soon. &amp;#0160;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;For now, please join me in a moment of silent reflection in Bob&amp;#39;s honor. &amp;#0160;And please join me in extending support and sympathy to Bob&amp;#39;s loving wife, and our friend and colleague, Margaret Hedstrom.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Jeff&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>