<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>West Branch Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/west-branch-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in West Branch Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 08:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/west-branch-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Emergency Incidents and overnight storm report</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan Emergency Incidents is a news service that covers emergency
dispatch around the state of Michigan. Members of a closed Facebook
group post call-outs of emergency services operations, and there&amp;rsquo;s
generally follow up from other members to note incidents in progress
or news stories written from the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All information contained in MEI posts is to come from received
radio transmissions heard directly from radios / scanners or via
an online broadcast, verified reliable sources, or first hand
knowledge (ie you are on scene).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow along on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/meidispatch&#34;&gt;@MEIDispatch&lt;/a&gt;;
the twitter feed has the current link to the private Facebook group,
which regularly accepts qualified new members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storm last night. We got a downpour, some wind and lightning, but nothing
too bad. A nearby &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.a2gov.org/RainGauges/&#34;&gt;City of Ann Arbor rain gauge&lt;/a&gt;
on S Industrial reported 1.12&amp;rdquo; of rain, and at the peak of the storm rain
was coming down at 0.41&amp;rdquo; in 15 minutes. The scanner was full of power
lines sparking and trees down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worst hit was the Sleeping Bear Dunes area, where some of the
adjacent communities had complete power blackouts. There was also a
tornado in the Thumb. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weather.gov/apx/2015Aug2recap&#34;&gt;National Weather Service recap&lt;/a&gt; for the August 2, 2015 storms gives much more detail.
Softball sized hail was seen near West Branch, MI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current 8:45 a.m. report is 60,318 DTE Energy customers without power, and
91,802 Consumers Energy customers without power. DTE does not generally
report outages by county, just by zip code, but I have all of the zip
codes so I should be able to estimate county level totals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>