<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or
is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage
everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging
environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have
my computer with me. On the other hand doing live-blogging from a phone is
not possible, not that it ever really was very practical with any previous setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your UMARC shack access code is &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Achievement unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The todo list right now for the shack is very short - &amp;ldquo;get in&amp;rdquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m
in I should have a longer list. There is a lot of gear in that room
to get familiar with, not least of which is HF equipment with tunable
and movable antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/twitter-marius-eriksen-finagle/&#34;&gt;Why Twitter Has More Freedom To Innovate Than Google&lt;/a&gt; is a 2013 Wired Magazine writeup.
Prominently featured are Marius Eriksen, Niels Provos, and Peter Honeyman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the early aughts, when Eriksen was an undergrad at
Michigan, studying computer science under a professor and lovable
eccentric named Peter Honeyman. Known as “Dr. Honey” among the
undergrads and PhD students at his Center for Information Technology
Integration, Honeyman was famous for making assignments without
really making assignments. “He would develop a particular obsession,
and he would give you random hints about it, but he wouldn’t actually
tell you what to do,” Eriksen remembers. “You would end up collaborating
with people on whatever it was, in this freeform way, without much
direction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to one of Peter&amp;rsquo;s current students. Evan is looking at ways to
direct RF energy at devices to make them fail in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan are working on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://it.slashdot.org/story/15/06/30/1917207/stanford-starts-the-secure-internet-of-things-project&#34;&gt;Secure Internet of Things Project (slashdot)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan have now started
the Secure Internet of Things Project, which aims to promote security
and transparency for IoT devices. They hope to unite regulators,
researchers, and manufacturers to ensure nascent internet-connected
tech is developed in a way that respects customer privacy and choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web site has more details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu&#34;&gt;http://iot.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the presentations at the Secure Internet of Things Project Retreat
in Half Moon Bay on June 5, 2015 was this by U of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Prabal Dutta,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu/retreat15/sitp15-swhw.pdf&#34;&gt;State of the Field: Hardware and Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(embed deck here, if I can)
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LP0965 Antenna is a Log Periodic PCB directional antenna, at 5-6dBi Gain.
The design is from Kent Britain WA5VJB, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wa5vjb.com/pcb-pdfs/LP8565.pdf&#34;&gt;data sheet for the antenna&lt;/a&gt; describes its
utility for signals from 850 Mhz to 6500 Mhz. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://wa5vjb.com&#34;&gt;http://wa5vjb.com&lt;/a&gt; for more
circuit board antennas for use for hobby, wifi, microwave and cellular use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic jam on Fuller on the return trip, backed up all the way to the river.
It took about 15 minutes to get through because of construction on westbound
Fuller taking traffic to one lane. It would have been faster to take the Route 1
AAATA bus via Pontiac Trail, even though it would have been a considerable detour,
or to walk to Plymouth Road and take the 2 in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fire at the Michigan League this afternoon. No sign of any issues
as I pass by this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question when taking Commuter South is always where to get off the bus. Today
I&amp;rsquo;ll take it all the way to the end of its route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Biggby Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a warm but pleasant mid-summer late Monday morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m
visiting the first cafe inbound on a walk to town. Biggby Packard
is where I end up when the inbound bus schedule timing is just so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summertime cafes near campus are odd. There&amp;rsquo;s not really enough here
to motivate someone to drive here for coffee, so it draws people
from the surrounding neighborhood and from the athletic campus.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been in here before when I was the only patron for more than
an hour but this morning there&amp;rsquo;s a few more people sitting typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first ran into the &amp;ldquo;pocketmod&amp;rdquo; planning technique in 2005, and
here it is 10 years later and there&amp;rsquo;s one in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pocketmod is a cleverly folded piece of paper with preprinted
templates for things like a mini calendar, todo list, quadrille
paper, checklist etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the smallest instance of a PDA that I
have seen yet, requiring nothing more than a blank piece of paper
and a pair of scissors to execute. You could even bypass the scissors
if you had good paper and a crisp straightedge to do a rip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astoundingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketmod.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pocketmod.com/&lt;/a&gt; is still online, in all of
its 2005-2007 glory. That system does an 8-up PDF from a set of templates,
so that you can print a lovingly detailed mini booklet. My own use
has long since devolved into scrap paper plus rip down the center.
When it fills up, invert the fold, and you have a brand new organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now playing, Johnny Cash&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;One Piece at a Time&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;GM wouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss just
one little piece.&amp;rdquo; Look for the promo photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Menu plan: green beans with walnuts and miso sauce, plus a few green beans
uncooked on the side for J who likes to eat the raw. A recipe of sorts is
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/recipe-review-green-beans-with-49874&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;,
which refers to a 2005 New York Times Dining article about Yumiko
Kano and her brand of Japanese cooking.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://justbento.com/handbook/bento-basics/review-saisai-lunch-vegan-bento-by-yumiko-kano&#34;&gt;Just Bento&lt;/a&gt; has some reviews of books by Yumiko Kano (aka Yumiko Kanoh or
Kanou Kumiko). &lt;a href=&#34;http://theunbearablelightnessofbeinghungry.com/2009/10/vegetarian-ramen/&#34;&gt;The Unbearable Lightness of Being Hungry&lt;/a&gt; has a 2009 vegetarian ramen recipe
from the same author. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://metropolis.co.jp/dining/table-talk/yumiko-kano/&#34;&gt;profile of Yumiko Kano&lt;/a&gt; in Metropolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some
very yummy new potatoes from Farmers Market that I cooked up last night,
which were 1000x more wonderful than storebought old potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exit Biggby heading north to North Campus to Mujo&amp;rsquo;s, for some
time spent writing. Close all of the windows, save all of the
documents, publish locally all of the works in progress. North
Campus has the virute of frequent free bus service from Central
Campus, and it&amp;rsquo;s far enough away to completely flush all of
the thoughts of what I had been doing so I can work on another project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lob a postcard: printer sends cards via API</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:05:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lob.com has an API to send postcards-as-a-service ($0.70 per each,
full custom both sides). Details at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lob.com/services/postcards&#34;&gt;https://lob.com/services/postcards&lt;/a&gt; .
It works, but all of the user interface is up to you; if you know
a good service for delivering a single full-custom postcard with
postage that actually has a user interface and not an API for less
than $1.00 each, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll update here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started checking in a few tiny utility programs that exercise
the Lob API. Look for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vielmetti/postcard&#34;&gt;https://github.com/vielmetti/postcard&lt;/a&gt; on Github.
The goal at some point is to have a &amp;ldquo;postcard&amp;rdquo; application
that has a user interface like so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;postcard --to mom --photo cute-kids.jpg --message &amp;quot;they get so big so fast! love ed&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in this business is PostalMethods with a Postcard API based on SOAP.
That&amp;rsquo;s not a convenient interface in the languages that I use, but you
can look at the API at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postalmethods.com/lp/postcard-api&#34;&gt;http://www.postalmethods.com/lp/postcard-api&lt;/a&gt; .
Their prices for postcards run $1.50 per each or less, with quantity
discounts - see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postalmethods.com/pricing&#34;&gt;http://www.postalmethods.com/pricing&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postful used to have an API for postcards. They were
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.click2mail.com/articles/view/click2mail-acquires-postful/&#34;&gt;bought by Click2Mail in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Pricing for Click2Mail&amp;rsquo;s postcards starts at $0.25
per card plus $0.284 postcard, but there&amp;rsquo;s a $2.00 minimum if
you don&amp;rsquo;t have credits on account. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to determine
at first glance whether their REST API applied to onesy-twoesy
printing options, though it was clear that if you wanted to send
1000 cards that the pricing would be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>espresso over ice with a little half and half</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 21:36:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple recipe that you can order from your favorite barista:
an espresso shot over ice. Leave enough room to add a spot of
half and half. Cold, refreshing, and very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try: a shot of espresso over shaved ice. I think this is
doable at Ann Arbor Farmers Market where you&amp;rsquo;d go to the stall
where a granny is selling shaved ice, and then walk a plain snow cone
over to the Roos Roast stand for your espresso shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a Facebook post from Allen Leibowitz in Texas ordering a snow cone
and the surrounding commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The weak ties of your social network are its greatest strength</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 14:01:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lior Zoref has a new book out called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1471756&#34;&gt;Mindsharing: the art of crowdsourcing everything&lt;/a&gt;
(Portfolio / Penguin, 2015). I have
a copy of it from the Ann Arbor District Library which was on the
new shelf at Mallett&amp;rsquo;s Creek on a sunny and hot summer Sunday
afternoon. Mallett&amp;rsquo;s has good air conditioning, a very good spot
to be on a warm day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.aadl.org/covers/1471756_200.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of a book like this is picking out the good bits
without repeating the author&amp;rsquo;s technique of using the word
&amp;ldquo;Mindsharing&amp;rdquo; (capitalized) at every opportunity. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to
unpack the approach with a simpler version of the
strategy, which seems to boil down to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make lots of connections online, even with people who you don&amp;rsquo;t
know very well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them really good questions when you are trying to make a decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of connections is the biggest suggestion here; rather than
get help from a small circle of trusted friends, the crowdsourcing
approach to human improvement relies on good ideas coming from
large or very large sets of people (at least 250), and relies on
pulling in unexpectedly good recommendations from people who don&amp;rsquo;t
know you very well.  Lior references Mark Granovetter&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Strength
of Weak Ties&amp;rdquo; (1973) early on, but of course Granovetter didn&amp;rsquo;t
know about Quora, Facebook, LinkedIn, and the host of other online
properties and lists that allow for computer-mediated interaction
with people at a distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an art to asking good questions that could fill a book.
If you look on the biggest question-answering websites like Quora
or Stack Exchange and start to follow along, you will quickly find
that good questions get rewarded with positive feedback and bad
questions (or impossible to answer questions) get ignored or criticized.
Lior points out the there&amp;rsquo;s a very big difference between typing a query
into a search engine and asking a live audience the same thing -
the human element of the search allows a personal connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lior is known for a TED talk (he brought an ox onstage) and is out
promoting his book. The book itself feels like an ideal airplane
read for someone who is aspiring to self-improvement, is facing a
career change, and who hasn&amp;rsquo;t figured out what the point is quite
yet with Facebook as a career tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular
&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years.
He died on July 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Hazen_Schumacher&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher&lt;/a&gt;
has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled
and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bixeibenhamburg.com/&#34;&gt;Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;,
and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bixrevisited.com&#34;&gt;http://bixrevisited.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited has reached millions, giving Hazen a good claim
to be America’s premier jazz educator.&amp;rdquo; (Art Hilgart - IAJRC Journal).
Bix Eiben Hamburg presents 24 different shows at regular intervals
for free listening. Dive into the wonderful world of classic Jazz.
Become part of the great Jazz fan community that already regularly
uses our service free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/84464117&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/84464117&#34;&gt;A tribute to The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and Jazz Revisited&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/bixeiben&#34;&gt;Jazz-Museum Bixeibenhamburg&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In remembrance of The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and a documentary report about the Jazz Revisited Radio Shows!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Midland G-227 GMRS/FRS radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 11:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Midland G-227 GMRS radio, quantity two, a gift from the
Wells-Becker Motorcycle Emporium in Dexter, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replaced batteries in both of them, they take 4xAAA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio 1 successfully hears static when the (M) monitor
button is depresssed; Radio 2 hears nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manual is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&#34;&gt;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&lt;/a&gt;
which describes the frequencies of the 22 channels it can transmit on.
A reasonable next step is to get my NooElec SDR tuner out and see if
I can monitor a transmission. If Radio 2 transmits, I suspect a loose
connection to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Midland-G-227C2-7-Mile-22-Channel-Two-Way/dp/B00008JOMG&#34;&gt;Amazon reviews&lt;/a&gt;
complain mostly that the range of the radios is not &amp;ldquo;7 miles&amp;rdquo; as
marketed, but closer to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; mile to 1 mile on land. That&amp;rsquo;s typical
for this band as I understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same gift also a Uniden labeled &amp;ldquo;Scramble&amp;rdquo; that has a NOAA
weather logo on it, so it probably also monitors weather frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can never have too many radios!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the memory palace
, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent
spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of
text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories
and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which
tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or
lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into
a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time. A good algorithm
will catch minor deviations from the norm and advise you when you
should go back with a fresh pair of eyes and do an edit.
The bigger problem is
deduplication
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at a proposed solution was to look for a version of
the old Unix program &amp;ldquo;uniq&amp;rdquo; that would have an approximate match.
There is also an old Unix program &amp;ldquo;agrep&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;approximate grep&amp;rdquo;) from
Udi Manber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[WM92a]
Wu S. and U. Manber, &amp;ldquo;Agrep - A Fast Approximate Pattern-Matching
Tool,&amp;rdquo; Usenix Winter 1992 Technical Conference, San Francisco (January
1992), pp. 153-162.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these first lines of attack to see if someone had
completely solved the problem before did the trick, but some
searching around and a conversation with
John Hritz

hit the neuron that remembered the algorithm called the
Levenshtein distance
.
That led me to
Wikibook: Algorithm Implementation
,
and its set of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Algorithm_Implementation/Strings/Levenshtein_distance&#34;&gt;Levenshtein distance code&lt;/a&gt;. It so happened that there
was a very slow implementation in the bash shell included
in that collection that was a cut and paste and two lines of
code from being exactly what I needed. A little bit of glue
code in awk and I was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the problem with cut and paste two lines of code is that this
particular implmentation is very slow, albeit correct. Given the
choice between slow correct code and fast code that&amp;rsquo;s wrong (because
of the bug that you don&amp;rsquo;t yet understand), I&amp;rsquo;ll take the slow code
plus a comment and a writeup that describes how to make it faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m really after is just the pairwise comparison of a set
of words where the two words are close to each other. If the
distance between two words is greater than some threshhold, I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to go any further. That algorithmic shortcut isn&amp;rsquo;t in the library
codes that I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger question is how to write a
checklist
and implement it in code to make sure that a big body of work stays
internally consistent. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to have a
categorization
rule for your writers that says &amp;ldquo;always use the
singular&amp;rdquo;, but very much something different to have Test 38 in
your automated test corpus apply that rule and notice when it&amp;rsquo;s
wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto, in checklist format</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-checklist-manifesto-summary-in-checklist-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-checklist-manifesto-summary-in-checklist-form/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My Checklist Manifesto summary (of course in checklist form) THANK YOU &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Atul_Gawande&#34;&gt;@Atul_Gawande&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PfsIMwcCiB&#34;&gt;http://t.co/PfsIMwcCiB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/ZfzP72RgiF&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZfzP72RgiF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Remo Uherek (@remouherek) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/remouherek/status/617272863599513600&#34;&gt;July 4, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy: Greystone Jazz rescue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Detroit Sound Conservancy went to the vacant Book Building
in Detroit on July 7, 2015 to salvage the collection of the
defunct Graystone International Jazz Museum. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice
writeup in MLive, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/detroit/index.ssf/2015/07/non-profit_group_salvages_detr.html&#34;&gt;Graystone jazz artifacts, forgotten in Detroit skyscraper, now being preserved&lt;/a&gt;. Photographer Doug Coombe went along
to document the effort with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.896394770433897.1073741832.170165396390175&amp;amp;type=3&#34;&gt;photo set on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We knew that things were bad,&amp;rdquo; said DSC&amp;rsquo;s Founder and President
Carleton Gholz about the neglected collection, but Gholz didn&amp;rsquo;t
know how bad until he discovered many of the former museum&amp;rsquo;s records
were broken and strewn across the floor. Historic band stands thrown
into a pile and historic concert posters and sheet music left
unprotected to the elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the DSC and its work and to get involved, see the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitsoundconservancy.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Sound Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;
web site, or join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DetroitSoundConservancy&#34;&gt;DSC on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/detroitsound&#34;&gt;@detroitsound&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>valuable archives or just fishwrap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-valuable-archives-or-just-fishwrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 22:33:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-valuable-archives-or-just-fishwrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re writing away, and you hit &amp;ldquo;publish&amp;rdquo;, and the thing
you pieced together flings its way through the ether to some
audience, real or imagined. The next day it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible
to find again unless you manage to produce the precise incantation
into a search engine. There is some long-lasting trail, to be sure,
easy enough to dredge up if someone is motivated by money or curiousity,
but for the most part the social networks of today (Facebook,
Twitter) generate most of their energy from capturing the attention of the
moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of what I write here is
worthwhile to save for longer than a day, and
some would be best to be deleted and never seen again.
I&amp;rsquo;m happy though that I have it all in one place that I
can grep through, happy that I can make changes to it
easily enough, and happy that it can be deleted or unpublished
without much fuss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custom views of taxonomies</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the motivation ideas behind going to the work to move
a big weblog to a new platform is to get better control over
categories. With Typepad, every category looks about the same;
the idea now is with Hugo I can have separate categories that
look different. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of recipes in the collection, which should
be sorted alphabetically or by key ingredient, not chronologically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of posts about books in the collection, which
should be connected to a lookup for that book in your favorite
bookstore or my favorite library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of people mentioned, and a people index would
be great so you can browse and not just search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly I&amp;rsquo;m after improving the browsing experience, as much for
me as for anyone else. If you have to find things with a search
engine, you are stuck in a world where you have to know that something
has a particular name. By offering a browsing infrastructure first,
you cherrypick the best search terms and put them up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of this will need pen and paper design&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight of us met for lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aysesturkishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; today. It was a normal
Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for
the lunch group these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time
to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning
or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a
remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make
sure that the things that needed to get done got done. Among the
tasks that took up lots more time than they deserved included
dealing with the health insurance marketplace and with other
healthcare providers for dealing with billing and accounting problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the people at lunch were new to the table, but since Ann
Arbor is bascially a small town, it was not a surprise to me that
I had easily identifiable mutual friends with two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was delicious, well prepared and well presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll be back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Madras_Masala&#34;&gt;Madras Masala&lt;/a&gt;, as art fair will have
ended and town will be more back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big event coming up is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makerfairedetroit.com/&#34;&gt;Maker Faire Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, to be held at The
Henry Ford in Dearborn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>diligently editing and converting for production</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to get this blog ready for production.
The tasks remaining include the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a reasonable home page with pagination. Somehow I need
to provide some kind of access to almost 2000 posts, and they
don&amp;rsquo;t all fit on a single page. Sort through the design to make
old things reachable, and then worry next about the formatter.
(This is done at least minimally, though the provided paginator
interface uses a list structure that&amp;rsquo;s not nice. Still, it gets
me to what I need to in a ping.) Open discussion on gohugo is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/pagination-and-group-by-date/1441/3&#34;&gt;Pagination and group by date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish to Github Pages, using vielmetti.github.io. I did this
once (using Octopress) so it should be straightforward to do it again.
I already do have a proper github repo (or nearly proper, it may
be missing some key bits). Done; don&amp;rsquo;t have a perfect build script
yet, but there&amp;rsquo;s at least a start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import all sorts more nonsense here, including a bunch of Superpatron
and Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Secret and FOIA Coordiator weblogs. There&amp;rsquo;s no particular
reason not to make it all one big soup. Import from Typepad is problematic
but not impossible and that would be a good addition to the supported work;
in particular it&amp;rsquo;s not evidently possible to export Markdown from Typepad,
just HTML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sort out theme issues so that I get a reasonable display for category
and subcategory pages. I may have to write some things down by hand
to get an understanding of what I really want. As it is right now
those pages render as blank, in part because I need to convert a bunch
of data imperfectly imported, which was throwing errors in my
templates, which in turn was breaking the build. Dealing with the
errored out builds is a question again for gohugo,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/taxononomy/1445&#34;&gt;taxononomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal with the date problems. Lots of dates got imported without a timezone,
but that was not the real issue; the real issue was also that lots got
imported with &amp;ldquo;layout: post&amp;rdquo;. Take that out and it seems to fix things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Request a dump of the image cache from Typepad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implement, somehow, &amp;ldquo;edit on github&amp;rdquo; so that my workflow is easier.
This might only be on the preview version. Some notes on the Hugo discussion
forums
describing how to do that are on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-to-implement-edit-this-page-on-github/1166&#34;&gt;How to implement “edit this page on github”?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>