<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 9999 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About this weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/about-this-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 9999 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/about-this-weblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Vielmetti has been writing the Vacuum weblog
since 1999 from Ann Arbor, Michigan. The topics vary
widely, with over 2000 entries in the whole collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of simplifying the presentation, some
parts of this collection are currently offline, and the
front page represents primarily current work and not
a diversity of interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current set of systems that are an area of focus -
and the places I draw from for inspiration on each -
are as follows. One might loosely couple these together
under the intersection of &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things&amp;rdquo;, but that
would be an oversimplification at many levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/sdr/&#34;&gt;Software defined radio&lt;/a&gt;.
Building radio receivers and decoders in software. I&amp;rsquo;m
using an &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/rtl-sdr/&#34;&gt;RTL-SDR&lt;/a&gt;
tuner stick and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/dump1090/&#34;&gt;dump1090&lt;/a&gt;
software as a way of getting ADS-B data that decodes to
airplane locations. From listening to distant radio
stations to decoding digital modes, SDR tools rapidly
are transforming the nature of radio experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/rpi/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;. This little ARM based single board computer
is a launching point for small scale situated experimental
computing interfaces to the outside world. I&amp;rsquo;m running
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; distribution on my
systems, which provides infrastructure to run Docker.
Pis are cheap and cheerful, and the ARM chips they are
built from have applications all the way from disposable
embedded computers to data center scale power efficient compute farms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/embedded&#34;&gt;Embedded controllers&lt;/a&gt; with wireless data. Products like
Particle&amp;rsquo;s Electron and the Hologram Dash systems point the
way to a future where small battery-operated devices
have some kind of always-on global connectivity. Battery
constraints and power consumption are the biggest considerations,
and there&amp;rsquo;s a wide variety of possible radio frequencies and
associated chipsets to be evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/docker&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. This tool allows you to encapsulate system dependencies
so that even complex software can be launched and run
without going through an extensive installation process.
Run this on small systems like the Raspberry Pi, for development on OS X or Linux,
and on servers like CoreOS on EC2. Container technology
and cluster technology are still changing rapidly, with
every new release offering new functions (and the risk of
a smattering of interesting new bugs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/coreos&#34;&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;.
This minimalist operating system is designed primarily
to run Docker containers and to handle system updates automatically.
As long as your services can handle being rebooted periodically
for externally scheduled system updates, it does a great job
of providing a stable platform for container-first system designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt;.
The sprawling set of Amazon capabilities
means that you should never need to have a data center of your
own, so long as you manage to figure out how to economically
build systems out of their mostly (but not completely) reliable
infrastructure. When AWS goes down, though, watch out - it&amp;rsquo;s likely
to break in some novel way that your application, no matter how
well engineered, will not expect to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws-iot&#34;&gt;AWS IoT&lt;/a&gt;.
This Amazon Web Services stack provides a message
broker based on MQTT, plus a set of services for triggering
functions in AWS Lambda when messages come in and a database
capture with AWS DynamoDB. It&amp;rsquo;s still an open question how
expensive this system is at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/mqtt&#34;&gt;MQTT&lt;/a&gt;.
This simple publish-subscribe message broker standard
lets very small systems communicate with the cloud in a method
that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require that the remote system have a globally
routed address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/node-red&#34;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;.
This IBM community project provides a nice drag and drop interface
for building message-oriented prototype software and hardware
interfaces. Built on top of node.js and npm, it also offers
neatly encapsulated access to hundreds of javascript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Lambda for Python with &#34;Chalice&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-13-aws-lambda-with-chalice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-13-aws-lambda-with-chalice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awslabs/chalice&#34;&gt;Chalice&lt;/a&gt; is a microframework for Python for &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&#34;&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;,
similar in spirit to &lt;a href=&#34;http://flask.pocoo.org/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;. What does that even mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A framework is a set of libraries and coding conventions
that makes development in a specific language for a specific
task easier. That usually involves making some simplifying
assumptions about the task you are trying to solve, and
embedding those assumptions in your code so that you don&amp;rsquo;t
have to spell out quite as much detail to get a task done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A microframework is a small version of a framework, and the
work echoes the current 2016 in-favor design principle of
microservices, where instead of building some all-singing,
all-dancing monolithic application that does everything,
you figure out some components that can stand alone and be
simplified away from the big thing so that they can change
faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do with a microframework for Python for AWS Lambda?
Well, you develop microservices in Lambda. Lambda is a hosting
environment on Amazon Web Services that is ideal for very
short lived processes or even just function calls that last
a few seconds (&amp;ldquo;micro&amp;rdquo;) and get just a few things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Chalice, you are carefully guided through the process
of setting up your first microservice in Python. It comes out of
the box with sample code to do a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; service, and
from that sample code the entire set of Lambda packaging
is built for you. There are a surprisingly large number of
moving parts to actually get a Lambda function running;
Chalice&amp;rsquo;s build system hides most of those from you at the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is available on Github, either to run as-is,
to fork for your own edification, or simply to study.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten as far as hello, world, but no farther than that
yet. There are lots of warnings to the effect of &amp;ldquo;not
yet ready for production use!&amp;rdquo; so use with care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS IoT to Node-RED</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 13:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duong Dinh Cuong (on Github as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuongquay&#34;&gt;cuongquay&lt;/a&gt;) has contributed a node
for Node-RED that encapsulates the AWS IoT service and allows
straightforward communication between the two systems over MQTT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The node, node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub,
includes support for the message-passing
part of AWS IoT using MQTT, allowing you to open
a channel to the IoT service and publish or subscribe
to message topics. The result is easy integration between
the two systems. As a part of this process, the node
includes support for AWS certificates that have to be
installed &amp;ldquo;just so&amp;rdquo; to allow AWS to trust Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current release is 0.1.5 from today, October 11, 2016.
You can find it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuongquay/node-red-contrib-aws-iot&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;,
on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;,
and in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub&#34;&gt;Node-RED flows library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tested this with my airplane tracking code which publishes
from a Raspberry Pi to AWS IoT using mosquitto, and it all seems
to check out OK. A next step on my part is to port the whole
experience up from my Mac where a test instance is running up to
CoreOS, and also to document the AWS command line to generate
the correct certificates in the correct format with the correct
file names.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrowband IoT (NB-IoT) as a low power cellular data protocol on the u-blox SARA-N2</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-nb-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 16:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-nb-iot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the process of looking at embedded radio components, I came across
the u-blox &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.u-blox.com/en/product/sara-n2&#34;&gt;SARA-N2&lt;/a&gt;, a low power
device designed to provide low bandwidth cellular data coverage for
Internet of Things devices - &amp;ldquo;low power consumption and extended coverage&amp;rdquo;
being the operative buzzwords. Speeds are 227 Kbps down and 21 Kbps up,
and it&amp;rsquo;s claimed to be &amp;ldquo;low power&amp;rdquo; though no specific power consumption
figures are provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s built on NB-IoT standards that are
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.3gpp.org/news-events/3gpp-news/1785-nb_iot_complete&#34;&gt;standardized in June 2016&lt;/a&gt;
by the 3GPP project and which are codified in their Release 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first announcement of use of this system is by Telenor in Norway, using it
for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mynewsdesk.com/uk/telenor/pressreleases/first-in-norway-with-narrowband-iot-1590130&#34;&gt;smart parking&lt;/a&gt;
demonstration application in the city of Trondheim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pilot commences in January 2017 and will test out how smart sensors can tell you where there is available parking, and in time make it possible to reserve a parking space on your mobile phone, obtain real-time information on when a space will be free and if necessary be guided to other parking spaces if it is full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No word yet on availability of dev boards for the SARA-N2. u-blox has been
good about getting some of their technologies into the DIY marketplace, with
the Particle Electron using their SARA‑G350, SARA‑U260 or SARA‑U270 chips,
and the Hologram Dash with the LISA-U200, SARA‑U260 or SARA‑U270 chips.
Still, u-blox&amp;rsquo;s product line is way bigger than the availability of
consumer-focused components to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More NB-IoT news from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huawei.com/minisite/hwmbbf15/en/nb-iot-accelerating-cellular-iot.html&#34;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt;
(from 2015), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vodafone.com/content/index/what/technology-blog/nb-iot-will-connect.html&#34;&gt;Vodafone&lt;/a&gt;
(indicating commerical rollout in 2017), and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gsma.com/connectedliving/narrow-band-internet-of-things-nb-iot/&#34;&gt;GSMA&lt;/a&gt;
(a vendor forum).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sdr.hu and the emergence of lots of small wideband SDR receivers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-sdr-hu-small-public-sdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-sdr-hu-small-public-sdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sdr.hu&#34;&gt;sdr.hu&lt;/a&gt; is the home base for OpenWebRX, a remote spectrum monitoring system
written by Andras HA7ILM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is designed to allow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simonyiszk/openwebrx&#34;&gt;OpenWebRX servers&lt;/a&gt;,
running on RTL-SDR or HackRF hardware, to share their radio spectrum and allow remote tuning
of the available radio bandwidth. A typical installation will allow up to four remote listeners
to independently tune in, and the tuning filters allow the listener to independently control
the bandwidth of the receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sample display shows WMVP-AM in Chicago monitored from SE Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Listening to the ALDS on ESPN 1000, WMVP-AM Chicago. Baseball (and radio DXing) instead of politics. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/qFUMHDlqti&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/qFUMHDlqti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Edward Vielmetti (@vielmetti) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti/status/785285239157370883&#34;&gt;October 10, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wide band version of this is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://kiwisdr.com/KiwiSDR/&#34;&gt;KiwiSDR&lt;/a&gt;, a BeagleBone
based receiver which has been developed as a Kickstarter campaign. Look for those
systems on the sdr.hu list with a receiver tunable between 0 and 30 Mhz. This covers
all of the broadcast AM range plus shortwave broadcast and HF amateur bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sdr.hu is not the only system with links to web-tunable SDR receivers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.org&#34;&gt;websdr.org&lt;/a&gt;,
hosted at U Twente in the Netherlands, has its own set of receiver software and hardware.
Coverage is by no means universal, but between the two collections there are hours of
DX listening ahead of you (including, for my purposes, lots of alternatives to pull in
baseball playoff broadcasts).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing assignment, 500 words</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-writing-assignment-500/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-writing-assignment-500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The writing prompt is simple scaffolding: write 500 words about what you&amp;rsquo;re
working on right now, so that when someone asks what you do, you have a proof
point of it. This is preparation for going to a conference where proof of
professional identity is the whole point of the exercise. The thing you
say you&amp;rsquo;re working on should be elaborated on at the top of the page, and
any supporting details that don&amp;rsquo;t fit into the narrative should be omitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this end it&amp;rsquo;s as important to note what not to write about as what to write
about. Better not to write about anything you don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone to pay you to
do. If there&amp;rsquo;s some old technology that is entirely non-commercial, you&amp;rsquo;re free
to discuss it on a mailing list, but for heaven&amp;rsquo;s sake don&amp;rsquo;t lead with it
in your writing. There may be one day a year that people save up their odd
tech stories for (like April 1 for the April Fools RFC series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfiltered personal observations are also out. If you are eating a piece of
pastry, save that for Twitter, where no one expects you to be on message all
the time. Cat memes can go on Facebook, sunset photos to Instagram, bookmarks
of recipes in Pinboard. They don&amp;rsquo;t belong in the professional blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easier to compose the identity exercise if the entire theme of what
you do fits into two or three words. I follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt;
weblog, which is all about Docker on ARM systems. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic channel,
always with something new in that field, carefully and cleverly presented.
Similarly the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rtl-sdr.com/&#34;&gt;RTL-SDR blog&lt;/a&gt; is always giving
updates about software defined radio, without exception. Dan KB6NU&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/&#34;&gt;ham radio weblog&lt;/a&gt; is all ham radio, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do if your writing to date is not conducive to minimalist
descriptors? The easiest thing to do is to unpublish (temporarily or permanently)
any distractions. If there&amp;rsquo;s something that in retrospect makes you cringe or
confuses you when you read it, temporarily mark it as a draft. That one
person who you want to have read a consistent and homogenized proof
point doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be distracted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time when I was a prolific local blogger, and every post had
the word &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor&amp;rdquo; in the lead paragraph. It hardly mattered what I wrote,
so long as that touchstone was there. That era is over - it turns out that
writing about a city in the face of the decline of local news is a career
limiting move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: the process of writing 500 words about a topic may be less about deciding
about what to write about, and more about deciding what not to write about.
&amp;ldquo;What is it exactly that you do&amp;rdquo; is the prompt question, and the desired
simple response is &amp;ldquo;Here is a sample of my work&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample carefully!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No longer prolific</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-no-longer-prolific/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 01:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-no-longer-prolific/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am no longer a prolific blogger, as the last of these posts was a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I like the idea of blogging, it&amp;rsquo;s just that it takes
a certain set of devotional habits to keep it going. Devotion like writing
without an editor, for an uncertain audience, and without expectation of
getting any compensation for it. All perfectly fine reasons to write, but
not all that are easy to sustain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can only do so many things, and when it comes to writing, I find
myself writing more for internal use to document a system that&amp;rsquo;s
under development or to encourage myself to get some unpleasant task
done. The era of writing for a general audience seems to be over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, September 6, 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-daily-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-daily-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee and wifi (double espresso over ice) at the &amp;ldquo;dog park Biggby&amp;rdquo;,
Platt Road at Ellsworth. It&amp;rsquo;s not an inconvenient location,
and the very large south-facing windows are good to know about
as the days get shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 90 degrees outside, and I&amp;rsquo;m preparing to make dinner.
The recipe is for &amp;ldquo;broccoli Calabrian style&amp;rdquo; from Martha Rose Shulman.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find that exact recipe online, but this
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.italycookingschools.com/bucatini-con-broccoli-alla-calabresebucatini-broccoli-calabrian-style/&#34;&gt;Bucatini Con Broccoli Alla Calabrese&lt;/a&gt; is close.
Substitute sunflower seeds for pine nuts.
The key to it is that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to cook anything too long,
because it&amp;rsquo;s hot out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First day of the 2016 school year for the boys. S. is at Community High School,
and J. had his first day at Tappan Middle School. I don&amp;rsquo;t write
about them much, but it sounded like today was a good day all in all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two new front tires for the car - one of them was quite flat, and they
were both quite worn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new venue for lunch, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sessionrooma2.com/&#34;&gt;Session Room&lt;/a&gt; on Jackson Road in Scio Township.
They have a very long list of beers which you can conveniently order
in very small glasses (4 oz) to try out and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current challenge is to get an instance of Salt running in a
Docker container, integrated with OpenVPN a la this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://garthwaite.org/virtually-secure-with-openvpn-pillars-and-salt.html&#34;&gt;OpenVPN provisioning with Salt&lt;/a&gt; recipe. We currently think that the
best way to manage this is to connect it to the Docker
container via an &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-elastic-file-system-shared-file-storage-for-amazon-ec2/&#34;&gt;Elastic File System&lt;/a&gt; mount.
A sub-challenge is finding the right way to run Salt in a container;
tooling for this is awkward because you really to run some commands
within the context of the container. Soon&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thisissoon/Docker-Salt-Master&#34;&gt;Docker Salt Master&lt;/a&gt; looks like a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, Ann Arbor City Council. Follow along on the #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/a2council&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt; hashtag on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 3, 2016 Oklahoma earthquakes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A magnitude 5.6 earthquake rattled oil country in Oklahoma
on September 3, 2016 at 7:02 a.m. The quake&amp;rsquo;s epicenter was
eight miles northwest of Pawnee, OK.  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/us10006jxs#executive&#34;&gt;USGS&lt;/a&gt; maps of
the quake are detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pawneenation.org/&#34;&gt;Pawnee Nation&lt;/a&gt; declared
a state of emergency after ordering evacuations of damaged buildings
in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the incidence of earthquakes in Oklahoma is
low, and there is concern in the state that these earthquakes
are of man-made origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous quakes in the area have been linked to the use of
injection wells to dispose of drilling waste. A March 2016
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/08/us/oklahoma-earthquakes-oil-gas-wells.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; story detailed the efforts of the state
government to limit the use of these wells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local news coverage from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news9.com/story/33010965/earthquake-causes-damage-for-historic-pawnee-buildings&#34;&gt;News 9&lt;/a&gt;, KFOR &lt;a href=&#34;http://kfor.com/2016/09/03/pawnee-earthquake-damages-homes-historic-pawnee-nation-buildings/&#34;&gt;Newschannel 4&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oklahoman.com/login?referer=/saturdays-5.6-magnitude-earthquake-ties-record-in-oklahoma/article/5516769&#34;&gt;The Oklahoman&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter is using the hashtag #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/okquake&#34;&gt;okquake&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MattSchroyer&#34;&gt;Matthew Schroyer&lt;/a&gt; has an automated @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OKQuakeWatch&#34;&gt;OKQuakeWatch&lt;/a&gt; account
tweeting USGS data about Oklahoma quakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New month, new theme</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-new-month-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-new-month-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve switched themes in this weblog, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/hugo-theme-casper&#34;&gt;Casper&lt;/a&gt;
from Valère JEANTET who ported it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of the theme is that it&amp;rsquo;s neat
and clean and looks like other people&amp;rsquo;s work. The
biggest disadvantage is that I have 80+ pages of
paginated weblog going back into the dim mists of time,
and this theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t come out of the box with
support for that kind of deep back list in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a bigger, more existential question here. I&amp;rsquo;ve
written on the order of 600,000 words &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rdquo;, whatever
&amp;ldquo;here&amp;rdquo; means, on some rather large number of different
topics. How on earth do you reorganize that into something
sensible, or do you simply not bother?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>full stack plane spotting and data analysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The task at hand is simple. Whenever a particular airplane is visible overhead,
send out a tweet with that notice. Don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself with this announcement
more than twice an hour, but try not to have too much lag in reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full stack of hardware and software to do this is not particularly
complicated to use once you get it all running, but there are a series
of issues and observations along the way that add to the complexity. I&amp;rsquo;ll
walk through the whole thing start to finish, and let you know where I
left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic toolkit is dump1090-mutability for plane spotting,
Node-RED for wiring flows for data processing, and
Docker to package up the bits that are stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plane-spotting:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Plane spotting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/&#34;&gt;When last I wrote&lt;/a&gt;,
I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;dump1090&lt;/a&gt;
running on my MacBook. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the same software and gotten
the latest dev release going on a Raspberry Pi 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to a smaller, simpler antenna, and the result was positive: instead of
having a 40 to 50 nautical mile range, now I&amp;rsquo;m in the 60 to 65 nm range (about 110 km).
It might also help that the Pi 2 is not really doing very much else. That
particular Pi 2 setup is using a slightly back-rev version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; software for the Pi, so it has all
of the modern conveniences plus an instance of Docker on board. The
temptation was to Dockerize everything, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone there yet;
the available Docker prebuilt releases don&amp;rsquo;t have the bleeding edge of
the dump1090-mutability code, and I want to see how the whole thing runs
native for a while before containerizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snag that slowed down this deployment a little was Google&amp;rsquo;s decision
to enforce an API key for personal use of Google Maps. In response, the
very latest dump1090-mutability pulled out its Google Maps support, and
went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://openlayers.org/&#34;&gt;OpenLayers&lt;/a&gt;. This new support gives
access to all kinds of base maps, including some aviation-specific
charts. (&amp;ldquo;Not for use in navigation.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another piece of this was bringing up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttpd.net/&#34;&gt;lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;
(&amp;ldquo;lighty&amp;rdquo;), a lightweight HTTP server that replaces the rickety
built-in HTTP server that dump1090 had originally shipped with.
Configuration following the supplied instructions was simple,
and lighttpd looks like a very suitable system to put in place to
serve HTTP on embedded-class system that need flexiblity but not
a big footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other component in the Pi setup is an ADS-B feed to the excellent
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;Planefinder&lt;/a&gt; site. Planefinder provides a Debian
package for setting up the feed, and it runs neatly with only a minimum
of overhead. As a bonus you get free use of their apps, which are
notable for running in much closer to real time than others I have seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi does not yet have a working OpenVPN configuration, so I can&amp;rsquo;t get
to it over the net directly. For that I plan to revisit the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-07-managing-raspberry-pi-openvpn-with-salt/&#34;&gt;SaltStack for Pi&lt;/a&gt;
configuration I wrote up last September. In the interim, salt has
been upgraded, and perhaps it will be a little more stable over bad
connections; we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090 provides a data feed in a convenient JSON format, available
through a URL on a standard configuruation. The ADS-B messages themselves
are binary encoded, but the system brings them into JSON so that all
of the downstream processing is very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data handling is so straightforward that you can do it all without
needing any special-purpose processing nodes in IBM&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org&#34;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;.
A standard HTTP in node polls the data at the pace that you choose,
and a simple function pulls apart the record of all planes into
individual records for each plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Node-RED running is continuing to get easier over time.
I&amp;rsquo;m doing prototyping work on my Macintosh again, using the
new &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2016/06/docker-mac-windows-public-beta/&#34;&gt;Docker for Mac&lt;/a&gt;
setup to pick up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/cpswan/node-red/&#34;&gt;Node-RED container&lt;/a&gt;
to do the work in. &lt;a href=&#34;https://kitematic.com/&#34;&gt;Kitematic&lt;/a&gt; comes with Docker for Mac,
providing a convenient dashboard and interface to Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Do note, however, that if you got Docker for Mac running a few months
ago, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go through a rebuild process to go to the latest
beta. To &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/troubleshoot/#/recreate-or-update-your-containers-after-beta-18-upgrade&#34;&gt;recreate or update your containers after Beta 18 upgrade&lt;/a&gt;
follow the provided instructions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have both Node-RED and dump1090 running, connecting the
two together is straightforward. I started with this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dceejay/3288996fefdc3aef04846496277b6444&#34;&gt;gist from dceejay&lt;/a&gt; which
provides the basic flow and feeds into a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-web-worldmap&#34;&gt;worldmap node&lt;/a&gt; that
is a general programmable interface for putting things on a map. My
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/vielmetti/6329ea5a49dadd2f106980a20727d16e&#34;&gt;updated dump1090 gist for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;
adapts the data for a slightly different format between dump1090 forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here in it&amp;rsquo;s relatively clear sailing. Set up a flow downstream
from the plane messages, using a filter node to match the name or
ICAO hex code of the airplane that you want to track. Wire it through
a delay filter to set the frequency of messages you want to
allow through, and a formatting node to pretty up the message in
a form suitable for Twitter output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;incomplete-image-and-next-steps:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Incomplete image and next steps.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively complex stack, but it all fits neatly on a Raspberry Pi 2,
and with a little bit more elbow grease it should be possible to containerize
everything so that it Just Works and can be made to reliably work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to have OpenVPN running on the Pi 2, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet, pending
rework of Salt to get that to a current version and to port all of the
work I did from an earlier version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m picking up planes from 60+ nm away, but I know that with a better
antenna, bandpass filter, and amplifier that I can do better.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://puck.nether.net/~jared/blog/?p=160&#34;&gt;Jared Mauch&amp;rsquo;s parts list&lt;/a&gt;
would be the place to go for starters with a very modest budget of
a couple of hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reception is best if you have a clear view of the sky, which suggests
an outdoors installation, powering the Pi with power over ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is running on a Pi 2, but reports from Jared and from Phil Karn KA9Q
suggest that if you do upgrade the reception that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
saturate the Pi 2. Fortunately a Pi 3 does even better at the intended task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out what the very best way to create a Docker image
that handles Node-RED, especially the installation of additional nodes
and the management of flows. You&amp;rsquo;d like to have the whole thing suitably
tidy that it could be all loaded in from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090-mutability is still mutating! It&amp;rsquo;s under active development,
both at the presentation layer and at the decoder layer. So it would
be appropriate to have the attitude for at least one development machine
to be sure that you were ready to rebuild from source whenever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only have half of this stack running (the Node-RED side) but no access
to radios, you can find an existing dump1090 installation and pull the
JSON from there. This is best done only via prior arrangement and only
for testing purposes or for specific tasks. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to crank up Node-RED
to poll a URL every second; don&amp;rsquo;t do that to a poor little Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planes I want to watch don&amp;rsquo;t take off very often - that&amp;rsquo;s the appeal
of watching for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plane finding with dump1090</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2015 I wrote briefly about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/&#34;&gt;plane spotting with dump1090&lt;/a&gt;.
In short, many airplanes have ADS-B transponders which squawk out
their location, airspeed, and current conditions, and you can pick
up those transmissions using an inexpensive RTL-SDR tuner stick and
a simple antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into this again to see if I can get a better
understanding of how it works as well as to take advantage of a year plus
of software development. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the state of the art
circa July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware: I&amp;rsquo;m using a Nooelec NESDR Mini 2 tuner stick plugged into a MacBook Air
as a portable plane-finding system. I have a Raspberry Pi 2 which looks
like it could be a permanent installation for this, though the recommendation
for busy skies is a Pi 3 which is enough faster to make a difference if you
have a good antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antenna: The Mini 2 comes with a small whip antenna with a magnetic base, and I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing
a larger antenna. There are scads of antenna designs out there for inexpensive
small antennas tuned to 1090 Mhz, but I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet. There are also
filters and amplifiers that can improve plane-finding capabilities; also not
there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software: Here&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;ve made progress. The dump1090 software has been
forked several times, each time with just a little bit more sophistication
on the visual display as well as refinements of the decoding system. The
one I&amp;rsquo;m using right now is a fork by &amp;ldquo;mutability&amp;rdquo;, available at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&lt;/a&gt; . It&amp;rsquo;s notable for being
designed to run on a Raspberry Pi, as well as a bunch of small changes
in the display that make it more pleasant to use than the older software
I had been using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Range: Just like I reported back in 2015, the typical results from my
house are a range of 40-50 nautical miles in every direction. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet taken the rig to my favorite plane-spotting cafe &amp;ndash; the Biggby at
Platt and Ellsworth &amp;ndash; which has a clear view of the southern sky at
a good elevation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweaking the setup: Aside from changing out the hardware and relocating
the antenna, the tweakable changes seem to be adjusting the gain control
on the SDR. Initial experiments don&amp;rsquo;t give me strong conclusions as to
what&amp;rsquo;s best. The reviews of a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/ADS-B-1090MHz-Band-pass-SMA-Filter/dp/B010GBQXK8&#34;&gt;$20 band pass filter&lt;/a&gt; are
promising for increasing the range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeding the data elsewhere: One of the collective efforts around looking for
airplanes is the ability to share the data with commerical and non-commericial
systems that aggregate data from around the world. I&amp;rsquo;m digging
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;http://planefinder.net&lt;/a&gt; which has a nifty near-real-time feed of ADS-B
and FAA and other international data for tracking flights. Planefinder is
fast enough that I can hear an airplane overheard, check the display,
and figure out which flight is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellite plane finding: The &lt;a href=&#34;https://directory.eoportal.org/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/gomx-3&#34;&gt;GOMX-3 satellite&lt;/a&gt;
has an SDR with ADS-B reception and has successfully
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airtrafficmanagement.net/2016/07/fr24-completes-satbased-adsb-tracking/&#34;&gt;fed data to Flightradar24&lt;/a&gt;,
another commericial plane tracking system. ADS-B receivers are expected
to be installed on the Iridium system over the next couple of years,
which should over time provide improved global coverage and visibility
into the current status of aircraft over oceans and the poles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it looks like: I don&amp;rsquo;t have a permanent installation running,
but if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the airspace above San Diego, you can
see Phil Karn KA9Q&amp;rsquo;s system at &lt;a href=&#34;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&#34;&gt;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&lt;/a&gt;
noting that he&amp;rsquo;s in easy range of picking traffic into LAX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github private repositories</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Github has changed their pricing strategy to allow individual
accounts to have more private repositories. This is a welcome
change for accounts like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their change, enterprise pricing has increased.
I&amp;rsquo;m told that this will multiply the bills that some companies
will see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post tests a new private repo, and links to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pricing&#34;&gt;Github pricing&lt;/a&gt; for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A commonplace reader</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easier and faster to fill a page by quoting from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace book is the annotated scrapbook, carefully collecting
bits from other writers with just enough commentary and selection to
make them your own. If these were written in this era you&amp;rsquo;d call it
&amp;ldquo;curation&amp;rdquo;, though I can only think of that word in the context of
&amp;ldquo;curated meats&amp;rdquo;, somewhat salty and dry and meant to be preserved for
some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the commonplace book. Why write your own words, when there are
so many other good ones already written to quote from? As it is said,
though &lt;a href=&#34;http://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/03/06/artists-steal/&#34;&gt;no attribution is reliable&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immature artists copy, great artists steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artist steal from tonight is Brian Eno, in particular his &lt;a href=&#34;http://oblicard.com/&#34;&gt;Oblique Strategies&lt;/a&gt;,
which I now have as three lines of shell script plus 128 lines of text. A sample, intended
to be drawn at random:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not building a wall but making a brick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to brick-machines, this from Popular Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bricks are fairly easy to make, but in the developing world, traditional fired bricks are sometimes weak and crumble-prone, while cement ones are often unaffordable. The Vermeer BP714 is the first compressed-earth-block machine that makes strong air-dried bricks out of dirt. Its bricks don&amp;rsquo;t just exceed U.S. cement-code strength requirements—they&amp;rsquo;re 20 to 30 percent stronger, and cheaper than other machines&amp;rsquo; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course that&amp;rsquo;s the story you want to tell when someone else
has a lot of mud and you have a lot of machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace style of writing allows you to fill a page
with text faster, since you&amp;rsquo;re cutting and pasting it in
rather than sweating to find the exact words yourself. The
downside is that you might sometimes have to hunt for the
correct word, and it will be obvious that it&amp;rsquo;s someone
else&amp;rsquo;s correct word. There is no question of plagiarism,
just of assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious crimes in terms of writing are that of plagiarism and copyright violation. (Reality Studio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long as we are going down this route, it&amp;rsquo;s worth rejecting
plagiarism as a thought-crime. From Kenneth Goldsmith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems an appropriate response to a new condition in writing: With an unprecedented amount of available text, our problem is not needing to write more of it; instead, we must learn to negotiate the vast quantity that exists. How I make my way through this thicket of information—how I manage it, parse it, organize and distribute it—is what distinguishes my writing from yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make patchworks. Most two word phrases can be easily found on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most two-word phrases are not produced under unpleasant stress, but in interest or excitement. (Penelope Leach, &amp;ldquo;Babyhood&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to provide the reader with enough information so that the article can be easily found on the References page. (Communication Research Methods in Postmodern Culture)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists of real-world materials and their refractive indexes are easily found on the Internet.  (Lanier, &amp;ldquo;Maya Studio Projects Texturing and Writing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retroactively we can construct some level of patchwork that we can crib from, in interest or excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bots are hot - again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title of the post is taken from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/1996/04/netbots/&#34;&gt;1996 Wired article&lt;/a&gt;
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/koxinga21&#34;&gt;Andrew Leonard&lt;/a&gt;
describing the state of automated systems in the dot-com
era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web robots – spiders, wanderers, and worms. Cancelbots, Lazarus, and Automoose. Chatterbots, softbots, userbots, taskbots, knowbots, and mailbots. MrBot and MrsBot. Warbots, clonebots, floodbots, annoybots, hackbots, and Vladbots. Gaybots, gossipbots, and gamebots. Skeleton bots, spybots, and sloth bots. Xbots and meta-bots. Eggdrop bots. Motorcycle bull dyke bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots are hot today in part because natural langauge processing
has improved to the point where &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/05/Google-supercharges-machine-learning-tasks-with-custom-chip.html&#34;&gt;Google can build hardware&lt;/a&gt;
to speed up their software algorithms and run their immense
training corpuses through it quickly to fine tune their approach.
The output of this effort is ASICs that speed up their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/&#34;&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/a&gt;
algorithm for machine learning. Thus Google can safely give away
their software, knowing that anyone else running it will use
a multiple of the energy that it takes Google to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s instructive to look at the changes throughout the years and
how bots have co-evolved with the networks and computer systems
that they inhabit. Early AIs like ELIZA and PARRY lived on
mainframes connected to very slow wide-area networks, and it
was years before the two of them talked to each other online.
The 1980s and 1990s brought Usenet and the automation that could
live on store-and-forward networks. AOL Instant Messenger&amp;rsquo;s
ubiquitous chat met popular culture and the emergence of
advertising bots like GooglyMinotaur, which promoted the music
of Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing what I think is some kind of manuscript about
bots and their personalities, a biographical dictionary of
emerging intelligences. I&amp;rsquo;m at about 10,000 words. It&amp;rsquo;s a challenge
to try to corral that much quasi-intelligence onto the page, including
trying as best I can to characterize some systems that are
known only by people&amp;rsquo;s memories of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>