<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist Rebecca Moss aboard the Hanjin Geneva</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-rebecca-moss-aboard-the-hanjin-geneva/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-rebecca-moss-aboard-the-hanjin-geneva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hanjin Shipping is a Korean container shipping firm that has gone into
bankruptcy, disrupting the worldwide container network. About 8 percent
of transpacific cargo goes through this carrier, and as of this writing
the ships are in an uncertain legal status, subject to seizure by creditors
at ports if they land with their cargo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hanjin&amp;rsquo;s bankruptcy is the largest ever to hit the shipping industry
so there&amp;rsquo;s no roadmap as to what will happen now, no precedent of
comparable scale.&amp;rdquo; - BBC News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Moss is aboard the Haijin Geneva, which is off the coast of Japan,
awaiting orders. She signed up for a 23 day artist&amp;rsquo;s residency aboard the
ship and then abruptly discovered that her cruise would not be quite what
she expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to follow all of the details of Haijin, and the situation
is fluid, changing from day to day. Here are some resources that capture
the current situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Moss&amp;rsquo;s odyssey is being chronicled by Kevin C. Griffin of the
Vancouver Sun. &lt;a href=&#34;http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/british-artist-on-vancouver-residency-stranded-on-hanjin-freighter&#34;&gt;British artist on Vancouver residency stranded on Hanjin freighter&lt;/a&gt;
from September 1, 2016; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vancouversun.com/entertainment/local-arts/art-seen-stranded-at-sea-british-artist-sees-her-surroundings-with-new-eyes&#34;&gt;ART SEEN: Stranded at sea, British artist sees her surroundings with new eyes&lt;/a&gt;
from September 2, 2016. Kimberly Phillips, the curator/director at Access Gallery,
is in touch with Rebecca by email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hanjin Geneva is tracked in global waters via a system known as AIS.
Follow its location through these services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vesselfinder.com/vessels/HANJIN-GENEVA-IMO-9215646-MMSI-211377300&#34;&gt;Vessel Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marinetraffic.com/en/ais/details/ships/shipid:133837/mmsi:211377300/imo:9215646/vessel:HANJIN_GENEVA&#34;&gt;Marine Traffic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marinetraffic.com/en/photos/of/ships/photo_keywords:9215646&#34;&gt;Marine Traffic photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fleetmon.com/vessels/hanjin-geneva_9215646_26729/&#34;&gt;Fleetmon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shipspotting.com&#34;&gt;Ship Spotting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A snapshot taken September 6 placed the ship off the cost of Chiba, Japan.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/images/Haijin-Geneva.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Haijin Geneva via Ship Spotting&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some good sources for news on Hanjin Shipping:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joc.com/maritime-news/container-lines/hanjin-shipping&#34;&gt;JOC.COM&lt;/a&gt; has a section; subscription required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lloydslist.com/ll/topic/hanjin/&#34;&gt;Lloyd&amp;rsquo;s List&lt;/a&gt; subscription required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/117930.KS/key-developments&#34;&gt;Reuters: Hanjin Shipping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wsj.com/news/types/asian-business-news&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal: Asian Business News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/business-37241727&#34;&gt;BBC News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always Twitter is going to move faster for news than most other news sources;
the hashtag #&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hashtag/hanjin&#34;&gt;hanjin&lt;/a&gt; or #&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hashtag/hanjinshipping&#34;&gt;hanjinshipping&lt;/a&gt; is worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 3, 2016 Oklahoma earthquakes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A magnitude 5.6 earthquake rattled oil country in Oklahoma
on September 3, 2016 at 7:02 a.m. The quake&amp;rsquo;s epicenter was
eight miles northwest of Pawnee, OK.  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/us10006jxs#executive&#34;&gt;USGS&lt;/a&gt; maps of
the quake are detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pawneenation.org/&#34;&gt;Pawnee Nation&lt;/a&gt; declared
a state of emergency after ordering evacuations of damaged buildings
in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the incidence of earthquakes in Oklahoma is
low, and there is concern in the state that these earthquakes
are of man-made origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous quakes in the area have been linked to the use of
injection wells to dispose of drilling waste. A March 2016
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/08/us/oklahoma-earthquakes-oil-gas-wells.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; story detailed the efforts of the state
government to limit the use of these wells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local news coverage from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news9.com/story/33010965/earthquake-causes-damage-for-historic-pawnee-buildings&#34;&gt;News 9&lt;/a&gt;, KFOR &lt;a href=&#34;http://kfor.com/2016/09/03/pawnee-earthquake-damages-homes-historic-pawnee-nation-buildings/&#34;&gt;Newschannel 4&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oklahoman.com/login?referer=/saturdays-5.6-magnitude-earthquake-ties-record-in-oklahoma/article/5516769&#34;&gt;The Oklahoman&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter is using the hashtag #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/okquake&#34;&gt;okquake&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MattSchroyer&#34;&gt;Matthew Schroyer&lt;/a&gt; has an automated @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OKQuakeWatch&#34;&gt;OKQuakeWatch&lt;/a&gt; account
tweeting USGS data about Oklahoma quakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 09 05 thinking in graphs vs thinking in lists</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-thinking-in-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-thinking-in-graphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing at the Biggby by the dog park with a 20 oz coffee close at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thinking style one&amp;rdquo; comes up with a topic with crisp edges,
and then enumerates a set of carefully constrained and
largely self-similar elements within that topic. You can
be sure at the end that the question at hand has been
thoroughly plumbed, and that nothing is missing because
you went through diligently to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thinking style two&amp;rdquo; starts with a topic, really anything,
and moves laterally and tangentially from one to the next.
The cafe reminds you not of other cafes but of the dog park
across the street and the converstaions there, but also of
the day that you set up a radio at the cafe to listen to
airplanes, and that moves tangentially along a trajectory
towards radio listening in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can do crisp edges and careful enumeration, but pretty soon
I get distracted by the butterfly and then reminded of places
in the world that I love where the butterfly lands on milkweed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging for me has been a process of catching thoughts as
they go by, writing them down thoroughly enough that I can
reconstruct the mindset at a later date, and then moving on
to the next butterfly. Faced with that ephemeral corpus, who
can complain that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to organize? There&amp;rsquo;s no one overarching
theme to anything, just ideas flitting from here to there
along a long migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have had good luck writing on a topic for a long time, it
has been the discipline of ensuring that the lead paragraph always
had a specific word. I could write anything I wanted to with the
words &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor&amp;rdquo; in the lead paragraph for AnnArbor.com; I can
write anything with &amp;ldquo;FOIA&amp;rdquo; or something similar and get neatly
pigeonholed there. But I don&amp;rsquo;t and won&amp;rsquo;t write about butterflies
often enough to make a &amp;ldquo;butterfly blog&amp;rdquo;, even if that&amp;rsquo;s my style,
flitting from one place to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Biggby is open until 6pm, even on Labor Day. Meijer is the
next stop, for back-to-school lunch shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some ideal size for a collection of posts that are all
related - if you can really write 150 separate things that are 500
words each and are all related, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a substantial body of work.
It may make sense to partition my blogging output into several
smaller batches and work from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day when listening to airplanes using dump1090 at this Biggby
I managed to pick up a plane over Indianapolis. I have a feeling
I&amp;rsquo;ll be buying more SDR radio gear in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milkweed grows at Michigania and at the Vielmetti-Peters Conservation
Reserve. It likes old fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to take some care when you have thoughts that go from one
idea to the next to explain the transition slowly and clearly
for the person listening to you. Sometimes you need to pretend like
your mind is grinding slowly and deliberately through a set of
predetermined tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New month, new theme</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-new-month-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-new-month-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve switched themes in this weblog, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/hugo-theme-casper&#34;&gt;Casper&lt;/a&gt;
from Valère JEANTET who ported it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of the theme is that it&amp;rsquo;s neat
and clean and looks like other people&amp;rsquo;s work. The
biggest disadvantage is that I have 80+ pages of
paginated weblog going back into the dim mists of time,
and this theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t come out of the box with
support for that kind of deep back list in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a bigger, more existential question here. I&amp;rsquo;ve
written on the order of 600,000 words &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rdquo;, whatever
&amp;ldquo;here&amp;rdquo; means, on some rather large number of different
topics. How on earth do you reorganize that into something
sensible, or do you simply not bother?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>full stack plane spotting and data analysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The task at hand is simple. Whenever a particular airplane is visible overhead,
send out a tweet with that notice. Don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself with this announcement
more than twice an hour, but try not to have too much lag in reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full stack of hardware and software to do this is not particularly
complicated to use once you get it all running, but there are a series
of issues and observations along the way that add to the complexity. I&amp;rsquo;ll
walk through the whole thing start to finish, and let you know where I
left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic toolkit is dump1090-mutability for plane spotting,
Node-RED for wiring flows for data processing, and
Docker to package up the bits that are stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plane-spotting:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Plane spotting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/&#34;&gt;When last I wrote&lt;/a&gt;,
I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;dump1090&lt;/a&gt;
running on my MacBook. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the same software and gotten
the latest dev release going on a Raspberry Pi 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to a smaller, simpler antenna, and the result was positive: instead of
having a 40 to 50 nautical mile range, now I&amp;rsquo;m in the 60 to 65 nm range (about 110 km).
It might also help that the Pi 2 is not really doing very much else. That
particular Pi 2 setup is using a slightly back-rev version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; software for the Pi, so it has all
of the modern conveniences plus an instance of Docker on board. The
temptation was to Dockerize everything, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone there yet;
the available Docker prebuilt releases don&amp;rsquo;t have the bleeding edge of
the dump1090-mutability code, and I want to see how the whole thing runs
native for a while before containerizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snag that slowed down this deployment a little was Google&amp;rsquo;s decision
to enforce an API key for personal use of Google Maps. In response, the
very latest dump1090-mutability pulled out its Google Maps support, and
went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://openlayers.org/&#34;&gt;OpenLayers&lt;/a&gt;. This new support gives
access to all kinds of base maps, including some aviation-specific
charts. (&amp;ldquo;Not for use in navigation.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another piece of this was bringing up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttpd.net/&#34;&gt;lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;
(&amp;ldquo;lighty&amp;rdquo;), a lightweight HTTP server that replaces the rickety
built-in HTTP server that dump1090 had originally shipped with.
Configuration following the supplied instructions was simple,
and lighttpd looks like a very suitable system to put in place to
serve HTTP on embedded-class system that need flexiblity but not
a big footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other component in the Pi setup is an ADS-B feed to the excellent
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;Planefinder&lt;/a&gt; site. Planefinder provides a Debian
package for setting up the feed, and it runs neatly with only a minimum
of overhead. As a bonus you get free use of their apps, which are
notable for running in much closer to real time than others I have seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi does not yet have a working OpenVPN configuration, so I can&amp;rsquo;t get
to it over the net directly. For that I plan to revisit the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-07-managing-raspberry-pi-openvpn-with-salt/&#34;&gt;SaltStack for Pi&lt;/a&gt;
configuration I wrote up last September. In the interim, salt has
been upgraded, and perhaps it will be a little more stable over bad
connections; we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090 provides a data feed in a convenient JSON format, available
through a URL on a standard configuruation. The ADS-B messages themselves
are binary encoded, but the system brings them into JSON so that all
of the downstream processing is very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data handling is so straightforward that you can do it all without
needing any special-purpose processing nodes in IBM&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org&#34;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;.
A standard HTTP in node polls the data at the pace that you choose,
and a simple function pulls apart the record of all planes into
individual records for each plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Node-RED running is continuing to get easier over time.
I&amp;rsquo;m doing prototyping work on my Macintosh again, using the
new &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2016/06/docker-mac-windows-public-beta/&#34;&gt;Docker for Mac&lt;/a&gt;
setup to pick up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/cpswan/node-red/&#34;&gt;Node-RED container&lt;/a&gt;
to do the work in. &lt;a href=&#34;https://kitematic.com/&#34;&gt;Kitematic&lt;/a&gt; comes with Docker for Mac,
providing a convenient dashboard and interface to Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Do note, however, that if you got Docker for Mac running a few months
ago, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go through a rebuild process to go to the latest
beta. To &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/troubleshoot/#/recreate-or-update-your-containers-after-beta-18-upgrade&#34;&gt;recreate or update your containers after Beta 18 upgrade&lt;/a&gt;
follow the provided instructions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have both Node-RED and dump1090 running, connecting the
two together is straightforward. I started with this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dceejay/3288996fefdc3aef04846496277b6444&#34;&gt;gist from dceejay&lt;/a&gt; which
provides the basic flow and feeds into a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-web-worldmap&#34;&gt;worldmap node&lt;/a&gt; that
is a general programmable interface for putting things on a map. My
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/vielmetti/6329ea5a49dadd2f106980a20727d16e&#34;&gt;updated dump1090 gist for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;
adapts the data for a slightly different format between dump1090 forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here in it&amp;rsquo;s relatively clear sailing. Set up a flow downstream
from the plane messages, using a filter node to match the name or
ICAO hex code of the airplane that you want to track. Wire it through
a delay filter to set the frequency of messages you want to
allow through, and a formatting node to pretty up the message in
a form suitable for Twitter output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;incomplete-image-and-next-steps:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Incomplete image and next steps.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively complex stack, but it all fits neatly on a Raspberry Pi 2,
and with a little bit more elbow grease it should be possible to containerize
everything so that it Just Works and can be made to reliably work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to have OpenVPN running on the Pi 2, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet, pending
rework of Salt to get that to a current version and to port all of the
work I did from an earlier version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m picking up planes from 60+ nm away, but I know that with a better
antenna, bandpass filter, and amplifier that I can do better.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://puck.nether.net/~jared/blog/?p=160&#34;&gt;Jared Mauch&amp;rsquo;s parts list&lt;/a&gt;
would be the place to go for starters with a very modest budget of
a couple of hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reception is best if you have a clear view of the sky, which suggests
an outdoors installation, powering the Pi with power over ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is running on a Pi 2, but reports from Jared and from Phil Karn KA9Q
suggest that if you do upgrade the reception that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
saturate the Pi 2. Fortunately a Pi 3 does even better at the intended task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out what the very best way to create a Docker image
that handles Node-RED, especially the installation of additional nodes
and the management of flows. You&amp;rsquo;d like to have the whole thing suitably
tidy that it could be all loaded in from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090-mutability is still mutating! It&amp;rsquo;s under active development,
both at the presentation layer and at the decoder layer. So it would
be appropriate to have the attitude for at least one development machine
to be sure that you were ready to rebuild from source whenever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only have half of this stack running (the Node-RED side) but no access
to radios, you can find an existing dump1090 installation and pull the
JSON from there. This is best done only via prior arrangement and only
for testing purposes or for specific tasks. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to crank up Node-RED
to poll a URL every second; don&amp;rsquo;t do that to a poor little Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planes I want to watch don&amp;rsquo;t take off very often - that&amp;rsquo;s the appeal
of watching for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plane finding with dump1090</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2015 I wrote briefly about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/&#34;&gt;plane spotting with dump1090&lt;/a&gt;.
In short, many airplanes have ADS-B transponders which squawk out
their location, airspeed, and current conditions, and you can pick
up those transmissions using an inexpensive RTL-SDR tuner stick and
a simple antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into this again to see if I can get a better
understanding of how it works as well as to take advantage of a year plus
of software development. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the state of the art
circa July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware: I&amp;rsquo;m using a Nooelec NESDR Mini 2 tuner stick plugged into a MacBook Air
as a portable plane-finding system. I have a Raspberry Pi 2 which looks
like it could be a permanent installation for this, though the recommendation
for busy skies is a Pi 3 which is enough faster to make a difference if you
have a good antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antenna: The Mini 2 comes with a small whip antenna with a magnetic base, and I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing
a larger antenna. There are scads of antenna designs out there for inexpensive
small antennas tuned to 1090 Mhz, but I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet. There are also
filters and amplifiers that can improve plane-finding capabilities; also not
there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software: Here&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;ve made progress. The dump1090 software has been
forked several times, each time with just a little bit more sophistication
on the visual display as well as refinements of the decoding system. The
one I&amp;rsquo;m using right now is a fork by &amp;ldquo;mutability&amp;rdquo;, available at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&lt;/a&gt; . It&amp;rsquo;s notable for being
designed to run on a Raspberry Pi, as well as a bunch of small changes
in the display that make it more pleasant to use than the older software
I had been using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Range: Just like I reported back in 2015, the typical results from my
house are a range of 40-50 nautical miles in every direction. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet taken the rig to my favorite plane-spotting cafe &amp;ndash; the Biggby at
Platt and Ellsworth &amp;ndash; which has a clear view of the southern sky at
a good elevation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweaking the setup: Aside from changing out the hardware and relocating
the antenna, the tweakable changes seem to be adjusting the gain control
on the SDR. Initial experiments don&amp;rsquo;t give me strong conclusions as to
what&amp;rsquo;s best. The reviews of a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/ADS-B-1090MHz-Band-pass-SMA-Filter/dp/B010GBQXK8&#34;&gt;$20 band pass filter&lt;/a&gt; are
promising for increasing the range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeding the data elsewhere: One of the collective efforts around looking for
airplanes is the ability to share the data with commerical and non-commericial
systems that aggregate data from around the world. I&amp;rsquo;m digging
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;http://planefinder.net&lt;/a&gt; which has a nifty near-real-time feed of ADS-B
and FAA and other international data for tracking flights. Planefinder is
fast enough that I can hear an airplane overheard, check the display,
and figure out which flight is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellite plane finding: The &lt;a href=&#34;https://directory.eoportal.org/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/gomx-3&#34;&gt;GOMX-3 satellite&lt;/a&gt;
has an SDR with ADS-B reception and has successfully
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airtrafficmanagement.net/2016/07/fr24-completes-satbased-adsb-tracking/&#34;&gt;fed data to Flightradar24&lt;/a&gt;,
another commericial plane tracking system. ADS-B receivers are expected
to be installed on the Iridium system over the next couple of years,
which should over time provide improved global coverage and visibility
into the current status of aircraft over oceans and the poles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it looks like: I don&amp;rsquo;t have a permanent installation running,
but if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the airspace above San Diego, you can
see Phil Karn KA9Q&amp;rsquo;s system at &lt;a href=&#34;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&#34;&gt;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&lt;/a&gt;
noting that he&amp;rsquo;s in easy range of picking traffic into LAX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github private repositories</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Github has changed their pricing strategy to allow individual
accounts to have more private repositories. This is a welcome
change for accounts like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their change, enterprise pricing has increased.
I&amp;rsquo;m told that this will multiply the bills that some companies
will see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post tests a new private repo, and links to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pricing&#34;&gt;Github pricing&lt;/a&gt; for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor quiet writing escapes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-ann-arbor-writing-escapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-ann-arbor-writing-escapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where to go in Ann Arbor to do some quiet writing, without distractions.
There are plenty of cafes where there are lots of people around; this
list looks for the empty places where you won&amp;rsquo;t have your attention broken
quite so easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a much easier task in the summer time than it is during the school
year, as the students thin out and University buildings are much quieter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Campus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackham.umich.edu/rackham-building/study-halls&#34;&gt;Rackham Building reading rooms&lt;/a&gt;, second floor. Very lovely, very quiet, recommended by many.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lib.umich.edu/hatcher-graduate-library/carrels-hatcher-graduate-library&#34;&gt;Hatcher Graduate Library study carrels&lt;/a&gt;, especially on the higher floors. You&amp;rsquo;ll have a little room of your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law Library reading room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan League, upper floors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Museum of Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palmer Commons, where the upper floors have writing desks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Work Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan Union first floor reading rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downtown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor City Hall, council chambers (not during a meeting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweetwaters, Liberty or Washington St&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor District Library, third floor (periodicals) or fourth floor (administration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s Next Door, upstairs in one of the smaller rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mighty Good Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthaei Botanical Gardens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duderstadt Center library, second floor (periodicals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Municipal Airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roos Roast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ypsilanti&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate in Depot Town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, external distractions are only one part of the complex question of
&amp;ldquo;why are no words appearing on the page&amp;rdquo;. There are some a few tricks that I
use to minimize distractions coming from the computer itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in a big &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo; window. Open up Terminal, maximize a window,
and then fire up &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m managing to get 62 lines on the screen without
having to squint, and the browser is not on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go offline. If your writing environment allows, do your writing without
a connection to the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you must stay online, mute notifications. On my Mac that&amp;rsquo;s a
&amp;ldquo;Do not disturb&amp;rdquo; setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a big screen up another functional way to avoid a distraction
is to keep sitting until the screen is full. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to
actually want to keep all of the words that you write - it&amp;rsquo;s OK to
discard some of them in a subsequent editing session - but the self
imposed constraint to fill the page all the way to the bottom on a 62
line screen produces a substantial quantity of work in a single sitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A useful quality to cultivate is &amp;ldquo;sitzfleisch&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Germans have aptly called Sitzfleisch the ability to spend endless hours at a desk doing grueling work. Sitzfleisch is considered by mathematicians to be a better guage of success than any of the attractive definitions of talent with which psychologists regale us from time to time.  Gian-Carlo Rota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull up a seat, open up the screen, start typing. Don&amp;rsquo;t look up until the page is full.
Set yourself a time limit and a word count and aim for that. The time limit can
be enforced by parking in a space where your time is limited, which reminds
me that I must be going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A commonplace reader</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easier and faster to fill a page by quoting from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace book is the annotated scrapbook, carefully collecting
bits from other writers with just enough commentary and selection to
make them your own. If these were written in this era you&amp;rsquo;d call it
&amp;ldquo;curation&amp;rdquo;, though I can only think of that word in the context of
&amp;ldquo;curated meats&amp;rdquo;, somewhat salty and dry and meant to be preserved for
some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the commonplace book. Why write your own words, when there are
so many other good ones already written to quote from? As it is said,
though &lt;a href=&#34;http://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/03/06/artists-steal/&#34;&gt;no attribution is reliable&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immature artists copy, great artists steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artist steal from tonight is Brian Eno, in particular his &lt;a href=&#34;http://oblicard.com/&#34;&gt;Oblique Strategies&lt;/a&gt;,
which I now have as three lines of shell script plus 128 lines of text. A sample, intended
to be drawn at random:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not building a wall but making a brick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to brick-machines, this from Popular Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bricks are fairly easy to make, but in the developing world, traditional fired bricks are sometimes weak and crumble-prone, while cement ones are often unaffordable. The Vermeer BP714 is the first compressed-earth-block machine that makes strong air-dried bricks out of dirt. Its bricks don&amp;rsquo;t just exceed U.S. cement-code strength requirements—they&amp;rsquo;re 20 to 30 percent stronger, and cheaper than other machines&amp;rsquo; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course that&amp;rsquo;s the story you want to tell when someone else
has a lot of mud and you have a lot of machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace style of writing allows you to fill a page
with text faster, since you&amp;rsquo;re cutting and pasting it in
rather than sweating to find the exact words yourself. The
downside is that you might sometimes have to hunt for the
correct word, and it will be obvious that it&amp;rsquo;s someone
else&amp;rsquo;s correct word. There is no question of plagiarism,
just of assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious crimes in terms of writing are that of plagiarism and copyright violation. (Reality Studio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long as we are going down this route, it&amp;rsquo;s worth rejecting
plagiarism as a thought-crime. From Kenneth Goldsmith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems an appropriate response to a new condition in writing: With an unprecedented amount of available text, our problem is not needing to write more of it; instead, we must learn to negotiate the vast quantity that exists. How I make my way through this thicket of information—how I manage it, parse it, organize and distribute it—is what distinguishes my writing from yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make patchworks. Most two word phrases can be easily found on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most two-word phrases are not produced under unpleasant stress, but in interest or excitement. (Penelope Leach, &amp;ldquo;Babyhood&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to provide the reader with enough information so that the article can be easily found on the References page. (Communication Research Methods in Postmodern Culture)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists of real-world materials and their refractive indexes are easily found on the Internet.  (Lanier, &amp;ldquo;Maya Studio Projects Texturing and Writing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retroactively we can construct some level of patchwork that we can crib from, in interest or excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day trips from Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-23-day-trips-from-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-23-day-trips-from-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some suggestions for places to go for same-day destination trips from Ann Arbor.
I&amp;rsquo;m collecting up ideas suitable for rides in support of driver&amp;rsquo;s ed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East via M-14&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Oak: &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitzoo.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novi: 12 Oaks Mall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East via I-94&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belleville: &lt;a href=&#34;http://yankeeairmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Yankee Air Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dearborn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehenryford.org/&#34;&gt;Greenfield Village&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dearborn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehenryford.org/&#34;&gt;Henry Ford Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dia.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Institute of Arts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroithistorical.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Historical Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michigan.org/property/belle-isle-park/&#34;&gt;Belle Isle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motownmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Motown Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windsor: Via tunnel or bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point Pelee: Bird sanctuary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marine City: ferry to Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South via US-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carleton: Calder Dairy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monroe: 1812 National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.toledomuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Toledo Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt; (45 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: Toledo Mud Hens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: Toledo Zoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Clinton: birdwatching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southwest via US-12&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tecumseh:  Michigan State Univ &lt;a href=&#34;http://hiddenlakegardens.msu.edu/&#34;&gt;Hidden Lake Gardens&lt;/a&gt;, (one of the better kept State secrets) &amp;hellip;beautiful trails, Hosta Garden and conifer collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishhillsrecreation.com/&#34;&gt;Irish Hills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West vis I-94&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kalamazoo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airzoo.org/&#34;&gt;Air Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;St Joseph: beaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northwest via US-23 and I-96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Rapids: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meijergardens.org/&#34;&gt;Frederik Meijer Gardens &amp;amp; Sculpture Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;East Lansing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dairystore.msu.edu/&#34;&gt;MSU Dairy Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North via US-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durand: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.durandstation.org/&#34;&gt;Union Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frankenmuth:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bronners.com/&#34;&gt;Bronners&lt;/a&gt; / Outlet Shopping at Birch Run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bay City: Polish food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midland: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dowgardens.org/&#34;&gt;Dow Gardens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumb: Port Crescent State Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to members of the a2b3 mailing list for suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bots are hot - again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title of the post is taken from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/1996/04/netbots/&#34;&gt;1996 Wired article&lt;/a&gt;
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/koxinga21&#34;&gt;Andrew Leonard&lt;/a&gt;
describing the state of automated systems in the dot-com
era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web robots – spiders, wanderers, and worms. Cancelbots, Lazarus, and Automoose. Chatterbots, softbots, userbots, taskbots, knowbots, and mailbots. MrBot and MrsBot. Warbots, clonebots, floodbots, annoybots, hackbots, and Vladbots. Gaybots, gossipbots, and gamebots. Skeleton bots, spybots, and sloth bots. Xbots and meta-bots. Eggdrop bots. Motorcycle bull dyke bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots are hot today in part because natural langauge processing
has improved to the point where &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/05/Google-supercharges-machine-learning-tasks-with-custom-chip.html&#34;&gt;Google can build hardware&lt;/a&gt;
to speed up their software algorithms and run their immense
training corpuses through it quickly to fine tune their approach.
The output of this effort is ASICs that speed up their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/&#34;&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/a&gt;
algorithm for machine learning. Thus Google can safely give away
their software, knowing that anyone else running it will use
a multiple of the energy that it takes Google to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s instructive to look at the changes throughout the years and
how bots have co-evolved with the networks and computer systems
that they inhabit. Early AIs like ELIZA and PARRY lived on
mainframes connected to very slow wide-area networks, and it
was years before the two of them talked to each other online.
The 1980s and 1990s brought Usenet and the automation that could
live on store-and-forward networks. AOL Instant Messenger&amp;rsquo;s
ubiquitous chat met popular culture and the emergence of
advertising bots like GooglyMinotaur, which promoted the music
of Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing what I think is some kind of manuscript about
bots and their personalities, a biographical dictionary of
emerging intelligences. I&amp;rsquo;m at about 10,000 words. It&amp;rsquo;s a challenge
to try to corral that much quasi-intelligence onto the page, including
trying as best I can to characterize some systems that are
known only by people&amp;rsquo;s memories of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical slaves and the Californian ideology</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-mechanical-slaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-mechanical-slaves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Noted elsewhere, saved here for reference, from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Barbrook and Andy Cameron,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imaginaryfutures.net/2007/04/17/the-californian-ideology-2/&#34;&gt;THE CALIFORNIAN IDEOLOGY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If human slaves are ultimately unreliable, then mechanical ones
will have to be invented. The search for the holy grail of Artificial
Intelligence reveals this desire for the Golem a strong and loyal
slave whose skin is the colour of the earth and whose innards are
made of sand. As in Asimov’s Robot novels, the techno-utopians
imagine that it is possible to obtain slave like labour from inanimate
machines. Yet, although technology can store or amplify labour, it
can never remove the necessity for humans to invent, build and
maintain these machines in the first place. Slave labour cannot be
obtained without somebody being enslaved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this and then think about Siri, Cortana, &amp;ldquo;Amy Ingram&amp;rdquo; and other
long-suffering inanimate machines that we imbue so much personality
into that some of us unknowingly
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/amy-ingram-personal-assistant-2015-7&#34;&gt;flirt with a robot&lt;/a&gt; because we are so charmed by their devotion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washtenaw restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-washtenaw-restaraunt-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-washtenaw-restaraunt-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who: Wayne Eaker and the a2civictech Slack team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What: Restaurant inspections from Washtenaw County&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where: &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&#34;&gt;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When: As they are updated, up to twice a momth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why: When you eat out, you care about food safety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some example searches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/?f[0]=field_count_total%3A%5B30%20TO%201000%5D&#34;&gt;Three restaurants with 30 or more violations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/?f[0]=field_inspection_violation_codes%3A6-501.111%3A%20Controlling%20Pests&amp;amp;f[1]=field_inspection_date%3A2016&#34;&gt;Reports from 2016 of pest problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of this project is that it&amp;rsquo;s dependent
on an undocumented interface from the contractor who
does the work for the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One very nice aspect of the system that Wayne put together is that
you can get alerts from every time a new inspection comes out that
matches your saved settings, so you can track a particular restaurant
or problem over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prince</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-prince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s radio was full of the Prince music catalog. The artist
passed away in his Minnesota home at the age of 57. In response
any radio station that had anything other that pre-programmed music
responded by playing his hits - &amp;ldquo;Little Red Corvette&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Raspberry Beret&amp;rdquo;,
&amp;ldquo;Purple Rain&amp;rdquo; - and the radio stations that had artistic control
also played B sides, live shows, bootlegs and whatever they could find.
Ann Arbor&amp;rsquo;s own WCBN was exemplary in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radio that I remember is from the 80s when Prince&amp;rsquo;s music was
in regular play on the Electrifyin&amp;rsquo; Mojo&amp;rsquo;s show on Detroit&amp;rsquo;s WJLB.
Prince did a very rare live radio interview with Mojo, and you can
hear it in two parts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJZCoxZ5COY&#34;&gt;part one&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ftKtWgXzMS8&#34;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt; - on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I haven&amp;rsquo;t found yet is the computer font with a perfect Prince
symbol in it. You can get close by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://parkerhiggins.net/2013/01/writing-the-prince-symbol-in-unicode/&#34;&gt;writing the prince symbol in unicode&lt;/a&gt;,
or this ASCII representation may suffice: O(+&amp;gt; . But the
real deal came on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://nymag.com/following/2016/04/princes-legendary-floppy-disk-symbol-font.html&#34;&gt;3.5&amp;rdquo; floppy disc&lt;/a&gt; from Warner Bros.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthquake in Ecuador, April 16, 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-17-ecuador-terremoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-17-ecuador-terremoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, MI, 17 April 2016: An earthquake hit near the coast of
Ecuador on the evening of 16 April 2016. As of 1:00 p.m. Eastern
time the current estimate is 235 killed and 1,557 wounded from the
incident. Reports are still coming in from the hardest hit areas
which lost telecommunications lines in the disaster, so expect these
numbers to increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early reports from Ecuador came in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/abenavidesgol/status/721506479866572800&#34;&gt;primarily via social media&lt;/a&gt;, as it took
a while for the nation&amp;rsquo;s news organization to cut over to flash reporting
of the news from their regularly scheduled programs. The country&amp;rsquo;s
vice president, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JorgeGlas&#34;&gt;Jorge Glas&lt;/a&gt;, provided
regular and authoritative reports on damage and emergency response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting on the damage was almost entirely in Spanish,
as there is no substantial English language media presence in the
county. I found the automated translation service provided by Bing
in the Twitter feed to be indispensible. Some words that you will
see over and over again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personas heridas = people injured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personas fallecidas = people killed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sin luz = without electricity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sismo, terremoto, temblor = earthquake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For music and (sometimes) news from Ecuador, I turned to Tunein, which
relays thousands of radio stations worldwide. At various times the following
channels were interesting or informative:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tunein.com/radio/Radio-Am%C3%A9rica-Estereo-%40Guayaquil%41-933-s68608/&#34;&gt;Radio America Estereo, Guayaquil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tunein.com/radio/Radio-Quito-760-s59649/&#34;&gt;Radio Quito, 760 AM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tunein.com/radio/Ecuador-Inmediato-Radio-s59648/&#34;&gt;Ecuador Inmediato Radio, Quito&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked for the shortwave broadcast of &lt;a href=&#34;http://radiohcjb.org/&#34;&gt;HCJB&lt;/a&gt; but
it would appear that its English language broadcasts are no more. There is
news in Spanish on the site under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://radiohcjb.org/author/noticias/&#34;&gt;Noticias&lt;/a&gt; banner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some individual news feeds to follow from the time of the event:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/lewisshepherd&#34;&gt;Lewis Shepherd&lt;/a&gt;, Washington DC based analyst&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/elcomerciocom&#34;&gt;El Comercio&lt;/a&gt;, Quito newspaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/_MayraPacheco&#34;&gt;Mayra Pacheco&lt;/a&gt;, reporter for El Comercio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ECU911Quito&#34;&gt;ECU 911 Quito&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/IGEcuador&#34;&gt;IG Ecuador&lt;/a&gt;, Instituto Geofísico with quake maps and scientific reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts go out to everyone affected by the quake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>