<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:50:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Detroit, Wednesday July 22, 2015, 6:00 pm, Troy, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope to see you at Docker Detroit&amp;rsquo;s kickoff meeting, to be held
at RIIS, 1250 Stephenson Highway, Suite 200 in Troy, MI starting
at 6:00 p.m. tonight July 22 2015.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming in from Ann
Arbor. The venue is between 14 Mile and Maple behind Beaumont Hospital.
Google Maps suggests that because of construction on I-75 in that
area you might want to head north on Campbell instead of taking
the I-75 / I-696 interchange north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading the meeting tonight is Pepijn Bruienne from the University
of Michigan. He will be speaking about &amp;ldquo;Docker in production&amp;rdquo;
and organizing a group discussion with Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Docker-Detroit/events/223111645/&#34;&gt;meetup announcement&lt;/a&gt;
for more details, refreshments will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meetup is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.riis.com&#34;&gt;RIIS&lt;/a&gt; a boutique web
and mobile development house. Hope to see you there!  I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking
notes and plan to do a writeup of the event, as well as sharing my
own experiences running Docker for ARM on a Raspberry PI 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Coffee and Wifi, Roos Roast Wednesday edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Roos, an espresso over ice with a little half and half and a hard
boiled egg. It&amp;rsquo;s a very compact breakfast. The espresso is served in
an appropriately sized glass mug and tastes like the strongest little
iced latte you will ever have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Mac, run &amp;lsquo;boot2docker upgrade&amp;rsquo;. That gets me up to current 1.7.1
revision of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Edwards-MacBook-Air:~ emv$ docker version
Client version: 1.7.1
Client API version: 1.19
Go version (client): go1.4.2
Git commit (client): 786b29d
OS/Arch (client): darwin/amd64
Server version: 1.7.1
Server API version: 1.19
Go version (server): go1.4.2
Git commit (server): 786b29d
OS/Arch (server): linux/amd64
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue that 1.7.1 resolves for me is certificate support - if I
understand the bug right, the Docker daemon was creating a key for
each interface it had, but not all of the interfaces were up at key
init time. The fix was to move DHCP init earlier in the start sequence
so that everything was initialized by the time key creation took place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker team is trying to improve code quality by having their
code base pass the &lt;code&gt;golint&lt;/code&gt; test. The open issue,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/pull/14784&#34;&gt;fix golint errors/warnings #14784&lt;/a&gt;,
has attracted a swarm of contributors, and a lot of them have
proposed changes that don&amp;rsquo;t pass the automated tests. The build
farm is managed with Jenkins, and you can see the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.dockerproject.org/&#34;&gt;status of every build of Docker&lt;/a&gt; on their
dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a full lintable codebase is a great goal. The challenge comes when
the suggested changes by lint send you in the direction of making an
incompatible change to some interface that has the &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; name but that
people were relying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps importantly for the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that currently
all of these tests are done on x86 platforms (Linux and Windows) and there
isn&amp;rsquo;t an official automated build on ARM. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;Docker distribution from Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; as my
baseline for working on the Raspberry Pi, with good success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bocker is a subset of Docker in 100 lines of shell script</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/p8952/bocker&#34;&gt;bocker&lt;/a&gt; is Docker (or at least
a good sized subset of it) in 100 lines of shell script.
I suppose the point is that even though there&amp;rsquo;s a huge
world of hype surrounding containerization as a next step
of systems management, when you get down to it, it&amp;rsquo;s just not
that complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coworking notes at Elixir Vitae</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 16:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A productive afternoon with Mohan Kartha in which I opened a great
many tabs in Chrome. This bit of writing to close those out. Elixir
Vitae is a great spot for writing - lots of quiet noise from the coolers
to keep a background hum, and close to the bus station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sorting out the simplest task that I&amp;rsquo;d like to do with Node-RED,
now that I have a Raspberry Pi 2 running it under Docker in a configuration
that&amp;rsquo;s reliable enough that it seems like it&amp;rsquo;s stable. The easiest
network test in the world is the ping test, and so my first stab at
a try for &amp;ldquo;run always&amp;rdquo; is a simple configuration to notice when the
network looks like it&amp;rsquo;s down and when it is to collect some more
detailed information and log it to a file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for that is this simple configuration from an idea
by Nathan Chantrell, implemented by Martin Harizanov in 2014.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://harizanov.com/2014/03/presence-detection-using-phones-wifi-and-node-red/&#34;&gt;Presence detection using phone’s WiFi and Node-RED&lt;/a&gt; relies on static
IP address assignments from DHCP, plus &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo;, to notice if
someone&amp;rsquo;s device is in the building, turned on, and listening to
wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough phones drain their battery to know that absence
of a wifi signal is not an unambiguous marker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantelope is doing a beta product launch at the final AFC Ann Arbor minor
league soccer game of the year, Saturday, July 25 at 6 PM at Hollway
Field (Pioneer High School, 601 W. Stadium, Ann Arbor). See
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fantelope.com/afc-ann-arbor-fantelope-beta-launch/&#34;&gt;the Fantelope web site&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at writing code to send postcards from Lob.com is
working. The note to self is that if you have a square bracket in
a URL, that you have to turn off curl&amp;rsquo;s globbing function, e.g.
with -g or &amp;ndash;globoff. &amp;ldquo;When you set this option, you can specify
URLs that contain the letters {}[] without having them being
interpreted by curl itself. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every card has a tracking code, so the next bit of reporting to write
is to see which cards are awaiting printing, which ones are in transit,
where they are going to and whether they have been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AAATA moved the endpoint URL for its old-school &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo;
mobile RideTrak application. To go to a particular route like
the 5, see e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&lt;/a&gt; .
The main &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org&lt;/a&gt; has a newer interface, but
alas my Windows Phone 8.1 with its Internet Explorer browser
doesn&amp;rsquo;t do that page justice. (That, and I prefer the old interface
because I managed to figure it out for the stop I&amp;rsquo;m always catching
the bus from.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getlittlebird.com/&#34;&gt;Little Bird&lt;/a&gt; promises to
&amp;ldquo;help businesses unlock the valuable information in structured social data&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve asked for a trial to see what they have in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wondering what the best approach is to the task of
&amp;ldquo;download all of my email from Gmail&amp;rdquo;, since the storage I
now have available on my laptop would make it straightforward
to have an 18 GB personal mail spool and because I really actually
would love to search through it so that I can mark some messages
for permanent deletion. One possibility is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enkive.org&#34;&gt;Enkive&lt;/a&gt;
from The Linux Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am reminded that I want to carry around a set of headphones with me
that plug into my Nokia 635 so that I can use the phone as a radio,
and also reminded that I want to try to construct a headphone dipole
as an antenna for my NooElec DVB-T tuner. The challenge will be remembering
those desires at the right time so that when I see the parts I need
in the junk pile at home that I can grab what I need for my every
day carry bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I need to track down an 8 GB USB stick to load a boot ISO on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink.
Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong
iced latte, just add a little half and half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending
postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite
images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence
of mind seven years ago to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-29-image-processing-on-the-mac-with-sips-imagemagick-watching-dte-restore-power-slowly/&#34;&gt;write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick&lt;/a&gt;
for image manipulation and that helped. In this case the magic incantation
was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sips -z 1275 1875 original.jpg --out new.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Mac, or want to do this on a server or container
somewhere, you&amp;rsquo;ll want Imagemagick. That venerable program has a
bazillion options, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find the image geometry options at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagemagick.org/script/command-line-processing.php#geometry&#34;&gt;http://www.imagemagick.org/script/command-line-processing.php#geometry&lt;/a&gt; .
Recreating this exact sips command is left as an exercise for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bit of image processing taken care of, the next iteration is to
launch a few actual postcards into the ether. After having confirmed
that everything goes OK on the test key, I sent out four cards. Estimated
delivery date is July 30, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting about a two week turnaround
for feedback that I got everything right. Lob has card tracking so I guess
the next step is to write the simple tools to know when things were
delivered so that I can plan some phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr  /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin Zorba has perhaps the best bio in the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has, in the course of his endeavors: been shot at by Navajos
in Utah; seized and threatened at knifepoint by rednecks in Arkansas;
chased by AK-47-toting soldiers in Hungary; run out of town by the
Penitentes in Truchas; shaken down by the Federales in Baja, and
forced to be rude to secure a cab in Rome. He has hung out of and
over: planes, balloons, helicopters, boats, rafts, race cars,
elevator shafts, too tall cliffs, and real deep canyons- and yet,
he still has enthusiasm and a good attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerry Davis asks why we still have academic journals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web has greatly reduced the barriers to entry for new journals
and other platforms for communicating scientific output, and the
number of journals continues to multiply. This leaves readers and
authors with the daunting cognitive challenge of navigating the
literature and discerning contributions that are both relevant and
significant. Meanwhile, measures of journal impact that might guide
the use of the literature have become more visible and consequential,
leading to “impact gamesmanship” that renders the measures increasingly
suspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay, published in &lt;a href=&#34;http://asq.sagepub.com/content/59/2/193&#34;&gt;Administrative Science Quarterly&lt;/a&gt; in June 2014, has the seeds of its own answer. Journals
exist to enrich academic publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay per Article - You may purchase this article for US$32.00. You
must download your purchase, which is yours to keep, within 24
hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just ask Jerry for a preprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously (1995!) I get quoted in the Times Higher Education Supplement.
The debate then centered around Stevan Harnad, an open access journal
advocate who saw clearly the trend towards low cost electronic publications,
thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It remains only to tally up these PostGutenberg values: If the
world&amp;rsquo;s esoteric scholarly/scientific literature were available to
everyone for free in electronic form, the first benefit to the
author would be the great increase in the visibility, accessibility
and hence the potential impact of his work (1). This would of course
also be a benefit to all scholars when they are wearing their
readers&amp;rsquo; rather than their authors&amp;rsquo; hats (2). Some fear that such
a literature would be overwhelming and un-navigable, but stop and
think: How do we currently manage it in paper? If the entire corpus
were transferred to the Net, instead of our eyes and fingers and
feet doing the walking to get to the papers or to get the papers
to us, electronic directories containing everything could be searched
using the kinds of keyword search already used today in searching
electronic databases that contain the titles and abstracts (but not
the articles) in the paper literature. Then, one more click, and
you have the paper itself! Or clever &amp;ldquo;knowbots&amp;rdquo; (automatic search
programmes) could be designed to go out instead of us and look for
papers fitting our profile of interests, leaving us even more time
to actually read what we want and to do our research, rather than
running after the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reply, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.timeshighereducation.co.uk/features/harnad-versus-fuller-round-2/98502.article&#34;&gt;immortalized from the past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Vielmetti (bottom) uncontroversially points out that there
is a lot of rubbish on the Internet; but he is sceptical of peer
review as a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original commentary is lost in the mists of time, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two institutions that went by the name of GopherCon.
(No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a furry convention; that&amp;rsquo;s Anthrocon.) One was
from the early 1990s surrounding the Gopher internet browsing
protocol; the other is for enthusiasts and programmers of the
Go programming language. I am not aware of anyone who can claim
to have gone to both events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.databaseteam.org/10-database/0722cf77b51ab4ba.htm&#34;&gt;GopherCon 1995&lt;/a&gt;
featured discussion of GopherVR and VRML for virtual reality in Gopher,
the Hyper-G Information System for hypertext authoring, and an
early morning session on Integrating Gopher and WWW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GopherCon 2015 was in early July in Colorado. Of the items on
the agenda this talk by Barak Michener was perhaps the most interesting
to follow through on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written in Go, Cayley is a graph database based on technology
behind Freebase.com. Starting with a short history of the inspirations
behind Cayley, this talk will deep-dive into the moving parts of
building a graph database, between the various query languages, the
storage engines, and the iterator trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course this blog is now powered by Hugo which is written in Go
so I&amp;rsquo;m learning a little about the Go template language as a side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or
is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage
everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging
environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have
my computer with me. On the other hand doing live-blogging from a phone is
not possible, not that it ever really was very practical with any previous setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your UMARC shack access code is &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Achievement unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The todo list right now for the shack is very short - &amp;ldquo;get in&amp;rdquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m
in I should have a longer list. There is a lot of gear in that room
to get familiar with, not least of which is HF equipment with tunable
and movable antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/twitter-marius-eriksen-finagle/&#34;&gt;Why Twitter Has More Freedom To Innovate Than Google&lt;/a&gt; is a 2013 Wired Magazine writeup.
Prominently featured are Marius Eriksen, Niels Provos, and Peter Honeyman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the early aughts, when Eriksen was an undergrad at
Michigan, studying computer science under a professor and lovable
eccentric named Peter Honeyman. Known as “Dr. Honey” among the
undergrads and PhD students at his Center for Information Technology
Integration, Honeyman was famous for making assignments without
really making assignments. “He would develop a particular obsession,
and he would give you random hints about it, but he wouldn’t actually
tell you what to do,” Eriksen remembers. “You would end up collaborating
with people on whatever it was, in this freeform way, without much
direction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to one of Peter&amp;rsquo;s current students. Evan is looking at ways to
direct RF energy at devices to make them fail in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan are working on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://it.slashdot.org/story/15/06/30/1917207/stanford-starts-the-secure-internet-of-things-project&#34;&gt;Secure Internet of Things Project (slashdot)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan have now started
the Secure Internet of Things Project, which aims to promote security
and transparency for IoT devices. They hope to unite regulators,
researchers, and manufacturers to ensure nascent internet-connected
tech is developed in a way that respects customer privacy and choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web site has more details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu&#34;&gt;http://iot.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the presentations at the Secure Internet of Things Project Retreat
in Half Moon Bay on June 5, 2015 was this by U of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Prabal Dutta,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu/retreat15/sitp15-swhw.pdf&#34;&gt;State of the Field: Hardware and Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(embed deck here, if I can)
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LP0965 Antenna is a Log Periodic PCB directional antenna, at 5-6dBi Gain.
The design is from Kent Britain WA5VJB, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wa5vjb.com/pcb-pdfs/LP8565.pdf&#34;&gt;data sheet for the antenna&lt;/a&gt; describes its
utility for signals from 850 Mhz to 6500 Mhz. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://wa5vjb.com&#34;&gt;http://wa5vjb.com&lt;/a&gt; for more
circuit board antennas for use for hobby, wifi, microwave and cellular use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic jam on Fuller on the return trip, backed up all the way to the river.
It took about 15 minutes to get through because of construction on westbound
Fuller taking traffic to one lane. It would have been faster to take the Route 1
AAATA bus via Pontiac Trail, even though it would have been a considerable detour,
or to walk to Plymouth Road and take the 2 in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fire at the Michigan League this afternoon. No sign of any issues
as I pass by this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question when taking Commuter South is always where to get off the bus. Today
I&amp;rsquo;ll take it all the way to the end of its route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Biggby Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a warm but pleasant mid-summer late Monday morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m
visiting the first cafe inbound on a walk to town. Biggby Packard
is where I end up when the inbound bus schedule timing is just so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summertime cafes near campus are odd. There&amp;rsquo;s not really enough here
to motivate someone to drive here for coffee, so it draws people
from the surrounding neighborhood and from the athletic campus.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been in here before when I was the only patron for more than
an hour but this morning there&amp;rsquo;s a few more people sitting typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first ran into the &amp;ldquo;pocketmod&amp;rdquo; planning technique in 2005, and
here it is 10 years later and there&amp;rsquo;s one in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pocketmod is a cleverly folded piece of paper with preprinted
templates for things like a mini calendar, todo list, quadrille
paper, checklist etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the smallest instance of a PDA that I
have seen yet, requiring nothing more than a blank piece of paper
and a pair of scissors to execute. You could even bypass the scissors
if you had good paper and a crisp straightedge to do a rip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astoundingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketmod.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pocketmod.com/&lt;/a&gt; is still online, in all of
its 2005-2007 glory. That system does an 8-up PDF from a set of templates,
so that you can print a lovingly detailed mini booklet. My own use
has long since devolved into scrap paper plus rip down the center.
When it fills up, invert the fold, and you have a brand new organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now playing, Johnny Cash&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;One Piece at a Time&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;GM wouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss just
one little piece.&amp;rdquo; Look for the promo photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Menu plan: green beans with walnuts and miso sauce, plus a few green beans
uncooked on the side for J who likes to eat the raw. A recipe of sorts is
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/recipe-review-green-beans-with-49874&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;,
which refers to a 2005 New York Times Dining article about Yumiko
Kano and her brand of Japanese cooking.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://justbento.com/handbook/bento-basics/review-saisai-lunch-vegan-bento-by-yumiko-kano&#34;&gt;Just Bento&lt;/a&gt; has some reviews of books by Yumiko Kano (aka Yumiko Kanoh or
Kanou Kumiko). &lt;a href=&#34;http://theunbearablelightnessofbeinghungry.com/2009/10/vegetarian-ramen/&#34;&gt;The Unbearable Lightness of Being Hungry&lt;/a&gt; has a 2009 vegetarian ramen recipe
from the same author. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://metropolis.co.jp/dining/table-talk/yumiko-kano/&#34;&gt;profile of Yumiko Kano&lt;/a&gt; in Metropolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some
very yummy new potatoes from Farmers Market that I cooked up last night,
which were 1000x more wonderful than storebought old potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exit Biggby heading north to North Campus to Mujo&amp;rsquo;s, for some
time spent writing. Close all of the windows, save all of the
documents, publish locally all of the works in progress. North
Campus has the virute of frequent free bus service from Central
Campus, and it&amp;rsquo;s far enough away to completely flush all of
the thoughts of what I had been doing so I can work on another project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lob a postcard: printer sends cards via API</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 22:05:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-lob-a-postcard-printer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lob.com has an API to send postcards-as-a-service ($0.70 per each,
full custom both sides). Details at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lob.com/services/postcards&#34;&gt;https://lob.com/services/postcards&lt;/a&gt; .
It works, but all of the user interface is up to you; if you know
a good service for delivering a single full-custom postcard with
postage that actually has a user interface and not an API for less
than $1.00 each, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll update here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started checking in a few tiny utility programs that exercise
the Lob API. Look for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vielmetti/postcard&#34;&gt;https://github.com/vielmetti/postcard&lt;/a&gt; on Github.
The goal at some point is to have a &amp;ldquo;postcard&amp;rdquo; application
that has a user interface like so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;postcard --to mom --photo cute-kids.jpg --message &amp;quot;they get so big so fast! love ed&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in this business is PostalMethods with a Postcard API based on SOAP.
That&amp;rsquo;s not a convenient interface in the languages that I use, but you
can look at the API at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postalmethods.com/lp/postcard-api&#34;&gt;http://www.postalmethods.com/lp/postcard-api&lt;/a&gt; .
Their prices for postcards run $1.50 per each or less, with quantity
discounts - see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postalmethods.com/pricing&#34;&gt;http://www.postalmethods.com/pricing&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postful used to have an API for postcards. They were
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.click2mail.com/articles/view/click2mail-acquires-postful/&#34;&gt;bought by Click2Mail in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Pricing for Click2Mail&amp;rsquo;s postcards starts at $0.25
per card plus $0.284 postcard, but there&amp;rsquo;s a $2.00 minimum if
you don&amp;rsquo;t have credits on account. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to determine
at first glance whether their REST API applied to onesy-twoesy
printing options, though it was clear that if you wanted to send
1000 cards that the pricing would be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>espresso over ice with a little half and half</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 21:36:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple recipe that you can order from your favorite barista:
an espresso shot over ice. Leave enough room to add a spot of
half and half. Cold, refreshing, and very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try: a shot of espresso over shaved ice. I think this is
doable at Ann Arbor Farmers Market where you&amp;rsquo;d go to the stall
where a granny is selling shaved ice, and then walk a plain snow cone
over to the Roos Roast stand for your espresso shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a Facebook post from Allen Leibowitz in Texas ordering a snow cone
and the surrounding commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The weak ties of your social network are its greatest strength</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 14:01:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lior Zoref has a new book out called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1471756&#34;&gt;Mindsharing: the art of crowdsourcing everything&lt;/a&gt;
(Portfolio / Penguin, 2015). I have
a copy of it from the Ann Arbor District Library which was on the
new shelf at Mallett&amp;rsquo;s Creek on a sunny and hot summer Sunday
afternoon. Mallett&amp;rsquo;s has good air conditioning, a very good spot
to be on a warm day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.aadl.org/covers/1471756_200.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of a book like this is picking out the good bits
without repeating the author&amp;rsquo;s technique of using the word
&amp;ldquo;Mindsharing&amp;rdquo; (capitalized) at every opportunity. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to
unpack the approach with a simpler version of the
strategy, which seems to boil down to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make lots of connections online, even with people who you don&amp;rsquo;t
know very well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them really good questions when you are trying to make a decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of connections is the biggest suggestion here; rather than
get help from a small circle of trusted friends, the crowdsourcing
approach to human improvement relies on good ideas coming from
large or very large sets of people (at least 250), and relies on
pulling in unexpectedly good recommendations from people who don&amp;rsquo;t
know you very well.  Lior references Mark Granovetter&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Strength
of Weak Ties&amp;rdquo; (1973) early on, but of course Granovetter didn&amp;rsquo;t
know about Quora, Facebook, LinkedIn, and the host of other online
properties and lists that allow for computer-mediated interaction
with people at a distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an art to asking good questions that could fill a book.
If you look on the biggest question-answering websites like Quora
or Stack Exchange and start to follow along, you will quickly find
that good questions get rewarded with positive feedback and bad
questions (or impossible to answer questions) get ignored or criticized.
Lior points out the there&amp;rsquo;s a very big difference between typing a query
into a search engine and asking a live audience the same thing -
the human element of the search allows a personal connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lior is known for a TED talk (he brought an ox onstage) and is out
promoting his book. The book itself feels like an ideal airplane
read for someone who is aspiring to self-improvement, is facing a
career change, and who hasn&amp;rsquo;t figured out what the point is quite
yet with Facebook as a career tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular
&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years.
He died on July 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Hazen_Schumacher&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher&lt;/a&gt;
has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled
and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bixeibenhamburg.com/&#34;&gt;Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;,
and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bixrevisited.com&#34;&gt;http://bixrevisited.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited has reached millions, giving Hazen a good claim
to be America’s premier jazz educator.&amp;rdquo; (Art Hilgart - IAJRC Journal).
Bix Eiben Hamburg presents 24 different shows at regular intervals
for free listening. Dive into the wonderful world of classic Jazz.
Become part of the great Jazz fan community that already regularly
uses our service free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/84464117&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/84464117&#34;&gt;A tribute to The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and Jazz Revisited&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/bixeiben&#34;&gt;Jazz-Museum Bixeibenhamburg&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In remembrance of The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and a documentary report about the Jazz Revisited Radio Shows!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Midland G-227 GMRS/FRS radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 11:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Midland G-227 GMRS radio, quantity two, a gift from the
Wells-Becker Motorcycle Emporium in Dexter, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replaced batteries in both of them, they take 4xAAA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio 1 successfully hears static when the (M) monitor
button is depresssed; Radio 2 hears nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manual is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&#34;&gt;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&lt;/a&gt;
which describes the frequencies of the 22 channels it can transmit on.
A reasonable next step is to get my NooElec SDR tuner out and see if
I can monitor a transmission. If Radio 2 transmits, I suspect a loose
connection to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Midland-G-227C2-7-Mile-22-Channel-Two-Way/dp/B00008JOMG&#34;&gt;Amazon reviews&lt;/a&gt;
complain mostly that the range of the radios is not &amp;ldquo;7 miles&amp;rdquo; as
marketed, but closer to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; mile to 1 mile on land. That&amp;rsquo;s typical
for this band as I understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same gift also a Uniden labeled &amp;ldquo;Scramble&amp;rdquo; that has a NOAA
weather logo on it, so it probably also monitors weather frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can never have too many radios!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the memory palace
, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent
spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of
text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories
and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which
tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or
lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into
a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time. A good algorithm
will catch minor deviations from the norm and advise you when you
should go back with a fresh pair of eyes and do an edit.
The bigger problem is
deduplication
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at a proposed solution was to look for a version of
the old Unix program &amp;ldquo;uniq&amp;rdquo; that would have an approximate match.
There is also an old Unix program &amp;ldquo;agrep&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;approximate grep&amp;rdquo;) from
Udi Manber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[WM92a]
Wu S. and U. Manber, &amp;ldquo;Agrep - A Fast Approximate Pattern-Matching
Tool,&amp;rdquo; Usenix Winter 1992 Technical Conference, San Francisco (January
1992), pp. 153-162.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these first lines of attack to see if someone had
completely solved the problem before did the trick, but some
searching around and a conversation with
John Hritz

hit the neuron that remembered the algorithm called the
Levenshtein distance
.
That led me to
Wikibook: Algorithm Implementation
,
and its set of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Algorithm_Implementation/Strings/Levenshtein_distance&#34;&gt;Levenshtein distance code&lt;/a&gt;. It so happened that there
was a very slow implementation in the bash shell included
in that collection that was a cut and paste and two lines of
code from being exactly what I needed. A little bit of glue
code in awk and I was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the problem with cut and paste two lines of code is that this
particular implmentation is very slow, albeit correct. Given the
choice between slow correct code and fast code that&amp;rsquo;s wrong (because
of the bug that you don&amp;rsquo;t yet understand), I&amp;rsquo;ll take the slow code
plus a comment and a writeup that describes how to make it faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m really after is just the pairwise comparison of a set
of words where the two words are close to each other. If the
distance between two words is greater than some threshhold, I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to go any further. That algorithmic shortcut isn&amp;rsquo;t in the library
codes that I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger question is how to write a
checklist
and implement it in code to make sure that a big body of work stays
internally consistent. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to have a
categorization
rule for your writers that says &amp;ldquo;always use the
singular&amp;rdquo;, but very much something different to have Test 38 in
your automated test corpus apply that rule and notice when it&amp;rsquo;s
wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto, in checklist format</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-checklist-manifesto-summary-in-checklist-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-checklist-manifesto-summary-in-checklist-form/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My Checklist Manifesto summary (of course in checklist form) THANK YOU &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Atul_Gawande&#34;&gt;@Atul_Gawande&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PfsIMwcCiB&#34;&gt;http://t.co/PfsIMwcCiB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/ZfzP72RgiF&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZfzP72RgiF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Remo Uherek (@remouherek) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/remouherek/status/617272863599513600&#34;&gt;July 4, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>