<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 22:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Requesting meeting minutes under the Open Meetings Act</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-08-open-meetings-act-minutes-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-08-open-meetings-act-minutes-request/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated in the past at the slow pace of getting meeting minutes
through Freedom of Information Act requests. Queries to the City of Ann Arbor
routinely get the full round of routine delays, with several cases where I&amp;rsquo;ve
had to wait 15 business days to get routine meeting minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, there&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to asking for minutes, using the
Michigan Open Meetings Act directly as your guide. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recent request
that gave me same-day results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello, this is a request under the Michigan Open Meetings Act.

Please make available for inspection the draft minutes of the (named)
Committee meeting of today, December 8, 2015.

Under the terms of the Act, draft minutes are to be made available
for inspection within 8 business days of the date of the meeting,
or by my calendar December 18, 2015.

(Name) is listed as the staff contact for this board.

Thank you for your cooperation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The request was routed to the staff member, and the minutes were prepared
and ready and shared with me the same day that the meeting was held.
Same day service!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodi, formerly XMBC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-07-kodi-formerly-xmbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-07-kodi-formerly-xmbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kodi.tv&#34;&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt; as a possible software
core for home media player for the living room. We have a whole
rack of CDs and a shelf of LPs from our music-buying days, and I
miss being able to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kodi is the software formerly known as XMBC, and XMBC is still
the name of the foundation that supports the work. It runs on
most systems, and there are several distributions of it specifically
for systems like the Raspberry Pi. in particular the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.openelec.tv/index.php/OpenELEC_FAQ&#34;&gt;OpenELEC&lt;/a&gt;
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a review or a how to, just some notes so that when
I come back to the task I will have a better running start at it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Farber talk at Stanford</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-dave-farber-stanford-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-dave-farber-stanford-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk at Stanford, &amp;ldquo;Backwards towards the Future&amp;rdquo;,
Dave Farber goes over some Internet history on the way to
suggesting some necessary features of the future network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wCl-bKaER-s&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split tunnels considered harmful</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://meyerweb.com/eric/comment/chech.html&#34;&gt;Considered harmful essays considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;, Eric Meyer, 2002; also Go To Statement Considered Harmful, CACM, 1968; also &lt;a href=&#34;http://harmful.cat-v.org/&#34;&gt;Encyclopedia of things considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;, from cat-v.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split tunnels are a VPN construction where instead of
sending all of your traffic for the network in a single
encrypted tunnel that collects everything, you instead
route some traffic down the encrypted link and other traffic
goes in the clear through your default connection. It&amp;rsquo;s
possible that you might have a tunnel configuration with
multiple splits if e.g. you needed to get to private
address space at two or more organizations simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a choice, don&amp;rsquo;t use a split tunnel. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost are security considerations. The user of
the split tunnel introduces a possible forwarding path between
the outside Internet world (full of nefarious intent) and
the inside Internet world that you have a secure path to and
its chewy center. If an attacker knows that you are using a
split tunnel, they can put something on the public Internet
that causes you to send their traffic directly through to your private
network while you have all your trust relationships intact.
This could be bad, and if your security instincts trend towards
professional paranoia, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand that there&amp;rsquo;s a real risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second security consideration is unplanned leakage of private
information into the Internet. The split tunnel in its ordinary
configuration expects that you can distinguish protected traffic
from unprotected traffic by its IP address. The nature of
the modern Internet is that a browser can and will connect to
dozens or hundreds of hosts on its way to filling out a web page,
and any one of those connections might expose or leak some
information about what you were doing on the &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; link
that could be of use to an adversary or snoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, split tunnels are difficult to verify as correctly
configured. The managed endpoint of the tunnel can only see
traffic destined for it, and can only verify that what&amp;rsquo;s
there is going to the endpoint. With a split, the managed
endpoint doesn&amp;rsquo;t have visibility into all traffic destinations
and thus is completely unaware of any exfiltration attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there may be reasons that a split tunnel is unavoidable.
Here are some considerations to balance against the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A split tunnel is more versatile than a full tunnel. If your
users need to connect to more than one administrative domain
simultaenously, they may need to configure their local host
setup to have two or more split tunnels running at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the tunnel endpoint is at the long end of a slow connection,
or if the trusted managed endpoint is bandwidth or CPU constrained,
performance through a full tunnel may be unacceptably bad.
Splitting the tunnel means that only necessary traffic goes through
it, allowing better use of network resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s the cost. If the user is going to be a typical
Internet use and do simultaneous Spotify or Netflix or other
streaming media, it seems insane to pay VPN charges or engineer
your own VPN endpoint to handle that full stream of data when it
could very easily go over a lowest-cost unencrypted link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The productivity oscillator</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Github issues for a long time as a todo list
tracking and general productivity tool. It works well enough that
I&amp;rsquo;ve opened over 4000 issues and have closed most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perpetual management challenge is in deciding how many issues
is OK to leave open. Put too few in, and it feels like you have
things to do that are not written down; put in too many, and you&amp;rsquo;re
likely to have duplication and you forget what it is that you were
trying to do in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of the challenge is having some illusion of
control over what is going on. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to work the queue
this way. Some times my goal will be to create more open issues,
putting things on the list to increase it up to a target goal.
Other times the goal will be to reduce the size of the list by
finishing tasks, clearing duplicates, or deciding not to get things
done. By framing it as a deliberate game of &amp;ldquo;add tasks up to a
target&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;clear tasks down to a target&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to trick
myself into taking on the easy things that I wrote down a month
ago that will take a minute to do but are off my immediate radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The productivity oscillator suggests both a pattern of work and
the illusion that whatever you are doing is the right thing to do.
If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck trying to get stubborn things accomplished, write
done some new easy goals and get those taken care of. It&amp;rsquo;s
a quantified form of &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/04/marginally_usef.html&#34;&gt;structured procrastination&lt;/a&gt; - which it turns out
I&amp;rsquo;ve been talknig about for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if there&amp;rsquo;s anything still on my todo list from 2005!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicked out of Nextdoor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-kicked-out-of-nextdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 19:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-kicked-out-of-nextdoor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Subject: Recent Tweet about Nextdoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Ed,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Michael and I work at Nextdoor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently it has come to our attention that there isn’t a Nextdoor
for your neighborhood, and that you have registered in a nearby
Nextdoor neighborhood. Thank you for your interest in joining
Nextdoor and becoming part of your community on our website. However
we do need people to register at their real addresses, as it helps
us add a sense of accountability, security and transparency to the
website. Due to privacy concerns, I am forced to place a hold on
your account. However, this need not be a long hold! If you give
me your address, you and I can work on building a neighborhood for
you together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know how you would like to proceed. I am excited to
get you started on your new Nextdoor neighborhood soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your day,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Michael [Last name redacted for privacy]
Nextdoor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Wanted, Ann Arbor City Administrator, via Craiglist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-30-ann-arbor-city-administrator-craigslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 20:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-30-ann-arbor-city-administrator-craigslist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://annarbor.craigslist.org/gov/5338653370.html&#34;&gt;As seen on Craigslist.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City Administrator (Ann Arbor) compensation: $150K/yr employment type: full-time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Administrator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job Responsibilities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed Council Members information on a bi-weekly schedule, sometimes more frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind Council Members of basic stuff like how object permanence is an actual thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond appropriately when Council Members insist &amp;ldquo;I can do it all by my self.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond appropriately when Council Members say &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how, you do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let Council Members feel they&amp;rsquo;re in control, but not so much that they wreck stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10-15 years experience in child care setting, with increasing responsibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to feign genuine interest in oddball ideas of Council Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversant in full range of ways Ann Arbor residents feel superior to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability look at a roomful of white people and remark on amazing diversity of perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attached to your resume, please respond with an essay on the topic
of: Is Public Engagement for the Birds, or for the Deer or for the
Dog Parks? Into the natural flow of your essay, please integrate
an answer to the question: If you were a dog, what kind of tree
would you choose to pee on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dave Askins for noticing this (via Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2015 food inspections for Washtenaw County</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-27-october-2015-food-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-27-october-2015-food-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month or so the Washtenaw County Health Department releases the previous month&amp;rsquo;s
health inspection reports. These are published to the county&amp;rsquo;s contracted web service,
and a copy of those is extracted for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/&#34;&gt;Food Inspections&lt;/a&gt;
service designed by Wayne Eaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 272 inspections for October 2015 and 50 more for November 2015 available. Here
are some of the low lights of this month&amp;rsquo;s round of inspections, places where you might
want to think about twice before making a visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-11-03-dalat-restaurant&#34;&gt;Dalat&lt;/a&gt;,
Ypsilanti, inspected on November 3. &amp;ldquo;Observed sewage backing up to
the floor underneath the food prep sink.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Raw chicken and beef
boxes being used to store other ready to eat foods (i.e. vegtables)
in various coolers in the facility.&amp;rdquo; 12 violations total, 8 critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-11-02-melting-pot&#34;&gt;Melting Pot&lt;/a&gt;,
Ann Arbor, their last inspection on November 2 before the restaurant closed
for good later in the month. &amp;ldquo;Observed the dishwasher go from loading soiled dishes to putting away clean dishes without washing hands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-21-great-plains-burger-company&#34;&gt;Great Plains Burger Company&lt;/a&gt;,
Ann Arbor, inspected on October 21 with 14 total violations.
&amp;ldquo;Observed many small flies (fruit flies) around prep sink where french fries are prepared.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Containers used to store french fries observed soiled. A cleaned inverted container observed with many flies trapped under it and were seen landing on container.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-29-shalimar-restaurant&#34;&gt;Shalimar Restaraunt&lt;/a&gt;
on Main Street in Ann Arbor, inspected on October 29 with 3 total violations.
&amp;ldquo;Observed 4 bottles of liquor with flies inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-21-haabs-restaurant&#34;&gt;Haab&amp;rsquo;s Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;
in Ypsilanti with 15 violations on October 21.
&amp;ldquo;Observed the hand sink for the basement kitchen wrapped in plastic wrap to avoid using due to unrepair leaking.
The only available hand sink is in another area through a door and significant distance away from this kitchen.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Observed severe infestation of drain flies noted at bar and main kitchen.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Observed drain flies in the bottom of open bottle of scotch at bar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check out your favorite destination before visiting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First snow of the 2015 season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-21-first-snow-of-the-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-21-first-snow-of-the-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first snow of the 2015 season for Ann Arbor happened
today, November 21. The forecast is 6 to 10 inches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roads are slippery, and there are reports of a number
of crashes and cars in the ditch on area freeways. I&amp;rsquo;m
listening to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broadcastify.com/listen/feed/3913/web/?rl=rr&#34;&gt;Washtenaw scanner&lt;/a&gt;
on Broadcastify and it&amp;rsquo;s a steady stream of road run-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farmers Market was busy but snowy. Holiday greenery
was well in evidence. We picked up smoked lake trout,
cabbage, garlic, rapini, and a cookie and a donut for
my market companions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite source of snow forecasting and snow reporting
is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nohrsc.noaa.gov/&#34;&gt;NOHRSC&lt;/a&gt;, the
National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center,
a slightly contrived acronym for the National Weather
Service&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive snow information service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of the snow season means that I dust off
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/heikkilunta&#34;&gt;Heikki Lunta twitter account&lt;/a&gt;,
@heikkilunta . Heikki is the Finnish-American god of snow,
and his Twitter account mostly retweets people who are
doing snow dances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November has been unusually mild and sunny, so this
snow brings us a little closer to normal. Time to check
to be sure that every has hats and gloves and suitably
durable boots and shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN in a container</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 16:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few notes on setting up OpenVPN in a container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using CoreOS, which gives me Docker 1.7.1 in the &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different Docker configurations are available that take on this task,
with slightly different setups. Kyle Manna&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kylemanna/docker-openvpn&#34;&gt;docker-openvpn&lt;/a&gt;
is what I&amp;rsquo;m working with; it in turn is derived from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jpetazzo/dockvpn&#34;&gt;jpetazzo/dockvpn&lt;/a&gt; which
solves the same problem slightly differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-run-openvpn-in-a-docker-container-on-ubuntu-14-04&#34;&gt;tutorial on Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;
that describes the setup including client-side support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second &lt;a href=&#34;https://stefanscherer.github.io/run-your-own-dockerized-openvpn-server-at-scaleway/&#34;&gt;tutorial by Stefan Scherer&lt;/a&gt;
gives instructions for use in the Scaleway ARM-based server cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m at the stage right now where I downloaded and installed
everything and created an &amp;ldquo;opvn&amp;rdquo; config file that successfully
loads into Tunnelblick, but where it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite yet have
all of the routing set up. The slight complication in the
configuration is that I want to give access to Amazon
VPCs, so I have a few layers of software-defined networking
to knit together (or to unravel depending on your perspective).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;network ho!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stage lighting protocols</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-stage-lighting-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-stage-lighting-protocols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes on stage lighting protocols and networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helpful reference pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dmx512-online.com/&#34;&gt;Ujjal&amp;rsquo;s DMX512 Website&lt;/a&gt; - protocol information,
tutorials, how to etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dmx512.com/&#34;&gt;DMX512.com, the Entertainment Technology Website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openlighting.org/&#34;&gt;Open Lighting Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standards bodies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usitt.org/lighting/&#34;&gt;USITT Lighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some protocols&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://art-net.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Art-Net&lt;/a&gt; is DMX512 over UDP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openlighting.org/libartnet-main/&#34;&gt;libartnet&lt;/a&gt; is an implementation of Art-Net.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s much much more, but this is a start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enjoy the attic while you can</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-enjoy-the-attic-while-you-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-enjoy-the-attic-while-you-can/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our attic is a three season room at best. In the depths
of winter it&amp;rsquo;s really cold, and in the summer time it can
be very hot. There&amp;rsquo;s a nod towards climate control but
it&amp;rsquo;s a long way from the furnace and the space is just
not really practical to equip as full fledged living space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a work table up there (where I am now) with some
tools, a few working shortwave radios, a couple of mostly
working computers, and a fair measure of junk. It&amp;rsquo;s been
the place where toys go when the boys have no interest in playing
with them again, which is to say that everything that&amp;rsquo;s
not Lego is up here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the weather stays mild, I have ambition to put
the space to better use. At the bare minimum I&amp;rsquo;d like to
get to the point where every day I get upstairs to do
something, and where every time I come back down I have
something in my hands to put to better use somewhere else
or to throw away or recycle. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do marathon
sorting and cleaning sessions and it&amp;rsquo;s just not me, but
the every day approach at least gives you a chance for a
series of small wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, bit by bit, work at it. At some point it will get too
cold, and let yourself quit then. Try not to do everything at once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write one paragraph, floss one tooth</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-write-one-paragraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-write-one-paragraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The a2b3 lunch today was at Madras Masala, we had a crowd of 10.
I had a question about productivity - &amp;ldquo;what do you do every day&amp;rdquo; -
and the answers were a good mix of attempts to be diligent and
questions about whether narrowly focused productivity was even
a good goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The small productivity approach that has stuck with me is BJ Fogg&amp;rsquo;s
&amp;ldquo;Tiny Habits&amp;rdquo; approach, which he writes about on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyhabits.com/&#34;&gt;http://tinyhabits.com/&lt;/a&gt; .
The focus is not on New Years Resolution style &amp;ldquo;be a better person&amp;rdquo; goals,
but on very small and attainable accompishments which you can use
to build upon. &amp;ldquo;Floss one tooth&amp;rdquo; is the smallest example goal I can give,
with the understanding that if you can build up a solid habit to do
that every day then there&amp;rsquo;s lots more you can do for better dental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing equivalent of that is &amp;ldquo;write one paragraph&amp;rdquo;. I know that
trying to blog every single day is a task I&amp;rsquo;ve tried and failed before,
but I also know that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take forever to write a paragraph, and
you don&amp;rsquo;t have to have more than one idea to express to make that paragraph
worthwhile. Faced with an impossibly big deadline for an impossibly big
project, the thought goes, you might break down your resistance to working
on the effort by declaring victory at the paragraph level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week&amp;rsquo;s lunch (the day after Thanksgiving 2015) is at Morgan and York,
hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine, old school email</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-alpine-old-school-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-alpine-old-school-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;alpine is an old school Unix mail user agent. It first arrived
on the scene as pine in 1992, and when it appeared I remember
how happy I was that there was finally a mailer that I could
hand to people who had never seen Unix before and that they
would get it and be productive on their 14.4 kb/sec dialup
modems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alpine appeared in 2007 as a rewrite of pine with Unicode
support and a new Apache license. The version of it I&amp;rsquo;m running
advertises itself as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Alpine 2.20 (OSX 67 2015-01-07) built Fri Oct 2 21:36:59 EDT 2015 on Edwards-MacBook-Air.local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and seems to work just fine. I&amp;rsquo;ve got it pointed at the
old-school shared multiuser mail system that I&amp;rsquo;ve had
for a long time at monkey.org and all is well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rubenerd weblog has a nice
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/p3302/&#34;&gt;guide to installing alpine on OS X&lt;/a&gt;
using your favorite package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of alpine over all web-based
mail systems is just how fast you can delete mail.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to select by pattern, sort, refile and
especially delete. In comparison, Google&amp;rsquo;s GMail
feels clumsy and slow and impossibly mouse-dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I moved all my email over to alpine? No. There&amp;rsquo;s
a very small number of people who I prefer to send
mail to that way, and it&amp;rsquo;s always good to have a
fully functional backup email system that works
perfectly well on a low-bandwidth setup. My workflow
inside GMail is pretty fine tuned at this point and
very different from how I used to use pine, and I&amp;rsquo;m
not willing to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does remind me of the days before spam, and of the
days when you were actually happy to get messages!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2016 construction plans for M-14 near Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-m-14-summer-2016-construction-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-m-14-summer-2016-construction-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MDOT plans to do major road construction work on M-14 in Ann Arbor
between Main Street and Miller Road during the spring and summer of 2016.
A construction start date has not been set yet as of November 2015.
In addition, bridge work will reduce M-14 to one lane between I-94
and Miller Road, and betwen Main Street and US-23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed set of plans is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.gov/mdot/0,4616,7-151-9621_11008_74324---,00.html&#34;&gt;on the MDOT web site&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.gov/documents/mdot/MDOT_M14AnnArborBrochure_504933_7.pdf&#34;&gt;in a helpful brochure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posted detour for M-14 will follow US-23 and I-94 around the freeway
loop around Ann Arbor. The following bridges will also have work done on
that that will close them for some amount of time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over the Huron River, the railroad tracks and Bandemer Park,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over Beechwood Drive,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newport Road over M-14,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over Maple Road, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miller Road over M-14.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was talk of a part of Bandemer Park to be used as a staging area
for MDOT construction equipment. A review of the city&amp;rsquo;s Legistar system
did not unearth anything that would have been a necessary city review or
approval of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Chuck Warpehoski for the heads up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>