<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave New N8SBE to speak at ARROW on Software Defined Radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dave New N8SBE will be speaking at the January 2016 meeting of
the ARROW radio club on the topic of Software Defined Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will present an introduction to GNU Radio and the GNU Radio
Companion visual programming environment, and the HackRF One Software
Defined Transceiver from Great Scott Gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo will include a disucssion of receiver and transmitter flow
graphs, as well as resources to learn more about
digital signal processing using the HackRF One and GNU Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARROW meets Wednesday, January 13, 2016, from 7:00 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. at
Washtenaw Community College, room BE-172 or nearby room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details contact ARROW at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w8pgw.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.w8pgw.org/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Michigan University spokesman responds to Morning Sun editorial regarding WCMU-TV spectrum auction</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 17:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 8, 2016, 5:30 pm (Ann Arbor time): Central Michigan University
spokesman Steve Smith answered questions today by telephone regarding
a Morning Sun editorial, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themorningsun.com/opinion/20160108/editorial-status-quo-cmu-mum-on-talk-of-shutting-tv-station&#34;&gt;Status quo: CMU mum on talk of shutting TV station&lt;/a&gt;, published in this Digital First Media newspaper
from Mt. Pleasant, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the lede, the newspaper writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Central Michigan University considers whether or not to shut
down its Public Broadcasting television network, the silence is
deafening.  CMU trustees almost a month ago voted to consider
shutting WCMU-TV and its three sister stations in exchange for up
to $726 million from the Federal Communications Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith poined out that the University had only approved to &amp;ldquo;apply
for eligibility&amp;rdquo;, which is not binding on CMU to proceed, and that
all options were open. In addition, he noted a Federal anti-collusion
rule that restricts the rights of potential auction participants
to speak freely about their intent leading up to the auction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Michigan University invites public comment on its decisions
to sell part or all of its broadcast spectrum back to the FCC, in an
auction that is scheduled to begin on March 29, 2016. Address your
comments in email to trustees@cmich.edu or by postal mail to
106 Warriner Hall, Central Michigan University, Mt. Pleasant, MI 48859.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmich.edu/bot/Pages/default.aspx&#34;&gt;The next public meeting of the Trustees is on February 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;,
and with prior arrangement there is time for the public to provide
comment on agenda items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for the Federal Communications Commission, which
manages this auction, was not available for comment at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference see the following FCC documents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://transition.fcc.gov/Daily_Releases/Daily_Business/2015/db0806/DOC-334756A1.pdf&#34;&gt;FCC ESTABLISHES BIDDING PROCEDURES FOR
2016 INCENTIVE AUCTION
Auction Scheduled to Begin March 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;, August 6, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.fcc.gov/edocs_public/attachmatch/DA-15-1129A1.pdf&#34;&gt;GUIDANCE REGARDING THE PROHIBITION OF CERTAIN COMMUNICATIONS DURING
THE INCENTIVE AUCTION, AUCTION 1000&lt;/a&gt;, FCC Public Notice DA 15-1129.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Liquor License Review Committee report, 8 January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-a2council-liquor-license-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-a2council-liquor-license-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Hall, January 8, 2016 - A brief report from a jammed
Council committee meeting held in the council workroom. The committee
moved public comment time to the begining of the meeting to hear
concerns of citizens who objected to a previous decision of the committee,
memorialized as follows on Legistar as 15-1179 enacted on October 16, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution to Approve a Request from Aquamarine Springs, LLC for a New Micro-Brewer, Small Wine-Maker, Small Distiller Liquor License and Dance/Entertainment Permit, to be Located at 507 S. Ashley Street Sponsors: Council Liquor License Review Committee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee noted that the building is located in the floodway and is also part of the Old West Side Historic District. Committee members discussed the fact that any renovation to the building would require further review by the Fire and Building Departments and may also require site plan approval. It was noted that this approval was only for the applicant to proceed with the liquor license application process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A motion was made by Councilmember Kailasapathy, seconded by Councilmember Lumm, that the Resolution be recommended for approval to the City Council on 10/19/2015. On a voice vote, the Chair declared the motion carried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The citizens at the meeting objected to this decision, both
that they were not properly informed of the decision making
at the time as well as the observation that there is a preschool
nearby that should have the right to object to the decision.
Several people at this meeting had gone to Lansing to register their
complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also on the docket was a proposal from Glass House Brewing LLC for
a &amp;ldquo;New Micro-Brewer Liquor License to be Located at 2350 W. Liberty
Street&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More later as time and space warrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Arborwiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Aquamarine_Springs&#34;&gt;Aquamarine Springs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Glass_House_Brewing&#34;&gt;Glass House Brewing&lt;/a&gt;,
both are just the start of the articles at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Flood Network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-oxford-flood-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-oxford-flood-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Oxford Flood Network is making a flood detection network in
the UK, using low cost sensors and volunteers. They are sharing
their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oxfloodnet&#34;&gt;code on Github&lt;/a&gt; and their
results on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flood_network&#34;&gt;Flood_Network&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They encourage you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://flood.network/join&#34;&gt;join their effort&lt;/a&gt;,
and no high technology is necessary. The network incorporates
both readings from automated sensors (about £250) as well as
manual readings from gaugeboards or photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New as of December 2015 is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nominet.uk/iot-technology-powers-an-interactive-flood-map-and-sensor-network/&#34;&gt;interactive flood map&lt;/a&gt;.
A post from Nominet describes the effort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominet, in association with the Flood Network, is today launching an interactive, online map which visualises river and stream levels around Oxford. The map, showing how technology can be a part of flood defence systems anywhere, has been developed following a successful pilot project with the Oxford Flood Network. The project has been focused on exploring the potential of the Internet of Things (IoT) to create an extensive, localised, early-warning system for flood-prone areas for the first time in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is using TVWS (&amp;ldquo;TV white space&amp;rdquo;) as its wide area backhaul
network for these sensors for hard-to-reach devices that are outside
of the range of wifi. Cost-effective and reliable access to remote
small sensors is one of the tough spots in Internet of Things development,
it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see TVWS as a possible solution to this issue.
The other relevant technology for low-cost metro area networks for
sensors is Lorawan, more about which later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire on Inverness in Dexter, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-dexter-fire-inverness-condo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 21:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-dexter-fire-inverness-condo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A condo on Inverness in Dexter, Michigan was on fire on
Thursday evening, January 7, 2016. A first report came
in at about 7:24 p.m. via MEI Dispatch.
Dexter Area Fire Chief Robert Smith said no one was injured in the fire,
according to MLive.
Reports were monitored on Twitter,
Facebook, and the Washtenaw County scanner on Broadcastify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least five fire departments - Scio Township, Putnam Township,
Chelsea, Ann Arbor Township and Ann Arbor City - came to the
aid of Dexter in fighting the blaze, according to reports
monitored on Facebook by MEI Dispatch. MLive reported that
Hamburg Township also assisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLive reporter Darcie Moran and photographer Melanie
Maxwell are at the scene and have filed this story,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2016/01/fire_tears_through_dexter_cond.html&#34;&gt;Fire tears through Dexter condo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt King, 23, was finishing up dinner in his ground-level condo on Jan. 7 in the 4500 block of Inverness Street in the Huron Farms development when he heard &amp;ldquo;explosions&amp;rdquo; in the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A photo from the scene was provided by ABC 7 (Washington DC)
meteorologist Steve Rudin on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/psa2&#34;&gt;@psa2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/a2kelly&#34;&gt;@a2kelly&lt;/a&gt; My longtime childhood friend posted this from her backyard. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9jkyXtUWga&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9jkyXtUWga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steve Rudin ABC7 (@SteveRudinABC7) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SteveRudinABC7/status/685282625657946112&#34;&gt;January 8, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WXYZ 7 Action News reported live from the scene,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wxyz.com/news/region/washtenaw-county/residents-of-dexter-condo-complex-homeless-after-their-units-are-destoyed-by-fire&#34;&gt;Residents of Dexter condo complex homeless after their units are destoyed by fire&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly Palkowski, Lorrie Shaw, Kelly Ann Arnold, and Rich Landskroener Jr.
contributed to this report. Special thanks to Paul Zekas of MEI Dispatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updated 10:52 p.m. with MLive story. Reports differ on the full
composition of the mutual aid team. Updated 11:30 p.m. with WXYZ story.
Some reports have &amp;ldquo;Huron Farms&amp;rdquo; as the condo complex, others have
&amp;ldquo;Huron Commons&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washtenaw County Health Department delays food inspection reporting from November 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-county-health-food-inspection-delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 08:15:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-county-health-food-inspection-delays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing this message from the Washtenaw County Health Department
regarding their delayed publication of restaurant inspection reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Angela Parsons
12/22/15

Greetings all,

Sincere apologies, but we are experiencing technical difficulties
with our inspection software and I am unable to retrieve the
restaurant inspection list for November. Kristen is currently on
vacation and will return on December 29th. I am hoping that she
will be able to remedy the issue and will be able to send along the
results at that time.

So sorry for any inconvenience!!

Angie

Angela Parsons, MA Environmental Health Education Coordinator
Washtenaw County Public Health - Environmental Health Division 705
N. Zeeb Rd., P.O. Box 8645 Ann Arbor, MI  48107-8645 Zeeb Office:
(734) 222-3869 Towner Office: (734) 544-6862 Cell: (734) 320-0094
parsonsa@ewashtenaw.org

Confidentiality Notice: This message, including any attachments is
intended solely for the use of the named recipient(s) and may contain
confidential and/or privileged information. Any unauthorized review,
use, disclosure, or distribution of this communication(s) is expressly
prohibited. If you are not the intended recipient, please contact
the sender by reply e-mail and destroy any and all copies of the
original message, including attachments.  

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuts coming to MLive, 2016 edition; 29 content positions eliminated</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-cuts-coming-to-mlive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-cuts-coming-to-mlive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR, MICHIGAN, January 6, 2016. Columbia Journalism Review&amp;rsquo;s
Anna Clark broke the news of cuts at MLive to journalist jobs there,
in this post on Twitter. Details to follow as I have them.
Reports, as of yet unconfirmed, suggest that MLive will shed
jobs statewide including at the Ann Arbor News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLive posted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/index.ssf/2016/01/mlive_media_group_announces_ne.html&#34;&gt;news release&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;MLive Media Group announces news restructuring&amp;rdquo;, which reads in part:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of staff members producing content – reporters, photographers and producers in video and social media – remains intact statewide, although some roles will evolve based on audience demands, Hiner said. Overall, 29 content positions will be eliminated, primarily through reducing management roles and jobs related to newspaper production, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Hiner, a former Bay City Times and Flint Journal editor, is
vice president of content at MLive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Maynard has commentary and some names of locals who are being
reassigned or laid off, in his post
&lt;a href=&#34;http://markmaynard.com/2016/01/a-terrible-blow-to-journalism-mlive-cuts-29-jobs-at-a-time-when-michigan-desperately-needs-quality-reporting/?utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&#34;&gt;A “terrible blow to journalism, ” MLive cuts 29 jobs at a time when Michigan desperately needs quality reporting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s not yet official, as far as I know, word is that several of these 29 jobs eliminated across the company were in the Ann Arbor office. As I understand it, the two managing producers, Cindy Heflin and Julie Taylor, were both laid off, as was entertainment reporter Jenn McKee. And others have been reassigned to statewide positions. Paula Gardener, for instance, will be stepping away from her editorial duties to become a statewide business reporter. Likewise, I’m told that John Counts and Jessica Webster will also be shifting to the statewide team. As for editorial duties, it’s unclear to me what they’ll be doing without Gardener in that role, but I’m told a few new people will be coming into the organization, so perhaps one of them will be charged with such tasks. For instance, I hear that someone named Jen Eyer has been named the new “team leader,” which I’m hoping is something at least approximating an editor. [Without an editor, it might as well be a blog, right?]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A request for comment from MLive Media Group president Dan Gaydou
was not immediately acknowledged. (To be fair, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Twitter
much, and it was my first DM to him.) Ann Arbor News editor
Paula Gardner also did not respond to a Twitter DM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Confirmed: Job cuts have come to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;, incl. on the journalism side. MLive will post a story shortly; I&amp;#39;ll have a CJR story in a bit too.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Anna Clark (@annaleighclark) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annaleighclark/status/684816176791326721&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Since reports are out there now:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I&amp;#39;m absolutely devastated by what&amp;#39;s going on at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;. Some amazing people are losing their jobs today.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kyle Feldscher (@Kyle_Feldscher) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Kyle_Feldscher/status/684824892198547456&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Thoughts are with my friends and former colleagues at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MuskegonChron&#34;&gt;@MuskegonChron&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;. Too many shorthanded newsrooms stretched even thinner.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dillon Davis (@DillonDavis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DillonDavis/status/684824272381054980&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Sad to hear about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt; staff cuts. It&amp;#39;s an org full of many talented journalists, &amp;amp; on a personal note, many friends/former Spartans.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Celeste Bott (@celestebott) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/celestebott/status/684823310950117377&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WKAR-TV television spectrum may be up for sale, and the station is at risk</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-wkar-television-spectrum-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-wkar-television-spectrum-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan State University is considering placing the spectrum
that it uses for WKAR-TV into an auction that the FCC is running,
in which case it might receive upwards of $200 million in exchange
for ceasing all of its terrestrial broadcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strikes me as a penny wise, pound foolish approach. Once
the spectrum is gone you can&amp;rsquo;t get it back, and as a land grant
institution should know it&amp;rsquo;s important to be a good steward of
the resources you have been handed not just for the short term
but for the long term. Selling off a 50+ year tradition of
public broadcasting for a quick buck seems like a bad approach,
no matter how appealing a big check would be, especially
considering the community&amp;rsquo;s investment in the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have a TV receiver for over the air broadcasts,
but my neighbor down the street who does make the trek from Ann
Arbor to Lansing to give her thoughts. Her family grew up on WKAR-TV
and have been supporters for years, and they rely on over the
air television to bring in the signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More as I have it; I&amp;rsquo;m collecting links and news articles at
the Lansing Localwiki, at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/lansing/WKAR-TV&#34;&gt;WKAR-TV&lt;/a&gt;
page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Morse Code</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-02-learning-morse-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:01:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-02-learning-morse-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn Morse Code, at least to be able to copy characters at a
a fast enough pace to understand what the IDs on the local 2 meter
amateur repeaters are saying. Over a previous holiday break I had
sorted out at least a little bit of sending Morse, so some letters
are already familiar (CQ, K, E, SOS). I don&amp;rsquo;t yet know how to either
send or recognize my call sign. There&amp;rsquo;s a ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward Cunningham K9OX has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/~ward/morse/&#34;&gt;page full of ham radio software&lt;/a&gt;, including a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/~ward/morse/morse.html&#34;&gt;Morse Code Teaching Machine&lt;/a&gt;
that does a nifty adaptive learning system to feed you the letters
you need work on. It dates from the article
&lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/morse/wiki.cgi?QstArticle&#34;&gt;A Fully Automatic Morse Code Teaching Machine, QST (May 1977)&lt;/a&gt;.
Ward wrote it to fit on a very tiny machine, and it&amp;rsquo;s been subsequently
ported and improved to run on bigger machines, but still at its heart
it&amp;rsquo;s old and tiny (and in some essential way very wonderful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using the Macintosh version; there&amp;rsquo;s an interesting
version for Ward&amp;rsquo;s federated wiki as well, which would
be worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;73 de Ed KD8OQG&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QSL card template for Lob.com</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-01-qsl-card-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-01-qsl-card-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As previously noted here I&amp;rsquo;m fond of getting and sending postcards.
I&amp;rsquo;m also a ham radio operator, which makes it reasonable to want
to get and send postcards as QSL cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a stockpile of preprinted cards, so my habit is to
recycle old postcards either from PTO Thrift ($0.10 each) or from
a local bookseller ($0.00 each), apply a postcard stamp, and hand
write the details. But I&amp;rsquo;ve also successfully send cards using
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lob.com&#34;&gt;lob.com service&lt;/a&gt; and the thought is that
if I got my act together I could pretty easily put together a
QSL printer that would run off a command line and lob full-custom cards
into the mail at about $0.70 each postage paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t yet have a QSL card template for lob.com. Some notes for
starting such a project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lob.com/blog/print-mail-custom-postcards-using-html-css-ruby-on-rails&#34;&gt;Print and Mail Custom Postcards using HTML, CSS, and Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lob.com/blog/free-4x6-postcard-templates/&#34;&gt;Free 4x6 Postcard Templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of &amp;ldquo;QSL template&amp;rdquo; pages on the net, but most
of them start from Microsoft Word, and I&amp;rsquo;m after an HTML
QSL template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;No results found for &amp;quot;html qsl template&amp;quot;.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of SQL, not much QSL. Will keep looking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I turned 99 cents worth of kale into half a gallon of delicious ice cream</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-22-kale-into-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-22-kale-into-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Learn this one weird trick&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Grocery stores hate him&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really though it&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple. Lucky&amp;rsquo;s had a sale on kale for
99 cents, so I bought one bunch. The clerk rang it up at $2.49, and
when I asked, they said it was organic. I figured I had pulled it
from the wrong bin, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get home, cook the kale (it&amp;rsquo;s delicious; recipe below). Check the
twist tie to check my mistake, and find out that the kale wasn&amp;rsquo;t
actually organic, and that I was overcharged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been through the &amp;ldquo;Lucky&amp;rsquo;s overcharges&amp;rdquo; before on our neighborhood
email list, where it comes up from time to time., I didn&amp;rsquo;t
have to quote chapter and verse of state law, just mention the
Michigan scan law. The manager hand wrote a receipt and gave me
$5.00 cash as well as refunding the purchase price of the kale on
my card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to buy any more kale. Chocolate ice cream
was $4.99 per half gallon, and it too was delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save your receipts, at least until the meal is eaten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the twist-ties on your produce to make sure you got what you were charged for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic produce PLU numbers are 5 digits starting with a 9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucky&amp;rsquo;s was friendly when I pointed out their error, no hassle at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauteed kale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bunch kale (organic preferred)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 clove garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat the oil until it shimmers. Slice the garlic into slices and
cook until fragrant but not yet browned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash the kale and trim the stems . Chop the leaves finely. Add to
hot pan and stir until the kale has wilted somewhat and has changed
color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of water to the pan, then cover quickly. Steam
the kale until cooked to taste.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe to a2b3 list through Mailchimp</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-21-mailchimp-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-21-mailchimp-form/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form --&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup&#34;&gt;
&lt;form action=&#34;//typepad.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=b49a88d15414eb4f2f3f65e10&amp;amp;id=5c925e726c&#34; method=&#34;post&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; name=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&#34; class=&#34;validate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; novalidate&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mc_embed_signup_scroll&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Subscribe to our mailing list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;indicates-required&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;asterisk&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; indicates required&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
    &lt;label for=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;Email Address  &lt;span class=&#34;asterisk&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;EMAIL&#34; class=&#34;required email&#34; id=&#34;mce-EMAIL&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
    &lt;label for=&#34;mce-FNAME&#34;&gt;First Name &lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;FNAME&#34; class=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;mce-FNAME&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mc-field-group&#34;&gt;
    &lt;label for=&#34;mce-LNAME&#34;&gt;Last Name &lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; value=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;LNAME&#34; class=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;mce-LNAME&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/home/?u=b49a88d15414eb4f2f3f65e10&amp;id=5c925e726c&#34; title=&#34;View previous campaigns&#34;&gt;View previous campaigns.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;mce-responses&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-error-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;response&#34; id=&#34;mce-success-response&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;!-- real people should not fill this in and expect good things - do not remove this or risk form bot signups--&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;b_b49a88d15414eb4f2f3f65e10_5c925e726c&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; value=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Subscribe&#34; name=&#34;subscribe&#34; id=&#34;mc-embedded-subscribe&#34; class=&#34;button&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--End mc_embed_signup--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit to the Computer and Video Game Archive, @umcvga</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-18-a-visit-to-um-cvga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-18-a-visit-to-um-cvga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/&#34;&gt;University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) Fifth Anniversary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a chance to spend some time at the U of Michigan
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guides.lib.umich.edu/cvga&#34;&gt;Computer and Video Game Archive&lt;/a&gt;
tonight, with J in tow (or perhaps I was in tow).
We played for about two hours in total, and then adjourned
for dinner to talk about new and classic gaming and game emulation.
He snuck in a few games of Tetris on his phone afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a few game reviews and observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first game I turn to at the UMCVGA is an arcade version of
Centipede. The archive has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arcadelegends.com/&#34;&gt;Arcade Legends&lt;/a&gt;
cabinet that has real arcade controls, and then emulated games
running on some kind of Linux system running MAME inside.
&amp;ldquo;Legendary arcade games authentic in every detail&amp;rdquo; says the pitch,
and the game comes with the crucial trackball that makes the
arcade version of Centipede a singular experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an Atari game, Centipede is also available on other systems, and
I looked at it on the Atari 2600, running on original hardware
including a vintage analog television set for the display. Centipede
is not very complex, and the 2600 version is faithful to the original
gameplay for the most part. The graphics are as flickery as I had
ever remembered, especially when you hit your target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reasonable life goal is to play Centipede on as many systems as
the Archive supports. The Mirlyn catalog currently suggests
that there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirlyn.lib.umich.edu/Search/Home?type%5B%5D=all&amp;amp;lookfor%5B%5D=centipede%20game&amp;amp;filter%5B%5D=format%3AVideo%20Games&#34;&gt;eight versions of Centipede&lt;/a&gt; available, on platforms including
Sega Dreamcast,
the TI-99,
Atari 2600,
Sega Genesis,
Playstation Portable (PSP),
Windows 95 / 98,
Playstation, and
Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animal Crossing on the Nintendo 3DS was new to me, though I had
heard &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chairckicker&#34;&gt;Brian Kerr&lt;/a&gt; talk about it
for quite some time. Animal Crossing is really fun in a quirky little
way that a social casual game that&amp;rsquo;s age-appropriate for seven year
olds can be. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far into the game, but it was clear
that every character in the game that interacted with me was super
happy to see me back in the system, and that kind of welcoming
reunion greeting was something I want to emulate myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent (January 2015) interview with David Carter (superman) on PRX
was a good 17 minute listen about the current state of the archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On PRX: &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.prx.org/stories/141395&#34;&gt;Six Years Inside the Computer &amp;amp; Video Game Archive with David Carter&lt;/a&gt; from Radio Free Culture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Carter of the Computer &amp;amp; Video Game Archive at University of
Michigan tells us about the collection, how it&amp;rsquo;s used in an academic
setting, and a little about the care and feeding of elderly video
game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a next visit already scheduled for January.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa visiting Swede&#39;s Diner, Ann Arbor, December 1950</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-santa-at-swedes-diner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 23:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-santa-at-swedes-diner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/taxonomy/term/617000&#34;&gt;Santa visiting Swede&amp;rsquo;s Diner&lt;/a&gt;, Ann Arbor, December 1950. From the
Ann Arbor District Library &amp;ldquo;Old News&amp;rdquo; collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/files/imagecache/800_width/photos/N021_0585_001.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original caption: Stockings wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hold the Christmas cheer served
up by Leonard Carlstrom, proprietor of a lunch counter at 208 S.
Fifth Ave., so he used cups. Carlstrom played his own version of
Santa Clause this morning when he hung up the &amp;ldquo;free coffee&amp;rdquo; sign
to old customers and newcomers alike. &amp;ldquo;Business kind of picked up
a little,&amp;rdquo; Carlstrom noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platforms for the Internet of Things, 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A discussion on one of the lists I follow covers the question
of &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; support for the Internet of Things. Since consumer
IoT is a kind of squooshy market right now with rapid changes
in prices and no one obvious choice for what technology to adopt,
it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile taking some kind of review of the landscape for
2015 and sort out what to watch for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is organized by vendor, and loosely grouped so that similar
systems are next to each other. It&amp;rsquo;s a highly dimensional space, but
all elements have something in common: engineers are trying to
change how we interact with simple devices like light bulbs through
our hand-held phones, and no one has the full correct answer that&amp;rsquo;s
obviously right. Indeed it&amp;rsquo;s not clear at all that there is
a right answer for some of these controls; the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/internetofshit&#34;&gt;Internet of Shit twitter account&lt;/a&gt;
collects with some glee the number of devices that emphatically should
not be on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the platforms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon&lt;/em&gt; is hard to ignore. Many smaller cloud platforms are
built on top of its AWS computing platforms, and Amazon has
entered the fray with its AWS IoT service that offers a hosted
MQTT message server. In addition Amazon has the Echo product
that does voice recognition. Nearly impossible to ignore, Amazon
is a clear central player in the IoT consumer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; is a distant second in the IoT world, mostly because
the Google Compute Engine isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a compute
platform, and the Android phone isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a top
end phone. Google does have the moxie to make it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Internet Thing&amp;rdquo;
be a self-driving car. The Nest thermostat is the most obvious
home point-of-entry for Google, and the platform and brand extension
to watch is more stuff that works with Nest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple&lt;/em&gt; has the phone to want, and the assistant (Siri) that people
have learned how to talk to to get things done. If the Internet of
Things is going to be controlled from an app, it&amp;rsquo;s an app that&amp;rsquo;s going
to run on an Apple phone, and you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to talk to it.
Less clear is Apple&amp;rsquo;s in-home device hub strategy - the AppleTV never
really has had that open platform feel to attract the first-mover developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft&lt;/em&gt; would dearly love to play in this world, but Windows 10
on ARM and the Raspberry Pi is a disappointment, and &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; is mostly
defined by problems too big for Excel. The Microsoft cloud platform,
Azure, mostly seems to be used by organizations that treat it as
a second or third data center, or who are locked in to Azure for
business and partnership reasons. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Cortana is capable, but
hardly anyone has Windows phones to talk with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IBM&lt;/em&gt; is the wild card here. Their Bluemix hosted platform service is
interesting if unusual and not really aimed at the consumer space. A
very interesting Node-RED project has extended IBM influence into
the Raspberry Pi and Bluetooth BLE sensor space, but it feels like
an interesting technology play and not a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, to major players with hardware. &amp;ldquo;How many engineers does it
take to change a lightbulb?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philips&lt;/em&gt; has the Hue line of home products, mostly lighting focused.
There was a hue and cry about the Philips decision to disable support
for some compatible products that did not have explicit partnership
agreements in place, and the nature of the complaining made it clear
that there&amp;rsquo;s an active hobbyist community around this product space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flex&lt;/em&gt; is the new player, with its recent acquisition of the
assets of Wink from the bankruptcy of Quirky.  Flex, formerly known
as Flextronics, is a large contract manufacturer, and it knows how
to build quite a few things; look for Wink&amp;rsquo;s technology to make its
way into a wider range of products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung&lt;/em&gt; and their SmartThings brand has enough market share to make
interesting efforts, but again to that point there&amp;rsquo;s no one breakout
product in their portfolio that brings that brand much to mind unless
you are using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest winner in the IoT space for this year and probably for
next year is an Internet tool with the unlikely name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifttt.com&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;ldquo;If this, then that&amp;rdquo; is the level of control you get with IFTTT,
and surprisingly enough that&amp;rsquo;s enough to do all sorts of things -
mostly because IFTTT speaks just enough of the protocols of over 100
systems that you can glue together a recipe that does something
when something else happens even when the two vendors you are dealing
with have never heard of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interoperability is the bugaboo of Internet of Things systems development.
Many vendors want you to sign up to their big bear hug of a partnership
agreement and work solely within their ecosystem. Others have narrow
APIs and proprietary protocols that discourage casual reuse. Where
IFTTT fits in is as a universal connector kit that lets you explore
how parts fit together.  The IFTTT
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/recipes/collections/32-recipes-for-the-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;recipes for the Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt; captures some of the essence of what
can be done right now without much of a fuss if you have wide protocol
support, even if it&amp;rsquo;s only very simple support.
Many vendors in the &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things&amp;rdquo;
space could benefit from thorough understanding of simple connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>