<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker Compose on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/keyphrases/docker-compose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker Compose on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 02:18:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/keyphrases/docker-compose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing up Node-RED and mosquitto under &#34;docker compose&#34; on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 02:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Progress, actually quite a lot of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, neatly stated. Docker is good for bringing up single services (&#34;microservices&#34;), but sometimes your application needs more than one thing running for the whole thing to work. Enter &#34;docker compose&#34;, formerly &#34;fig&#34;, which automates the process of running various Docker commands in the right order with the right arguments all driven from a configuration file. As described by their documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular task I have in front of me is launching Node-RED and mosquitto (an MQTT broker) together on a Raspberry Pi 2 which is running Hypriot and Docker. Most of the background for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; that&#39;s a relevant task is at this post on Hypriot, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;How to use Docker Compose to run complex multi container apps on your Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, which I dutifully and successfully managed to run all of the examples from. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emboldened by this I tried to get Wordpress running with MySQL but got stuck because of a variety of things (not the least of which was some over-enthusiastic documentation that downplayed the complexity of that task, and the lack of a Pi-specific Wordpress Docker images). But having had the taste of what might be I carried on until I managed to get something to work for what I really wanted: Node-RED running alongside mosquitto so that I could have a local MQTT broker to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
nodered:
  image: nieleyde/rpi2-nodered
  command: flows.json
  volumes:
    - /home/pi/node-red:/root/.node-red
  ports: 
    - &#34;1880:1880&#34;
  links:
    - mosquitto

mosquitto:
  image: nieleyde/rpi-mosquitto
  ports:
    - &#34;1883:1883&#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some subtleties to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nieleyde/rpi2-nodered runs on the Pi 2; there&#39;s a corresponding nieleyde/rpi-nodered for the Pi. Both are ARM images. I haven&#39;t yet tweaked this to run on x86, but if you do, you&#39;ll need to update the &#34;image&#34; stanzas everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;command&#34; and &#34;volumes&#34; stanzas in the nodered configuration serve to make Docker mount a subdirectory on the host machine where the flows.json file is stored; this makes changes to the configuration persistent. If you want a read-only configuration, you&#39;ll need to change this; I haven&#39;t gotten that far yet. It might also make sense to have a data volume container, but again I&#39;m not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;mosquitto&#34; configuration is extremely bare bones and runs the default config, which is wide open. I haven&#39;t gotten far enough to replace the config file with something better, but that&#39;s an obvious next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From within Node-RED you refer to this internal MQTT server at hostname &#34;mosquitto&#34;, port &#34;1883&#34;. If the links stanza was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; and the mosquitto section was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; you&#39;d then refer to the MQTT server at hostname &#34;mqtt&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An issue open on Niel Eyde&#39;s rpi-nodered Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/issues/5&#34;&gt;documentation for how to extend this image with your own nodes and flows&lt;/a&gt;, where I&#39;m working some of this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Node-RED Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/node-red/node-red/issues/603&#34;&gt;Support for Docker install for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;, which is epic and helpful in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essential &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/&#34;&gt;Hypriot weblog&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose examples&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/compose&#34;&gt;Hypriot Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>