<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback Loop Writing on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/feedback-loop-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feedback Loop Writing on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 19:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/feedback-loop-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Addicted to feedback</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-12-28-addicted-to-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-12-28-addicted-to-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I read Facebook for too long, I want to post short quips, &amp;quot;like&amp;quot; things, and generally let people know that I exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I read Twitter for too long, I want to post short quips, &amp;quot;favorite&amp;quot; things, and generally let people know that they exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sit in front of Typepad ready to type, it&amp;#39;s not always for the short post, and often it&amp;#39;s not even for an audience. My working assumption is that unless I&amp;#39;m writing about something that the world cares about, only a handful of people will see it. The other working assumption is that I really don&amp;#39;t know before I write it how it will be received, so it better be good enough for me to want to refer to again just for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve referred to Vacuum as an unpolished open notebook. It&amp;#39;s also a place to capture &amp;quot;interior stories&amp;quot;, internal monologue that makes sense about how you do things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getstoried.com/2010/05/19/interview-christina-baldwin/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;(Christina) Baldwin&lt;/a&gt; says that if people aren’t attached to their interior stories, they get &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #80ffff;&#34;&gt;addicted to feedback&lt;/span&gt;. Although I would have considered myself attached to my interior story, I also recognize a social-media feedback addiction in myself. I’m always curious about what kinds of comments that my, for example, Facebook status updates, have generated. (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://astoriedcareer.com/2010/06/those-unattached-to-their-inte.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A Storied Career&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#0160;a blog by&amp;#0160;Kathy Hansen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you write to inform yourself, and the goal isn&amp;#39;t to create or please your followers, or to get new ones, or to up your page view count or close a new lead. It&amp;#39;s just to write, and to capture what&amp;#39;s going by in your head to the level that you can recreate it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing in a blog has always been for me an exercise in locating other people&amp;#39;s words to help illustrate my point. That gives it some measure of similarity to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/secret/2010/12/its-worth-writing-it-down-even-if-you-dont-know-who-the-audience-is-yet.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;commonplace book&lt;/a&gt;, a traditional way to copy out bits of prose that you wish to make your own into a kind of clippings book or scrapbook of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m content, really, to be &amp;quot;addicted to feedback&amp;quot;, but I reserve the right to look for the right kind of feedback to tune into. The feedback of blogging is the long, low rumble of old notebooks that have just the right relevant bits to tune into, and not just the shrill, high ping of social media contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spectral overseers as guides to good online behavior</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;James Poulos in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ricochet.com/conversations/Where-Are-All-the-Editors/(comment)/8368&#34;&gt;comment on Ricochet&lt;/a&gt; on the role of editors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Writers now have competing pressures -- to be witty, quick, ironic, noticeable, flip, to dispatch every clay pigeon tossed up by a culture pandemic with pigeons; but also to self-edit, to self-moderate, to be reticent at the right time, to pussyfoot expertly, to pick battles, to avoid perils, to besmirch rarely, to duck blame, to satisfy spectral overseers. This is a serious pickle, is it not? And yet it now appears to be the cost of doing business. Possibly, this is the internet imitating life.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved the &amp;quot;satisfy spectral overseers&amp;quot; bit. Where did that come from? Who gets that description?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knute Rockne, in a H.W. Wilson Company 1942 biography:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;blockquote&gt;No one will ever tackle the job of football coach at the University of Notre Dame without a sense of solemn obligation, for the spirit of Knute Rockne still hovers above the campus like a spectral overseer. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walt Disney, as referenced in two 1990s management texts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Eisner came aboard and cleared the deck, bringing in new managers, most of whom had never met Disney. The new crew, freed of the spectral overseer, began to create a culture that was more sophisticated than stodgy, more adventurous than cautious, more ambitious than content.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Edward McCullough, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaltheatre.org/location/ghost.htm&#34;&gt;National Theatre&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The shade of Actor John Edward McCullough, a popular American thespian of the 1800&amp;#39;s, is said to roam the premises of the theatre in the dark of night. No longer thirsting for an audience&amp;#39;s applause, the once famed star performer has taken on the lonely role of ghostly custodian and spectral overseer, checking to be sure that all is in readiness for the next performance.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one welcome the editorial guidance of our spectral overseers. But whose guidance should we channel for this task? &amp;#0160;That&amp;#39;s some other post about people (not necessarily &amp;quot;writers&amp;quot;) who have mastered the online form.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>