<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skywarn Weather on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/skywarn-weather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skywarn Weather on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 22:51:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/skywarn-weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane season, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-hurricane-season-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 22:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-hurricane-season-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each year is a new hurricane season, and each year the internet is a little different. Here&amp;#39;s some things that are new that I&amp;#39;ve noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single meteorologist is on Twitter (or close enough), and there&amp;#39;s an ample supply of both local weather reporting and national weather forecasting to satisfy anyone&amp;#39;s need to look at weather models for hurricanes to come. The word of the year is &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spaghettimodels.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;spaghetti model&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, illustrated below, showing a whole series of separate tracks from different atmospheric models to predict a set of possible futures for the storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c31710ad8970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;643281402&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c31710ad8970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c31710ad8970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;643281402&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another novel thing this year is the appearance of the hurricane app for your smart phone or iPad. &lt;a href=&#34;http://kittycode.com/products/hurricane-hd/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Hurricane HD&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;for your iPad focuses solely on hurricane tracking, giving you alerts and forecasts and graphical updates as conditions change. (I haven&amp;#39;t used it, but the screen shots look good and straightforward). The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redcross.org/news/press-release/New-Hurricane-App-Brings-Safety-Information-to-Smart-Phones&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Red Cross Hurricane App&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;includes&amp;#0160;“I’m safe” messaging that allows users to broadcast reassurance to family and friends via social media outlets that they are out of harm’s way. Both have access to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nws.noaa.gov/nwr/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;NOAA Weather Radio&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the typical channels found on any of the scanner apps that are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in listening to hurricane radio traffic, one good source is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radioreference.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Radio Reference&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to listening to police scanners and fire service radios, you can also tune into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radioreference.com/apps/audio/?feedId=9559&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;National Hurricane Center SKYWARN network&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and hear weather and condition reports directly from amateur radio operators in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that hasn&amp;#39;t changed is the excellent hurricane coverage from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderground.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Weather Underground&lt;/a&gt;, with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://classic.wunderground.com/blog/JeffMasters/article.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;weblog of Dr. Jeff Masters&lt;/a&gt; a clear and precise account as conditions change. The comment board on this blog is notable for being well behaved and well informed, a rarity in this day and age. Weather Underground was recently purchased by Weather.com. There&amp;#39;s no visible changes yet to hurricane information, but a few more TWC meteorologists are blogging on the wunderground site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in Michigan, the worst we can expect from a hurricane is flooding from the far-north remnants of a storm. Others will not be so lucky. Do your best to be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>