<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Planning Commission on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-planning-commission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Planning Commission on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 22:25:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-planning-commission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Sump Pumps, and citizen opposition to Glendale Condos, at the Ann Arbor City Planning Commission - July 1, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-01-the-internet-of-sump-pumps-and-citizen-opposition-to-glendale-place-condos-ann-arbor-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 22:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-01-the-internet-of-sump-pumps-and-citizen-opposition-to-glendale-place-condos-ann-arbor-planning/</guid>
      <description>Sumpy Status: The sump is full! This looks like a job for SUMPY MCPUMPERTON!
&amp;mdash; Sumpy McPumperton (@GregsSumpPump) July 1, 2014 
ANN ARBOR, July 1, 2014: The Ann Arbor City Planning Commission is considering the Glendale Condominiums, a proposed development at 312 Glendale Place. Neighbors came out in force to oppose the development, citing among other things the impact that the proposed new impervious surface would exacerbate the existing flooding events that have affected the nearby neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Ann Arbor City Planning Commission of August 7, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-08-notes-from-the-ann-arbor-city-planning-commission-of-august-7-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-08-notes-from-the-ann-arbor-city-planning-commission-of-august-7-2013/</guid>
      <description>I went to the City Planning Commission meeting on Wednesday, August 7, 2013. Here&amp;#39;s a few notes. The AnnArbor.com story about the meeting and a Civic News Ticker from the Ann Arbor Chronicle focus on a vacant parcel on Packard near Platt that&amp;#39;s currently zoned for single-family residential. The owner of the property wants to put a duplex on the site, and asked to have the the parcel rezoned to a new zoning that would also allow duplexes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>