<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Planning Commission on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-city-planning-commission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Planning Commission on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 22:25:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-city-planning-commission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Sump Pumps, and citizen opposition to Glendale Condos, at the Ann Arbor City Planning Commission - July 1, 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-07-01-the-internet-of-sump-pumps-and-citizen-opposition-to-glendale-place-condos-ann-arbor-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 22:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-07-01-the-internet-of-sump-pumps-and-citizen-opposition-to-glendale-place-condos-ann-arbor-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sumpy Status: The sump is full! This looks like a job for SUMPY MCPUMPERTON!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sumpy McPumperton (@GregsSumpPump) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GregsSumpPump/statuses/483779086377291776&#34;&gt;July 1, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR, July 1, 2014: The Ann Arbor City Planning Commission is considering the Glendale Condominiums, a proposed development at 312 Glendale Place. Neighbors came out in force to oppose the development, citing among other things the impact that the proposed new impervious surface would exacerbate the existing flooding events that have affected the nearby neighborhoods. The developer has proposed an above ground storm water retention system, using a pond to capture the runoff and retain water on site so that the water from the parking lots doesn&#39;t rush into neighbor basements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of homeowners downstream from the development are already using sump pumps to keep their basements dry. Having a sump pump running in your basement continuously for hours or even days is not something that homeowners look forward to managing. Since the water flow through the entire system (Allen Creek) can make its way into basements anywhere downstream, the residents from the whole watershed have an interest in the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet of sump pumps, if it were to exist, would give some overall understanding for city planners and water resources managers. It would let you know not only whether your sump pump is running, but also whether your neighbors pumps are running, and maybe also the total flows and total energy consumed by the pumping systems. If it existed - and it doesn&#39;t yet, not to my knowledge - we could make decisions about developments like this based on actual stormwater data and not anecdotes and stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a number of attempts made by individual homeowners around the world to control their sump pumps or monitor their sump pumps with the current set of small internet devices like the Raspberry Pi. Expensive industrial pumps come with network interfaces like MODBUS that offer site managers control and integration into SCADA systems. To make this work you need level sensors, controllable pumps, moisture sensors, and other sensor and control infrastructure just to make the system work. Beyond that, you&#39;d want remote monitoring of the various sensor so that you could tell whether it&#39;s working or not and also generate pretty graphs and reports and urgent pages to your favorite plumber to bring the system back online if it fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet of sump pumps is in its infancy. You&#39;ll find home made systems like Greg&#39;s Sump Pump, aka Sumpy McPumperton, which tweets out its current status. You&#39;ll also find top-of-the-line systems with built-in hardwired internet connections and some kind of artificial intelligence. (Sumpy is pretty smart, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=superpatron-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B007R8I1BI&amp;asins=B007R8I1BI&amp;linkId=RJDFOYUGQBV67FQE&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>