<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DynamoDB downtime, Sunday am, September 20, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A distributed system is one in which the failure of a computer
you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed can render your own computer unusable.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/lamport/pubs/distributed-system.txt&#34;&gt;Leslie Lamport, 1987&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services DynamoDB experienced downtime in the N Virginia
availability zone early Sunday morning, September 20, 2015. As
a result, a number of other AWS services inside N Virginia that
depend on DynamoDB also had downtime. Companies and organizations
that built services on top of those systems who didn&amp;rsquo;t have
geographic load balancing were having problems as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affected services include at least CloudWatch, SES, SNS, SQS, SWS,
AutoScale, Cloud Formation, Directory Service, Key Mgmt and Lambda,
according to a report on Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://status.aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.aws.amazon.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/ylastic&#34;&gt;@ylastic&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter
have been helpful in keeping track of outages. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ylastic.com&#34;&gt;http://www.ylastic.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down Detector has a page of AWS outages trouble reports, and
details pulled from Twitter. &lt;a href=&#34;https://downdetector.com/status/aws-amazon-web-services&#34;&gt;https://downdetector.com/status/aws-amazon-web-services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When core infrastructure goes down, it tends to affect other platforms
that depend on that core infrastructure and that hide it from their
users. This in turn affects applications built on those platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker: &amp;ldquo;We are currently seeing intermittent errors when pushing
and pulling, related to issues that AWS is having. We are currently
investigating the causes, and doing what we can to mitigate the
problems.&amp;rdquo; @dockerstatus and &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.docker.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.docker.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heroku: &amp;ldquo;Starting new dynos (unidling, one-off, scaling or
restarting crashed apps, new releases) is still unavailable.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Until
this incident is resolved, you might be unable to open new support
tickets with us. If you need to communicate with our support staff
during this time, please email outage-support@heroku.com.&amp;rdquo; @herokustatus
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.heroku.com/incidents/811&#34;&gt;https://status.heroku.com/incidents/811&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CircleCI: &amp;ldquo;Experiencing Issues with Heroku and AWS&amp;rdquo;. @circleci
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.circleci.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.circleci.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;TravisCI: &amp;ldquo;Partial System Outage&amp;rdquo;. @traviscistatus and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.traviscistatus.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.traviscistatus.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of applications built on AWS and on Heroku,
which are at risk of downtime. A comprehensive list is probably
impossible, but here are some reports, in alphabetical order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airbnb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Echo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Instant Video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Support Tickets. Use this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/html-forms-controller/support-center-issues-u&#34;&gt;workaround&lt;/a&gt; ???&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clickfunnels. &amp;ldquo;Our development team is aware of this, however, at this time, the only thing that we can do is wait until the issues at Amazon AWS are resolved completely.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.clickfunnels.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.clickfunnels.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoinSimple. &amp;ldquo;Widespread outage in Amazon Web Services is affecting several Internet services, including @CoinSimple. Please check here for updates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DuoLingo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FastSpring. &amp;ldquo;We were having some intermittent problems due to #awsoutage. The problem is being resolved by Amazon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GroupMe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HashiCorp. &amp;ldquo;Our infrastructure provider is experiencing issues which may cause our project websites to be inaccessible. Sorry for the inconvenience.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IFTTT. &amp;ldquo;We have identified an issue with our service provider. We will continue to provide updates as more information becomes available.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.ifttt.com/incidents/xnbwnqj608hg&#34;&gt;http://status.ifttt.com/incidents/xnbwnqj608hg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightspeed POS. &amp;ldquo;Monitoring - Our service provider is experiencing a major issue with several of their services. Our engineers are working to reduce our reliance on these components until their issues are resolved. Some customers may experience slowness related to this problem.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.lightspeedretail.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.lightspeedretail.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mediacom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium. &amp;ldquo;Identified - We&amp;rsquo;re working to fix a major outage and will be back online as soon as possible.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.statuspage.io/&#34;&gt;https://medium.statuspage.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nest. &amp;ldquo;We’re investigating a service outage with the Nest mobile app and Cam services, and the team is working on a fix. Details to come.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/support/#status&#34;&gt;https://nest.com/support/#status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netflix. &amp;ldquo;We are currently experiencing issues streaming on all devices.
We are working to resolve the problem. We apologize for any inconvenience.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.netflix.com/help&#34;&gt;https://help.netflix.com/help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper. &amp;ldquo;account related activities in Paper are down due to problems with our infrastructure provider #AWS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pocket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product Hunt. &amp;ldquo;Our servers are sick. We’re working on it right meow 😻&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quandl. &amp;ldquo;The Quandl website and API are temporarily unavailable, due to problems at #AWS.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://quandl.statuspage.io&#34;&gt;http://quandl.statuspage.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipt. &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, we&amp;rsquo;re down right now with the #AWSOutage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takipi. &amp;ldquo;Due to an AWS outage, we&amp;rsquo;re experiencing some slowness and connectivity issues. Stay tuned for updates&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tinder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twilio. &amp;ldquo;Update - We have established the DynamoDB backend in another AWS region and are re-routing requests from upstream services to the new region. We will provide another update once we verify that the requests are being serviced properly. &amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.twilio.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.twilio.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viber. &amp;ldquo;We are experiencing disruptions in our service. We are working to resolve this issue. Sorry for the inconvenience.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.viber.com/&#34;&gt;https://support.viber.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waffle.io &amp;ldquo;Experiencing Issues with Heroku&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.waffle.io/&#34;&gt;http://status.waffle.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walt Disney World app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wink.  &amp;ldquo;We are noticing increased connection issues for Wink users. Our engineers are working with Amazon to get this resolved ASAP.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.winkapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://status.winkapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the discussion on Twitter on the #AWS hashtag, as well as
#awsoutage and #awsdown . Twitter is unaffected by this outage,
and Slack is also unaffected, which devops teams are both happy about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-coverage:0bf1024f29774b00d48e1402990b91e9&#34;&gt;News coverage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10247307&#34;&gt;Hacker News discussion&lt;/a&gt;
is a good one as startups radio in their woes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TNW: &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/insider/2015/09/20/amazon-web-services-goes-down-taking-netflix-reddit-pocket-and-more-with-it/&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services goes down, taking Netflix, Reddit, Pocket and more with it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Register: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2015/09/20/aws_database_outage/&#34;&gt;AWS knocks Amazon, Netflix, Tinder and IMDb offline in MEGA data collapse; Cloudopocalypse stalks Sunday sofa surfers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VentureBeat: &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2015/09/20/amazons-aws-outage-takes-down-netflix-reddit-medium-and-more/&#34;&gt;Amazon’s AWS outage takes down Netflix, Reddit, Medium, and more
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth and bluez inside Docker</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-11-bluetooth-bluez-inside-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-11-bluetooth-bluez-inside-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a Bluetooth device attached to a Linux system, it&amp;rsquo;s
not clear how to attach that device to a Docker container on that
same system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bluez&lt;/code&gt;, the Bluetooth driver for Linux, uses the &lt;code&gt;D-Bus&lt;/code&gt; to communicate.
This is more complex than a FIFO or socket interface, and thus less
easy to obviously say how it should be mapped into the Docker processs
and file system space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The references below show several ways of not doing this task,
and hopefully at some point will get answers on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References for further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/16208&#34;&gt;Bluetooth socket can&amp;rsquo;t be opened inside container&lt;/a&gt;, Docker Github issues 16208&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/28868393/accessing-bluetooth-dongle-from-inside-docker&#34;&gt;Accessing Bluetooth dongle from inside Docker?&lt;/a&gt;, Stack Overflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing up Node-RED and mosquitto under &#34;docker compose&#34; on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 02:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Progress, actually quite a lot of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, neatly stated. Docker is good for bringing up single services (&#34;microservices&#34;), but sometimes your application needs more than one thing running for the whole thing to work. Enter &#34;docker compose&#34;, formerly &#34;fig&#34;, which automates the process of running various Docker commands in the right order with the right arguments all driven from a configuration file. As described by their documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular task I have in front of me is launching Node-RED and mosquitto (an MQTT broker) together on a Raspberry Pi 2 which is running Hypriot and Docker. Most of the background for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; that&#39;s a relevant task is at this post on Hypriot, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;How to use Docker Compose to run complex multi container apps on your Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, which I dutifully and successfully managed to run all of the examples from. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emboldened by this I tried to get Wordpress running with MySQL but got stuck because of a variety of things (not the least of which was some over-enthusiastic documentation that downplayed the complexity of that task, and the lack of a Pi-specific Wordpress Docker images). But having had the taste of what might be I carried on until I managed to get something to work for what I really wanted: Node-RED running alongside mosquitto so that I could have a local MQTT broker to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
nodered:
  image: nieleyde/rpi2-nodered
  command: flows.json
  volumes:
    - /home/pi/node-red:/root/.node-red
  ports: 
    - &#34;1880:1880&#34;
  links:
    - mosquitto

mosquitto:
  image: nieleyde/rpi-mosquitto
  ports:
    - &#34;1883:1883&#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some subtleties to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nieleyde/rpi2-nodered runs on the Pi 2; there&#39;s a corresponding nieleyde/rpi-nodered for the Pi. Both are ARM images. I haven&#39;t yet tweaked this to run on x86, but if you do, you&#39;ll need to update the &#34;image&#34; stanzas everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;command&#34; and &#34;volumes&#34; stanzas in the nodered configuration serve to make Docker mount a subdirectory on the host machine where the flows.json file is stored; this makes changes to the configuration persistent. If you want a read-only configuration, you&#39;ll need to change this; I haven&#39;t gotten that far yet. It might also make sense to have a data volume container, but again I&#39;m not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;mosquitto&#34; configuration is extremely bare bones and runs the default config, which is wide open. I haven&#39;t gotten far enough to replace the config file with something better, but that&#39;s an obvious next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From within Node-RED you refer to this internal MQTT server at hostname &#34;mosquitto&#34;, port &#34;1883&#34;. If the links stanza was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; and the mosquitto section was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; you&#39;d then refer to the MQTT server at hostname &#34;mqtt&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An issue open on Niel Eyde&#39;s rpi-nodered Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/issues/5&#34;&gt;documentation for how to extend this image with your own nodes and flows&lt;/a&gt;, where I&#39;m working some of this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Node-RED Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/node-red/node-red/issues/603&#34;&gt;Support for Docker install for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;, which is epic and helpful in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essential &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/&#34;&gt;Hypriot weblog&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose examples&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/compose&#34;&gt;Hypriot Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine
under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old
olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction
site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building
that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the day is a death on State Street. A young man was
climbing over the skylights at the Nickels Arcade and fell to his
death when the skylight glass gave way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 1915, the SS Eastland was packed with employees from
the Western Electric Hawthorne Works when it rolled over in
the Chicago River. 844 passengers and crew lost their lives, making
the Eastland disaster the worst shipwreck on the Great Lakes.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastlanddisaster.org/&#34;&gt;Eastland Disaster Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;
for extensive notes on and photos of the scene and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2civictech/&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt;
is coming up on Monday, July 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literatibookstore.com/&#34;&gt;Literati Bookstore&lt;/a&gt; is open
again after a water leak caused them to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote a tiny R script that generates maps. The challenge
today is to find a portable environment so that I can deploy this script
on shared infrastructure. The project took 30 minutes of MacBook Air processor
time running full blast parallel, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t care about wall clock time
to complete the effort I do care about building something that I can hand
off to someone else to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocker-org/ropensci&#34;&gt;ropensci&lt;/a&gt; Docker
package from the Rocker project is the answer, or most of the answer, for this.
Rocker has built R images where lots of useful packages have been installed,
including systems where the install directions are a little bit complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all complicated software environments the biggest challenge is dealing
with dependencies. If you want to use the latest and greatest fast algorithms,
you have to be prepared to spin up on what the cool kids are doing in the
rest of their environment. If somehow you can jump to the edge of the development
in the algorithm world without being tripped up by the hairy dependency graph
that got you there, it can be a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So; install Docker on the Mac with &amp;lsquo;boot2docker&amp;rsquo;; then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;docker pull rocker/ropensci
docker run -it rocker/ropensci R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and poof, you have an environment current to this month&amp;rsquo;s desktop of leading
R developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 1.7.0 issues: problems with Mac and boot2docker, ARM, Ubuntu, and disk size of images</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-26-docker-170-issues-problems-with-mac-and-boot2docker-arm-and-disk-size-of-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:50:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-26-docker-170-issues-problems-with-mac-and-boot2docker-arm-and-disk-size-of-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker 1.7.0 has been released into the wild. Every .0 release of software should be expected to have some issues, no matter how good the QA and automated test process. Here&#39;s what to expect if you&#39;re getting Docker 1.7.0 up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;boot2docker on Mac&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Mac, with boot2docker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boot2docker/boot2docker/issues/938&#34;&gt;Docker certs not valid with 1.7 upgrade&lt;/a&gt; is issue 938 on boot2docker. The symptom is a message like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An error occurred trying to connect: Get https://192.168.59.103:2376/v1.19/containers/json: x509: certificate is valid for 127.0.0.1, 10.0.2.15, not 192.168.59.103&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and restarting docker on the VM with &lt;code&gt;boot2docker ssh sudo /etc/init.d/docker restart&lt;/code&gt; fixes it, at least temporarily. Read through the issue on github to see the full diagnosis - as best I understand it, eth1 is not up when certificates are generated, hence the cert not valid error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Raspberry Pi or any other ARM system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a Raspberry Pi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14184&#34;&gt;Docker 1.7 on RaspberryPI : &#34;socket operation on non-socket&#34;&lt;/a&gt; is issue 14184 on docker. The symptom is a message like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[tki@anzu ~]$ docker start redis
  Error response from daemon: Cannot start container redis: socket operation on non-socket
  Error: failed to start containers: [redis]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The error flushed out a whole set of people running Docker on ARM on a variety of platforms, all having similar issues. If you&#39;re running a Scaleway C1, ODROID C1, ODROID XU3-Lite, Utilite Pro, Cubox 4x4, and all flavors of Raspberry Pi or Pi 2 you&#39;ll see this. &#34;When using --net host the container starts&#34; is the report, but port forwarding fails to work in that case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ubuntu: problems with statically compiled Docker binaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14035&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 15.04 vivid can not start docker 1.7.0&lt;/a&gt;, docker issue 14035. The relevant bits of the error message are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ERRO[0000] Udev sync is not supported. This will lead to unexpected behavior, data loss and errors. For more information, see https://docs.docker.com/reference/commandline/cli/#daemon-storage-driver-option &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;ERRO[0000] [graphdriver] prior storage driver &#34;devicemapper&#34; failed: driver not supported &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;FATA[0000] Error starting daemon: error initializing graphdriver: driver not supported &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a long discussion, culminating in &lt;code&gt;In the end, removing /var/lib/docker/devicemapper/ will fix the issue&lt;/code&gt;, but people are also rolling back to 1.6.2. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ubuntu on x86: large file sizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report that &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.docker.com/t/docker-1-7-0-is-using-huge-amount-of-disk-space/2046&#34;&gt;Docker 1.7.0 is using huge amounts of disk space&lt;/a&gt; appears on the Docker forum, item 2046. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14204&#34;&gt;Pulling image fills disk/image size is huge, version 1.7.0&lt;/a&gt; is issue 14204 on Docker. Not much insight into this one yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Detroit, Wednesday July 22, 2015, 6:00 pm, Troy, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope to see you at Docker Detroit&amp;rsquo;s kickoff meeting, to be held
at RIIS, 1250 Stephenson Highway, Suite 200 in Troy, MI starting
at 6:00 p.m. tonight July 22 2015.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming in from Ann
Arbor. The venue is between 14 Mile and Maple behind Beaumont Hospital.
Google Maps suggests that because of construction on I-75 in that
area you might want to head north on Campbell instead of taking
the I-75 / I-696 interchange north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading the meeting tonight is Pepijn Bruienne from the University
of Michigan. He will be speaking about &amp;ldquo;Docker in production&amp;rdquo;
and organizing a group discussion with Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Docker-Detroit/events/223111645/&#34;&gt;meetup announcement&lt;/a&gt;
for more details, refreshments will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meetup is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.riis.com&#34;&gt;RIIS&lt;/a&gt; a boutique web
and mobile development house. Hope to see you there!  I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking
notes and plan to do a writeup of the event, as well as sharing my
own experiences running Docker for ARM on a Raspberry PI 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker&#39;s new RunC doesn&#39;t (yet?) work on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-22-dockers-new-runc-doesnt-yet-work-on-mac-os-x-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 16:53:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-22-dockers-new-runc-doesnt-yet-work-on-mac-os-x-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker has a new runtime environment that they are releasing called &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.docker.com/2015/06/runc/&#34;&gt;runC&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s a &#34;lightweight universal plumbing&#34; that tries to encapsulate all of the Docker dependencies and infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To build Docker we have re-used large quantities of plumbing: Linux, Go, lxc, aufs, lvm, iptables, virtualbox, vxlan, mesos, etcd, consul, systemd… the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of Docker&#39;s start on Linux systems, it&#39;s been tricky to get it running under Mac OS X. Some tries to make it work depend on setting up virtual machines (with the likes of boot2docker) which makes it work at the cost of performance and flexibility. Docker on OS X has not been exceptionally easy though it does work once you commit to doing all of your Docker server work inside a VM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;runC would be an answer to the problem of native Docker on OSX X, one might hope, but as of its first release it doesn&#39;t work. The first of what is probably many hurdles is the extensive use of the clone(2) system call instead of fork(2). This &lt;a href=&#34;http://files.meetup.com/10602292/See%20Docker%20from%20the%20Perspective%20of%20Linux%20Process.pdf&#34;&gt;presentation from Allen Sun at DaoCloud&lt;/a&gt; goes into the details of Docker&#39;s use of clone(2) from the perspective of Linux processes. It is notable that the OS X &#34;Darwin&#34; kernel doesn&#39;t have clone(2), and it&#39;s as far as I can tell not readily possible to mimic all of clone&#39;s semantics strictly by using fork in clever ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An open issue on Github is tracking &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/runc/issues/9&#34;&gt;Build fails on Mac OS X 10.9&lt;/a&gt;. I don&#39;t see an easy fix without work by Apple on their kernel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Node-RED on a Raspberry Pi with Docker and Hypriot</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 02:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal for the week was to empty out my inbox sufficiently that I would be able to make progress on some programming tasks that are hard to do when there&#39;s distractions. The inbox got all the way down to zero, and that meant that there was a chunk of evening time suitable for hacking. Happy to report that the result of this is Node-RED running on a Raspberry Pi under Docker on top of Hypriot. A word of explanation of how this all works in detail is too much, but here&#39;s where I got the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device/&#34;&gt;Hypriot&#39;s gettting started guide&lt;/a&gt; brings you up to speed on getting Docker running on your ARM device (e.g. your Raspberry Pi). They have bootable images that you can download and burn to SD card, and from there you load up applications from Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypriot has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/hypriot/talk&#34;&gt;chat window&lt;/a&gt; on Gitter, so you can pop in and there will be occasionally people to assist. Best to do things European time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/&#34;&gt;DockerHub&lt;/a&gt; is a one stop shop for packaged applications. When you&#39;re running on the Pi, you&#39;ll want to seek out versions with &#39;rpi&#39; or &#39;arm&#39; in their names as they have likely been adapted for that system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up pulling Niel Eyde&#39;s Raspberry Pi versions of Node-RED from DockerHub as &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/u/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/&#34;&gt;nieleyde/rpi-nodered&lt;/a&gt;. It has all sorts of interesting modules that I had not previously built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is at 0.10.6 at this writing. Its &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org/docs/hardware/raspberrypi.html&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi support&lt;/a&gt; includes hardware support using &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiringpi.com/&#34;&gt;WiringPi&lt;/a&gt; to access the GPIO pins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED currently supports Node.JS 0.10. Node.JS and IO.JS have &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdtimes.com/node-js-and-io-js-to-merge-under-node-js-foundation/&#34;&gt;merged forces&lt;/a&gt; after a fork, which means hopefully development will start to be sane again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all said I am not sure I have everything I need yet but as a leap forward it&#39;s pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a few notes from Dockercon 2015, as seen via Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-a-few-notes-from-dockercon-2015-as-seen-via-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 13:27:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-a-few-notes-from-dockercon-2015-as-seen-via-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The annual conference for Docker, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;Dockercon&lt;/a&gt;, has been going on. A few highlights from the event as seen through Twitter - I was not there to attend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker is real on the Raspberry Pi through support for the ARM processor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Awesome live demo of Docker on a Raspberry Pi by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Quintus23M&#34;&gt;@Quintus23M&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dockercon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#dockercon&lt;/a&gt; closing keynote. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/DJfBtpcYws&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DJfBtpcYws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bridget Kromhout (@bridgetkromhout) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bridgetkromhout/status/613495958089785344&#34;&gt;June 23, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details from the presenter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/dockercon2015/&#34;&gt;Hypriot-Demo and challenge at DockerCon 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker&#39;s plumbing is being spun out as &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.docker.com/2015/06/runc/&#34;&gt;runC&lt;/a&gt;. The new infrastructure supports migration of containers from one server to another, illustrated through a Quake III demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;QuakeIII in a container, migrated seamlessly from Singapore to Amsterdam to London using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/runc?src=hash&#34;&gt;#runc&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dockercon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#dockercon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/no3c0G1MDY&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/no3c0G1MDY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Paul V. Novarese (@pvnovarese) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pvnovarese/status/613499654219526144&#34;&gt;June 24, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more highlights, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2015/06/22/everything-announced-at-dockercon-2015/&#34;&gt;Venturebeat roundup of Dockercon 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bocker is a subset of Docker in 100 lines of shell script</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/p8952/bocker&#34;&gt;bocker&lt;/a&gt; is Docker (or at least
a good sized subset of it) in 100 lines of shell script.
I suppose the point is that even though there&amp;rsquo;s a huge
world of hype surrounding containerization as a next step
of systems management, when you get down to it, it&amp;rsquo;s just not
that complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>