<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bradley Horowitz on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bradley-horowitz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bradley Horowitz on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 17:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bradley-horowitz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bradley Horowitz at U of Michigan campus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-27-bradley-horowit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-27-bradley-horowit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Brad Horowitz talked at UMich today.  Here are unedited notes&amp;hellip;.(well, lightly edited).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was deliciousing links along the way too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
thanks for coming!  good to hear the talk.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
some notes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
john laird introduces; yahoo speaker series.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
bradley grew up in flordia, moved to michigan, &amp;ldquo;flower king&amp;rdquo; in livonia
&lt;br /&gt;michigan, gymnast in high school.  as undergrad in ATL down in the lab
&lt;br /&gt;doing all kinds of ramesh jain, terry weymouth, brian shunk (sp??)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
from here we lost him to mit media lab to entrepreneur with ramesh,
&lt;br /&gt;a bunch of companies, most recently landed at yahoo.  vp product strategy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
another indication of us building relationships with yahoo.  connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;p-p:92ffccef95f124c813de8b18361cdcc1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
here to convince you to work with or work at; phd dropout, stay in school kids.
&lt;br /&gt;thank my host, incredible day, saw my parents in livonia, overwhelmed by the
&lt;br /&gt;work today and its resonance with yahoo.  working with us despite us and
&lt;br /&gt;around us.  a lot to make that easier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
the worst student to stand up in front of you all and profess to have knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
almost failued out a couple of times.  came in as CS via LSA and took great books
&lt;br /&gt;and history of music and art and not interested in requirements.  instead up in
&lt;br /&gt;ATL building having fun.  took 6 years to get degree and graduate.  like george
&lt;br /&gt;costanza, scholarship for &amp;ldquo;rebel bad students&amp;rdquo;, on teh verge of dropping out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
really cool job, now VP Advanced Development Divions, &amp;ldquo;VP ADD&amp;rdquo;.  advanced
&lt;br /&gt;in the sense of a scout on the horizon, what&amp;rsquo;s next.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
career: looking for first real job, a place to park between startups, fell into yaho0
&lt;br /&gt;(after virage&amp;hellip;)  attitude lasted for a day.  quality and caliber of people there.  not
&lt;br /&gt;a company crowing about how smart they are, &amp;ldquo;very humble guys&amp;rdquo;.  taken by
&lt;br /&gt;level of their game.  one report, doing multimedia search, image search; launched
&lt;br /&gt;video, audio, desktop search.  then stumbled across flickr.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
helped bring flickr to acquire them.  poster child for web 2.0 movement.  user-generated
&lt;br /&gt;content, rich interfaces with ajax.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
runs speaker series for yahoo, brought in Negativland band for IP theft
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>