<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parking Structures on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/parking-structures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parking Structures on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:19:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/parking-structures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor DDA has a new web site, and real time parking information is available again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-ann-arbor-dda-has-a-new-web-site-and-real-time-parking-information-is-available-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-ann-arbor-dda-has-a-new-web-site-and-real-time-parking-information-is-available-again/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor DDA has launched a new web site, and one of the features of it is a map with information available in real time about parking availability at various structures.
 
The structures are in a shade of pale blue, and the lots are in pale green; my current location is marked with a bubble. If you&amp;#39;re looking for just space available information, there&amp;#39;s a JSON file with that data; you&amp;#39;ll have to unpack it to map structures to their ID numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public hearing December 7, 2011 to discuss increase of hourly parking rates in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-a2dda-parking-increase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-a2dda-parking-increase/</guid>
      <description>Notice of Public Hearing
Under Paragraph 8 of the City/DDA Parking Agreement, the public must be provided with an opportunity to speak at a public hearing before changes are made to hourly parking meter rates. A public hearing has been scheduled to elicit feedback on a proposed change to increase the hourly parking meter rate $0.10/hour, from $1.40/hour to $1.50/hour in September 2012.
Wednesday, December 7, 2011 at 12 noon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partial failure of retaining wall near Earthen Jar, Jerusalem Garden at Library Lot</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-24-library-lot-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-24-library-lot-construction/</guid>
      <description>A portion of a retaining wall failed on March 24, 2011 before 5:00 p.m. at the Ann Arbor &amp;quot;Library Lot&amp;quot; construction project, and Earthen Jar and Jerusalem Garden have been evacuated as a result.
 Contractors from Christman, Soil and Materials Engineers, DTE Energy, and Doan Companies&amp;#0160;were on site at 9:00 p.m. to stabilize the sinkhole that formed when a portion of the retaining wall gave way.&amp;#0160;
 I spoke with senior project manager&amp;#0160;Adrian Iraola&amp;#0160;of&amp;#0160;Park Avenue Consultants, who got on site about when I did shortly after 5:00 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>parking lot indicators: art fair 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-18-parking-lot-indicators-art-fair-2009-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 01:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-18-parking-lot-indicators-art-fair-2009-/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve been collecting data on parking prices for Michigan football games in yards near the stadium for a couple of years now; the better the team is doing, the better the chance that the $20 parking turns into $25 parking, or $15 turns into $20.&amp;#0160; The one data point I have for Art Fair parking pricing for 2009 is that a lot near the new office is offering $15 parking, in a location that in previous years had fetched $20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is the nearest free parking space?  How to fill parking structures at more than 85%</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-01-where-is-the-nearest-free-parking-space-how-to-fill-parking-structures-at-more-than-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 09:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-01-where-is-the-nearest-free-parking-space-how-to-fill-parking-structures-at-more-than-85/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled into a world of &amp;ldquo;parking advocacy organizations&amp;rdquo; (trade associations for parking structure operators) and this video about how a garage in California is using per-space lights and sensors to speed up the process of people finding parking in a structure that&amp;rsquo;s mostly full.
The parking rhetoric in Ann Arbor is that a structure is full if it&amp;rsquo;s at 85% capacity, based on one consultant&amp;rsquo;s recommendations.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;d like to challenge that and say that no one really cares how full a garage is if you know that you won&amp;rsquo;t be frustrated finding a space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2parking build notes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-15-a2parking-build-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 14:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-15-a2parking-build-notes/</guid>
      <description>This page will have build notes for the real time parking system described in the Ann Arbor News on Friday, 16 January 2008.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m posting it incomplete now to make a URL that can go into print before the story is run.
UPDATE: the story is online; it references the link http://bit.ly/a2parking which points here.&amp;#0160; Still working on the complete how-to so that you could do this yourself, if you happened to have a parking garage of your own.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>