<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Meetings Act Ypsilanti on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/open-meetings-act-ypsilanti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Meetings Act Ypsilanti on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:03:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/open-meetings-act-ypsilanti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ypsilanti, Michigan to adopt more stringent Open Meetings Act rules</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-10-ypsilanti-michigan-to-adopt-more-stringent-open-meetings-act-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-10-ypsilanti-michigan-to-adopt-more-stringent-open-meetings-act-rules/</guid>
      <description>YPSILANTI - A very straightforward yet revolutionary approach to open meetings in Ypsilanti says that every subcommittee of City Council must abide by the Michigan Open Meetings Act - including providing advance notice of meetings - just in case enough council members show up to form a quorum.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ypsiciti.com/section/News/Ypsi+broadens+scope+of+Open+Meetings+Act-article-1325.html&#34;&gt;Ypsilanti Citizen story&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The OMA resolution, which was added to council’s agenda at 5 p.m. on
Oct. 20, was discussed in relation to the approval of the Ypsilanti
Downtown Development Authority bylaws - a separate agenda item at the
meeting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murdock said the resolution is simply about “having meetings where decisions are made open to the public.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although
he had previous discussions with City Manager Ed Koryzno during
Council’s goal-setting sessions in January, Murdock moved forward with
the resolution Oct. 20, when the DDA violated the Open Meetings Act
earlier in the month by having a quorum, or more than seven members of
the board, participate at a planning committee meeting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://advanceypsilanti.com/?p=655&#34;&gt;Advance Ypsilanti PAC&lt;/a&gt; notes that the resolution snuck in at the last possible minute&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sadly, the process by which this open meetings resolution
was enacted is exactly the opposite of an open process. This is not
just ironic, but suspect.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, consider that this resolution was sent to the city
clerk and posted to the council packets at 4:16 p.m. the day of the
city council meeting, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;less than 3 hours &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;before
council was to convene. AY PAC asks ‘why’? There was no emergency, no
timeline that needed to be met on this issue. There was no pressing
need that forced this to be addressed and resolved THAT NIGHT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anyone can inform AY PAC as to why this was so urgent that it
needed to be addressed in a timeline that included NO opportunity for
public comment and little reflection by council, we welcome the
information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The back story is the Ypsi DDA meeting in October 2008 which was held in closed session, in evident violation of the Open Meetings Act.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ypsinews.com/index.php/200810-ypsilanti-dda-violates-open-meetings-act-twice-in-one-meeting/comment-page-1/&#34;&gt;From YpsiNews (Steve Pierce) at the time:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(October 7, 2008) During a meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ypsilantidda.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ypsilanti Downtown Development&lt;/a&gt;, the DDA board violated not one, but two sections of the Open Meetings Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Director of the Ypsilanti DDA, Brian Vosburg, called an
emergency closed session meeting to be held on Friday, October 3, 2008
at 12 noon. The purpose of the meeting was to meet with DDA attorney
Tammie Tischler. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DDA Director said in the meeting notice the “Closed Session (is)
to consider material exempt from discussion or disclosure by state or
federal statute - (Open Meetings Act 15.268, Section 8(h))”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, neither the DDA Director nor the DDA attorney would cite
which state or federal statute exempts the DDA from the Open Meetings
Act. Failing to publicly state the reason for a closed session is a
violation of the Open Meetings Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




 &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>