<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/weblogs/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/weblogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>export everything is missing on ello</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-export-everything-is-missing-on-ello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 23:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-export-everything-is-missing-on-ello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t see an &#34;export all my work here&#34; button on ello, the new trendy social network. So I am unlikely to put anything there that I am unwilling to have destroyed on a moment&#39;s notice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Power Of The Blog&#34;, Ann Arbor Observer, June 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-30-the-power-of-the-blog-ann-arbor-observer-june-2013-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-30-the-power-of-the-blog-ann-arbor-observer-june-2013-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborweb.com/articles/the_power_of_the_blog_full_article.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Power Of The Blog&lt;/a&gt;&#34;, Ann Arbor Observer, June 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vacuum&#39;s subject material is a hodgepodge, but that&#39;s because Vielmetti sees the blog very much in the classical context: as a personal, yet very public, journal. A longtime notebook keeper, Vielmetti sees Vacuum mostly as just another way to record and archive his own thoughts--although it recently hit a traffic milestone, with one million total page views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Dunn&#39;s story also has accounts from &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gastroboy.com&#34;&gt;A2Gastroboy&lt;/a&gt;, Ben Connor Barrie of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com&#34;&gt;Damn Arbor&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://markmaynard.com&#34;&gt;Mark Maynard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo in talks to acquire Tumblr, users are not happy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-19-yahoo-in-talks-to-acquire-tumblr-users-are-not-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-19-yahoo-in-talks-to-acquire-tumblr-users-are-not-happy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo is in talks to acquire Tumblr, with a price tag north of a billion dollars. Who knew that simplifying the blogging interface could be so profitable? I wonder, though, how Yahoo is going to make money off of Tumblr page views without ruining the service. (cf Flickr) (cf &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/10/google-analytics-real-time-vs-mybloglog.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;MyBlogLog&lt;/a&gt;) (cf GeoCities) etc. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/yahoo&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;See what Tumblr users think of the acquisition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;You know that house your friends got that was the best hang out, watch tv, party you face off, great pot lucks, still clean and comfy to chill in place? Then the landlords were like ugh, yall gotta go, and then the best hang out place was gone?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, so where is everyone heading now that Yahoo bought this place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s nothing like a big messy purple smooch from Yahoo to make users fear for their accumulated friendships on a service that just wants to monetize page views with ads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The import-export problem and fragile Internet services</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-18-the-import-export-problem-and-fragile-internet-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 09:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-18-the-import-export-problem-and-fragile-internet-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the scenario. You and your team work hard to use a
new piece of collaboration software that offers some unique features
that are suited either to the work at hand or that appeal to your
sense of novelty. The tool works great and you get into it, using
some of the more complex parts of the system to great advantage.
Then the system&amp;rsquo;s owners send out the dreaded self-congratulatory
message saying that they have been acquired by a big company, or
some beleagured product manager announces that their system is being
sunsetted. You need to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving turns out to be hard. Once upon a time when the only thing
you needed to move was electronic mail, there were only a handful
of email file formats, and though they were incompletely specified
you could readily move among them. Moving between news readers was
just a matter of reusing your .newsrc file. Life was simpler then
(cue sad violins).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation now is much more complicated. If you are extremely
lucky, the system you have has an export file that is the same as
its import file, and someone has built a faithful clone of your
original service for you to migrate to. That was the case in my
move from &lt;a  href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delicious_%28website%29&#34;
rel=&#34;wikipedia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Delicious (website)&#34;&gt;Delicious&lt;/a&gt;
to &lt;a  href=&#34;http://www.pinboard.in&#34; rel=&#34;homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;
title=&#34;Pinboard&#34;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re keeping a weblog,
though, things can get really unhappy really fast, and a friend to
recently migrated from &lt;a  href=&#34;http://www.posterous.com&#34;
rel=&#34;homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Posterous&#34;&gt;Posterous&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a  href=&#34;http://wordpress.org&#34; rel=&#34;homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;
title=&#34;WordPress&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; went through gyrations that I&amp;rsquo;m
not sure that I would have tolerated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental problem, I suppose, is that the more innovating the
service the less likely that its data is structured so simply that
you can drop it in to someting else. Brand new user interfaces, the
ones that attract traffic because of the ever present need for
novelty, also have novel data structures. Watch out when getting
into something new that you may find it easier to start than to
stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll miss Google Reader, but it&#39;s no longer how people read this site</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-13-ill-miss-google-reader-but-its-no-longer-how-people-read-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-13-ill-miss-google-reader-but-its-no-longer-how-people-read-this-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c37a66185970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot 2013-03-13 at 11.29.45 PM&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c37a66185970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c37a66185970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2013-03-13 at 11.29.45 PM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If my Google Analytics reporting is to be behaved, the peak of Google Reader usage for me was in mid 2008, and by early 2010 it had been reduced to background noise. I can understand based on this graph (and perhaps millions of other graphs like it) that it might be time to call it quits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like from other charts (that I won&amp;#39;t show here) that Twitter picked up the slack, as did Facebook.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Google&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;sunset&amp;quot; announcement for Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;says that you can get your data out; I&amp;#39;m sure that at least one service will appear to let you load it in and carry on reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>some details of setting up Movable Type: day 13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-16-some-details-of-setting-up-movable-type-day-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 23:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-16-some-details-of-setting-up-movable-type-day-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;public notes from day 13 at &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com&#34;&gt;AnnArbor.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m noting some MT setup details here, since I need a spot for it, and since I&amp;#39;ve been relatively spoiled by having the Typepad crew figure out how to make things just work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;1. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.org/documentation/administrator/managing-blogs/settings/entry-settings.html&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Replace Word Characters&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;A default setting when you paste in Word documents is to have them paste in with entity characters; this setting converts those to ASCII. &amp;#0160;(Word, bleah, but it&amp;#39;s the norm.)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;2. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.org/documentation/appendices/tags/entryifextended.html&#34;&gt;EntryIfExtended&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;A template tag to use to conditionally include a &amp;quot;more...&amp;quot; button at the bottom of a page or entry, to link to the whole thing. &amp;#0160;(Typepad doesn&amp;#39;t do extended entries.)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;3. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.movabletype.org/2009/06/how-can-i-edit-my-rss-comment-feed-template.html&#34;&gt;Creating comment feeds&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;A forum post showing a couple of wrong ways and a right way to do it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;more to come, but that&amp;#39;s tonight; spelunking through the docs to see what&amp;#39;s possible.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blogger vs journalist, day 5</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-blogger-vs-journalist-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 09:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-blogger-vs-journalist-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to keep the chronology going - this is back to Monday of this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a nice and mostly non-confrontational interview with a journalist-with-a-capital-J about my new role at &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com&#34;&gt;AnnArbor.com&lt;/a&gt; .&amp;#0160; The discussion seemed to center on what kinds of standards (or lack of standards) people have when they self-identify as bloggers, and how that compares with the ideal of what a professional journalist is supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been wrestling with this, in part because I&amp;#39;ve been blogging so long (since 1999) that there has been a big shift in what the popular press has characterized and categorized bloggers as.&amp;#0160; When I started, the blogger was either the extremely widely read Internet explorer who kept a log of the many interesting things that came across their path, or it was the expert in some field (at times a very narrow field) who used a less formal sequential writing tool to capture details and query others in their niche interest about what was going on and relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s only much later that in some people&amp;#39;s minds that blogger turned into the text equivalent of political talk radio show host as seen in text.&amp;#0160; There it&amp;#39;s been obvious that whatever standards of practice there are are much less interested in pursuit of Truth or of careful observation and much more about propoganda in one form or another.&amp;#0160; Not that the press and the media and public relations hasn&amp;#39;t done propoganda for many years - it&amp;#39;s just that it&amp;#39;s not the norm for old school blogging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m hopeful as I suppose I have to be that AnnArbor.com&amp;#39;s experiment with giving voice to readers as contributors makes for something that adds to the whole operation.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve talked to any number of people for whom when I describe what I&amp;#39;m looking for as &amp;quot;experts who can write but who are not professional writers&amp;quot;, rather than &amp;quot;bloggers with free reign to spew unsourced and unedited opinion&amp;quot;, that some of the concerns ease.&amp;#0160; But I suspect it will take a whole year of refining what the Ann Arbor School of Blogging has as a style and attitude that sets it apart from the rest of the world that will make the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movable Type rich text editors and stripping weird tags</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-01-movable-type-rich-text-editors-and-stripping-weird-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 11:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-01-movable-type-rich-text-editors-and-stripping-weird-tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another part of day 3 -&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re going through Movable Type training again today (thanks Natalie!)&amp;#0160; And the question came up, because it&amp;#39;s going to be part of the process, what are people going to do so that the workflow of someone pasting in what they write in some other text editor gets published in such a way that it doesn&amp;#39;t include weird tags, weird HTML, or funky or smelly javascript.&amp;#0160; Microsoft Word is one version of that process; there&amp;#39;s lots more paths that get there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that when I used to use Typepad, that the rich text editor I had was pretty good about stripping out tags and attributes that were weird.&amp;#0160; Font tags disappeared, for instance, which made it possible to be sure that stuff didn&amp;#39;t show up as Comic Sans unless I really wanted them to be in Comic Sans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ve found out so far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.org/documentation/developer/rich-text-editors.html&#34;&gt;MT supports multiple kinds of rich text editor abstractions.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160; There&amp;#39;s currently support for the YUI editor, for TinyMCE, and for FCK.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; The relevant bit of configuration code is wrapped in&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mt:setvarblock name=&amp;quot;editor_content&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/tinymce-mtplugin/&#34;&gt;TinyMCE MT plugin source&lt;/a&gt; posted on Google Code.&amp;#0160; The current release, supporting Japanese and English, is in active development and is at version 0.1.11 as of 29 hours ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Richard Benson wrote and supports the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.richardbenson.co.uk/projects/yui-rich-text-editor-in-movabl.html?utm_source=mt-plugins&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=yui-editor&#34;&gt;YUI MT plugin&lt;/a&gt;, which is at version 1.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, to the actual MT rich text editor:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rant from&lt;a accesskey=&#34;1&#34; href=&#34;http://padawan.info/en/2007/07/upgrading-to-mt.html&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;François Nonnenmacher&lt;/a&gt; about the HTML generated by the MT rich text editor:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rich Text Editor produces tons of ugly fucking code behind the screen&lt;/strong&gt;, especially when using Safari. So it&amp;#39;s an &lt;a href=&#34;http://padawan.info/web/oldschool_rich_text_editors.html&#34;&gt;old-school editor&lt;/a&gt; such &lt;a href=&#34;http://padawan.info/web/midas.html&#34;&gt;Midas&lt;/a&gt;, only a slight improvement over &lt;abbr title=&#34;What You See Is Fucking Ugly Code&#34;&gt;WYSIFUC&lt;/abbr&gt; in the sense that it hides it from you (unless you select &amp;quot;none&amp;quot; in the Format menu or &amp;quot;HTML Mode&amp;quot; and scream in horror at the &lt;abbr title=&#34;Fucking Ugly Code&#34;&gt;FUC&lt;/abbr&gt;
it generates, like &amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;Apple-style-span&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;font-style:
italic;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; instead of &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;!). For
example, on Safari it generates a DIV per paragraph, while on Firefox
it just spits out &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags or cosmetic &amp;lt;i&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;
tags (not even &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;, or &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; tags, mind
you).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And generally that&amp;#39;s my experience to date; weird tags, bad semantics, and unpredictable behavior.&amp;#0160; What I don&amp;#39;t know yet (and hope to figure out) is what the data path is through the system that would let things be cleaned up and filtered on the back end so that they are consistent, or fixed on the front end so that the generated code from the rich text editor is better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is, this used to work better: old versions of Typepad, and old versions of MT, both had a very conservative rich text editor that denatured the text quite a bit, removing a lot of tags and operating in &amp;quot;safe mode&amp;quot; much more so than &amp;quot;rich mode&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a puzzle...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Movable Type on day two</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-learning-movable-type-on-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 17:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-learning-movable-type-on-day-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;day two of my new position at &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com&#34;&gt;annarbor.com&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full day of training on Movable Type.&amp;#0160; We started with a mostly empty install (hosted on a temporary EC2 instance; nice setup) and the team added users, made comments, posted entries and worked through the admin screens.&amp;#0160; I know that most people won&amp;#39;t be working at this level most of the time, but it&amp;#39;s also really good to give people some sense of what is possible with the tool and how the workflow and process starts to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can only imagine what it would take to run a newspaper in the era before content management systems, the world of green screen terminals and baroque editorial process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m also incredibly happy that I have been using Typepad, because the full MT system looks and feels familiar in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some references for MT admin details:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.com/&#34;&gt;movabletype.com&lt;/a&gt; home page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.org/documentation/administrator/managing-community/&#34;&gt;managing a community with Movable Type&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.org/documentation/&#34;&gt;MT 4 documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlb.com/blogs/&#34;&gt;major league baseball blogs&lt;/a&gt; runs on MT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movabletype.com/blog/2008/02/talking-points-memo-a-blog-jou.html&#34;&gt;talking points memo runs on MT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>