<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brady Hoke on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/brady-hoke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brady Hoke on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 22:18:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/brady-hoke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan vs Virginia Tech (Hoke vs Hokies) in Sugar Bowl, January 3, 2012 in New Orleans; also, sandwiches</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 22:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Follow the coverage from all sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National coverage: ESPN&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://espn.go.com/colleges/michigan/&#34;&gt;WolverineNation&lt;/a&gt; coverage from beat writer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikerothstein&#34;&gt;Michael Rothstein&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://espn.go.com/colleges/michigan/football/story/_/id/7316280/michigan-wolverines-land-sugar-bowl&#34;&gt;Michigan Wolverines Land Sugar Bowl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It almost didn&#39;t happen, however. After finishing the regular season 10-2, the Wolverines needed help from other teams around the country on Saturday and from the pollsters on Sunday morning in order to be in this position -- and they received it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Virginia Tech, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/colleges/virginia-tech-hokies-a-surprise-pick-for-sugar-bowl/2011/12/04/gIQAghsCUO_story.html&#34;&gt;Washington Post writes&lt;/a&gt; &#34;one of the most surprising Bowl Championship Series at-large picks ever&#34;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virginia Tech’s BCS at-large hopes appeared to evaporate after its 38-10 loss to Clemson in the ACC championship game Saturday. While the Hokies have been ranked all season, they have not defeated a team currently in the Associated Press top 25 poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is in New Orleans, and Michigan&#39;s ever-efficient alumni association has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://alumni.umich.edu/sports/athletic-tours-and-travel-packages/official-bowl-tours&#34;&gt;official bowl tour package&lt;/a&gt; complete with chartered flights. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Orleans is a great place to eat a sandwich. &lt;a href=&#34;http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/686440&#34;&gt;Chowhound has a best sandwiches&lt;/a&gt; thread that&#39;s got a lot of great suggestions; I&#39;d pick a banh mi (in its role as a Vietnamese po&#39;boy). In Ann Arbor the blog &#34;Meg Goes Nom Nom&#34; has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://meggoesnomnom.wordpress.com/2011/02/10/meggoesnomnoms-one-year-birthday-banh-mi/&#34;&gt;glowing review of the banh mi from Zingerman&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And a few months after this occurred, I discovered that the featured sandwich at local favorite Zingerman’s Delicatessen was the Banh Mi. It was time! And not only get to try the sandwich, I got to meet the talented creator of this legit sandwich while I was there. Awesome! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zing sandwich was done by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/sanstreetfood&#34;&gt;San Street&lt;/a&gt;, a food cart which alas I have not checked out myself yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Viet World Kitchen blog has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vietworldkitchen.com/blog/2009/06/banh-mi-sandwich-recipe.html&#34;&gt;master banh mi recipe&lt;/a&gt; which pretty much sums up what you&#39;d need to put together your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is essentially one sandwich in Vietnamese cooking and it is quite a tour de force. It started out very simply, with baguette smeared with liver pate and that was it. That&#39;s how my mom knew it in the 1940s when she was growing up in Northern Vietnam. What we know today as banh mi is a light, crispy small baguette that is split and hollowed before it is invariably filled with homemade mayonnaise or butter (which I don&#39;t like), sliced chili pepper, cilantro leaves, cucumber, a tangy-sweet daikon and carrot pickle (do chua), and a drizzle of soy sauce. The variation comes in when you choose what protein component(s) will be center stage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recipe action gets you a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stickygooeycreamychewy.com/2010/08/13/do-chua-vietnamese-carrot-and-daikon-pickle/&#34;&gt;do chua recipe from the blog Sticky Gooey Creamy Chewy&lt;/a&gt;, which sounds easy enough to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do chua is so incredibly easy to make. Since it is a “fresh” pickle, there is no boiling or cooking involved. All you do is julienne the carrots and daikon, and soak them in a brine made with white vinegar, rice wine vinegar, a little water, sugar and a pinch of salt. That’s it!  Plus, the pickles only need to marinate in their brine for about an hour before they’re ready to devour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you are ready for some football.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>