<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Preview for 17 August 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Council meets at 7:00 p.m. on Monday, 17 August 2015.
A preview of the agenda is on Arborwiki, complete with a map, on the
tag &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/tags/20150817ccmtg&#34;&gt;2015-08-17CCMTG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some highlights to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consent agenda includes $36,412 for the purchase of 21 Taser weapons.
This is a sole-source purchase, to replace weapons purchased in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also on the consent agenda is $83,000 for a sole-source purchase to
renew the CityWorks license, which is used for asset tracking and
maintenance of city owned resources. Of that amount, $20,000 will be
billed back to the Washtenaw County Water Resources Commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$110,000 would go for the continuation of CLEMIS Public Safety Information
Sharing Services for the Ann Arbor Police Department for FY2016. CLEMIS
runs the dispatch system for police and allows &amp;ldquo;information sharing&amp;rdquo;
with other departments. It&amp;rsquo;s run by Oakland County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HathiTrust has digitized many decades of Ann Arbor City Council minutes,
and it it proposed that the city approve publication of those minutes through
HathiTrust by clearing the copyright on those materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public hearings include one on deer management, and there&amp;rsquo;s a proposal
on the agenda to spend $90,000 on some combination of a deer cull by
sharpshooters and sterlization of deer. Expect this to be a long public
hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In development news, there&amp;rsquo;s a proposed condominium development on N Main St
adjacent to North Main Park, and hearings on proposed annexations on Nixon
Road and on Ann Arbor - Saline Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re following the footing drain disconnect program closely, you&amp;rsquo;ll
note that there&amp;rsquo;s a proposal to lend the builder of 618 South Main
footing drain disconnect credits to allow for full occupancy of that building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More of course at the full agenda. See you on the site plan barricades
(er, see you at council).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I voted, summer 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor is one of three peculiar communities in the state of Michigan
to have partisan City Council elections; the other two are Ypsilanti and
Ionia. This has in recent years meant that the races that decide the makeup
of City Council happen in the summer when students are gone and when
voter turnout is very low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did vote, and I do plan to go to at least one of the parties celebrating
victory or acknowledging defeat by the candidates who have the remaining
funds from their campaign to put out a nice spread for supporters, hangers-on,
or the perpetually politically curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few rounds of picking up result tapes from Ward Four precincts, I ended up
at Arbor Brewing Company which was Council Party HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Sabra Briere&lt;/span&gt; over Will Leaf, handily with 70%+ of the vote,
though only 6% of registered voters actually voted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Ward: We&amp;rsquo;ll wait until the fall for this as Jane Lumm (I) meets
Sally Hart Petersen (D) in November.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Zachary Ackerman&lt;/span&gt; defeats Steve Kunselman by about 40 votes.
This was the surprise of the night. Ackerman&amp;rsquo;s entire margin of victory was
his strong showing in 3-3 (Burns Park) where he outpaced Kunselman 345-171.
Turnout was under 11%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fourth Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Jack Eaton&lt;/span&gt; defeats Jamie Magiera with about 60% of the vote.
Jack held his party at Wolverine Brewing; Jamie was at ABC, looking subdued.
Turnout was about 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifth Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Chip Smith&lt;/span&gt; defeated Mike Anglin with about 55% of the vote.
Voter turnout in the mighty Fifth Ward was strong compared to the other wards,
with a mighty 14% of the electorate turning out to vote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 85%+ of Ann Arbor voters who didn&amp;rsquo;t know enough or didn&amp;rsquo;t bother
to turn out to vote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://electionresults.ewashtenaw.org/electionreporting/aug2015/index.jsp&#34;&gt;UnOfficial Election Results, August 4, 2015 City Primary Election&lt;/a&gt;, Wasthenaw County&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Emergency Incidents and overnight storm report</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan Emergency Incidents is a news service that covers emergency
dispatch around the state of Michigan. Members of a closed Facebook
group post call-outs of emergency services operations, and there&amp;rsquo;s
generally follow up from other members to note incidents in progress
or news stories written from the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All information contained in MEI posts is to come from received
radio transmissions heard directly from radios / scanners or via
an online broadcast, verified reliable sources, or first hand
knowledge (ie you are on scene).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow along on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/meidispatch&#34;&gt;@MEIDispatch&lt;/a&gt;;
the twitter feed has the current link to the private Facebook group,
which regularly accepts qualified new members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storm last night. We got a downpour, some wind and lightning, but nothing
too bad. A nearby &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.a2gov.org/RainGauges/&#34;&gt;City of Ann Arbor rain gauge&lt;/a&gt;
on S Industrial reported 1.12&amp;rdquo; of rain, and at the peak of the storm rain
was coming down at 0.41&amp;rdquo; in 15 minutes. The scanner was full of power
lines sparking and trees down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worst hit was the Sleeping Bear Dunes area, where some of the
adjacent communities had complete power blackouts. There was also a
tornado in the Thumb. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weather.gov/apx/2015Aug2recap&#34;&gt;National Weather Service recap&lt;/a&gt; for the August 2, 2015 storms gives much more detail.
Softball sized hail was seen near West Branch, MI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current 8:45 a.m. report is 60,318 DTE Energy customers without power, and
91,802 Consumers Energy customers without power. DTE does not generally
report outages by county, just by zip code, but I have all of the zip
codes so I should be able to estimate county level totals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department does a round
of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;restaurant inspections&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Wayne Eaker&lt;/span&gt; built
an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zengenuity/food-inspections&#34;&gt;importer&lt;/a&gt; that
pulls in data from the site that hosts the official county inspections,
and is storing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zengenuity/food-inspections-data&#34;&gt;inspection data&lt;/a&gt;
on Github to make it easier for the next person who wants to build
a nice interface to all the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne was good enough to find a spot to host an interface to this data
that lets you browse through it; you can find it at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&#34;&gt;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are permalinks to each inspection so that you can link to them.
See e.g. recent inspections for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-06-17-slurping-turtle&#34;&gt;Slurping Turtle&lt;/a&gt;, June 17, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-04-27-china-chef-restaurant&#34;&gt;China Chef&lt;/a&gt;, Ypsilanti, April 27, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-06-22-nu-wave-fish-chicken&#34;&gt;Nu Wave Fish and Chicken&lt;/a&gt;, June 22, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for three examples of places where I want to see a clean inspection on a followup
visit before I go or go back to there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine
under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old
olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction
site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building
that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the day is a death on State Street. A young man was
climbing over the skylights at the Nickels Arcade and fell to his
death when the skylight glass gave way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 1915, the SS Eastland was packed with employees from
the Western Electric Hawthorne Works when it rolled over in
the Chicago River. 844 passengers and crew lost their lives, making
the Eastland disaster the worst shipwreck on the Great Lakes.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastlanddisaster.org/&#34;&gt;Eastland Disaster Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;
for extensive notes on and photos of the scene and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2civictech/&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt;
is coming up on Monday, July 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literatibookstore.com/&#34;&gt;Literati Bookstore&lt;/a&gt; is open
again after a water leak caused them to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote a tiny R script that generates maps. The challenge
today is to find a portable environment so that I can deploy this script
on shared infrastructure. The project took 30 minutes of MacBook Air processor
time running full blast parallel, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t care about wall clock time
to complete the effort I do care about building something that I can hand
off to someone else to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocker-org/ropensci&#34;&gt;ropensci&lt;/a&gt; Docker
package from the Rocker project is the answer, or most of the answer, for this.
Rocker has built R images where lots of useful packages have been installed,
including systems where the install directions are a little bit complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all complicated software environments the biggest challenge is dealing
with dependencies. If you want to use the latest and greatest fast algorithms,
you have to be prepared to spin up on what the cool kids are doing in the
rest of their environment. If somehow you can jump to the edge of the development
in the algorithm world without being tripped up by the hairy dependency graph
that got you there, it can be a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So; install Docker on the Mac with &amp;lsquo;boot2docker&amp;rsquo;; then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;docker pull rocker/ropensci
docker run -it rocker/ropensci R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and poof, you have an environment current to this month&amp;rsquo;s desktop of leading
R developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of
BBQ at Ricewood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting
an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately
cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command
line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately
sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and
manual file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I know doesn&amp;rsquo;t work is upload via Twitter, because the series of
resizings generate visible compression artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can upload from the phone to OneDrive, which gives me a photo of size
2592 × 1456 pixels (1.78:1, 16:9). The target size is 1875 x 1275
(1.47:1, 25:17), which is postcard format. I can keep all of the pixels
in the image by letterboxing it, or I can crop off the edges. What I
can&amp;rsquo;t really do is stretch the image to fit because it&amp;rsquo;s too far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking further at my camera software (Lumia Camera) it appears
that I can also take photos at 4:3. There&amp;rsquo;s more experimenting to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more documentation, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/06/efficient-image-resizing-with-imagemagick/&#34;&gt;Efficient Image Resizing With ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt;,
Dave Newton in Smashing Magazine, June 25, 2015. Dave goes through a
professionally thorough view of resizing and resampling images for the web,
comparing his results against Photoshop. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested 31 different settings for &lt;code&gt;-filter&lt;/code&gt; and got the best results
with &lt;code&gt;Triangle&lt;/code&gt;. The Triangle resampling filter is also known as
bilinear interpolation, which I discussed above. It determines pixel
color by looking at a support area of neighboring pixels and produces
a weighted average of their colors. I found it best to specify this
support area at two pixels using the &lt;code&gt;-define filter:support=2&lt;/code&gt;
setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave uses DSSIM from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pornel.net/dssim&#34;&gt;https://pornel.net/dssim&lt;/a&gt; to test his results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool computes (dis)similarity between two PNG images using
(my approximation of) algorithms approximating human vision.
Comparison is done in L*a&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; color space using a multi-scale variant
of the SSIM algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are sites that have automatic crop algorithms, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet found a package that&amp;rsquo;s usable without licensing. The interactive
web site of &lt;a href=&#34;http://croppola.com/&#34;&gt;Croppola&lt;/a&gt; is one useful example of
this genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pittsburgh&amp;rsquo;s smallest jazz club is installed in a bus stop on Liberty
Avenue, across from 9th Street.  The shelter was installed on July
6 and will remain until late August 2015. From the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://newpittsburghcourieronline.com/2015/07/09/the-worlds-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;New Pittsburgh Courier Online&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://awesomepgh.com/2015/01/15/award-36-pittsburghs-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;Awesome Pittsburgh&lt;/a&gt;’s trustees smiled unanimously when they decided
to choose the proposal for one of 2014’s $1000 grants, envisioning
a bus patron who pushes a button, only to have an iPod play jazz
music from one of MCG Jazz’s Grammy Award winning recordings. The
interior walls of a bus shelter will feature images of Pittsburgh’s
jazz legends, and a blank “Your Face Here!” space to take a picture
of yourself at “Pittsburgh’s Smallest Jazz Club.” Lamar Outdoor,
owner of the bus shelters in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, is
already on board to help make the project happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was done by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcgjazz.org/&#34;&gt;MCG Jazz&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Amy_MCGJazz&#34;&gt;Amy Kline&lt;/a&gt; is their marketing manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network issues at Malletts Creek branch were a good reason to exit back
towards town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or
is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage
everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging
environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have
my computer with me. On the other hand doing live-blogging from a phone is
not possible, not that it ever really was very practical with any previous setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your UMARC shack access code is &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Achievement unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The todo list right now for the shack is very short - &amp;ldquo;get in&amp;rdquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m
in I should have a longer list. There is a lot of gear in that room
to get familiar with, not least of which is HF equipment with tunable
and movable antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/twitter-marius-eriksen-finagle/&#34;&gt;Why Twitter Has More Freedom To Innovate Than Google&lt;/a&gt; is a 2013 Wired Magazine writeup.
Prominently featured are Marius Eriksen, Niels Provos, and Peter Honeyman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the early aughts, when Eriksen was an undergrad at
Michigan, studying computer science under a professor and lovable
eccentric named Peter Honeyman. Known as “Dr. Honey” among the
undergrads and PhD students at his Center for Information Technology
Integration, Honeyman was famous for making assignments without
really making assignments. “He would develop a particular obsession,
and he would give you random hints about it, but he wouldn’t actually
tell you what to do,” Eriksen remembers. “You would end up collaborating
with people on whatever it was, in this freeform way, without much
direction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to one of Peter&amp;rsquo;s current students. Evan is looking at ways to
direct RF energy at devices to make them fail in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan are working on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://it.slashdot.org/story/15/06/30/1917207/stanford-starts-the-secure-internet-of-things-project&#34;&gt;Secure Internet of Things Project (slashdot)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan have now started
the Secure Internet of Things Project, which aims to promote security
and transparency for IoT devices. They hope to unite regulators,
researchers, and manufacturers to ensure nascent internet-connected
tech is developed in a way that respects customer privacy and choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web site has more details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu&#34;&gt;http://iot.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the presentations at the Secure Internet of Things Project Retreat
in Half Moon Bay on June 5, 2015 was this by U of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Prabal Dutta,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu/retreat15/sitp15-swhw.pdf&#34;&gt;State of the Field: Hardware and Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(embed deck here, if I can)
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LP0965 Antenna is a Log Periodic PCB directional antenna, at 5-6dBi Gain.
The design is from Kent Britain WA5VJB, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wa5vjb.com/pcb-pdfs/LP8565.pdf&#34;&gt;data sheet for the antenna&lt;/a&gt; describes its
utility for signals from 850 Mhz to 6500 Mhz. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://wa5vjb.com&#34;&gt;http://wa5vjb.com&lt;/a&gt; for more
circuit board antennas for use for hobby, wifi, microwave and cellular use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic jam on Fuller on the return trip, backed up all the way to the river.
It took about 15 minutes to get through because of construction on westbound
Fuller taking traffic to one lane. It would have been faster to take the Route 1
AAATA bus via Pontiac Trail, even though it would have been a considerable detour,
or to walk to Plymouth Road and take the 2 in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fire at the Michigan League this afternoon. No sign of any issues
as I pass by this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question when taking Commuter South is always where to get off the bus. Today
I&amp;rsquo;ll take it all the way to the end of its route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Biggby Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a warm but pleasant mid-summer late Monday morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m
visiting the first cafe inbound on a walk to town. Biggby Packard
is where I end up when the inbound bus schedule timing is just so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summertime cafes near campus are odd. There&amp;rsquo;s not really enough here
to motivate someone to drive here for coffee, so it draws people
from the surrounding neighborhood and from the athletic campus.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been in here before when I was the only patron for more than
an hour but this morning there&amp;rsquo;s a few more people sitting typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first ran into the &amp;ldquo;pocketmod&amp;rdquo; planning technique in 2005, and
here it is 10 years later and there&amp;rsquo;s one in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pocketmod is a cleverly folded piece of paper with preprinted
templates for things like a mini calendar, todo list, quadrille
paper, checklist etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the smallest instance of a PDA that I
have seen yet, requiring nothing more than a blank piece of paper
and a pair of scissors to execute. You could even bypass the scissors
if you had good paper and a crisp straightedge to do a rip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astoundingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketmod.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pocketmod.com/&lt;/a&gt; is still online, in all of
its 2005-2007 glory. That system does an 8-up PDF from a set of templates,
so that you can print a lovingly detailed mini booklet. My own use
has long since devolved into scrap paper plus rip down the center.
When it fills up, invert the fold, and you have a brand new organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now playing, Johnny Cash&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;One Piece at a Time&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;GM wouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss just
one little piece.&amp;rdquo; Look for the promo photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Menu plan: green beans with walnuts and miso sauce, plus a few green beans
uncooked on the side for J who likes to eat the raw. A recipe of sorts is
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/recipe-review-green-beans-with-49874&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;,
which refers to a 2005 New York Times Dining article about Yumiko
Kano and her brand of Japanese cooking.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://justbento.com/handbook/bento-basics/review-saisai-lunch-vegan-bento-by-yumiko-kano&#34;&gt;Just Bento&lt;/a&gt; has some reviews of books by Yumiko Kano (aka Yumiko Kanoh or
Kanou Kumiko). &lt;a href=&#34;http://theunbearablelightnessofbeinghungry.com/2009/10/vegetarian-ramen/&#34;&gt;The Unbearable Lightness of Being Hungry&lt;/a&gt; has a 2009 vegetarian ramen recipe
from the same author. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://metropolis.co.jp/dining/table-talk/yumiko-kano/&#34;&gt;profile of Yumiko Kano&lt;/a&gt; in Metropolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some
very yummy new potatoes from Farmers Market that I cooked up last night,
which were 1000x more wonderful than storebought old potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exit Biggby heading north to North Campus to Mujo&amp;rsquo;s, for some
time spent writing. Close all of the windows, save all of the
documents, publish locally all of the works in progress. North
Campus has the virute of frequent free bus service from Central
Campus, and it&amp;rsquo;s far enough away to completely flush all of
the thoughts of what I had been doing so I can work on another project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular
&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years.
He died on July 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Hazen_Schumacher&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher&lt;/a&gt;
has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled
and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bixeibenhamburg.com/&#34;&gt;Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;,
and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bixrevisited.com&#34;&gt;http://bixrevisited.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited has reached millions, giving Hazen a good claim
to be America’s premier jazz educator.&amp;rdquo; (Art Hilgart - IAJRC Journal).
Bix Eiben Hamburg presents 24 different shows at regular intervals
for free listening. Dive into the wonderful world of classic Jazz.
Become part of the great Jazz fan community that already regularly
uses our service free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/84464117&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/84464117&#34;&gt;A tribute to The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and Jazz Revisited&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/bixeiben&#34;&gt;Jazz-Museum Bixeibenhamburg&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In remembrance of The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and a documentary report about the Jazz Revisited Radio Shows!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight of us met for lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aysesturkishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; today. It was a normal
Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for
the lunch group these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time
to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning
or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a
remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make
sure that the things that needed to get done got done. Among the
tasks that took up lots more time than they deserved included
dealing with the health insurance marketplace and with other
healthcare providers for dealing with billing and accounting problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the people at lunch were new to the table, but since Ann
Arbor is bascially a small town, it was not a surprise to me that
I had easily identifiable mutual friends with two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was delicious, well prepared and well presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll be back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Madras_Masala&#34;&gt;Madras Masala&lt;/a&gt;, as art fair will have
ended and town will be more back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big event coming up is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makerfairedetroit.com/&#34;&gt;Maker Faire Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, to be held at The
Henry Ford in Dearborn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lunch with jonathan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:30:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan and I went to Paradise, a Vietnamese place in the
Colonade that also serves Chinese food. He got Mongolian Beef,
and I got pho deluxe. It was perfectly adequate if not spectacular.
The topic of conversation was an elaborate storyline in a game
that involved animatronics in a creepy Chuck E. Cheese type
abandoned pizza parlor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the Malletts Creek library, until about 4:00 p.m.
I worked on Hugo and constructed a theme from scratch.
At the end he got bored.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council for July 6, 2015: online video stream goes dark</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-ann-arbor-city-council-for-july-6-2015-online-video-stream-goes-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 20:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-ann-arbor-city-council-for-july-6-2015-online-video-stream-goes-dark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re trying to follow Ann Arbor City Council via the online feed, you&#39;ll be disappointed tonight as the feed is not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d133bbbf970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d133bbbf970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 570px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-07-06 at 8.11.01 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-07-06 at 8.11.01 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d133bbbf970c-580wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The CTN live stream for channel 16 is currently down and being looked at. Sorry for the inconvenience. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ctnannarbor?src=hash&#34;&gt;#ctnannarbor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; CTN Ann Arbor (@CTNAnnArbor) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CTNAnnArbor/status/618198005737488384&#34;&gt;July 6, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arborbike, a first review</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 10:42:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;arborbike&#34; title=&#34;IMG_0636&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus: fun to ride, big front basket. It&#39;s a very nice bike that you&#39;re riding, with a good 3 speed shifter and a very sturdy construction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minus: no lights, no bell, no helmets. More specifically, I am told that the lights come on automatically, and that there is a bell somewhere, but I didn&#39;t find it and it wasn&#39;t labeled. I did have a helmet with me so I wore that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborbike.org/&#34;&gt;arborbike.org&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to John Hritz - photo credit Ryan Stanton.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>