<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Paid for by * for mayor of Ann Arbor&#34; - an analysis of campaign advertising &amp; disclosure</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 19:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After getting one too many political ads in my Facebook newsfeed, I started paying closer attention to the &#34;Paid for by&#34; language that I expect to see on every paid political campaign message. The mayoral candidates for the City of Ann Arbor all have some work to do to get their disclosures in order for the 2014 campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked for campaign disclosures on Facebook pages, on Twitter feeds, and on event pages created by the campaign on Facebook. I also looked generally at Google, searching for the phrase in question. The four candidates for the Democratic side of the Ann Arbor mayoral ballot are Stephen Kunselman, Sally Hart Petersen, Sabra Briere and Christopher Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Kunselman: while I can find a &#34;Kunselman for Council&#34; web site, I can&#39;t locate a &#34;Kunselman for Mayor&#34; web site. The candidate&#39;s Facebook page doesn&#39;t mention the candidacy that I can see. I haven&#39;t seen any ads from the candidate yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sally Hart Petersen: No search results on Google for the mayoral campaign. A Facebook page for the candidate has 294 likes; in the header, it says &#34;Paid for by the Committee to Elect Sally Hart Petersen to Mayor&#34;, but that header omits the expected address of the committee. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sabra Briere: A search for &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for Mayor&#34; generates two pages. The http://sabrabriereformayor.org/ web page has &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for City Council&#34; at the bottom, in white type on a yellow background making it virtually unreadable; it also has bunches of Latin text where the real text should be, making me suspicious that it&#39;s not real. On Facebook, the page &#34;Vote for Sabra for Ann Arbor Mayor in the Democratic Primary on Tuesday August 5th 2014&#34; has invited 500 people, but has no &#34;Paid for by&#34; disclosure. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Sabra Briere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clearly, sabrabriereformayor.org is a non-working website.  A completely different set of pages should be up soon - but in the meantime, I changed the accent yellow to an accent blue - so the white lettering is now higher contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t at all ready to be published, and is just there as filler for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Taylor: A search for &#34;Paid for by Christopher Taylor for Mayor&#34; has 49 results, from the candidate&#39;s own web site and from &#34;ngpvanhost&#34;. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ngpvan.com/&#34;&gt;NGP VAN&lt;/a&gt; is a campaign website hosting platform for Democrats.) The &#34;Christopher Taylor for Ann Arbor&#34; Facebook page has 686 likes, with no &#34;Paid for by&#34; until you get to the &#34;Contribute&#34; page. Facebook ads for Taylor say &#34;Sponsored&#34;, but do not disclose who is paying for them in either the text of the ad or in the image associated with the ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Christopher Taylor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My understanding is that we included the proper disclosure language in the initial ad, but that for some reason it is not appearing. We&#39;re on it and will fix it pronto.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I appreciate the notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any of these clearcut campaign violations? Probably not. The relevant text of the law is &#34;Any other medium used for campaign purposes shall clearly and unequivocally include the identification or disclaimer, or both, provided in section 47 of the act.&#34; Michigan campaign finance law has not been updated to provide specific rules for Facebook (or Twitter), so you can&#39;t point to a specific line of text that says &#34;you did this wrong&#34;. Without specific guidance, there&#39;s wiggle room, and a wait for an opinion from the Attorney General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this &#34;flyspecking&#34;, as one candidate described my efforts, or mere &#34;piffle&#34; as another political operative chided me? It&#39;s still early in the race, but expectations are that this will be one of the most expensive political races in Ann Arbor mayoral history, with four primary campaigns going and an empty mayoral seat at stake. I fully expect my Facebook timeline and Google search results to be full of paid advertising, and that that advertising will get more and more political as the primary draws near. Close attention to who is paying how much for what is worthwhile, especially in the presence of &#34;free media&#34; like Facebook where you can sent out an unrelenting stream of updates and invites at no obvious direct cost to anyone except the poor reader who just wants to see funny cat videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;a2parking&#34; app provides Android users with access to real time information about Ann Arbor parking structures</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2parking-app-provides-android-users-with-access-to-real-time-information-about-ann-arbor-parking-st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2parking-app-provides-android-users-with-access-to-real-time-information-about-ann-arbor-parking-st/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcdbe762970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcdbe762970b img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;A2parking-icon&#34; title=&#34;A2parking-icon&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcdbe762970b-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#34;a2 parking&#34; is an Android application that provides real time updates of available parking spaces in Ann Arbor parking structures. It is based on data published on the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority web site, and in addition to showing spaces free in structures it has one-touch access to directions to your favorite lot or structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download from Google Play: &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.douglasperlin.a2parking&#34;&gt;a2 parking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a long time coming; an &lt;a href=&#34;http://homelessdave.com/tt20080411stephensmith.htm&#34;&gt;interview with Steve Smith of Republic Parking&lt;/a&gt; in 2008 described the basic outlines of this data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 urban berry foraging report part 1: Juneberries in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-17-2008-urban-berr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 22:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-17-2008-urban-berr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year around this time (June 17) the juneberry trees in the streets of Ann Arbor are ripe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juneberries - variously shadbush, shadberry, or serviceberry, depending on where you&#39;re from - are iron ore pellet sized, dark purple when ripe, slightly sweet with soft seeds inside that are vaguely almondy.  They are not delicious, not in the sense that strawberries are delicious, but they are good to grab a handful of and snack on as you&#39;re walking down the street.   If you have lots and lots of these berries (also called saskatoons), you can make a pie out of them - make a two crust pie, with a filling of 3.5 cups juneberries to 3/4 cup of sugar and 2 Tbs of flour.    Here&#39;s a video from &lt;a href=&#34;http://wildfoodplants.com/article/113/aunt-marilyns-juneberry-pie&#34;&gt;Wild Food Plants&lt;/a&gt; about Aunt Marilyn&#39;s Juneberry Pie.  You can also dry them and use them like dried blueberries - if you get any of them home, or you can pound them with buffalo meat (from your favorite local supplier of buffalo meat) and make pemmican.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src=&#39;http://www.brightcove.tv/playerswf&#39; bgcolor=&#39;#FFFFFF&#39; flashVars=&#39;allowFullScreen=true&amp;initVideoId=1113939678&amp;servicesURL=http://www.brightcove.tv&amp;viewerSecureGatewayURL=https://www.brightcove.tv&amp;cdnURL=http://admin.brightcove.com&amp;autoStart=false&#39; base=&#39;http://admin.brightcove.com&#39; name=&#39;bcPlayer&#39; width=&#39;486&#39; height=&#39;412&#39; allowFullScreen=&#39;true&#39; allowScriptAccess=&#39;always&#39; seamlesstabbing=&#39;false&#39; type=&#39;application/x-shockwave-flash&#39; swLiveConnect=&#39;true&#39; pluginspage=&#39;http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&#39;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, if you have surplus juneberries *and* surplus grasshoppers, and a taste for them both, there&#39;s a traditional Utah Indian recipe for &#34;grasshopper fruitcake&#34;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Edwin Bryant15 (circa 1848) provided one of the few assessments of grasshopper palatability by a white. following an encounter with Utah Indians, an occasion when three women appeared, &#34;bringing baskets containing a substance, which, upon examination, we ascertained to be service-berries, crushed to a jam and mixed with pulverized grasshoppers. This composition being dried in the sun until it becomes hard, is what may be called the &#39;fruitcake&#39; of these poor children of the desert. No doubt these women regarded it as one of the most acceptable offerings they could make to us. We purchased all they brought with them, paying them in darning needles and other small articles, with which they were much pleased. The prejudice against the grasshopper &#39;fruitcake&#39; was strong at first, but it soon wore off, and none of the delicacy was thrown away or lost .... After being killed, they [the grasshoppers] are baked before the fire or dried in the sun, and then pulverized between smooth stones. Prejudice aside, I have tasted what are called delicacies, less agree able to the palate.&#34; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hollowtop.com/finl_html/amerindians.htm&#34;&gt;The Food Insects Newsletter: Some Insect Foods of the American Indians: And How the Early Whites Reacted to Them November 1994. Volume 7, Issue #3.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret to juneberry picking in Ann Arbor is to know that you can have a big pile of delicious berries simply by walking across town in such a way that you hit a series of trees in order, no need to backtrack.  Here&#39;s the juneberry tour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Zingerman&#39;s&#34;&gt;Zingerman&#39;s Deli&lt;/a&gt; on Detroit St.  If you can&#39;t find it, ask a native, they&#39;ll be glad to direct you there, they&#39;re used to it.  The juneberry trees are around the side on Kingsley St.  Stop inside, ask if they have any &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zingermans.com/Search.aspx?kw=juneberry&#34;&gt;juneberry jam&lt;/a&gt; for sale, furrow your brow disappointedly if they don&#39;t, taste something else thoughfully, then head out the front and pick more from a tree on Detroit St.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep heading up Detroit St and cross over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Farmers_Market&#34;&gt;Farmer&#39;s Market&lt;/a&gt;, open Weds. and Sat.  Look around the stalls, ask the farmers nicely if their juneberry crop is good this year, furrow your brow when they say they won&#39;t have any at market, admire the solar panels, pick up from spinach from Shannon, and then walk towards the Ann Arbor Observer on Catherine St.  You&#39;ll find more berries on the side of that building, they are a bit shaded so they ripen later.  Pick a small box full, head back to market, put a price tag on it, sell it - PROFIT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross back toward Fifth Avenue, head over Huron St and towards the Bank of Ann Arbor.  With your newfound gains make a deposit, but only after you do your harvest from the trees in front of the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep heading south on Fifth heading towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt;, but stop before you get there at the Library Lot parking lot and admire the prolific trees there.  Consider whether the &lt;A href=&#34;http://arborupdate.com/article/1660/downtown-library-project-discussion&#34;&gt;downtown library project&lt;/a&gt; plans for that surface lot which call for a structure to be built on that lot preserve the fruiting trees which are so characteristic of historical Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head into the library, and start figuring out what you are going to do to preserve those berries for the winter.  Check the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/sopac/tag/juneberry&#34;&gt;juneberry&lt;/a&gt; tag in the catalog; if you don&#39;t find anything, go to the MEL inter-library loan, &lt;a href=&#34;http://elibrary.mel.org/search/X?%28juneberry%29&amp;Da=&amp;Db=&amp;SORT=D&amp;backlink=http://www.aadl.org/cat/seek/search/X?(juneberry)&amp;Da=&amp;Db=&amp;SORT=D&amp;topformsub=1&#34;&gt;search for Juneberry&lt;/a&gt;, and end up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Juneberry-tree-French-writers-Canada/dp/0887721583/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1213754418&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Jacque Ferron&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; &#34;The Juneberry Tree&#34;.  Sit and eat your berries until it arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 ann arbor farmers market peaches are in - apricots too</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-2009-ann-arbor-farmers-market-peaches-are-in-apricots-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 10:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-2009-ann-arbor-farmers-market-peaches-are-in-apricots-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A quick post on my way from the Ann Arbor Farmers Market to work at AnnArbor.com. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s art fair today, so there will be a zillion people on Liberty Street; the food coop is pretty quiet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The notable new item at farmer&amp;#39;s market today was peaches. &amp;#0160;Two vendors, Erie Orchards and Kapnick Orchards, both had peaches for sale - Kapnick had the Flaming Fury variety, and Erie had Garnet Beauty. &amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s what the net has to say about both of these:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flaminfury.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Flamin&amp;#39; Fury&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; is a line of patented fruit varieties (23 different sorts of peaches) which includes cultivars ranging from &lt;a href=&#34;http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-bool.html&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;co1=AND&amp;amp;d=PTXT&amp;amp;s1=PP09129&amp;amp;OS=PP09129&amp;amp;RS=PP09129&#34;&gt;PF 1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;which matures very early to &lt;a href=&#34;http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-bool.html&amp;amp;r=1&amp;amp;f=G&amp;amp;l=50&amp;amp;co1=AND&amp;amp;d=PTXT&amp;amp;s1=PP19639.PN.&amp;amp;OS=PN/PP19639&amp;amp;RS=PN/PP19639&#34;&gt;PF Big George&lt;/a&gt; which matures very late. &amp;#0160;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://flaminfury.com/?a=PG:412&#34;&gt;list of varieties&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;shows the whole range - most are clingstone or semiclingstone, especially the earlier ones.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Garnet Beauty is a bud mutation of the Red Haven peaches and was discovered in Garnet Bruner&amp;#39;s orchard in Ontario. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s listed as a semiclingstone.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;There were apricots at market too - yum.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: arial; font-size: 13px; line-height: normal; &#34;&gt;A bud mutation of Red Haven, this cultivar was selected in the&amp;#0160;&lt;em style=&#34;font-weight: bold; font-style: normal; &#34;&gt;Garnet Bruner Orchard&lt;/em&gt;, of Ontario, Canada&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Water Hill Music Fest, Sunday, May 1, 2-6pm in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-water-hill-music-fest-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-water-hill-music-fest-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://waterhill.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;WaterHill.ORG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://30.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_li6wbvXeH51qi545eo1_500.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image from 30.media.tumblr.com&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e378041a970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e378041a970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;image from 30.media.tumblr.com&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti used to live on Fountain Street on Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Water Hill, which is also sometimes known as the Mack School neighborhood.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>410 Miller still stands</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is 410 Miller still standing, after the Building Board of Appeals issued an order for it to be demolished? In part, because the Notice and Order to demolish was never sent. From FOIA 15-210:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.11.33 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.11.33 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further it is stated that the hearing at which the decision to demolish was made was recorded, yet a transcription of the hearing was not made available on account of the audio being illegible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.25.40 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.25.40 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my FOIA I neglected to ask for this transcription, not knowing that it might exist. I&#39;ve filed a subsequent FOIA to figure out more, and plan to be at today&#39;s Building Board of Appeals meeting to share these findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7th annual Lower Burns Park Block Party, Sunday September 28, 2014, 2p-6p on Rose between Golden and E Park Place</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-7th-annual-lower-burns-park-block-party-sunday-september-28-2014-2p-6p-on-rose-between-golden-and-e-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 22:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-7th-annual-lower-burns-park-block-party-sunday-september-28-2014-2p-6p-on-rose-between-golden-and-e-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7392970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7392970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 402px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-07 at 9.56.36 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-07 at 9.56.36 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7392970b-450wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What: 7th annual &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Lower_Burns_Park&#34;&gt;Lower Burns Park&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/ann-arbor/LoBuPa_Block_Party&#34;&gt;Block Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Sunday, September 28th 2014 2 pm - 6 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Rain Date: Sunday, October 5th, 2014)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where: Rose Ave. between Golden Ave. and East Park Place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who: You, if you live in Lower Burns Park (E Stadium / State St / Packard / Dewey) or are near enough to appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why: Who doesn&#39;t like a block party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a bounce house there; please chip in a dollar to help out with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7481970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7481970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Lobupa party notice 2014&#34; title=&#34;Lobupa party notice 2014&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c6db7481970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A design for an an Ann Arbor events channel, @a2events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a design for a low overhead way to post about events coming up in Ann Arbor. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2events&#34;&gt;@a2events on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you want to play along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule of business is that every event has to have a URL, and the more simple and direct the URL is the more likely it is that it&#39;s authoritative for the event. If an event doesn&#39;t have a URL yet, I&#39;ll blog about it here if I need to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second rule of business is that I&#39;m not keeping a calendar, just a feed, and the feed is not going to be a 100% comprehensive feed; you have to be prepared to get events info from multiple sources and I&#39;m just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third rule of business of course is that if you want to pay for this service we&#39;ll find a way to let you pay, though the specifics are TBD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic idea for technology is to use a tag on my Pinboard account to feed a specific tag, and to use that tag to feed IFTTT to feed Twitter so that events get pushed out. I&#39;ll probably also use a Node-RED page to help construct something that does the right thing, and there will be a Slack channel on the a2b3 slack to do - something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Brian Kerr for having the foresight to reserve the name a2events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of Ridescout for Ann Arbor multi-modal transit use</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 16:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RideScout is an app that provides info about a whole range of
transit options, including taxi, car share, bus, parking, and
more. They have support for Ann Arbor as a city, so I tried it
while riding AAATA (The Ride).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ridescoutapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.ridescoutapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the first independent app that I&#39;ve seen that shows where
every AAATA stop is, in a nice little app that works on your phone
with a zippy little map that scrolls nicely. That&#39;s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RideScout has bus arrival and departure information for schedules,
but it doesn&#39;t have real-time bus location info. So it thought that
I had made it to N Campus when really I was still waiting on the bus at
BTC. It could also have real-time parking info in Ann Arbor from
the Ann Arbor DDA, but it also doesn&#39;t. I didn&#39;t see the Arborbike
system in there either though that&#39;s pretty new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company behind RideScout has been bought by Car2Go, a car-sharing
service. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xconomy.com/texas/2014/09/03/austins-ridescout-bought-by-daimler-car-rental-service-car2go/&#34;&gt;Xconomy&lt;/a&gt; has the story. Since Car2Go doesn&#39;t
have operations in Ann Arbor, I don&#39;t know what to expect of their
continued development here, but I like the idea!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AATA Local Advisory Committee meeting, unofficial notes, 2/10/2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 14:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;Ann Arbor Transportation Authority&lt;br /&gt;Local Advisory Committee&lt;br /&gt;Feb 10, 2009&lt;br /&gt;unofficial notes&lt;br /&gt;Edward Vielmetti&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is my notes from the LAC meeting of 2/10/09,&lt;br /&gt;edited slightly but not intended as a faithful&lt;br /&gt;transcript of the meeting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I came in 10 minutes late; the meeting starts at&lt;br /&gt;10:00am, and the AATA #6 from downtown gets there&lt;br /&gt;at 10:01am. The meeting ends at 12:00 noon; the &lt;br /&gt;inbound #6 arrives at 11:58am.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The board discussed Tom Partridge&amp;#39;s comments and reporting on same&lt;br /&gt;in the minutes to the previous meeting.&lt;br /&gt;He was apparently somewhat disruptive in the meeting,&lt;br /&gt;and the meeting minutes attempt to reflect that. Some&lt;br /&gt;discussion among the (relatively unprepared) board &lt;br /&gt;on how to prepare an accurate reporting of this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;a lot of disorganization going on in the meeting&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;apparently tom created a lot of interruptions. he&lt;br /&gt;derailed the agenda. (was that his agenda).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a recording device at the table; is that&lt;br /&gt;going to be shared? I don&amp;#39;t know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No one has name tags or table tents showing their names.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;chris white&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;AOS calculates schedule adherence for each service at each&lt;br /&gt;bus stop. &amp;quot;from our point of view we publish a time point&lt;br /&gt;the driver can&amp;#39;t leave before that time&amp;quot;. 57 after the hour.&lt;br /&gt;can&amp;#39;t leave before 57. intermediate times keep track of it.&lt;br /&gt;trying to publish that information, in a different way,&lt;br /&gt;not guarantee . keyed to places where bus can sit. &amp;quot;not&lt;br /&gt;beyond the realm of possibility&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;real time information move to do it on cell phones. attraction&lt;br /&gt;of cell phones is to call up anywhere you want and find&lt;br /&gt;the schedule adherence of the next bus. do it in office,&lt;br /&gt;on way to office, on bus stop. difficulty of maintaining&lt;br /&gt;information at bus stops, struggling with. easier to put it&lt;br /&gt;up than it is to maintain it. schedule cases difficult to&lt;br /&gt;maintain. a few real time signs at stops, issue of getting&lt;br /&gt;power to them. solar power next thing. from our point of view&lt;br /&gt;the best option is cell phones. last survey: most riders did&lt;br /&gt;have them. limited income, almost all cell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;text &amp;#39;AATABUS 6&amp;#39; to 41411&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;detail discussion of time adherence at all stops. leave a little&lt;br /&gt;early if traffic is clear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;services with cognitive impariments, difficult time riding the bus.&lt;br /&gt;difficultiy accessing information.&lt;br /&gt;do have support systems, talk to, &lt;br /&gt;call taker on the phone, schedule in person, general training.&lt;br /&gt;one on one travel training, general mobility education.&lt;br /&gt;work with individuals with disabilities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;don&amp;#39;t even use the book, it&amp;#39;s too confusing.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;too hard to train on a timetable.&lt;br /&gt;best way tot do it is based on locatoin time to be there.&lt;br /&gt;individual schedule, prepare it for them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;alternate formats, audio cd for indivduals.&lt;br /&gt;schedule is read in audio format.&lt;br /&gt;on request.&lt;br /&gt;large print format.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;important that need to be worked on.&lt;br /&gt;meeting needs of those indivdiuals.&lt;br /&gt;systemic basis, right down to the individual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I told the story of going from mary markley to burns park elementary,&lt;br /&gt;and how my son in 3d grade was asked to help prepare&lt;br /&gt;a route for someone visiting the school. It might be&lt;br /&gt;hard if you try to mix University and AATA routes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;problem of getting buses to CIL in the middle of Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;Research Park. Nothing from the city side. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CIL, Social Security moved to research park drive just off&lt;br /&gt;of ellsworth road. No sidewalks on S side of Ellsworth,&lt;br /&gt;N side no curb and gutter. Very busy, difficult for bus &lt;br /&gt;stops, hard to cross. Cross busy road, stand on shoulder.&lt;br /&gt;city looking at a signal. S side in Pittsfield Twp no &lt;br /&gt;sidewalks until development. A lot of time to cross&lt;br /&gt;Ellsworth +5 at the corner. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stimulus package: $200k for bus stops. Added money for&lt;br /&gt;urban transit systems, amount up in the air, somewhere&lt;br /&gt;between $6 and $8 million, must be spent in 1.5 yrs.&lt;br /&gt;Short term: lead walks, benches; sidewalk design work;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Design of park and ride lot at Plymouth Road and US-23,&lt;br /&gt;in the interchange at SW quadrant. 300 spaces. P&amp;amp;R&lt;br /&gt;plan, 1st thing to do. Intercept traffic before it&lt;br /&gt;gets into the more crowded part of Ann Arbor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Internet service is back up and running. Email lost when&lt;br /&gt;provider had &amp;quot;financial difficulties&amp;quot;. Now working as&lt;br /&gt;a part of the city&amp;#39;s email and internet with the county&lt;br /&gt;as well. So far 2 weeks, things working real well. Ridetrak&lt;br /&gt;lost at the worst time possible, bad weather, snow and&lt;br /&gt;the cold. Really a terrible time, couldn&amp;#39;t have been&lt;br /&gt;worse.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Public participation at board committee meetings, PMER,&lt;br /&gt;Planning and Development, Governance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1. &amp;quot;Should not be open to the public&amp;quot;. Board did not&lt;br /&gt;adopt that as the policy. Communicate those comments&lt;br /&gt;to the board. Comment in writing? Committees new, trying&lt;br /&gt;to reorganize how the work is done. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Proposal for fare changes. Two phone calls in past three weeks,&lt;br /&gt;both not in support of the fare change proposal; affects&lt;br /&gt;the people who need the service the most. Make trips less&lt;br /&gt;frequently, take less and save up money.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Haven&amp;#39;t had any other calls. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;people&amp;#39;s express is running now&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;northfield&lt;br /&gt;salem&lt;br /&gt;superior&lt;br /&gt;ypsilanti&lt;br /&gt;pittsfield&lt;br /&gt;augusta&lt;br /&gt;york&lt;br /&gt;lodi&lt;br /&gt;bridgewater&lt;br /&gt;scio (parts of; cdbg funds; $1/ride to go anywhere)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;anyone can get. all senior centers at least once a year.&lt;br /&gt;information on aata web site? not getting the word out.&lt;br /&gt;washtenaw county commissioners, some meetings are televised.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;other places to meet?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;can aata provide added access to the meeting?&lt;br /&gt;podcast, recording, other access.&lt;br /&gt;community television network across the street.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;what would be possible?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;would podcasting be viewed by more people?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;#39;t want to spend money, just access &lt;br /&gt;for what people?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;can you take the recording? whose recording?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;end of notes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AATA proposes fare hikes; mobile ridetrack still down, 6 weeks after going offline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-aata-proposes-fare-hikes-mobile-ridetrack-still-down-6-weeks-after-going-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 15:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-aata-proposes-fare-hikes-mobile-ridetrack-still-down-6-weeks-after-going-offline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 144pt; text-indent: -144pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 16pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34; size=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Bus data is not available at this time.
This does not necessarily indicate that buses are not running. Please
check your schedule for times.&amp;quot;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 144pt; text-indent: -144pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 144pt; text-indent: -144pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span size=&#34;2;&#34; style=&#34;font-family: Arial&#34;&gt;Mobile Ridetrack is still down, six weeks after going offline.&amp;#0160; I suggest that you contact the AATA to get a current piece of information from them about restoration of service.&amp;#0160; I have no idea what to expect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 144pt; text-indent: -144pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 16pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 144pt; text-indent: -144pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 16pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;PRESS RELEASE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 16pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;For immediate release&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;Fare proposal attached&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;January 19, 2008&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; margin: 0pt; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; Transportation Authority&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; margin: 0pt; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;2700 South Industrial Hwy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48104&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; margin: 0pt; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;734.973.6500; 734.973.6338F; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theride.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.theride.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; margin: 0pt; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;Mary K. Stasiak, Mgr. Community Relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; margin: 0pt; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;734.677.3901; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mstasiak@TheRide.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mstasiak@TheRide.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: 150%; text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11pt; line-height: 150%; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 20pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;AATA proposes changes to fare structure &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 16pt; font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ANN ARBOR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, MI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
– The Ann Arbor Transportation Authority (AATA) is seeking public input
on proposed changes to its fare structure for fixed-route and
paratransit services at a series of public meetings to be held in
February.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;According
to AATA Board Chair David Nacht, the adult full fare for AATA
fixed-route service has not changed since August, 2002. Since that
time, AATA has experienced significant increases in the cost of
operations, as well as the tightening of available funding. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;“AATA
has cut costs for aspects of our operations under our control, as well
as generating revenue through the sale of advertising space on our
buses,” Nacht said.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;AATA
reduced its 2009 fixed-route operating costs by $5 per service hour
through a variety of cost-saving measures. A review of comparable
transit systems revealed that AATA had the lowest fares among its peers.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;In
addition, AATA has implemented continuous improvement teams to further
control and reduce energy use, facility and vehicle maintenance,
employee benefits and expenses related to its paratransit services.
Approximately $300,000 in savings has been identified by the teams
through projects which are expected to be implemented in the current
fiscal year.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;“The
board is reluctant to raise fares, and actually rejected a fare
increase proposal in 2006. Now we find that we must balance the impact
on our riders with our need to run the authority in a financially
prudent manner.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;AATA
has reached the point where we must consider revisions to our fare
structure in order to assure that we are successful in meeting the
growing demand for our services during this time of economic challenge,
and also to ensure the future financial health of the authority,” Nacht
said.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;AATA’s
proposal includes a two-phase increase to change the current
fixed-route adult full fare of $1.00 to $1.25 in May, 2009 and to $1.50
in May, 2010. Current half-fare charges would go from 50 cents to 60
and 75 cents, respectively. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The
proposal would eliminate the 25-cent fare on fixed-route service for
Seniors and A-Ride customers; however, the fares on paratransit service
would increase from $2.00 for an advance reservation trip to $2.50 in
2009 and $3.00 in 2010. Same-day trip fares would increase from $3.00
to $3.50 and $4.00, respectively.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;Night Ride and Holiday Ride fares would remain at $5.00, with the fare for Senior and A-Ride cardholders remaining at $2.50.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;In
addition to 30-day passes, shorter-term passes are being considered at
both regular and reduced-fare levels. These may include passes for a
smaller number of days, or a specific number of trips.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The full draft proposal is available on the AATA web site, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.TheRide.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.TheRide.org&lt;/a&gt;,
and by request at 734.973.6500. The proposal will also be available
beginning January 24, 2009 in the February, 2009 issue of “RideLines”
on all AATA buses and at the AATA main office and transit centers.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The
proposed fare structure is expected to generate an estimated $314,000
in additional revenue in the first year and $540,000 in the second
year. It will also create opportunities for frequent riders who qualify
to take advantage of discounted passes.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;Comments
and questions about the proposed fare changes are being received by
AATA through February 27, 2009 by the following methods:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt; font-family: Wingdings;&#34;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; Call the AATA Service Change Hotline at 734.677.3934.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt; font-family: Wingdings;&#34;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; E-mail AATA at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:aatainfo@theride.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;aatainfo@theride.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;; put “Fare Changes” in the subject line.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt; font-family: Wingdings;&#34;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; Fax AATA at 734.973.6338; address the fax to “Fare Changes”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt; font-family: Wingdings;&#34;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; Write to “Fare Changes”, AATA, 2700 S. Industrial Hwy., Ann Arbor, MI 48104.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt; font-family: Wingdings;&#34;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt; Attend one of the following public meetings:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 8pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;Ann Arbor District Library, Multipurpose Room, 343 S. Fifth, Ann Arbor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 36pt; text-indent: 36pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;Tuesday, February 10, 2009; 1-3 p.m.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 36pt; text-indent: 36pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;Tuesday February 17, 2009; 6-8 p.m.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 36pt; text-indent: 36pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 8pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;City of Ypsilanti Council Chambers, One S. Huron St., Ypsilanti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 36pt; text-indent: 36pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;Thursday, February 19, 2009; 4-7 p.m.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 36pt; text-indent: 36pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;Thursday, February 26, 2009; 1-3 p.m.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;Upon request, additional meetings at the requesters’ locations will be added.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;At each
public meeting, people will have an opportunity to discuss the change
individually with AATA staff members. Each meeting will also include a
presentation on the proposed fare changes and the opportunity to ask
questions or make comments in a group setting.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The
facilities are accessible. Reasonable accommodation to permit persons
with disabilities to participate will be made if requested at least two
days in advance at 734.973.6500. Two weeks notice is required for
interpreter service for persons with hearing impairments.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;A copy
of all written comments and a summary of verbal comments will be
provided to the AATA Board of Directors before a decision is made on
adopting any of the proposed changes.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About sidewalks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To the Editor: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question has been asked your correspondent by several citizens: Can the city legally compel the owners or occupants of property in this city to construct, at their own expense, sidewalks in front of their premises? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city certainly claims ownership of the street from fence to fence, and exercises absolute control thereof. Even if a man desires to plant shade trees on the street in front of his property, the city prescribes the exact distance at which they shall be placed from the property owner&#39;s street line; and notwithstanding the fact that the property owner pays for the trees himself and also for the planting and subsequent care of them until their growth is assured, yet he is denied by the city any ownership in them, and is forbidden to remove or even to trim them, should he at any time desire to do so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these people wish to know, then, is, if the city owns the streets and their shade trees and side walks, why the city should not itself build the sidewalks, do all grading and plant all shade trees? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that when a man builds his sidewalk it immediately becomes city property, and he has no more ownership of it than any other citizen. In fact, in a single day hundreds will use it when he uses it once. In short, it is built not for him, but for the public. Then why should not the public pay for it? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building of sidewalks under the existing ordinance is a heavy burden upon very many citizens, some of whom have been compelled by their circumstances to borrow the money at interest to enable them to comply with the order of the council. This seems to your correspondent to be a matter worthy of deliberate consideration by the city fathers. The claim of these people is that the city, owning the streets, should itself put down all sidewalks, and spread the expense upon he general tax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may do no good to open up this question at this time; but the voice of the people should at least be heard in the matter, and this communication certainly expresses it in some degree. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SUMMIT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/node/103463&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Argus, August 28, 1891&lt;/a&gt;, via the Old News archive at the Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affinia Group to move headquarters from Ann Arbor, MI to Gastonia, NC; 50 jobs at stake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.charlotteobserver.com/2013/10/15/4390165/ann-arbor-mich-company-to-relocate.html&#34;&gt;Charlotte Observer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Affinia Group Inc., a firm that designs, manufactures, distributes and markets industrial grade products and services, will relocate its Ann Arbor, Mich., headquarters to Gastonia, home of its Global Filtration group.
  The transition to the new corporate headquarters will occur in phases during 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia gives a little background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Affinia Group, a motor industry company, was formed in 2004 and specializes in the design, manufacture and replacement of parts for and on and off-road vehicles. Specifically filtration and chassis components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gastongazette.com/spotlight/affinia-group-moving-headquarters-to-gastonia-1.218940&#34;&gt;Gaston Gazette&lt;/a&gt; has additional details -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Affinia has approximately 50 jobs at its current headquarters, but that doesn’t mean all those jobs will relocate here. “We’re still putting together the transition plan,” said Keith Wilson, president of WIX Global Filtration. “It’s more of a consolidation than it is a big addition of people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bizjournals.com/charlotte/blog/outside_the_loop/2013/10/affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-to.html&#34;&gt;Charlotte Business Journal&lt;/a&gt; points to a new CFO at Affinia as an impetus for the move:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It all started in December, when Affinia spun off its brakes unit that makes Raybestos brand of automobile brakes. That unit, called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/brake-parts-inc-is-back-199857601.html&#34;&gt;Brake Parts Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, was sold to members of Affinia’s brakes unit management team. The price of the deal for Brake Parts, which contributed one-third of Affinia’s sales in 2011, wasn’t disclosed. Then on Monday, Affinia announced it had hired a Charlotte executive, Steve Klueg, as its new chief financial officer. Klueg, CFO at ReCommunity Recycling in Charlotte, will stay in the Charlotte area after he replaces Thomas Madden at Affinia, Howat says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Madden, the former Affinia CFO, is retiring, notes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aftermarketnews.com/Item/119412/affinia_group_cfo_tom_madden_announces_retirement.aspx&#34;&gt;Aftermarket News&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;Tom Madden has almost 40 years of financial leadership to our company, and his guidance has been an immeasurable ingredient in helping us achieve our status as a worldwide leader,&#34; said Terry McCormack, president and CEO of Affinia Group. &#34;In a continuing demonstration of the commitment he has shown throughout his career, Tom will work side by side with our incoming CFO Steve Klueg to seamlessly transfer financial leadership over the coming months.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affinia&#39;s Ann Arbor headquarters is located at 1101 Technology Drive, Ann Arbor, MI 48108.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Hands Active open house, September 19, 2014, 7:00 p.m - 10:00 p.m., 525 E Liberty St Ann Arbor MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 22:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Post the poster! &lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Openhouse-20140919-e1410474571147&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Openhouse-20140919-e1410474571147&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amelanchier (Shadbush, Juneberry, Sugar Plum) inventory for Ann Arbor, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-amelanchier-shadbush-juneberry-sugar-plum-inventory-for-ann-arbor-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-amelanchier-shadbush-juneberry-sugar-plum-inventory-for-ann-arbor-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a complete list of where all of the Amelanchier (juneberry, shadbush, sugar plum depending on where you are from) trees are on the public streets in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; The complete inventory shows 356 trees, each geocoded; rather than try to pin them on a map, this is by street name in alphabetical order, with quite a bit of duplicates eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole program to do this is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grep -i Amelanchier trees09.csv | awk -F, &amp;#39;{ print $3, &amp;quot;between&amp;quot;, $4, &amp;quot;and &amp;quot; $5}&amp;#39; | sort | uniq &amp;gt; juneberry.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where the trees09.csv file is downloadable from the Ann Arbor Chronicle who originally sourced this data from the city of Ann Arbor; &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2009/07/01/city-and-residents-to-make-tree-policy/&#34;&gt;see their story about it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas this post is a little bit too late for this season; by July 2, 2009, many of the juneberry trees are completely ripe, so get picking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABBOTT AVE between MONTGOMERY AVE and S REVENA BLVD&lt;br /&gt;ALLMENDINGER PARK between ALLMENDINGER PARK and ALLMENDINGER PARK&lt;br /&gt;ANTIETAM DR between CUL DE SAC and LEXINGTON DR&lt;br /&gt;ANTIETAM DR between LEXINGTON DR and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;ARBANA DR between W HURON ST and MARK HANNAH PL&lt;br /&gt;ARBOR OAKS PARK between ARBOR OAKS PARK and ARBOR OAKS PARK&lt;br /&gt;ARBORDALE ST between W STADIUM BLVD and EVELYN CT&lt;br /&gt;ARDMOOR AVE between CUL DE SAC and MARTHA AVE&lt;br /&gt;ARDMOOR AVE between MARTHA AVE and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;ASCOT RD between CHAUCER DR and CHAUCER DR&lt;br /&gt;BADER PARK between BADER PARK and BADER PARK&lt;br /&gt;BANDEMER PARK between BANDEMER PARK and BANDEMER PARK&lt;br /&gt;BARDSTOWN TRL between LARCHMONT DR and MIDDLETON DR&lt;br /&gt;BIRD RD between NEWPORT CREEK DR and W HURON RIVER DR&lt;br /&gt;BIRK AVE between PAULINE BLVD and SNYDER AVE&lt;br /&gt;BLAIN CT between CUL DE SAC and SHADOWOOD DR&lt;br /&gt;BRANDYWINE DR between GALLWAY CT and PACKARD RD&lt;br /&gt;BRIAN CT between CUL DE SAC and MEADOWSIDE DR&lt;br /&gt;BRIARCLIFF ST between PRAIRIE ST and AURORA ST&lt;br /&gt;BROOKS ST between MIXTWOOD RD and MILLER AVE&lt;br /&gt;BROOKSIDE PARK between BROOKSIDE PARK and BROOKSIDE PARK&lt;br /&gt;BUHR PARK between BUHR PARK and BUHR PARK&lt;br /&gt;CAMBRIDGE RD between DAY ST and HILL ST&lt;br /&gt;CATHERINE ST between N FOURTH AVE and N FIFTH AVE&lt;br /&gt;CATHERINE ST between N INGALLS ST and GLEN AVE&lt;br /&gt;CHARLES ST between BROOKRIDGE RD and DANIEL ST&lt;br /&gt;CHAUCER DR between SCIO CHURCH RD and WEMBLEY CT&lt;br /&gt;CHERRY ST between SPRING ST and FOUNTAIN ST&lt;br /&gt;COLONY RD between ESSEX RD and PACKARD RD&lt;br /&gt;COLUMBIA AVE between KIMBERLEY RD and DEAD END&lt;br /&gt;CORONADA DR between LAS VEGAS DR and ALHAMBRA DR&lt;br /&gt;CRANBROOK PARK between CRANBROOK PARK and CRANBROOK PARK&lt;br /&gt;CREEKBEND CT between CUL DE SAC and MEADOWSIDE DR&lt;br /&gt;CRESTLAND DR between HALL AVE and CARHART AVE&lt;br /&gt;CUMBERLAND AVE between HAMPSHIRE RD and CANTERBURY RD&lt;br /&gt;DEVONSHIRE RD between ARLINGTON BLVD and AVON RD&lt;br /&gt;DHU VARREN RD between LESLIE PARK CIR and OMLESAAD DR&lt;br /&gt;DHU VARREN RD between PONTIAC TRL and LESLIE PARK CIR&lt;br /&gt;DONEGAL CT between BRANDYWINE DR and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;DOUGLAS PARK between DOUGLAS PARK and DOUGLAS PARK&lt;br /&gt;DUNDEE DR between DEAD END and MOREHEAD DR&lt;br /&gt;E ANN ST between N STATE ST and N DIVISION ST&lt;br /&gt;E KINGSLEY ST between DETROIT ST and N DIVISION ST&lt;br /&gt;E LIBERTY ST between S DIVISION ST and S FIFTH AVE&lt;br /&gt;EDDY ST between DEAD END and VERLE AVE&lt;br /&gt;ELI DR between YOST BLVD and LILLIAN RD&lt;br /&gt;ELLSWORTH PARK between ELLSWORTH PARK and ELLSWORTH PARK&lt;br /&gt;EMILY CT between CUL DE SAC and MEADOWSIDE DR&lt;br /&gt;ESCH AVE between PAGE AVE and PINE VALLEY BLVD&lt;br /&gt;FALCON CT between HICKORY POINT DR and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;FARMERS MARKET between FARMERS MARKET and FARMERS MARKET&lt;br /&gt;FERNDALE PL between HENRY ST and GARDNER AVE&lt;br /&gt;FIFTH ST between W DAVIS AVE and W MADISON ST&lt;br /&gt;FIFTH ST between W JEFFERSON ST and W LIBERTY ST&lt;br /&gt;FIFTH ST between W LIBERTY ST and W JEFFERSON ST&lt;br /&gt;FOUNTAIN ST between W SUMMIT ST and SUNSET RD&lt;br /&gt;FOURTH ST between W LIBERTY ST and W JEFFERSON ST&lt;br /&gt;FRANKLIN BLVD between SNYDER AVE and BIRK AVE&lt;br /&gt;FULLER PARK between FULLER PARK and FULLER PARK&lt;br /&gt;FULLER RD between CEDAR BEND DR and MAIDEN LN&lt;br /&gt;FURSTENBURG NATURE AREA between FURSTENBURG NATURE AREA and FURSTENBURG NATURE AREA&lt;br /&gt;GALLUP PARK between GALLUP PARK and GALLUP PARK&lt;br /&gt;GEDDES AVE between OSWEGO ST and ONONDAGA ST&lt;br /&gt;GEDDES AVE between S HURON PKWY and RIVERVIEW DR&lt;br /&gt;GEORGETOWN BLVD between YORKTOWN DR and YORKTOWN DR&lt;br /&gt;GLAZIER WAY between WOLVERHAMPTON LN and HURON PKWY&lt;br /&gt;GLENWOOD ST between DEXTER AVE and VALLEY DR&lt;br /&gt;GOTT ST between PEARL ST and W SUMMIT ST&lt;br /&gt;GOTT ST between W SUMMIT ST and HISCOCK ST&lt;br /&gt;GRACE ST between WESTWOOD AVE and ALICE ST&lt;br /&gt;GREEN RD between WATERSHED DR and FOX HUNT DR&lt;br /&gt;HAISLEY DR between N MAPLE RD and CARBECK DR&lt;br /&gt;HAZELWOOD AVE between CENTRAL AVE and SUNNYWOOD DR&lt;br /&gt;HEMLOCK DR between CHAMPAGNE DR and SHADOWOOD DR&lt;br /&gt;HEMLOCK DR between SHADOWOOD DR and PLAINVIEW CT&lt;br /&gt;HENRY ST between FERNDALE PL and WESTMINSTER PL&lt;br /&gt;HEWETT DR between REDEEMER AVE and RUSSETT RD&lt;br /&gt;HICKORY POINT DR between OTTER CREEK CT and BIRCHWOOD CT&lt;br /&gt;HILL ST between GREENE ST and S DIVISION ST&lt;br /&gt;HILLDALE DR between BREDE PL and DELAFIELD DR&lt;br /&gt;HOLYOKE LN between NEWPORT RD and LOWELL RD&lt;br /&gt;HUNTINGTON PL between ONAWAY PL and HUNTINGTON DR&lt;br /&gt;HURON HIGHLANDS PARK between HURON HIGHLANDS PARK and HURON HIGHLANDS PARK&lt;br /&gt;INDEPENDENCE BLVD between JAMES ST and VICTORIA AVE&lt;br /&gt;IROQUOIS PARK between IROQUOIS PARK and IROQUOIS PARK&lt;br /&gt;JONES DR between PLYMOUTH RD and BROADWAY ST&lt;br /&gt;KELLY PARK between KELLY PARK and KELLY PARK&lt;br /&gt;KEMPF HOUSE between KEMPF HOUSE and KEMPF HOUSE&lt;br /&gt;KIRTLAND DR between GLEN LEVEN RD and W STADIUM BLVD&lt;br /&gt;LAKEVIEW AVE between W LIBERTY RD and DEAD END&lt;br /&gt;LAWTON PARK between LAWTON PARK and LAWTON PARK&lt;br /&gt;LENNOX ST between CUL DE SAC and ARBORDALE ST&lt;br /&gt;LESLIE SCIENCE CENTER between LESLIE SCIENCE CENTER and LESLIE SCIENCE CENTER&lt;br /&gt;LIBERTY PLAZA between LIBERTY PLAZA and LIBERTY PLAZA&lt;br /&gt;LONG SHORE DR between AMHERST AVE and BARTON DR&lt;br /&gt;LORRAINE ST between FERNWOOD AVE and LA SALLE DR&lt;br /&gt;LOYOLA DR between CUL DE SAC and COLGATE CIR&lt;br /&gt;MARSHALL ST between SPRINGBROOK AVE and VERLE AVE&lt;br /&gt;MARY BETH DOYLE PARK between MARY BETH DOYLE PARK and MARY BETH DOYLE PARK&lt;br /&gt;MARYFIELD DR between PINE RIDGE ST and WESTWOOD AVE&lt;br /&gt;MARYFIELD WILDWOOD PARK between MARYFIELD WILDWOOD PARK and MARYFIELD WILDWOOD PARK&lt;br /&gt;MEADOWSIDE DR between WOODCREEK BLVD and WOODCREEK BLVD&lt;br /&gt;MEDFORD RD between MANCHESTER RD and ST FRANCIS DR&lt;br /&gt;MEDFORD RD between NEEDHAM RD and MANCHESTER RD&lt;br /&gt;MELROSE AVE between BELMONT RD and DEVONSHIRE RD&lt;br /&gt;MERSHON DR between DELAWARE DR and SCIO CHURCH RD&lt;br /&gt;MERSHON DR between HANOVER RD and SCIO CHURCH RD&lt;br /&gt;MERSHON DR between HARTFORD ST and HANOVER RD&lt;br /&gt;MERSHON DR between NORMANDY RD and GLEN LEVEN RD&lt;br /&gt;MERSHON DR between SCIO CHURCH RD and DELAWARE DR&lt;br /&gt;MILLER NATURE AREA between MILLER NATURE AREA and MILLER NATURE AREA&lt;br /&gt;MINER ST between W SUMMIT ST and ELMCREST DR&lt;br /&gt;MOREHEAD DR between NEWBURY CT and PICADILLY CIR&lt;br /&gt;MORTON AVE between WOODSIDE RD and HARDING RD&lt;br /&gt;MT PLEASANT AVE between SUNNYSIDE BLVD and W MADISON ST&lt;br /&gt;N FOURTH AVE between E ANN ST and CATHERINE ST&lt;br /&gt;N FOURTH AVE between E KINGSLEY ST and CATHERINE ST&lt;br /&gt;N MAPLE RD between PAMELA AVE and HOLLYWOOD DR&lt;br /&gt;N REVENA BLVD between LINWOOD AVE and HARBROOKE AVE&lt;br /&gt;NOTTINGHAM RD between MANCHESTER RD and INDEPENDENCE BLVD&lt;br /&gt;OLIVIA AVE between CAMBRIDGE RD and MINERVA RD&lt;br /&gt;OLSON PARK between OLSON PARK and OLSON PARK&lt;br /&gt;ORCHARD HILLS DR between CUL DE SAC and EVERGREEN PL&lt;br /&gt;PARKWOOD AVE between JEANNE ST and FERNWOOD AVE&lt;br /&gt;PEAR ST between APPLE ST and TRAVER ST&lt;br /&gt;PILGRIM PARK between PILGRIM PARK and PILGRIM PARK&lt;br /&gt;PLYMOUTH PARKWAY between PLYMOUTH PARKWAY and PLYMOUTH PARKWAY&lt;br /&gt;POMONA RD between RED OAK RD and LOYOLA DR&lt;br /&gt;REDEEMER AVE between HEWETT DR and RUSSELL RD&lt;br /&gt;REDEEMER AVE between RUSSELL RD and RUSSETT RD&lt;br /&gt;REDWOOD PARK between REDWOOD PARK and REDWOOD PARK&lt;br /&gt;RIVERSIDE PARK between RIVERSIDE PARK and RIVERSIDE PARK&lt;br /&gt;RUNNYMEDE BLVD between COVINGTON DR and SUE PKWY&lt;br /&gt;S ASHLEY ST between W WASHINGTON ST and W HURON ST&lt;br /&gt;S DIVISION ST between E WILLIAM ST and E LIBERTY ST&lt;br /&gt;S FOREST AVE between GRANGER AVE and WELLS ST&lt;br /&gt;S FOURTH AVE between E LIBERTY ST and E WASHINGTON ST&lt;br /&gt;S FOURTH AVE between E MADISON ST and PACKARD ST&lt;br /&gt;S FOURTH AVE between E WASHINGTON ST and E LIBERTY ST&lt;br /&gt;S FOURTH AVE between PACKARD ST and E MADISON ST&lt;br /&gt;S MAPLE RD between DICKEN DR and PAULINE BLVD&lt;br /&gt;SCIO CHURCH RD between GREENVIEW DR and S SEVENTH ST&lt;br /&gt;SECOND ST between W MOSLEY ST and W MADISON ST&lt;br /&gt;SENECA AVE between OSWEGO ST and ONONDAGA ST&lt;br /&gt;SEQUOIA PKWY between N MAPLE RD and PATRICIA AVE&lt;br /&gt;SEQUOIA PKWY between PATRICIA AVE and N MAPLE RD&lt;br /&gt;SHADFORD RD between FERDON RD and HARDING RD&lt;br /&gt;SHADFORD RD between PACKARD ST and BALDWIN AVE&lt;br /&gt;SHADFORD RD between WOODSIDE RD and HARDING RD&lt;br /&gt;SHADOWOOD DR between HEMLOCK DR and CHAMPAGNE DR&lt;br /&gt;SIXTH ST between W MADISON ST and W JEFFERSON ST&lt;br /&gt;SOUTHEAST AREA PARK between SOUTHEAST AREA PARK and SOUTHEAST AREA PARK&lt;br /&gt;SPRING HOLLOW CT between CUL DE SAC and FOXWAY DR&lt;br /&gt;SPRINGBROOK AVE between MARSHALL ST and SHARON DR&lt;br /&gt;SUGARBUSH PARK between SUGARBUSH PARK and SUGARBUSH PARK&lt;br /&gt;SYLVAN PARK between SYLVAN PARK and SYLVAN PARK&lt;br /&gt;TACOMA CIR between KING GEORGE BLVD and KING GEORGE BLVD&lt;br /&gt;THOMAS CT between SUSAN DR and THOMAS CT&lt;br /&gt;TREMONT PL between WALDENWOOD DR and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;TURNBERRY LN between MONUMENT DR and MONUMENT DR&lt;br /&gt;VERLE AVE between DEAD END and EDDY ST&lt;br /&gt;VERLE AVE between EDDY ST and PLATT RD&lt;br /&gt;VERLE AVE between MARSHALL ST and DEAD END&lt;br /&gt;VERLE AVE between MARSHALL ST and MARSHALL ST&lt;br /&gt;VERLE AVE between PLATT RD and MARSHALL ST&lt;br /&gt;VICTORIA AVE between RIDGE AVE and INDEPENDENCE BLVD&lt;br /&gt;VIRNANKAY CIR between PAULINE BLVD and PAULINE BLVD&lt;br /&gt;W DOBSON PL between CUL DE SAC and WOLVERHAMPTON LN&lt;br /&gt;W JEFFERSON ST between SIXTH ST and FIFTH ST&lt;br /&gt;W SUMMIT ST between GOTT ST and MINER ST&lt;br /&gt;W WASHINGTON ST between S MAIN ST and S ASHLEY ST&lt;br /&gt;WALDENWOOD DR between PENBERTON DR and TREMONT PL&lt;br /&gt;WESTOVER AVE between RHEA ST and PORTER AVE&lt;br /&gt;WHITE OAK DR between ENGLISH OAK DR and NEWPORT RD&lt;br /&gt;WOODCREEK BLVD between CHALMERS DR and MEADOWSIDE DR&lt;br /&gt;WOODCREEK BLVD between MEADOWSIDE DR and CHALMERS DR&lt;br /&gt;WOODDALE CT between CUL DE SAC and WOODCREEK BLVD&lt;br /&gt;WOODDALE CT between WOODCREEK BLVD and CUL DE SAC&lt;br /&gt;YELLOWSTONE DR between YELLOWSTONE DR and BLUETT DR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;fieldset class=&#34;zemanta-related&#34;&gt;&lt;legend class=&#34;zemanta-related-title&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/expect-the-2013-crop-of-juneberries-to-be-a-good-one-in-ann-arbor.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/noimg_57_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/expect-the-2013-crop-of-juneberries-to-be-a-good-one-in-ann-arbor.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Expect the 2013 crop of juneberries to be a good one in Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/167104764_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Juneberry season is on its way - trees are in bloom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>