<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Preview for 17 August 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council meets at 7:00 p.m. on Monday, 17 August 2015. A preview of the agenda is on Arborwiki, complete with a map, on the tag 2015-08-17CCMTG.
Some highlights to note:
The consent agenda includes $36,412 for the purchase of 21 Taser weapons. This is a sole-source purchase, to replace weapons purchased in 2003.
Also on the consent agenda is $83,000 for a sole-source purchase to renew the CityWorks license, which is used for asset tracking and maintenance of city owned resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I voted, summer 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor is one of three peculiar communities in the state of Michigan to have partisan City Council elections; the other two are Ypsilanti and Ionia. This has in recent years meant that the races that decide the makeup of City Council happen in the summer when students are gone and when voter turnout is very low.
I did vote, and I do plan to go to at least one of the parties celebrating victory or acknowledging defeat by the candidates who have the remaining funds from their campaign to put out a nice spread for supporters, hangers-on, or the perpetually politically curious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Emergency Incidents and overnight storm report</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-michigan-emergency-incidents/</guid>
      <description>Michigan Emergency Incidents is a news service that covers emergency dispatch around the state of Michigan. Members of a closed Facebook group post call-outs of emergency services operations, and there&amp;rsquo;s generally follow up from other members to note incidents in progress or news stories written from the scene.
 All information contained in MEI posts is to come from received radio transmissions heard directly from radios / scanners or via an online broadcast, verified reliable sources, or first hand knowledge (ie you are on scene).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away. I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).
The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch a postcard from the command line of my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department does a round of restaurant inspections. Wayne Eaker built an importer that pulls in data from the site that hosts the official county inspections, and is storing the inspection data on Github to make it easier for the next person who wants to build a nice interface to all the data.
Wayne was good enough to find a spot to host an interface to this data that lets you browse through it; you can find it at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.
 The news of the day is a death on State Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of BBQ at Ricewood.
 One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and manual file transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.
Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.
Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?
I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have my computer with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Biggby Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-daily-coffee-wifi-packard-biggby/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a warm but pleasant mid-summer late Monday morning, and I&amp;rsquo;m visiting the first cafe inbound on a walk to town. Biggby Packard is where I end up when the inbound bus schedule timing is just so.
Summertime cafes near campus are odd. There&amp;rsquo;s not really enough here to motivate someone to drive here for coffee, so it draws people from the surrounding neighborhood and from the athletic campus. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in here before when I was the only patron for more than an hour but this morning there&amp;rsquo;s a few more people sitting typing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular &amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years. He died on July 18, 2015.
Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg, and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening at http://bixrevisited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>Eight of us met for lunch at Ayse&amp;rsquo;s today. It was a normal Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for the lunch group these days.
We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make sure that the things that needed to get done got done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lunch with jonathan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:30:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</guid>
      <description>Jonathan and I went to Paradise, a Vietnamese place in the Colonade that also serves Chinese food. He got Mongolian Beef, and I got pho deluxe. It was perfectly adequate if not spectacular. The topic of conversation was an elaborate storyline in a game that involved animatronics in a creepy Chuck E. Cheese type abandoned pizza parlor.
We then went to the Malletts Creek library, until about 4:00 p.m. I worked on Hugo and constructed a theme from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council for July 6, 2015: online video stream goes dark</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-ann-arbor-city-council-for-july-6-2015-online-video-stream-goes-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 20:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-ann-arbor-city-council-for-july-6-2015-online-video-stream-goes-dark/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re trying to follow Ann Arbor City Council via the online feed, you&#39;ll be disappointed tonight as the feed is not working.

The CTN live stream for channel 16 is currently down and being looked at. Sorry for the inconvenience. #ctnannarbor
&amp;mdash; CTN Ann Arbor (@CTNAnnArbor) July 6, 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arborbike, a first review</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 10:42:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</guid>
      <description>Plus: fun to ride, big front basket. It&#39;s a very nice bike that you&#39;re riding, with a good 3 speed shifter and a very sturdy construction. Minus: no lights, no bell, no helmets. More specifically, I am told that the lights come on automatically, and that there is a bell somewhere, but I didn&#39;t find it and it wasn&#39;t labeled. I did have a helmet with me so I wore that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juneberries are ripe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-15-juneberries-are-ripe-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 22:30:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-15-juneberries-are-ripe-/</guid>
      <description>Juneberries are ripe in Ann Arbor on June 15 - I was able to harvest a few of them on North Campus by the Duderstadt building and on Central Campus by the detours around the Engineering Arch. Get them before the birds do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor flooding on Sunday, June 14, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</guid>
      <description>A severe storm dumped a bunch of water on Ann Arbor on Sunday, June 14, 2015. Here are reports of flood locations as monitored on Twitter. All times Eastern.
6:09 p.m. Huron River well down from its crest at 14.95 feet; flood stage is 16 feet, last observation is 13.57 feet at 5:15 P.M.

4:28 p.m. Huron River downstream from Allen Creek surged from about 700 cfs to over 2200 cfs in the span of less than an hour at about 2:00 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>410 Miller still stands</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</guid>
      <description>Why is 410 Miller still standing, after the Building Board of Appeals issued an order for it to be demolished? In part, because the Notice and Order to demolish was never sent. From FOIA 15-210:

Further it is stated that the hearing at which the decision to demolish was made was recorded, yet a transcription of the hearing was not made available on account of the audio being illegible:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When is Ann Arbor going to have a full time building official?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 21:44:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor does not have a full time building official, and the routine operations of the building department are suffering as a result.
I was at a Building Board of Appeals meeting today, 14 May 2015. The group just barely met quorum and had just three members seated, with one member absent and one vacant position. The regular staff member who handles the meetings is on medical leave, and the building official who had been present at previous meetings (Ralph Welton) has left the city&#39;s employment under circumstances which have not been fully and adequately explained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>A nice lunch at Argus Farm Stop. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from Harnois Farm, and we had 9 at the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily telegraph: A new routine with the Argus Farm Stop and the Ann Arbor Y</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</guid>
      <description>Last week was spring break, so my routines were completely upended. The boys didn&#39;t have school and so I didn&#39;t actually have to be anywhere in the morning. Yet I was up and out of bed and awake by 7:00 a.m. and the weather was nice. Perfect weather to try out a new spring routine.
The first piece of the new routine is getting to the Ann Arbor YMCA. If the weather is nice and I don&#39;t have anything else going on, it&#39;s a nice bike ride; if I&#39;m making a car trip into town for school, it&#39;s close enough to be a good next stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the most expensive parking space in Ann Arbor?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 08:56:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Last night was the a2civictech meetup. We met at Zingerman&#39;s Next Door, there were 9 people who showed up, some familiar faces and some new ones.
The nominal topic of the discussion was data quality, understanding how various data sets that come from civic sources have noise in them and looking at ways to deal with that. The best story was that of a well map that showed a hill in the middle of a lake, because the underlying data set had two wells with the same name and the person who built the map picked the wrong data to map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>super cold (but sunny; don&#39;t forget that it was sunny)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-20-super-cold-but-sunny-dont-forget-that-it-was-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-20-super-cold-but-sunny-dont-forget-that-it-was-sunny/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite weather forecasts comes from forecast.io. This screen shows the ensemble set of forecasts they have for temperature for tomorrow (February 20, 2015), highlighting the 8:00 a.m. reading.

You&#39;ll note from this graph that there are several weather models they are pulling from. The one of them that has the coldest predicted weather is RAP from the National Center for Atmospheric Research in Boulder, Colorado. Looking at their set of pages they have a nice cold temperature forecast map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychedelic Rangers, Ann Arbor, 1972</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-25-psychedelic-rangers-ann-arbor-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 10:32:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-25-psychedelic-rangers-ann-arbor-1972/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority is considering hiring &#34;downtown ambassadors&#34; to patrol city streets, help out visitors, and keep the downtown neat and clean and welcoming. As a counterpoint to this corporatized welcoming function, I give you the Psychedelic Rangers, a project of the Rainbow People&#39;s Party (1972) which provided security to concerts and generally kept the peace without bringing in the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: John Gall, 1925-2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</guid>
      <description>Gall, John C. 9/18/1925 - 12/15/2014 Walker, MN John C. Gall, Jr., beloved husband, father, pediatrician, scholar and author, passed away with his wife by his side Dec. 15, 2014, in Walker, MN, from natural causes. He was 89. John was born on September 18, 1925 in Washington, D.C. and grew up near Upperville, VA. In 1945 he was drafted into the Army Air Corps and sent to Germany, where he served as a medic in the Allied army of occupation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appeal of FOIA 14-315, redaction of names and email addresses</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-11-appeal-of-foia-14-315-redaction-of-names-and-email-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 09:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-11-appeal-of-foia-14-315-redaction-of-names-and-email-addresses/</guid>
      <description>Update: The list below is of individuals and organizations that have requested the Absentee Voter file (AV file) for the most recent Ann Arbor election.
The file includes the full names and addresses of individuals who have requested absentee ballots, as well as the status of the ballot in the current election (whether it has been voted yet or not). Political campaigns use this information to identify likely voters for campaign mailings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applesauce recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-applesauce-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 12:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-applesauce-recipe/</guid>
      <description>APPLESAUCE At farmer&#39;s market, ask the farmer for a half a peck or a peck of &#34;mixed seconds for sauce&#34;. Use whatever apples they give you. In November 2014 I paid $7 for a peck of mixed seconds at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market.
Quarter and core many apples; do not peel. Cover bottom of pot with water, put in the apples, half (or a whole) orange (pref. organic, with seeds removed), one (or two) cinnamon sticks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of Ridescout for Ann Arbor multi-modal transit use</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 16:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</guid>
      <description>RideScout is an app that provides info about a whole range of transit options, including taxi, car share, bus, parking, and more. They have support for Ann Arbor as a city, so I tried it while riding AAATA (The Ride).
http://www.ridescoutapp.com/
It&#39;s the first independent app that I&#39;ve seen that shows where every AAATA stop is, in a nice little app that works on your phone with a zippy little map that scrolls nicely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers from CTN regarding City of Ann Arbor closed captioning</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</guid>
      <description>Answers to questions sent to Greg McDonald, CTN manager, regarding closed captioning at on City of Ann Arbor&#39;s Community Television Network.
Why are you providing closed captioning?
The Commission on Disability Issues made a request to add captions to their meetings to increase meeting accessibility.
Who is providing the closed captioning for CTN?
ScreenLine, L.L.C.
How much is the size of the contract, and for how long does it run?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Hands Active open house, September 19, 2014, 7:00 p.m - 10:00 p.m., 525 E Liberty St Ann Arbor MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 22:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</guid>
      <description>Post the poster!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 22, 2014 Ann Arbor Civic Technology meetup, and a2civictech Github issues repo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-922-a2civictech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-922-a2civictech/</guid>
      <description>The RSVP for the Ann Arbor Civic Technology Meetup has been posted. The event is September 22, 2014 at 7:00 p.m. and will be held at the Washtenaw County Building at 200 N Main St in Ann Arbor in the lower level.
If you want some action earlier than 9/22 and can&#39;t wait to get your civics on, you can join in to the action on Twitter by following the #a2council tag and coming to the Monday September 15, 2014 Ann Arbor City Council meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7th annual Lower Burns Park Block Party, Sunday September 28, 2014, 2p-6p on Rose between Golden and E Park Place</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-7th-annual-lower-burns-park-block-party-sunday-september-28-2014-2p-6p-on-rose-between-golden-and-e-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 22:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-7th-annual-lower-burns-park-block-party-sunday-september-28-2014-2p-6p-on-rose-between-golden-and-e-/</guid>
      <description>What: 7th annual Lower Burns Park Block Party
When: Sunday, September 28th 2014 2 pm - 6 pm
(Rain Date: Sunday, October 5th, 2014)
Where: Rose Ave. between Golden Ave. and East Park Place.
Who: You, if you live in Lower Burns Park (E Stadium / State St / Packard / Dewey) or are near enough to appreciate it.
Why: Who doesn&#39;t like a block party!
There will be a bounce house there; please chip in a dollar to help out with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools expects transportation disruption on Monday, 8 September 2014 because of aftereffects of Friday storms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-ann-arbor-public-schools-expects-transportation-disruption-on-monday-8-september-2014-because-of-aft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 19:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-ann-arbor-public-schools-expects-transportation-disruption-on-monday-8-september-2014-because-of-aft/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR - Sunday, 7 September, 2014 - This letter was sent to all Ann Arbor Public Schools families and staff. The worst of the traffic will be in south Ann Arbor where there&#39;s detours on the Stone School bridge over I-94 and the Eisenhower bridge over over the Ann Arbor Railroad.


Dear AAPS Families and Staff,
We want to check in this evening to update you on our AAPS status regarding the numerous impacts of the storm that passed through our area on Friday evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ann Arbor Chronicle, September 2, 2008 - September 2, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-09-the-ann-arbor-chronicle-september-2-2008-september-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-09-the-ann-arbor-chronicle-september-2-2008-september-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>The 6 year run of the Ann Arbor Chronicle is coming to a close. The end date will be Septmeber 2, 2014, which happens to be an Ann Arbor City Council night as well.
The Chronicle was noted for its relentless and exhausting coverage of civic meetings. You could get the feeling that you too had sat on the hard benches for hours as you read through a 15,000 word account of what transpired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zingerman&#39;s Secret Menu (not really)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-30-zingermans-secret-menu-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 23:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-30-zingermans-secret-menu-not-really/</guid>
      <description>Avoid the long lines and sit down quickly with these tips at Zingerman&#39;s Deli.
 Go to the bread counter in the deli. After you taste the samples, get a bagel. Ask them to slice it. (Or ask for one of their yummy bialys which I did last time I was there.)
 Proceed to the deli counter or the fish counter, if you&#39;re hungry for same. Ask for something you&#39;d like to put on that bagel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor DDA Operations Committee meeting agenda, Wednesday July 30, 2014, 11:00 a.m., 150 S Fifth Ave Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-25-ann-arbor-dda-operations-committee-meeting-agenda-wednesday-july-30-2014-1100-am-150-s-fifth-ave-ann/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 15:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-25-ann-arbor-dda-operations-committee-meeting-agenda-wednesday-july-30-2014-1100-am-150-s-fifth-ave-ann/</guid>
      <description>Meeting of the DDA Operations Committee
Wednesday, July 30, 2014 at 11:00 AM
DDA Office 150 S. Fifth Ave, Suite 301
Suggested Agenda
&amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;
1.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Ed Vielmetti, parking app demonstration
&amp;#0160;
2.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Transportation
a.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Michael Ford AAATA – pedestrian walkway request
b.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;WALLY downtown train station location recommendation
&amp;#0160;
3.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Parking Operations
a.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;DDA year to year comparison
b.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Art Fair 2014
c.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;2014 summer parking structure repair/maintenance details
&amp;#0160;
4.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;New Business
a.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Ann &amp;amp; Ashley commercial space build out analysis&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Paid for by * for mayor of Ann Arbor&#34; - an analysis of campaign advertising &amp; disclosure</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 19:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>After getting one too many political ads in my Facebook newsfeed, I started paying closer attention to the &#34;Paid for by&#34; language that I expect to see on every paid political campaign message. The mayoral candidates for the City of Ann Arbor all have some work ahead of them to get their disclosures in order for the 2014 campaign.
I looked for campaign disclosures on Facebook pages, on Twitter feeds, and on event pages created by the campaign on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vacuum Cleaners for sale, Ann Arbor area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-vintage-vacuum-cleaners-for-sale-ann-arbor-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 16:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-vintage-vacuum-cleaners-for-sale-ann-arbor-area/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested, please contact Rusty at rra359@gmail.com . He writes on April 16, 2014:
 I used to belong to the Vacuum Cleaners Collector Club a few years back. I live in Ann Arbor on the west side, and am interested in selling off my Vacuum collection. I am hoping you may know of some people who may be interested, since I am no longer in the club. I have about 60 vacuums, dating back to the “coffee can Hoovers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsubscribing from a bitter local politics list (before I get kicked off)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve unsubscribed from a local politics mailing list that I&#39;ve been on for a while. Out of an abundance of not wanting to name names, I&#39;m not naming names; chances are there&#39;s one of these in your community too.
The ground rules of this list are almost certainly that of typical politics lists. There&#39;s a list owner, who sets the rules. One of the rules is that the list is a private list, with no reporters on it and no one is supposed to share anything they get from the list to anyone who&#39;s not on the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U of Michigan to announce &#34;historic event&#34; at Michigan Stadium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</guid>
      <description>BREAKING: Special Event Press Conference today @ Noon (EDT). Historic event to be held at Michigan Stadium. #BigHouse
&amp;mdash; Michigan Tix Office (@umichtix) April 4, 2014 
The working assumption is that this is the long-rumored summer soccer game between Manchester United and Real Madrid in August. From Crain&#39;s Detroit:
 Global soccer powerhouses Manchester United — wearing its new Chevrolet-sponsored jerseys — and Real Madrid will square off at Michigan Stadium in Ann Arbor at 4 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2014 Web Analytics Wednesday at Enlighten, a meeting non-summary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-02-april-2014-web-analytics-wednesday-at-enlighten-a-meeting-non-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 22:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-02-april-2014-web-analytics-wednesday-at-enlighten-a-meeting-non-summary/</guid>
      <description>We had 11 in attendance for the April 2014 edition of the Ann Arbor Web Analytics Wednesday group, which meets roughly monthly at Enlighten on the west side of Ann Arbor. This month&#39;s meeting was sponsored by Tealium, a tag management vendor. Thanks to Chris Grant for being my co-organizer for the event. I won&#39;t try to summarize what was said by whom in what order, because discussion went around and around the table a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Douglas Perlin, author of a2parking Android application</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-interview-with-douglas-perlin-author-of-a2parking-android-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 11:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-interview-with-douglas-perlin-author-of-a2parking-android-application/</guid>
      <description>This interview of Douglas Perlin, author of the a2parking Android application for locating Ann Arbor parking structures, was done via email. It is lightly edited to include hyperlinks.
 When did you get the idea to do an a2parking application, and how long did it take you to go from idea to first version?  In October or November 2011 I was looking at the a2dda website and happened to see the parking space availability on one of the pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Day Tech Class: Saturday, May 3, 2014 9a-3p at Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</guid>
      <description>From Dan Romanchik KB6NU &amp;#x63;&amp;#x77;&amp;#103;&amp;#x65;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#64;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#98;&amp;#x36;&amp;#x6E;&amp;#x75;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;m - lightly edited:
Dan Romanchik, KB6NU will be conducting the next One-Day Tech Class will be held on Saturday, May 3, 2014 from 9am to 3pm at the Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum, 220 E. Ann St. Ann Arbor, MI 48104. Immediately after the class, the Technician Class license exam will be administered. Pre-registration is required, and there is a $10 fee to take the class. We often fill the class and have to put people on the waiting list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire, May 10, 2014, Washtenaw Community College</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-24-ann-arbor-mini-maker-faire-may-10-2014-washtenaw-community-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 22:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-24-ann-arbor-mini-maker-faire-may-10-2014-washtenaw-community-college/</guid>
      <description>Please share this Save the Date with your friends, family, neighbors, and colleagues across the area.
Now in its sixth year, the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire features dozens of makers from across the region and draws over three thousand members of the community for the day’s free events. Metalworkers, inventors, papermakers, artists, students, robot designers, enthusiasts and professional alike teach the public how they make their work. Many participants come away with more than just inspiration, but new skills they can use to fuel their own creations and lasting connections to other makers and resources in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;a2parking&#34; app provides Android users with access to real time information about Ann Arbor parking structures</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2parking-app-provides-android-users-with-access-to-real-time-information-about-ann-arbor-parking-st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2parking-app-provides-android-users-with-access-to-real-time-information-about-ann-arbor-parking-st/</guid>
      <description>&#34;a2 parking&#34; is an Android application that provides real time updates of available parking spaces in Ann Arbor parking structures. It is based on data published on the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority web site, and in addition to showing spaces free in structures it has one-touch access to directions to your favorite lot or structure.
Download from Google Play: a2 parking.
This has been a long time coming; an interview with Steve Smith of Republic Parking in 2008 described the basic outlines of this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 3, 2014: Finn Brunton on Cryptocurrencies, North Quad Space 2435, 4:00 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-april-3-2014-finn-brunton-on-cryptocurrencies-north-quad-space-2435-400-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-april-3-2014-finn-brunton-on-cryptocurrencies-north-quad-space-2435-400-pm/</guid>
      <description>This wide-ranging talk uses the current state of cryptocurrencies (most notably Bitcoin) and their underlying technologies to consider contemporary digital culture and its future. Professor Finn Brunton will discuss peer-to-peer networks, public key cryptography, proof-of-work systems, and the blockchain, illuminating their underlying social, political, and theoretical models and concepts. We will travel from sixth century Chang&#39;an, seventeenth century Switzerland, and the vault of the New York Federal Reserve to IRC channels, software development communities, and closely guarded facilities in Iceland and Hong Kong to understand a system with fascinating implications for identity, ownership, authorship and trust online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: James Doyle, Lower Burns Park resident whose home was rehabbed by community groups in 2006</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</guid>
      <description>Mr. Jim Doyle, a long time Lower Burns Park resident, passed away late last month at the Grand Rapids VA. Mr. Doyle had lived at 1023 Granger Ave. for over 50 years. He served in the Philippines on General MacArthur&#39;s staff during the war. After the war, Mr. Doyle returned to Ann Arbor where after the passing of his parents, he spent the majority of his adult life taking care of his younger brother who was severely disabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Snow Removal Ordinance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-removal-ordinance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 22:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-removal-ordinance/</guid>
      <description>Because it&#39;s that time of year when sidewalks are full of snow and ice.
4:60. Snow and ice. All snow and ice which has accumulated prior to 6:00 a.m. on a public sidewalk adjacent to property not zoned residentially shall be removed by the owner or occupant by noon. Immediately after the accumulation of ice on such sidewalk it shall be treated with sand, salt or other substance to prevent it from being slippery and the ice shall be removed within the time limits of this paragraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feburary 6, 2014, 7:00 p.m. at Crazy Wisdom: Sunday School: Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-29-feburary-6-2014-700-pm-at-crazy-wisdom-sunday-school-yesterday-today-and-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 23:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-29-feburary-6-2014-700-pm-at-crazy-wisdom-sunday-school-yesterday-today-and-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Join interfaith minister [Lauren Zinn] at SUNDAY SCHOOL: YESTERDAY, TODAY &amp;amp; TOMORROW for an interesting and energizing conversation about what&#39;s happening, not happening and will be happening in Sunday Schools, and why you might want to know.
Encourage religious school teachers, clergy, intermarried friends, parents of young children, students, etc. to attend this open conversation initiated by several local Sunday School teachers involved in interfaith education for youth. See you there, with a cup of hot tea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About sidewalks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</guid>
      <description>To the Editor: The question has been asked your correspondent by several citizens: Can the city legally compel the owners or occupants of property in this city to construct, at their own expense, sidewalks in front of their premises? The city certainly claims ownership of the street from fence to fence, and exercises absolute control thereof. Even if a man desires to plant shade trees on the street in front of his property, the city prescribes the exact distance at which they shall be placed from the property owner&#39;s street line; and notwithstanding the fact that the property owner pays for the trees himself and also for the planting and subsequent care of them until their growth is assured, yet he is denied by the city any ownership in them, and is forbidden to remove or even to trim them, should he at any time desire to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of a deep freeze on the emerald ash borer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-the-impact-of-a-deep-freeze-on-the-emerald-ash-borer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 23:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-the-impact-of-a-deep-freeze-on-the-emerald-ash-borer/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s bitter cold in the Ann Arbor area and throughout the country; temperatures have been below zero most of the last two days. One of the things we&#39;re looking for a silver lining in super cold weather is its impact on bugs, especially invasive species like the emerald ash borer that are not used to unusual weather. A story in the The Gazette (Cedar Rapids Iowa) has a description of the effects of extreme cold on these destructive beetles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 5, 2014: City of Ann Arbor response to snow non-emergency (11&#34;&#43; of snow)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-05-january-5-2014-city-of-ann-arbor-response-to-snow-non-emergency-11-of-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 23:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-05-january-5-2014-city-of-ann-arbor-response-to-snow-non-emergency-11-of-snow/</guid>
      <description>From email sent by Ann Arbor City Council member Christopher Taylor (D-3d Ward).
 Friends,
Here is a quick update for you about the snow and the City’s response.
As of 9:00 pm, we have had 11+ inches of snow. We have not declared a formal snow emergency and street parking is unrestricted. All City facilities will be open Monday and trash collection will run on its ordinary schedule. Road crews are out working 12 – 14 hour shifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan 5, 2014: Snow condition yellow: alert from Washtenaw County Snow Emergency Council</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-05-jan-5-2014-snow-condition-yellow-alert-from-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 21:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-05-jan-5-2014-snow-condition-yellow-alert-from-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council/</guid>
      <description>SNOW CONDITION YELLOW  WASHTENAW COUNTY EMERGENCY OPERATIONS CENTER  SUN JAN 5 2014 8:50 PM EST   DUE TO SIGNIFICANT SNOWFALL ACCUMULATION, NUMEROUS MOTOR VEHICLE ACCIDENTS AND DETERIORATING TRAVEL CONDITIONS THIS EVENING, THE WASHTENAW COUNTY SNOW EMERGENCY COUNCIL HAS ISSUED A SNOW CONDITION YELLOW FOR WASHTENAW COUNTY UNTIL 12:00 NOON ON MONDAY. A SNOW CONDITION YELLOW MEANS VERY HAZARDOUS DRIVING CONDITIONS EXIST WITH HEAVY SNOW OR ICE, DRIFTING, OR LIMITED VISIBILITY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-apocalyptic snow shopping, Meijer edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-pre-apocalyptic-snow-shopping-meijer-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-pre-apocalyptic-snow-shopping-meijer-edition/</guid>
      <description>The day&#39;s news brings stories of shoppers trying to get their grocery shopping in before the storm of January 5, 2014 hits. Trader Joe&#39;s and Kroger were packed, and it looks like at least a few Ann Arbor area Meijer stores had shelves stripped bare. From Damn Arbor:
So the Carpenter Road @meijer has been picked clean. Should I be worried? pic.twitter.com/sQgGoaK7PR
&amp;mdash; Damn Arbor (@damnarbor) January 5, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Snow Emergency Ordinance, 10:143</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 16:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</guid>
      <description>This is current as of January 4, 2014. Check on the Municode web site for the absolute latest information, though it&#39;s unlikely that the ordinance will change.
Note that as of 9:30pm January 5, 2014, there is no snow emergency declared for the City of Ann Arbor, but Washtenaw County has declared a &#34;Snow Condition Yellow&#34;. From the City of Ann Arbor Facebook:
 The City of Ann Arbor is not declaring a snow emergency at this point, but we are recommending residents move their cars off the streets, if possible, to make it easier for city trucks to plow the full width of streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HE WENT OUT WITHOUT A HAT. WHAT HAPPENS NEXT WILL CHILL YOU TO THE BONE</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-upworthy-wx-wind-chill-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-upworthy-wx-wind-chill-advisory/</guid>
      <description>Or, Upworthy does weather in the imitable National Weather Service style.
For January 2-3 2014 we are looking at a wind chill advisory for the Ann Arbor area with wind chills going all the way past 15 below F. From the NWS Detroit:  Cold overnight temperatures in the single digits below zero will combine with 10 to 15 mph winds to cause dangerous Wind Chill Values of -17 to -23 across all of southeast Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Library Lot exit problems on New Years Eve 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-01-ann-arbor-library-lot-exit-problems-on-new-years-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 01:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-01-ann-arbor-library-lot-exit-problems-on-new-years-eve/</guid>
      <description>Kai Petainen writes that the downtown &#34;Library Lot&#34; parking structure so full on New Years Eve that when everyone went to leave it at once, the lines were so long that people&#39;s paid tickets ran out of time. This caused additional delays of up to 45 minutes on exit and confusion as people had to turn around to re-pay.
I have heard of previous times where other unattended structures (notably Liberty Square) have had similar problems with the prepaid ticket system in busy events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plowing snow at midnight</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-15-plowing-snow-at-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-15-plowing-snow-at-midnight/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor&#39;s plow truck fleet is out in force in the wee hours of Sunday, 15 December 2013. You can follow along your self on the city snow plow tracking page.

No, I don&#39;t know either why Jackson Road is labeled as US-12. More details of the City of Ann Arbor plowing program at http://a2gov.org/snow.
How much snow did we get? The National Weather Service map says about 6 inches in Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blimpy Burger Indiegogo campaign</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-14-blimpy-burger-indiegogo-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 15:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-14-blimpy-burger-indiegogo-campaign/</guid>
      <description>Blimpy Burger is running an Indiegogo campaign to help them reopen. Their location on Division Street in Ann Arbor was demolished to build student housing. Find out more at http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/krazy-jim-s-blimpyburger - as of this writing they have raised $1,245 of a $60,000 goal.
While you are thinking of that triple with blue cheese, brush up on your Blimpy ordering skills at Arborwiki&#39;s Blimpy Burger page.

Photo from Arborwiki, credit to Flickr user dokas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teddy bear toss at Yost</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-teddy-bear-toss-at-yost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 20:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-teddy-bear-toss-at-yost/</guid>
      <description>This Vine video is from Julie Weatherbee showing the annual Teddy bear toss at Yost Ice Arena.
 
Listen to the Michigan - Ferris State game online or follow #UMichHockey on the twitters.
1,071 teddy bears were donated to local charities from the teddy bear toss at Yost tonight!!! #awesome
&amp;mdash; Julie Weatherbee (@juliewbee) December 12, 2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor DDA, 4 December 2013, meeting notes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-04-ann-arbor-dda-4-december-2013-meeting-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 22:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-04-ann-arbor-dda-4-december-2013-meeting-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is a lightly edited version of the notes I took at the Ann Arbor DDA meeting for 4 December 2013. The notes are a bit rough; they are notes, not a proper meeting report.

New on the board: Steve Powers
Media in the audience: Dave Askins, Ann Arbor Chronicle; Andrew Cluley, WEMU; Ryan Stanton, Ann Arbor News.
Audience Participation
Main Street BIZ, Ellie Serras. January 28, coffee and pastries (9am, board meeting at 8am).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test of embedded video from Ann Arbor Community Television Network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-02-test-of-embedded-video-from-ann-arbor-community-television-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-02-test-of-embedded-video-from-ann-arbor-community-television-network/</guid>
      <description>This should be the meeting of City Council for 2/21/2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3d Ann Arbor Civic Tech meetup - a writeup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-the-3d-ann-arbor-civic-tech-meetup-a-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 08:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-the-3d-ann-arbor-civic-tech-meetup-a-writeup/</guid>
      <description>We had a good time and a lively discussion at the 3d Ann Arbor Civic Technology meetup. There were about 18 people in attendance, including the City of Ann Arbor CFO/CIO, the webmaster from Washtenaw County, several U of Michigan SI students, some townies, a fellow who drove down from Lansing who had organized Code Michigan hackathon, and a number of folks who were drawn in from Meetup. (who did I miss)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area closings for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>High winds took down trees and knocked out power to thousands in Washtenaw County the night of 17 November 2013, and the next morning a number of schools and government offices closed because of lack of power.
From various sources including email and twitter; this is surely incomplete.
Ann Arbor Public Schools: Tappan and King are closed today due to power outages at both schools. Tonight&#39;s Listen and Learn at Tappan will be rescheduled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dug Song&#39;s letter to the Ann Arbor News endorsing Kirk Westphal, annotated</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-dug-songs-letter-to-the-ann-arbor-news-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 23:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-dug-songs-letter-to-the-ann-arbor-news-annotated/</guid>
      <description>Dug Song wrote a letter to the editor of the Ann Arbor News which was published on Sunday, 27 October 2013. It is annotated here with the hyperlinks to a variety of sources for further reading. The letter includes a political endorsement.
  While I deeply appreciate city council&#39;s dedication to a balanced budget and basic services, we cannot simply save our way to success. Post-Pfizer, Ann Arbor must increase its tax base by supporting a strong and diversified economy of high-growth, high tech companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affinia Group to move headquarters from Ann Arbor, MI to Gastonia, NC; 50 jobs at stake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</guid>
      <description>From the Charlotte Observer:
 Affinia Group Inc., a firm that designs, manufactures, distributes and markets industrial grade products and services, will relocate its Ann Arbor, Mich., headquarters to Gastonia, home of its Global Filtration group. The transition to the new corporate headquarters will occur in phases during 2014.
 Wikipedia gives a little background
 The Affinia Group, a motor industry company, was formed in 2004 and specializes in the design, manufacture and replacement of parts for and on and off-road vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Bialek, Ann Arbor Nights photographer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-mark-bialek-ann-arbor-nights-photographer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-mark-bialek-ann-arbor-nights-photographer/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m hanging out at Roos Roast with photojournalist Mark Bialek, who is doing a photo shoot for them. Mark is known for his night time photos of Ann Arbor on his Ann Arbor Nights weblog. We&#39;re talking about working together in some way to have some of his photos show up here on this weblog. As a start, here&#39;s one of his favorites: a night time winter scene from Kerrytown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homegrown Festival, Saturday September 7, 2013, 6p-10p at Ann Arbor Farmers Market</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-05-homegrown-festival-saturday-september-7-2013-6p-10p-at-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-05-homegrown-festival-saturday-september-7-2013-6p-10p-at-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s the poster! More details about the program at the HomeGrown Festival home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are squirrels disappearing from campus?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-20-are-squirrels-disappearing-from-campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-20-are-squirrels-disappearing-from-campus/</guid>
      <description>Anyone else notice a sudden lack of squirrels on the Diag? There are a few still, but not like last week. Human or hawk predators?
&amp;mdash; Julie Weatherbee (@juliewbee) June 19, 2013  @mariahc @juliewbee I saw a barred owl eating a squirrel in the woods today. So maybe owls.
&amp;mdash; Damn Arbor (@damnarbor) June 20, 2013  @damnarbor @mariahc Could be! I&amp;#39;ve only seen hawks on the Diag, but owls might take the night shift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amtrak accident at Foster Bridge (Maple Rd and Huron River Dr) in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-25-amtrak-accident-at-foster-bridge-maple-rd-and-huron-river-dr-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 13:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-25-amtrak-accident-at-foster-bridge-maple-rd-and-huron-river-dr-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#0160;From Cynthia Hodges on Facebook:
 Train hit a semi carrying kayaks at Foster Bridge Maple Rd Huron River Dr. Truck driver jumped out of cab before impact. We came upon it right after it happened...doesn&amp;#39;t look like anyone was hurt.
 This happened at about 1:00pm on Saturday, May 25, 2013, according to AnnArbor.com.
Photo credit: Cynthia Hodges.
 
UPDATE: The Ann Arbor Chronicle has a longer account of what happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastern Accents is closing for good on March 16, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 13:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (Monday, February 18, 2013)
From a news release from Carol Sun of Eastern Accents.&amp;#0160;
Eastern Accents will be closing its doors for good at 7:00 p.m. on Saturday, March 16, 2013 (end of the day). &amp;#0160;A long-simmering dispute with our landlord has finally come to a head, and we’ve decided that it is time for change.
Carol writes:
Feel free to help spread the word. &amp;#0160;We want to get the word out--especially to anyone who might have gift card values to redeem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finn Brunton, The Accidental Archive. Notes on a talk Monday January 28 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-28-finn-brunton-the-accidental-archive-notes-on-a-talk-monday-january-28-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-28-finn-brunton-the-accidental-archive-notes-on-a-talk-monday-january-28-2013/</guid>
      <description>Finn Brunton, U-M Assistant Professor of Information, will present &amp;quot;The Accidental Archive.&amp;quot; Brunton&amp;#39;s talk, with the alternative title &amp;quot;Researching criminals, otherkin, cipher anarchists, spammers and the online history that doesn&amp;#39;t want to be kept,&amp;quot; kicks off a new series of monthly events addressing emergent research. Light refreshments will be served.
Notes to follow. There&amp;#39;s a hashtag, #MLibRes, on which a half dozen people are tracking. This is an impressionistic transcript, not a summary or tidy narrative, more notes drawn from what I remember from the time and some of my own thoughts mixed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brrr! Cold overnight temperatures on Tuesday, January 22, 2013 in the Ann Arbor area.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-22-brrr-cold-overnight-temperatures-on-tuesday-january-22-2013-in-the-ann-arbor-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-22-brrr-cold-overnight-temperatures-on-tuesday-january-22-2013-in-the-ann-arbor-area/</guid>
      <description>The cold overnight temperatures in the Ann Arbor area are illustrated nicely by the Weather Underground&amp;#39;s Wundermap for the area - here&amp;#39;s a snapshot from 12:30 a.m. Brrr!
Assuming that school is on tomorrow (and not called off because of bitter cold), this should be one of the few days of the year I don&amp;#39;t just send my second grader off to make it to school on his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jon Udell, &#34;Why Johnny Can&#39;t Syndicate&#34;, Friday January 18 2013, noon to 1:00 p.m., University of Michigan School of Information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-17-jon-udell-why-johnny-cant-syndicate-friday-january-18-2013-umsi-umich-school-infomration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 18:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-17-jon-udell-why-johnny-cant-syndicate-friday-january-18-2013-umsi-umich-school-infomration/</guid>
      <description>Copied from the event announcement:  Date and time:&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;01/18/2013 -&amp;#0160;12:00pm&amp;#0160;-&amp;#0160;1:00pm     Location:&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;Ehrlicher Room, 3100 North Quad      Speaker:&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;Jon Udell      Sponsor:&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;Yahoo, School of Information   In this lecture on &amp;quot;Why Johnny Can&amp;#39;t Syndicate,&amp;quot; speaker Jon Udell will review a case study — conducted in Ann Arbor and elsewhere — that uses the syndication of public calendars to explore what people do and don&amp;#39;t understand about the Web&amp;#39;s core principles, how we can enlarge that understanding, and why it matters that we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apartment fire at 1310 Packard, Ann Arbor injures 6</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-13-fire-at-1310-packard-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 22:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-13-fire-at-1310-packard-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (January 13, 2013, 11:06 pm) - A fire at a 6 unit apartment building at 1310 Packard in Ann Arbor sent 6 people to the hospital, all in stable condition, according to a report from Michigan Daily reporter Sam Gringlas who is on the scene and who spoke with Huron Valley Ambulance spokeswoman Joyce Williams. A photograph from the reporter shows smoke billowing out of a window.
At 9:13 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting William Street</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-06-connecting-william-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 13:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-06-connecting-william-street/</guid>
      <description>Connecting William Street is a redevelopment project that the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority is working on to make better use of properties which are currently surface parking lots. The grand plan envisions relatively dense development on these lots.
For background reading see the DDA site for Connecting William Street, the AnnArbor.com coverage of Connecting William Street, and &amp;#0160;the Ann Arbor Chronicle coverage of Connecting William Street. If you&amp;#39;re coming at it from scratch, expect to spend about an hour chewing on the debates to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewritten news, blah</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-05-rewritten-news-blah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 17:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-05-rewritten-news-blah/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m irritated when so-called newspapers fill their pages by rewriting stories from other newspapers. It&amp;#39;s worst when the rewrite is as long as the original and contains no new reporting, just regurgitage.
A typical example:
Dexter Patch writes a story about the township losing out to another bidder on land for a new fire station. AnnArbor.com follows up with the same story, too lazy even to call any of the officials named in the story to get its own quote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Death Cafe series starts Saturday, November 17, 2012, 10:00 a.m.  at Eastern Accents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-ann-arbor-death-cafe-series-starts-saturday-november-17-2012-1000-am-at-eastern-accents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 14:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-ann-arbor-death-cafe-series-starts-saturday-november-17-2012-1000-am-at-eastern-accents/</guid>
      <description>A Death Cafe is a safe place where people get together to talk about death and have tea and delicious cake. The idea originated in Switzerland as the &amp;quot;cafe mortel&amp;quot;, is organized from the UK, and has spread to France, Australia and the US. Events are low key, held in public places, and are safe and informal.&amp;#0160;
The Ann Arbor Death Cafe is the first of these events to be held in Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a public meeting with five windows open to the world -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor City Council holds meetings twice each month, which are streamed online through the city&amp;#39;s CTN network. I tuned in last night on my laptop to listen and watch.
While I was listening, I had a few other windows open on my computer. First and foremost, I had a twitter stream that I was watching for the #a2council&amp;#0160;hash tag; that caught commentary from a few other people who were watching at home, plus some reporters in the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On public art in public places in Ann Arbor&#39;s City Hall</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-08-on-public-art-in-public-places-in-ann-arbors-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-08-on-public-art-in-public-places-in-ann-arbors-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>Tonight&amp;#39;s Ann Arbor City Council meeting discussed at great length the expenditure of some sizable sum of money for art that would be installed in the secured lobby of the Justice Center part of City Hall, where would you have to go through a security check to visit it.
What I have noticed from visits to City Hall is that the art that&amp;#39;s there is quite accessible is a tile mural that you can not only see without going through a checkpoint, but is even so ready to hand that you can touch it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. at the University of Michigan, 1962</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-29-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-at-the-university-of-michigan-1962/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 22:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-29-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-at-the-university-of-michigan-1962/</guid>
      <description>The Michigan Daily story of April 15, 2012 has an excellent set of photos of MLK&amp;#39;s visit to Ann Arbor on&amp;#0160;November 5, 1962, and the story of how they were discovered.
 David Erdody, a digital curator at the Bentley Historical Library, discovered a series of 20 photo negatives in early January that feature King giving a speech and hosting a discussion at the University. These photographs, which have never been printed or published, depict King speaking and greeting a crowd at Hill Auditorium, attending a small discussion in the Michigan Union and having dinner at the University on Nov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summers-Knoll School open house for Middle and Elementary School, April 22, 2012, 1:00 p.m. to 3:00 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-11-sk-open-house-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 23:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-11-sk-open-house-2012/</guid>
      <description>Summers-Knoll School offers students rich academic experiences in an intimate and vibrant environment. Come meet the teachers, learn about our unique approach and tour our new building, located at 2203 Platt Road in Ann Arbor across from the entrance to County Farm Park.
Complimentary childcare for ages 4 and up will be available at our current campus at 2015 Manchester Road from 12:45 p.m. to 3:15 p.m. Directions to 2015 Manchester Road&amp;#0160;will take you near the base of the Ann Arbor water tower visible from Washtenaw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area FM radio, scanning left to right on your radio dial</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</guid>
      <description>A band scan from Ann Arbor, with notes especially on how to get ahold of the station if you like the tunes being played. This list is incomplete, because you can always have a better radio with a better antenna that can pick out one more low power station at the edge of its range. It&#39;s also incomplete, because it only points to stations I&#39;m likely to listen to, and because it&#39;s starting at the left edge of the dial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QR codes made from sugar cubes at the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-05-nqrt-a2mmf-qrcode-sugar-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 09:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-05-nqrt-a2mmf-qrcode-sugar-cubes/</guid>
      <description>The NQRT project had its first sighting in the wild at the 2011 Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire. Ryan Burns organized a group of passers by to our booth to assemble a pound of sugar cubes into a scannable QR code, and Jamie Lausch and I took over mid-way and explained what we had done and helped people make &amp;quot;cootie catchers&amp;quot; with the &amp;quot;Save the date&amp;quot; message for the October 2011 event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you are interested in going to public meetings, you must be interested in advance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-24-a2dda-aacitycouncil-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 23:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-24-a2dda-aacitycouncil-notice/</guid>
      <description>The Michigan Open Meetings Act requires 18 hours advance notice of special meetings, and even less time (though I am not clear how much less time) for special meetings of committees. Thus, if you were not on a mailing list (with a relatively small number of people on the list), you did not receive notice directly of this meeting which is needed to resolve the City of Ann Arbor and the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority&amp;#39;s mutual disagreements over the city budget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meetings now simulcast online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council meetings are now simulcast online, which is handy if you don&amp;#39;t get local CTN cable service. &amp;#0160;This link
http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html
goes to an experimental setup which also tracks the Twitter #aacitycouncil tag.
The CTN Meetingplace page now hosts the current broadcast (both live and delayed) for CTN Channel 16. Meetings are held the first and third Monday nights of the month starting at 7:00 p.m., unless they aren&amp;#39;t for some reason like a holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Central River flood outlook, April 3-8, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-04-north-central-river-flood-outlook-april-3-8-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-04-north-central-river-flood-outlook-april-3-8-2011/</guid>
      <description>A snapshot of the flood outlook from the North Central River Forecast Center&amp;#0160;shows what a wet spring week will do to river levels.

 The Huron River in Ann Arbor will have high water this week.
 Edward Vielmetti splashes in puddles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to watch on CTN, April 1-7, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</guid>
      <description>What to watch on CTN is the City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s weekly programming guide to public access cable. Download this week&amp;#39;s flyer as a PDF.&amp;#0160;Here&amp;#39;s show listings for April 1-7, 2011. Note that several of these are also available on demand over the Internet at http://a2gov.org/ctn .

Edward Vielmetti is certain to make it big in television if he ever gets a chance to break in to the big time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expense report: Cafe Ambrosia, 3/28/11, $1.00; support the go!pass program!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-cafe-ambrosia-go-pass-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 11:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-cafe-ambrosia-go-pass-coffee/</guid>
      <description>Cafe Ambrosia is located on Maynard Street in Ann Arbor, across the street from the Nickels Arcade and adjacent to the Maynard Street parking structure. A cup of coffee is $0.95 with your go!pass discount. Ed Renoullet runs the cafe. This photograph captures the morning sunlight that reaches the cafe&amp;#39;s front window on a late March morning in Ann Arbor.
Ambrosia is distinctive for having one of the best events bulletin boards in town (another story), for having power outlets at every table, and for its relatively new front seating arrangement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Water Hill Music Fest, Sunday, May 1, 2-6pm in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-water-hill-music-fest-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-water-hill-music-fest-2011/</guid>
      <description>Details at WaterHill.ORG.

Edward Vielmetti used to live on Fountain Street on Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Water Hill, which is also sometimes known as the Mack School neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 A2A3 Box Car Derby results</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-26-3d-a2a3-box-car-derby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 09:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-26-3d-a2a3-box-car-derby/</guid>
      <description>Car 49 &amp;quot;The Parkers&amp;quot;, engineered by a Ford Motor Company marketing employee and driven by his son, a student at Ann Arbor Christian School, won the third annual Ann Arbor Box Car Derby. The derby, sponsored by Ann Arbor Active Against ALS and the Phi Delta Theta fraternity, raised an estimated $4,000 today to help families affected by ALS (Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis), commonly known as Lou Gehrig’s Disease. The winning vehicle was designed and built in less than a week from engineered cellulose biomaterials and recycled automotive marketing materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Jeff Lamb, photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Lamb (January 16, 1949 - March 22, 2011) was a photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula. He is survived by his wife, Leyla Lau-Lamb, his dog, Sonny, and other relations and many friends.&amp;#0160;There will be a celebration of Jeff&amp;#39;s life at Hathaway&amp;#39;s Hideaway, 310 S. Ashley, Ann Arbor, on Saturday, April 9th beginning at 4:00 p.m. In lieu of flowers, donations to&amp;#0160;The Advocacy Department of the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River water level watching: USGS National Water Information System</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 13:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</guid>
      <description>Follow the level of the Huron River as it goes through Ann Arbor&amp;#0160;with the USGS National Water Information System. On March 23, the river is rising, but it&amp;#39;s also fluctuating in levels, enough that it&amp;#39;s difficult to determine whether current trends would lead you to believe that there is any risk of flooding.
If you were to watch this closely, what would you watch?
The USGS will give you an alert if the level of the river is above or below a certain level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 22 is World Water Day; tracking the Ann Arbor dioxane plume toward the Huron River</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-22-world-water-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 06:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-22-world-water-day/</guid>
      <description>March 22 is World Water Day. The 2011 theme is Water for Cities: Responding to the Urban Challenge. The Ann Arbor District Library is hosting a 7:00 p.m. panel &amp;quot;Our Water, Our Future&amp;quot;, with&amp;#0160;Mike Wiley from the University of Michigan School of Natural Resources and Environment hosting.
A recording of the event is available for viewing or download at the Ann Abor District Library.
In Ann Arbor, the slow-moving but inexorable urban water supply problem is the spread of a dioxane plume towards the Huron River and the City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s drinking water supply source at Barton Pond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Citizen Request System: tracking trouble</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-21-a2csr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 10:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-21-a2csr/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s hard to have great weird ideas when you&amp;#39;re busy closing trouble tickets.
 Use the City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Citizen Request System (A2CSR) to bring a matter of concern to the attention of the city.
Requests currently being tracked include the following; there is no complete list of citizen-initiated open tickets online, and URL used to link to requests exposes citizen electronic mail addresses.
207216 Potholes - very large ones - on the westbound approach to the East Stadium bridge over State Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brick Bash 2011: Ann Arbor Lego event March 19 at WCC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-brick-bash-lego-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 12:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-brick-bash-lego-2011/</guid>
      <description>Brick Bash 2011 was March 19 at Washtenaw Community College in Ann Arbor Township. Show details are at BrickBash.com. I may have seen you there. The event is organized annually by&amp;#0160;Duane Collicott, who runs the Bricks For Brains&amp;#0160;organization that does educational, hands-on building exhibits with LEGO.
From previous years, a photo set: Brick Bash 2008.
Some highlights of this show; photos and links to come:
Big layouts with trains from the Michigan LEGO Users Group and the Central Ohio LEGO Train Club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I wish I had already written, October 2010 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-october-2010-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-october-2010-edition/</guid>
      <description>A monthly recounting of stories not told, or code not written, or things otherwise that should have been done by me or at least discovered by me, but not done; this, the October 2010 edition.
A detailed breakdown of AATA route productivity by hour and by route, showing which of the routes are the busiest at which times of day. &amp;#0160;(A start at bus tracking; the easy to grab data is late times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Father&#39;s day: stick fishing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-21-fathers-day-stick-fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-21-fathers-day-stick-fishing/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#39;s brown and sticky? &amp;#0160;A stick.One of my favorite parts of the Huron River, strange as it may seem, is the mill race downstream of Argo Dam. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s utterly unloved, used for recreation only as a canoe portage.
M. and I went to the spillway that connects this mill race with the Huron, just upstream of the Detroit Edison Argo Substation. &amp;#0160;There was a lot of trash - sticks, logs, aquatic weeds of various kinds, the odd can and bottle - clogging the spillway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>danah boyd to speak at the U of Michigan John Seely Brown symposium, October 13, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-07-danah-boyd-to-speak-at-the-u-of-michigan-john-seely-brown-symposium-october-13-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-07-danah-boyd-to-speak-at-the-u-of-michigan-john-seely-brown-symposium-october-13-2009/</guid>
      <description>from the JSB Symposium web site at the U of Michigan School of Information:

This year&amp;#39;s JSB Symposium featuring&amp;#0160;danah boyd, a social media researcher at Microsoft Research New England and a fellow at the Berkman Center for Internet and Society at Harvard Law School. Her talk will be on &amp;quot;Youth-Generated Culture: Growing Up in an Era of Social Media.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160;
Note new location:&amp;#0160;The presentation will be at 2 p.m. Tuesday, Oct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2geeks: weekly events for week of 8/3/09 via @dugsong</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-03-a2geeks-weekly-events-for-week-of-8309-via-dugsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-03-a2geeks-weekly-events-for-week-of-8309-via-dugsong/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Dug Song for this events listing - posted as he emailed it out to the a2geeks list.Monthly events piled up again on Wednesday. Have a great week!
Wednesday:
- Weekly CITI donuts, 10 AM at CITI:&amp;#0160;http://www.citi.umich.edu
- Weekly LA2M meeting, noon at Conor O&amp;#39;Neill&amp;#39;s.
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=10523192702
- Weekly CoffeeHouseCoders hackathon, 9 PM at Espresso Royale on State
St. (through the summer).&amp;#0160;http://coffeehousecoders.org
- Monthly SPARK Mingle &amp;amp; Match networking session, 5 PM at SPARK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 ann arbor farmers market peaches are in - apricots too</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-2009-ann-arbor-farmers-market-peaches-are-in-apricots-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 10:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-2009-ann-arbor-farmers-market-peaches-are-in-apricots-too/</guid>
      <description>A quick post on my way from the Ann Arbor Farmers Market to work at AnnArbor.com. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s art fair today, so there will be a zillion people on Liberty Street; the food coop is pretty quiet.
The notable new item at farmer&amp;#39;s market today was peaches. &amp;#0160;Two vendors, Erie Orchards and Kapnick Orchards, both had peaches for sale - Kapnick had the Flaming Fury variety, and Erie had Garnet Beauty. &amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s what the net has to say about both of these:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday Ann Arbor farmer&#39;s market report, u-pick fruit coming up, and what&#39;s in bloom</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-12-saturday-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-upick-fruit-coming-up-and-whats-in-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 15:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-12-saturday-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-upick-fruit-coming-up-and-whats-in-bloom/</guid>
      <description>I was at market on Saturday (yesterday) and kept an eye out for fruit and for new things at market.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s some details.
Sour cherries were gone; sweet cherries were $5-$6 per quart.
Both Erie Orchards and Sodt&amp;#39;s Berry Farm had blueberries for $40 for a 10# lug.
Basil, $1.00 to $1.25 a small bag, or $10/# (organic).
Grandma from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen brought 70 dozen eggs and was sold out at noon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary, day 8</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 14:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-day-8/</guid>
      <description>day 8 of notes on my new job at annarbor.com
Almost every week for the last 4 years I&amp;#39;ve been organizing a Thursday lunch.&amp;#0160; It started with 4 people, and the mailing list now has almost 400; our record attendance at lunch was 41 but the typical table size is much like today, with 22 people sitting around a long table plus one person who came late sitting by themselves.&amp;#0160; As with any mostly-open lunch series, you get to know people bit by bit over time, and some people take a few weeks to gain the confidence to describe who they are to a group of strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the farmer&#39;s market report, day 7</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-the-farmers-market-report-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 14:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-the-farmers-market-report-day-7/</guid>
      <description>day 7 of a continuing series documenting my new job at annarbor.com
There&amp;#39;s a wonderful weekly program on KCRW in Santa Monica called Good Food.&amp;#0160; Host Evan Kleiman does a roundup of reporting from the restaurants and farmers markets around Los Angeles, with interviews with restaurant owners, talks with farmers at markets about the produce they are bringing to market this week, and feature stories about restaurant excursions into the many cuisines that make up LA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amelanchier (Shadbush, Juneberry, Sugar Plum) inventory for Ann Arbor, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-amelanchier-shadbush-juneberry-sugar-plum-inventory-for-ann-arbor-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-amelanchier-shadbush-juneberry-sugar-plum-inventory-for-ann-arbor-2009/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s a complete list of where all of the Amelanchier (juneberry, shadbush, sugar plum depending on where you are from) trees are on the public streets in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; The complete inventory shows 356 trees, each geocoded; rather than try to pin them on a map, this is by street name in alphabetical order, with quite a bit of duplicates eliminated.
The whole program to do this is
grep -i Amelanchier trees09.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grady Burnett leaves Google Ann Arbor to head up Facebook global sales</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-04-grady-burnett-leaves-google-ann-arbor-to-head-up-facebook-global-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 11:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-04-grady-burnett-leaves-google-ann-arbor-to-head-up-facebook-global-sales/</guid>
      <description>this in from Crain&amp;#39;s Detroit:
Grady Burnett, who led Google Inc.’s advertising operation in Ann Arbor, has taken a position with Palo Alto, Calif.-based social media giant Facebook.com as it launches a revenue growth push.
Burnett now runs Facebook’s global online and inside sales.
Ann Arbor is the headquarters of Mountain View, Calif.-based Google’s AdWords division, the pay-per-click, search term-based advertising that’s the company’s primary source of revenue.
I would think this would be worthy of mention on TechMeme but no other stories up yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday: menu plan, Used Cars, 1880s ann arbor panorama</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</guid>
      <description>The menu plan for tonight for the late supper for the resident scholar: spring salad w/asparagus, oyster mushrooms from Alpena, eggs from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen, spinach from Brines Farm, savory tofu from the coop, and a curry dressing. The boys will probably get something a lot simpler.
I wish I had rhubarb to have made stewed rhubarb but I got there to market too late.&amp;#0160; A stewed rhubarb is a compote, which is not to say a compost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make linoleum block prints with the DIY HIPSTER</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-27-how-to-make-linoleum-block-prints-with-the-diy-hipster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 23:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-27-how-to-make-linoleum-block-prints-with-the-diy-hipster/</guid>
      <description>John Roos from roosroast.com has an excellent short DIYHIPSTER how-to on linoleum block printing.  See him in action at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where and when to find pea greens or pea tips?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-18-where-and-when-to-find-pea-greens-or-pea-tips/</guid>
      <description>Every year I look forward to finding pea greens, so that I can stir fry them up.&amp;#0160; And every year at the farmer&amp;#39;s market I don&amp;#39;t find them.&amp;#0160; I hope this year can be different, but I have some questions.
If I wanted to grow pea greens on my own, what variety of peas would I use?
Are pea vines usually sprayed, and would you want to look out for no-spray vendors?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>records request: ann arbor downtown development authority parking data</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-14-records-request-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-parking-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 02:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-14-records-request-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-parking-data/</guid>
      <description>update: broken links fixed to interview, thanks John Balogh for the heads up as sent by postal mail and email
March 14, 2009
&amp;#0160;
Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority 150 South Fifth Avenue Suite 301 Ann Arbor, MI 48104
&amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;RECORDS REQUEST
&amp;#0160;
Dear Records Request Officer:
&amp;#0160;
Pursuant to the state open records act, I request access to and copies of the continuously updated information about the current availability of parking structure occupancy and free spaces, as currently provided to the general public on the web page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AATA Local Advisory Committee meeting, unofficial notes, 2/10/2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 14:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor Transportation Authority
Local Advisory Committee
Feb 10, 2009
unofficial notes
Edward Vielmetti
This is my notes from the LAC meeting of 2/10/09,
edited slightly but not intended as a faithful
transcript of the meeting.
I came in 10 minutes late; the meeting starts at
10:00am, and the AATA #6 from downtown gets there
at 10:01am. The meeting ends at 12:00 noon; the inbound #6 arrives at 11:58am.
--</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aata mobile ridetrak via SMS demo; SuperHathawayDevHouse Feb 18, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-03-aata-mobile-ridetrak-via-sms-demo-superhathawaydevhouse-feb-18-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 22:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-03-aata-mobile-ridetrak-via-sms-demo-superhathawaydevhouse-feb-18-2009/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Transportation Authority has a system to let you check where the bus is by going to a web page; it&amp;#39;s called Mobile Ridetrak.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve written about it before, both when it has not been working and when it has been working.
The current Mobile Ridetrak is available only by a web page, which puts it out of reach for most mobile phones that don&amp;#39;t have a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council, agenda, Feb 2 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</guid>
      <description>This is the January 29, 2009 draft of the Feb 2, 2009 Ann Arbor City Council agenda, as retrieved from the city web site.&amp;#0160; Any errors in transcription from PDF to text are my own; there are some small number of edits throughout, clearly marked, including hyperlinks as appropriate.
My copy of the PDF had various bits redacted, or at least it looked like they were redacted; in fact these are hyperlinks to the underlying documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor February 2009 calendar (rescued from a PDF)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-27-city-of-ann-arbor-february-calendar-rescued-from-a-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 16:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-27-city-of-ann-arbor-february-calendar-rescued-from-a-pdf/</guid>
      <description>The original &amp;quot;Tree Town Log (PDF)&amp;quot; is here, with minor edits for links, line breaks, additional phone number etc; times and dates subject to change; no warranty etc etc.
For more information, call the city information desk at 734.994.2700 during regular business hours or visit our Web site at: www.a2gov.org. Meetings and events can also be found at www.a2gov.org/calendar.
PLEASE NOTE: As of January 2009, some city public meetings have been relocated due to the upcoming construction of the Ann Arbor Municipal Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tues 1/27: Lunch meeting to plan coworking space at Arcadian Too, Main St Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-26-tues-127-lunch-meeting-to-plan-coworking-space-at-arcadian-too-main-st-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 16:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-26-tues-127-lunch-meeting-to-plan-coworking-space-at-arcadian-too-main-st-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Noted 3/2011: this is the space that turned into the Workantile Exchange.
Forwarded for Mike Kessler:
What:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; A free lunch meeting to introduce, create, and design the new coworking space in Ann Arbor
Where:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; 118 S. Main St. in the former Arcadian Too Antiques space
When:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Tuesday, January 27,&amp;#0160; 2009 12 Noon
What:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Work has begun!&amp;#0160; The space is being created.&amp;#0160; Come and be an advocate for your vision of what the space looks like, acts like and how it is organized</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AATA proposes fare hikes; mobile ridetrack still down, 6 weeks after going offline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-aata-proposes-fare-hikes-mobile-ridetrack-still-down-6-weeks-after-going-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 15:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-aata-proposes-fare-hikes-mobile-ridetrack-still-down-6-weeks-after-going-offline/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Bus data is not available at this time. This does not necessarily indicate that buses are not running. Please check your schedule for times.&amp;quot;
Mobile Ridetrack is still down, six weeks after going offline.&amp;#0160; I suggest that you contact the AATA to get a current piece of information from them about restoration of service.&amp;#0160; I have no idea what to expect.


PRESS RELEASE&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;
For immediate release</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge the Ann Arbor Community Television Network with the Ann Arbor District Library&#39;s video services?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-31-ann-arbors-community-television-network-a-study-by-matt-hampel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 15:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-31-ann-arbors-community-television-network-a-study-by-matt-hampel/</guid>
      <description>Matt Hampel has released a study of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Community Television Network.&amp;#0160; He writes about an organization that was innovative and forward-looking in the 1970s that is now running with little public oversight and with only the most tentative ways of engaging with the public through networks other than cable television.
Most notable in the whole discussion is a comparison of CTN&amp;#39;s video archiving and online access system with a similar setup at the Ann Arbor District Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>community organizer&#39;s checklist: weekly lunch meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 11:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</guid>
      <description>A checklist of things to do for the weekly lunch.
1.&amp;#0160; Day of the week: Mo - Tu - We - Th - Fri
2.&amp;#0160; Frequency: Every - First - Second - Third - Fourth - Last - Even - Odd
3.&amp;#0160; Location: Fixed (Eastern Accents) - Floating - Alternate (Ypsilanti TBD)
4.&amp;#0160; Holiday schedule: Skip - Alternate Day (Weds or Fri) - Alternate Week 5.&amp;#0160; Summer schedule: Skip - Alternate Time - Alternate Location (Ypsilanti TBD)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Futurtech 2008, December 5 at the Michigan Union</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-futurtech-2008-december-5-at-the-michigan-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 16:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-futurtech-2008-december-5-at-the-michigan-union/</guid>
      <description>Ami Arnault reminds me of the Futurtech conference happening this week at the U of Michigan - December 5, 2008 at the Michigan Union.&amp;#0160; A bio of the afternoon keynote speaker:
Rohit Bhargava Author, Personality Not Included (www.readpni.com) SVP, Ogilvy 360 Digital Influence (blog.ogilvypr.com) Blogger, Influential Marketing Blog (http://rohitbhargava.typepad.com) &amp;#0160; Rohit is a founding member of the 360 Digital Influence group at Ogilvy and author of the best selling new marketing book Personality Not Included, an engaging and useful guide on the future of business and technology and how companies can use their personality to drive real business results in the social media era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arbcamp planning non-summary: lunch, Kai Garden, Nov 21 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-21-arbcamp-planning-nonsummary-lunch-kai-garden-nov-21-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 14:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-21-arbcamp-planning-nonsummary-lunch-kai-garden-nov-21-2008/</guid>
      <description>Ten of us met for lunch at Kai Garden on Friday, Nov 21 to help plan Arbcamp, which is coming up the evening of December 18, 2008 in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; I had the Mongolian beef and egg drop soup; Dug ordered a round of scallion pancakes.
Here&amp;#39;s a summary (or not).
Dug Song summed up the discussion at the end including:
Schedule: how the event will be structured, how much time we have, how many parallel tracks can happen, how to accomodate both short &amp;quot;lightning&amp;quot; style talks and longer sessions, how to wrap up at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put a local coupon in your weblog: November 2008 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-13-put-a-local-coupon-in-your-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-13-put-a-local-coupon-in-your-weblog/</guid>
      <description>Mark Maynard, Ypsilanti, November 2008: Cafe Luwak
This month, the MM.com special can be found at&amp;#0160;Cafe Luwak, where, if you buy one sandwich, you’ll get one free… And the same goes for those urban elitist coffee drinks known as lattes… Seriously, how better to celebrate an Obama win in Michigan than with the official drink of the liberal elite?
 Todd Waller, Team366, morgan and york, $5 off on $50 w/coupon (PDF)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>coffee house coders: Wednesdays, 9pm-11pm Eastern, Espresso Royale Cafe, State St</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-coffee-house-coders-wednesdays-9pm-11pm-eastern-espresso-royale-cafe-state-st/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-coffee-house-coders-wednesdays-9pm-11pm-eastern-espresso-royale-cafe-state-st/</guid>
      <description>Coffee House Coders is a programmer&amp;#39;s group that meets Wednesday nights at ERC State St in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; A large long table in the back hosts a dozen or so laptops, and the assembled crowd works on whatever code they are working on.
Organized by Zach Steindler and Matt Pizzimenti, this group when I visited last week was mostly current and recent UM engineering students, with a few people from out of town visiting old friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 7-9, 2008: Language as a Complex Adaptive System, Ann Arbor, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-november-7-9-2008-language-as-a-complex-adaptive-system-ann-arbor-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 12:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-november-7-9-2008-language-as-a-complex-adaptive-system-ann-arbor-mi/</guid>
      <description>The theme builds upon foundations laid by colleagues from different branches of linguistics, psychology, and complex systems. The speakers are active in their recognition of complexity in their respective areas, ranging from language usage, structure, and change, sociolinguistics, cognitive linguistics, anthropology, language evolution, first language acquisition, second language acquisition, psycholinguistics and language processing, language education, individual differences, and language testing.
Conference Schedule is available at http://elicorpora.info/LLC/schedule
(Free) Registration required
Dates: November 7-9, 2008</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HealthMedia acquired by Johnson and Johnson</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-healthmedia-acquired-by-johnson-and-johnson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 15:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-healthmedia-acquired-by-johnson-and-johnson/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor based Healthmedia, Inc has been acquired by Johnson and Johnson (NYSE:JNJ).&amp;#0160; Terms of the transaction were not disclosed.
HealthMedia combines advanced technology and behavioral science to effectively emulate a health coach via the web. HealthMedia&amp;#39;s suite of interventions provides automated web-based coaching for wellness, disease management, behavioral health, and medication adherence with proven outcomes, increased compliance, reduced medical utilization, and increased productivity. HealthMedia&amp;#39;s products have demonstrated improved cost savings for health plans and employers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor real estate marketing seminar with Missy Caulk, Bob Stewart (Active Rain)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-ann-arbor-real-estate-marketing-seminar-with-missy-caulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 10:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-ann-arbor-real-estate-marketing-seminar-with-missy-caulk/</guid>
      <description>Missy Caulk is doing a seminar at Keller Williams about blogging in real estate in the Ann Arbor market.&amp;#0160; Some impressionistic notes.
&amp;quot;Google likes fresh content&amp;quot; - static content with 10 years worth of stuff that is mostly the same.
Examples of real estate content - information about schools, neighborhoods, real estate issues.
Blog to learn, blog to grow, blog to share, blog for relationships.
&amp;quot;MIssy, you need to do more hyperlocal&amp;quot; = become an expert on that subdivision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor, Michigan sample ballot for November 4, 2008 presidential election</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-09-ann-arbor-michi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 16:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-09-ann-arbor-michi/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s that time of year.&amp;#0160; Ballot information:
Washtenaw County&amp;#39;s Washtenaw Votes site has complete details about precinct locations etc.
The State of Michigan&amp;#39;s Web Voter Information Center will spit out your personal sample ballot, if you are registered in a particular place; there doesn&amp;#39;t seem to be an easy way to get a sample ballot for an arbitrary location.
The City of Ann Arbor has a detailed page of voting information and a voting FAQ online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten more places to have a birthday party in the Ann Arbor area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-ten-more-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 22:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-ten-more-places/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a list of ten places to have a birthday party for kids in Ann Arbor about a year ago; it&#39;s proven to be a popular post.&amp;nbsp; I thought I&#39;d do a new list completely different from the first.&amp;nbsp; As always check for availability and pricing before you plan.
1.&amp;nbsp; Frisinger Park (summer and fall).&amp;nbsp; A few picnic tables near the playground with lots of things to do for kids (slides, swings, a merry-go-round, a sandbox) and a big field to run in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thank you for supporting arborwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</guid>
      <description>From time to time people ask questions about Ann Arbor, and from time to time there are what appear to be encyclopedic responses to them. Part of the reason for this is Arborwiki, a wiki that covers information about Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, Washtenaw County and the rest of the area.
Matt Hampel runs this with an ad hoc collective doing editorial direction and the Ann Arbor District Library providing hosting. It&#39;s not advertising driven, and while is has a lot of information about businesses any obviously marketing copy gets edited out pretty quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Street View comes to Ann Arbor, at least some of it</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-google-street-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 10:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-google-street-v/</guid>
      <description>Google&#39;s Street View has come to Ann Arbor. From the looks of it, the photos were taken last fall; gas was $2.899 a gallon. The photo of my street showed Mario and Luigi&#39;s toys out in the front, and a neighbor across the street was working on his lawn.

Notable from the map above is the scrupulous adherence to the freeway boundaries of Ann Arbor in the mapping effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GO Tech notes for May 13, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-14-go-tech-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 09:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-14-go-tech-notes/</guid>
      <description>welcome; impressionistic notes. (posted without links, links to follow!)
three cohousing communities in ann arbor, great oak is one of them
dale (lives here) - cnc machines, embedded systems
keith mcclary - robotics, cnc, automation, embedded, &#34;local area first&#34; robotics teams
mike - interested in everything
bob smit? - EE, data acquisition, cnc, cad/cam, free cnc toolkit mco f-1&#39;s converting
peter jensen - tubeclock.com nixie tube clocks
john berry - &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor sign ordinances</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-21-ann-arbor-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 23:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-21-ann-arbor-sign/</guid>
      <description>If your neighbor erects a giant sign on their lawn, or on the side of their house, what is your recourse?  UPDATE: In Ann Arbor the simple and direct way to deal with this is to call the city&amp;rsquo;s Community Standards department at 734-994-1613. A neighbor who has been through this before says that they deal with sign problems promptly.  The appropriate part of the city code reads as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>