<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Orleans Louisiana on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-orleans-louisiana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Orleans Louisiana on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-orleans-louisiana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;An obituary for Greg Peters is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.
 
Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan vs Virginia Tech (Hoke vs Hokies) in Sugar Bowl, January 3, 2012 in New Orleans; also, sandwiches</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 22:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Follow the coverage from all sides.
National coverage: ESPN&#39;s WolverineNation coverage from beat writer Michael Rothstein. Michigan Wolverines Land Sugar Bowl.
 It almost didn&#39;t happen, however. After finishing the regular season 10-2, the Wolverines needed help from other teams around the country on Saturday and from the pollsters on Sunday morning in order to be in this position -- and they received it.  On Virginia Tech, the Washington Post writes &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Jeff Lamb, photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Lamb (January 16, 1949 - March 22, 2011) was a photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula. He is survived by his wife, Leyla Lau-Lamb, his dog, Sonny, and other relations and many friends.&amp;#0160;There will be a celebration of Jeff&amp;#39;s life at Hathaway&amp;#39;s Hideaway, 310 S. Ashley, Ann Arbor, on Saturday, April 9th beginning at 4:00 p.m. In lieu of flowers, donations to&amp;#0160;The Advocacy Department of the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Mississippi cottages, tearing down New Orleans houses</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-22-building-missis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-22-building-missis/</guid>
      <description>The Christian Science Monitor has a good story with pictures of the current state of the &#34;Mississippi Cottage&#34; design of manufactured housing.
Hurricane Katrina downsized his domain to nothing. Today, his new castle is about one-seventh the size of his old one, measuring 450 square feet. But surveying the familiar view from the dollhouse porch of his &amp;ldquo;Mississippi cottage,&amp;rdquo; Mr. Voorhies is one of many storm survivors who have reassessed their coastal existence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>