<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fire on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/fire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fire on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 12:39:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/fire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire breaks out at Fifth Third Park in Grand Rapids (with map, scanner info)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-03-fire-breaks-out-at-fifth-third-park-in-grand-rapids-with-map-scanner-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 12:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-03-fire-breaks-out-at-fifth-third-park-in-grand-rapids-with-map-scanner-info/</guid>
      <description>January 3, 2014: Fifth Third Park in Grand Rapids is on fire. Some news coverage from local sources.
Listen to scanner traffic on Kent County Fire North via Broadcastify.
The map shows a blue circle around the traffic camera, with heavy smoke visible, just north of Grand Rapids along highway US-131 at I-96. Two orange diamonds mark where MDOT warns travelers of the fire. Map from WZZM 13.

WZZM 13 has live video coverage -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire in downtown Lapeer, Michigan on the evening of 12 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-12-fire-in-downtown-lapeer-michigan-on-the-evening-of-12-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 20:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-12-fire-in-downtown-lapeer-michigan-on-the-evening-of-12-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>As monitored via the Lapeer County Michigan scanner and via Twitter, there is a large fire in downtown Lapeer, Michigan. I&#39;m listening to the scanner and the fire is being actively fought, and there are over 700 people listening to the stream. The PIX Theater is the center of firefighting efforts, as far as I can tell. This is a snapshot of news coverage at 9:15 pm Eastern on November 12, 2013, and is bound to be updated by local media as details emerge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A map of the October 2013 wildfires in New South Wales, Australia</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-19-a-map-of-the-october-2013-wildfires-in-new-south-wales-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 01:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-19-a-map-of-the-october-2013-wildfires-in-new-south-wales-australia/</guid>
      <description>Bush fires are burning in New South Wales, Australia in October 2013. If you are near the fire, you must find a more accurate and timely source of information than this blog post.
A BBC report quotes from a local official:
 Minister for Police and Emergency Services Michael Gallacher told the BBC that &#34;the speed and the ferocity&#34; of the fires was something &#34;not seen for many, many years&#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to the Yosemite &#34;Rim Fire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-listening-to-the-yosemite-rim-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 22:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-listening-to-the-yosemite-rim-fire/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m listening to the Tuolumne County Sheriff, Fire, and Police scanner feed via Broadcastify. The scanner chatter includes the usual traffic reports but also the distinctive cadence of firefighting operations - calls for &#34;Charlies&#34; (?), water tenders, and other fire equipment, and a fire coordinator asking a crew leader what additional resources they need.
This webcam photo from within Yosemite shows the intense smoke that characterizes this fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arson on Mary Street? The Michigan Daily is on it, the AnnArbor.com not so much</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-arson-on-mary-street-the-michigan-daily-is-on-it-the-annarborcom-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 17:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-arson-on-mary-street-the-michigan-daily-is-on-it-the-annarborcom-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>Two reports of a fire on the 900 block of Mary Street on Saturday at around 3:00 a.m. The sirens woke me up.
The AnnArbor.com story notes that a 3 car garage was destroyed and gives the &#34;we don&#39;t know very much&#34; report:
 The cause of the fire was not immediately known. The cost of the damage is unknown.
 The Michigan Daily story gives more details, including a photo from neighbor Raymond Brokowski, and has this disturbing detail: it&#39;s being investigated as arson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yarnell Hill Fire (Yarnell, AZ): 19 firefighters dead - worst incident since 1933 - with map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-01-yarnell-hill-fire-yarnell-az-19-firefighters-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-01-yarnell-hill-fire-yarnell-az-19-firefighters-dead/</guid>
      <description>19 firefighters have died fighting the Yarnell Hills fire in Yarnell, AZ, about 80 miles northwest of Phoenix, AZ.&amp;nbsp;
Wundermap fire layer map for Yarnell, AZ

Multiple news sources have confirmed this tragedy.&amp;nbsp;
CNN: Official: 19 firefighters dead in Arizona. Quotes&amp;nbsp;Wade Ward with the Prescott Fire Department.
Prescott, AZ Daily Courier: BREAKING NEWS: 19 die in Yarnell fire; 18 were Prescott firefighters Quotes State Forestry Division Spokesman Mike Reichling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore haze map for 24 June 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-24-singapore-haze-map-for-24-june-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-24-singapore-haze-map-for-24-june-2013/</guid>
      <description>The BBC World Service has reporting on the dense haze that&amp;rsquo;s covering Singapore and parts of Malaysia as a result of land-clearing fires in Indonesia. The map below is from the Meteorological Service Singapore. The Indonesian president has apologized for the haze, notes the Straits Times.

Singaporeans are advised to wear masks when going outdoors, and to stay indoors if at all possible. SingPost has issued masks for postal workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Forest Fire near Colorado Springs, Colorado (with maps updated Thursday 6/13 5:37 p.m MT)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-11-black-forest-fire-near-colorado-springs-colorado-with-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 23:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-11-black-forest-fire-near-colorado-springs-colorado-with-map/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED Thursday June 13, 6:00 p.m MT with new maps at the top.
The fast-moving Black Forest Fire is burning homes northeast of Colorado Springs, Colorado. High temperatures, high winds, and low humidity are fanning the flames. Two people are known to have died in the fire, and more than 360 homes have been lost. If you are near the fire, please seek out current and official information rather than relying on this weblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtown Ann Arbor fire at 401 S Division St</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-downtown-ann-arbor-fire-at-401-s-division-st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 20:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-downtown-ann-arbor-fire-at-401-s-division-st/</guid>
      <description>A downtown rental house caught fire on the evening of Friday, January 25, 2013. Initial reports did not include any mention of injuries, and two dogs were reported rescued.
Coverage:
Damn Arbor: &amp;nbsp;Huge fire!
AnnArbor.com:&amp;nbsp;Fire breaks out at apartment house in downtown Ann Arbor; pets saved; Saturday 1/26/2013 update Ann Arbor fire aftermath: &#39;I&#39;m so grateful&#39; about dog rescue and resident safety
Michigan Daily: Fire breaks out at house near ISR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duck Lake Fire, north of Newberry MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</guid>
      <description>Some sources for information on the Duck Lake Fire, which started on Wednesday, May 23, 2012 and is burning rapidly in Luce County, north of Newberry, MI. The fire is dangerous and has caused evacuations; if you are reading this and you are in the area, seek authoritative and current information from official sources.
The fire brings to mind the 2007 Sleeper Lake Fire&amp;#0160;which burned over 18,000 acres in Luce County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riverwood house fire, Ann Arbor MI 48103 (with video)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-11-riverwood-fire-ann-arbor-mi-48103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-11-riverwood-fire-ann-arbor-mi-48103/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (Friday, November 11, 2011) - A house on Riverwood (at Timber Trail, off Newport north of M-14) caught fire at about 10:00 a.m. this morning. No estimate on damages yet, no report of injuries to people. Details follow.
(ANN ARBOR CITY - INTEROP 4) FULLY INVOLVED 2 STORY HOUSE FIRE. FULL AAFD RESPONSE. MA YPSI CITY, YPSI TWN, AND PITTSFIELD FIRE DEPARTMENT. (as seen on Radio Reference)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoky house fire on Harpst Street in Ann Arbor on the evening of October 7, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-07-fire-harpst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 22:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-07-fire-harpst/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, October 7, 11:30 p.m. - A house near the corner of Harpst Street and Tremmell Avenue was on fire on the evening of October 7, 2011. This photo is provided courtesy of Mike Nowak (@snackdog) and is used with permission. The Ann Arbor Fire Department cleared the scene just after 11:00 p.m, according to radio monitoring reports.
 Enough smoke was generated by the fire that residents of the nearby Woodbury Gardens complex called for help, and trucks from Pittsfield Township and Ypsilanti Township were seen departing the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire map layer on Weather Underground&#39;s WunderMap for Central Texas fires</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-06-central-texas-fires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 10:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-06-central-texas-fires/</guid>
      <description>Labor Day was a particularly bad day for fires in central Texas. If you&amp;#39;re in that area, you may be looking for maps of where the fires are around you. Of course, you&amp;#39;re already listening to local radio and television for news that you would need to make a decision quickly.
The Weather Underground&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;WunderMap&amp;quot; product has a &amp;quot;fire&amp;quot; layer, which displays smoke plumes, areas that have active fires, and the perimeters of contained fires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2011 Howes Lake Wildfire west of Grayling, Michigan (Crawford, Kalkaska counties)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-howes-lake-fire-grayling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 16:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-howes-lake-fire-grayling/</guid>
      <description>Update June 8, 2011: the Howes Lake Wildfire has been contained. Here is a wildfire map, from the Michigan DNR. See also an incident action plan (PDF), 8.5 x 11&amp;quot; version of this map, and an area map for reference.
News stories, many of which have photos: Andrew Keller at UpNorthLive: &amp;quot;Families go home&amp;quot;
 The firefighters looked exhausted today, but those men and women were still at it, making sure this fire wouldn&amp;#39;t pick back up and damage would stay at 817 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grayling area fires - Range 9 fire, Meridian Boundary fire</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-20-grayling-area-fires-range-9-fire-meridian-boundary-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-20-grayling-area-fires-range-9-fire-meridian-boundary-fire/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;  &amp;nbsp;A few notes, mostly to figure out where the real coverage is.
Interlochen Public Radio

A fire started on a range at Camp Grayling yesterday is out. But firefighters continue to battle another, larger blaze north of Roscommon.&amp;nbsp;

Michigan DNRE is on Twitter (@mdnre) and Facebook, plus their regular web page.
Fire maps: Range 9 fire, Meridian Boundary fire. &amp;nbsp;Maps subject to change.
Local news: Crawford County Avalanche news story, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesusita fire in Santa Barbara, CA in May 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-08-jesusita-fire-in-santa-barbara-ca-in-may-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 02:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-08-jesusita-fire-in-santa-barbara-ca-in-may-2009/</guid>
      <description>When the Tea Fire hit Santa Barbara, California, I happened to be there at the right point to blog about it.&amp;#0160; The latest big fire there, the Jesusita Fire, is going as of this writing, and some people are finding this blog because of searches for keywords.
As a small public service, the best one blog I&amp;#39;d direct you to is Doc Searls weblog, because he has been doing the best blogging coverage of it and has more in depth roundup and review of the news than I would or could ever do again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>