<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>December on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/december/</link>
    <description>Recent content in December on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 16:28:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/december/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice storm of December 21-22, 2013 and the Sperry-Piltz Ice Accumulation Index</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-21-ice-storm-of-december-21-22-2013-and-the-sperry-piltz-ice-accumulation-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 16:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-21-ice-storm-of-december-21-22-2013-and-the-sperry-piltz-ice-accumulation-index/</guid>
      <description>On the Sperry-Piltz Ice Accumulation Index:
 The Sperry–Piltz Ice Accumulation Index, or SPIA Index, is a forward-looking, ice accumulation and ice damage prediction index that uses an algorithm of researched parameters that, when combined with National Weather Service forecast data, predicts the projected footprint, total ice accumulation, and resulting potential damage from approaching ice storms. It is a tool to be used for risk management and/or winter weather preparedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 most popular maps of 2011 for this blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-5-popular-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 23:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-5-popular-maps/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s the 5 most popular mapping pages on Vacuum over the past 12 months - these are all in the top 10 most popular pages on this blog overall in that time span.
1. Power outage maps for 50 states. I only really have about 44 states with maps, but the collection is otherwise excellent, and it gets lots of search traffic when there are big storms. Peak storm action of Hurricane Irene and of the Halloween snowstorm that hit the Northeast both saw 3000+ visits per day of people looking for outage maps for their area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lumineria of upper Brooklyn Avenue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-the-lumineria-of-upper-brooklyn-avenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 21:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-the-lumineria-of-upper-brooklyn-avenue/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: next year, on the solstice, arrange that lower Brooklyn Avenue joins in the collection of lumineria that grace upper Brooklyn Avneue (between Packard and Lincoln) tonight.
(photo to follow)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>