<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian Eno on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/brian-eno/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brian Eno on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/brian-eno/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.
One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s no internal inconsistencies.
The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging, memory and forgetting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</guid>
      <description>750 words on blogging, memory and forgetting
I&amp;#39;ve been blogging for a long time, and writing online for longer than that - 27 years of typing. In the process, a lot of it has been saved, and a lot of it has been discarded. I&amp;#39;m luckier than most to have a complete set of my writing since 2003 all in Typepad. Heaven help anyone who wrote seriously on Prodigy or Compuserve or Facebook and tried to save any of it permanently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>