<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular
&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years.
He died on July 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Hazen_Schumacher&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher&lt;/a&gt;
has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled
and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bixeibenhamburg.com/&#34;&gt;Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;,
and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bixrevisited.com&#34;&gt;http://bixrevisited.com&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited has reached millions, giving Hazen a good claim
to be America’s premier jazz educator.&amp;rdquo; (Art Hilgart - IAJRC Journal).
Bix Eiben Hamburg presents 24 different shows at regular intervals
for free listening. Dive into the wonderful world of classic Jazz.
Become part of the great Jazz fan community that already regularly
uses our service free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/84464117&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/84464117&#34;&gt;A tribute to The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and Jazz Revisited&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/bixeiben&#34;&gt;Jazz-Museum Bixeibenhamburg&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In remembrance of The Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg and a documentary report about the Jazz Revisited Radio Shows!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Midland G-227 GMRS/FRS radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 11:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Midland G-227 GMRS radio, quantity two, a gift from the
Wells-Becker Motorcycle Emporium in Dexter, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replaced batteries in both of them, they take 4xAAA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio 1 successfully hears static when the (M) monitor
button is depresssed; Radio 2 hears nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manual is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&#34;&gt;http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html&lt;/a&gt;
which describes the frequencies of the 22 channels it can transmit on.
A reasonable next step is to get my NooElec SDR tuner out and see if
I can monitor a transmission. If Radio 2 transmits, I suspect a loose
connection to the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Midland-G-227C2-7-Mile-22-Channel-Two-Way/dp/B00008JOMG&#34;&gt;Amazon reviews&lt;/a&gt;
complain mostly that the range of the radios is not &amp;ldquo;7 miles&amp;rdquo; as
marketed, but closer to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; mile to 1 mile on land. That&amp;rsquo;s typical
for this band as I understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same gift also a Uniden labeled &amp;ldquo;Scramble&amp;rdquo; that has a NOAA
weather logo on it, so it probably also monitors weather frequencies.
Indeed, if I tune both of them to channel 4, they hear each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can never have too many radios!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dipole antenna for your SDR tuner stick from an old set of headphones</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:50:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes before I try to do the build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts I have or know I can get: cheap earbud headphones, NooElec NESDR Mini 2 SDR tuner stick with whip antenna, Nokia 635 phone, antenna from an older NESDR Mini SDR tuner stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parts I need: a short adapter cable that provides antenna in for the SDR stick as a headphone jack socket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SDR tuner comes with an antenna, but I want to replace it with a dipole - especially one cut to have a center point for FM broadcast on 88.3 (WCBN) and a second one for 2 meter ham radio on local repeaters (W8UM on 145.23 and N8DUY on 145.15). Some sort of adapter jack (or alligator clips) should be all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can test the antenna on my Nokia 635 which has an FM tuner connected with the headphone jack as the antenna, and the ideal situation will be to have an antenna that I can just plug either into my phone or into my SDR tuner interchangeably. Once I figure all that out, the next next step is to make these antenna inputs for other radios. One step at a time though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be working from the tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;http://willus.com/author/antenna.shtml&#34;&gt;Making a Dipole FM Antenna&lt;/a&gt; on willus.com .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two repaired shortwave receivers in one day !</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the fix-it-yourself department, two successful radio repairs in one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my dad&#39;s old Kenwood R-2000, a replaced 100ma 5x20mm fuse brought it back to life. The antenna fuse search took a rather long time to get started, but the help of the UMARC club and Dean KD8VXR was enough to unearth the right part. For reference the Mouser part number is 693-0034.3107 for a Schurter fuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my old Sony ICF-2010, a fresh set of AA batteries for the computer was enough to get it going again. I&#39;m especially happy about the Sony because I had feared that it was a complicated repair. There&#39;s some corrosion on the battery terminals and I might be forewarned that would be the first thing to look at again. A discussion of another repair is written up by &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlenot.com/?p=1481&#34;&gt;KE1RI&lt;/a&gt; to replace an audio capacitor, fortunately I haven&#39;t had to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both stations are tuned to R Havana Cuba&#39;s Sunday night programming on 6000 KHz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W8UM 145.23 repeater for Sunday night net, 19 April 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-19-w8um-14523-repeater-for-sunday-night-net-19-april-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 21:06:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-19-w8um-14523-repeater-for-sunday-night-net-19-april-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As seen with gqrx on my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c77c1585970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c77c1585970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-04-19 at 8.15.39 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-04-19 at 8.15.39 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c77c1585970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The readout on the radio says 145.2169 Mhz instead of 145.2300 Mhz, I think that means the receiver has drifted 16.1 KHz from peak, or perhaps the listed frequency is not what I&#39;m looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson. Ann captured the opening slide. There was a nifty online multiplayer game (can&#39;t recall the site it was built on) which had 95 people playing along from their smart phones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skywarn Spotter Training in A2 now! Hanging w/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jhritz&#34;&gt;@jhritz&lt;/a&gt; Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NWSDetroit&#34;&gt;@NWSDetroit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/0X078Jl5Dg&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/0X078Jl5Dg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; annyhanny (@annyhanny) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annyhanny/status/586890972371386368&#34;&gt;April 11, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My spotter ID good for 2 years is 242.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought my radio to the event and made a contact from the car with Marty KD8RGL from Canton MI. We were both using 5 watt radios contacting the W8UM repeater in Ann Arbor - I&#39;m always surprised how well things work when they do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered that it works a lot better to identify myself as &#34;Eddie&#34; when on the air. This because &#34;Ed&#34; gets misinterpreted as &#34;Andy&#34; all too often, and &#34;Edward&#34; seems awfully formal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plane spotting; some quick notes on a new software-defined radio setup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 18:50:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-29 at 9.50.47 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-29 at 9.50.47 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 490px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-30 at 11.35.53 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-30 at 11.35.53 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b-500wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I got one of the first-generation RTL-SDR USB software defined radio units. These inexpensive devices are originally designed as TV tuners, but clever radio hackers figured out how to turn them into software-defined radios that tune to a broad spectrum of radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some experimental use I managed to cook the original unit which in its death throes no longer listened. The vendor (Nooelec) generously offered a modest discount on my next purchase, so I took them up on the 2d generation unit. Same form factor, bright blue in color, and the supplied antenna is a retractable whip with a magnetic base. As always it comes with no documentation and no software (you are expected to provide those).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had previously used a version of &#34;gqrx&#34; as a radio receiver, in a package that had been built for the Mac. This time I thought I&#39;d build from source. I went to the &#39;homebrew&#39; port system and found a version that said it worked for OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), but I&#39;m on OS X 10.9 (Mavericks) and the build didn&#39;t work (it crapped out in building scipy). Reading the documentation more closely the distribution says it&#39;s available through Macports, so I installed that and did &#34;sudo port install gnuradio&#34; and &#34;sudo port install gqrx&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macports is one of those amazing feats of modern software engineering where someone (or really a lot of people) have carefully and meticulously figured out how to take a package of source code and make it build, including tracing all of the dependencies upon which everything else needs to be built. For gqrx and GNU Radio this means (at the very bottom) that I had to have a working FORTRAN compiler so that I could compile the FORTRAN code hiding in the numerical analysis libraries. This brings me right back to the 1970s learning FORTRAN at Michigan Tech in their Summer Youth Program. I can&#39;t even imagine how old the code was that I compiled but it might actually date from then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything did build just fine, and then I had a radio. The first test is always to tune into WCBN, which came in with a strong signal, and to key up my ham radio transmitter via Echolink to make the W8UM repeater make some noise, and to get some weather radio going. Everything I tried worked just fine and passed with flying colors, the gqrx software is more modern than it once was in a couple of very helpful ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was to grab one of the many versions of &#34;dump1090&#34; which uses the SDR radio to tune to aircraft ADS-B broadcasts that give you a version of aircraft radar. This also worked well, perhaps better than I could have expected. From home with an antenna in the middle of the house I could hear airplanes just north of Jackson, MI from Ann Arbor, MI (about 40 miles). I relocated to a cafe near the dog park (Ellsworth at Platt) that has a good view of the southern sky, and the same little bitty antenna pulled in reception from airplanes near Fort Wayne, IN (about 120 miles). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s always more to try, of course. GNU Radio is a full toolkit for building your own radio design, complete with FM decoders and the like, and it has a fairly simple to understand user interface compared to how complex the underpinnings are (remember, FORTRAN). There&#39;s lots more software that uses the RTL-SDR libraries and even a port to the Raspberry Pi which I&#39;d like to try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Radio Havana Cuba via shortwave</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-17-listening-to-radio-havana-cuba-via-shortwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 15:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-17-listening-to-radio-havana-cuba-via-shortwave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Radio Havana Cuba was one of my cold war era shortwave radio presets. I don&#39;t have a working shortwave radio of my own any more, and the miracle of the Internet means that you can now tune in broadcasts directly from the broadcaster without the inconvenience of shortwave tuning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way really to listen to a station like R Havana Cuba is via shortwave. Here are a couple of ways that you can do that. Note that broadcasts in English are not 24 hours a day, and that shortwave reception varies widely by time of day and location of receiving station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to do this is to acquaint yourself with &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.org/&#34;&gt;WebSDR&lt;/a&gt;, a project that allows multiple listeners to tune into the signal of a single wideband radio. You&#39;ll need to pick a receiver that has an antenna that covers the appropriate part of the broadcast band, and you&#39;ll need also a schedule for when the station is broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many shortwave schedules and stations can be located via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.short-wave.info/&#34;&gt;short-wave.info&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0abdf50970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0abdf50970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-12-17 at 3.30.59 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-12-17 at 3.30.59 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0abdf50970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a schedule and a frequency, use WebSDR to find a suitable listening location. My two favorites for monitoring Havana are the original &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/&#34;&gt;WedSDR at U Twente&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://96.225.100.244:8902/&#34;&gt;K2SDR in New Jersey&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can tune in via &lt;a href=&#34;http://tunein.com/radio/Radio-Havana-Cuba-p1687/&#34;&gt;TuneIn&lt;/a&gt; and get to the broadcast direct. The sound will be more clear, and the reception more reasonable. But there&#39;s really something to be said for experiencing broadcast radio through the medium of radio rather than this newfangled Internet thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Echolink and websdr</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-09-some-notes-on-echolink-and-websdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 01:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-09-some-notes-on-echolink-and-websdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Echolink is a system that lets amateur radio operators transmit from their computer, through a relay at a suitable Echolink server. You have to be a licensed ham to get on the network, and typically there&#39;s a two-way repeater set up to some radio station so that you can hear what&#39;s being said on RF and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;websdr is a system that lets anyone listen to a slice of radio spectrum. There are websdr servers running around the globe, each tuned in to some particular slice of the radio waves. Multiple people can tune in at the same time and hear their own piece of the airwaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing happens when you connect these two systems together. Some small number of the websdr receivers tune into the 2 meter band, which is the typical band used by Echolink. Using Echolink (or in my case the Mac application Echomac) I identified an Echolink host in the vicinity of the websdr receiver, then connected to it. Sure enough, I was able to hear my call sign back in through the websdr front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This little image shows the result. Transmitted via DM0ZHS, and monitored at http://129.187.5.188:8901/ on 145237.50 kHz, I&#39;m sending from Isen, Germany and receiving the transmission at the Olympic Tower in Munich, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0a4d614970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0a4d614970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 590px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-12-09 at 1.00.38 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-12-09 at 1.00.38 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0a4d614970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an emergency, call 911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;911 trunk lines can go down in storms. The Ann Arbor non-emergency police number is (734) 994-2911, put it in your cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirens: City sirens are tested on the second Tuesdays of the month at 1 pm. A small handful of us notice this and tweet SIRENS. Generally siren activation in any quantity will prompt twitter chatter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hashtags: #miwx is primary, but I also watch or post to #annarbor and #skywarn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amateur radio: get your ham radio license (check), an inexpensive handheld 2m VHF radio (check), a decent antenna (check), and Skywarn spotter training (to do for 2015). During severe weather monitor N8DUY 145.15 Mhz, located at the corner of I-94 and M-14 in Scio Township. Someone, somewhere, should have a Broadcastify feed for a scanner listening to that channel with backup power and good solid Internet; that&#39;s a missing link right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who to follow: you&#39;re going to have to figure some of that out by yourself, but the list https://twitter.com/vielmetti/lists/annarbor and https://twitter.com/vielmetti/lists/weather might be a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power outages: If you have a smart enough smart phone, get the DTE Energy mobile app. If not, add the DTE Energy number 800-477-4747 to your phone to report outages. Follow @dte_energy and use hashtag #poweroutage I guess. The DTE outage map: http://www.dteenergy.com/map/outage.html . A snapshot of the September 5, 2014 map is below after severe storms knocked out power to more than 10,000 subscribers in Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e105e16970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e105e16970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-05 at 10.05.48 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-05 at 10.05.48 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e105e16970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: if you report severe weather or storm damage or a power outage, give a neighborhood name or a cross street. If you don&#39;t know every neighborhood, Arborwiki can be a good place to look them up. Find at least one other person who is geographically nearby to you and follow them - there&#39;s no where near the neighborhood density on Twitter that there is on Facebook or email, but in Ann Arbor at least the network is dense enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameras: Post your favorite weather photos or videos to your favorite social network. Note that the current structure of Twitter, Instagram, and Vine all lend themselves to real-time reporting in ways that Facebook does not, but Facebook and Youtube might reach more people over all if your post is interesting. Tag with your favorite hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teenage Twitter: Adults and teens don&#39;t often mix on Twitter, so it&#39;s good to follow parents of teens who will relay news and give you a heads up about what&#39;s happening. As an alternative, create a Twitter list of teenagers and don&#39;t follow them but do check in when conditions warrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adult Twitter: Teens and adults don&#39;t often mix on Twitter, so it&#39;s good to follow teenagers whose parents are also on Twitter who will similarly relay news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College Twitter: Sometimes the U of Michigan seems like it&#39;s its own city within a city, but during severe weather the official @umich account will be aware of what&#39;s going on especially if there are alerts that need to go to all students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local government Twitter: In an emergency, call 911. The @a2gov account is not always monitored, but when it is monitored during weather it can be helpful to guide you through the maze of municipal issues to report a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real time lightning maps: Several services have real time or near real time lightning. I like the non-commercial blitzortung.org and its companion site lightningmaps.org . &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Day Tech Class: Saturday, May 3, 2014 9a-3p at Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Dan Romanchik KB6NU &lt;a href=&#34;&amp;#x6D;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x6C;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6F;:&amp;#x63;&amp;#x77;&amp;#103;&amp;#x65;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#64;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#98;&amp;#x36;&amp;#x6E;&amp;#x75;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;m&#34;&gt;&amp;#x63;&amp;#x77;&amp;#103;&amp;#x65;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#64;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#98;&amp;#x36;&amp;#x6E;&amp;#x75;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;m&lt;/a&gt; - lightly edited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Romanchik, KB6NU will be conducting the next One-Day Tech Class will be held on Saturday, May 3, 2014 from 9am to 3pm at  the Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum, 220 E. Ann St. Ann Arbor, MI 48104.  Immediately after the class, the Technician Class license exam will be administered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-registration is required, and there is a $10 fee to take the class. We often fill the class and have to put people on the waiting list. So, if you&#39;d like to take this class, you should send a check or money order sooner rather than later to reserve their spot. Dan&#39;s address is 1325 Orkney Drive, Ann Arbor, MI 48103. People can also pay via PayPal by sending $10 to cwgeek@kb6nu.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a $15 fee to take the test. This fee is payable to the volunteer examiners just before they take the test. DO NOT send me the $15 exam fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prospective students can download the study guide from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/tech-manual&#34;&gt;www.kb6nu.com/tech-manual&lt;/a&gt;. Read through it a couple of times and take some online practice tests (URLs for practice test websites can be found in the study guide) before taking the test.  They greatly increase the chances that you will pass the test if you do some studying beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please send an email to cwgeek@kb6nu.com or phone Dan at 734-930-6564.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;73!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Romanchik, KB6NU&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>decoding radio digital modes without a radio, using WebSDR and fldigi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 02:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in decoding radio digital modes without actually having a radio. The idea is that by using a web-based software defined radio (to tune in the signals) and the fldigi program (to decode the signals) that I should be able to &amp;ldquo;listen&amp;rdquo; to digital modes and start to explore the digital parts of the amateur and broadcast radio bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Fldigi-HB9ERN&#34; title=&#34;Fldigi-HB9ERN&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I have all of the components, but I have yet to be able to get everything to work as expected. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/&#34;&gt;WebSDR&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/&#34;&gt;http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/&lt;/a&gt; . This is a software-defined radio tuning  to the radio airwaves at the University of Twente in the Netherlands; it runs in your browser. There are 87 of these systems running around the world, listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.org/&#34;&gt;websdr.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w1hkj.com/Fldigi.html&#34;&gt;fldigi&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w1hkj.com/Fldigi.html&#34;&gt;http://www.w1hkj.com/Fldigi.html&lt;/a&gt; . This software for Windows, Linux and OS X, runs on your local system and takes an audio signal and decodes it in one of many digital modes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/soundflower/&#34;&gt;Soundflower&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/soundflower/&#34;&gt;https://code.google.com/p/soundflower/&lt;/a&gt; . This is a Mac system extension that allows you to redirect the audio output of one program (e.g. your browser) into the audio input of another program (e.g. fldigi). Not strictly necessary because the fldigi can also just decode whatever it hears through the computer&amp;rsquo;s built in microphone. I picked up the recommendation from an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hamradioandvision.com/websdr-digital-modes/&#34;&gt;HamRadioAndVision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of people have done Youtube videos describing what they are doing to make this work. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oz9aec.net/index.php/component/content/article/63-sdr/290-fun-with-websdr-and-fldigi&#34;&gt;OZ9AEC&lt;/a&gt; has a 6 minute Youtube from 2009 shows reception in single channel and multichannel mode. He doesn&#39;t use Soundflower, just the built in mic of his Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not described here - and probably what I need to figure out next - are two key bits of information. Where do you tune to pick up digital signals? And, more importantly, which decoder do you use? It&#39;s not hard to pick out which modulation is being used if you have some practice, but as of this writing I couldn&#39;t readily tell you what WEFAX sounds like compared to RTTY. Still sorting through those details before I can claim to have mastered this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note also that this should work with a local software-defined radio as well, or even with a &#34;hardware-defined radio&#34; placed near your mic or patched in with a mic cable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to baseball online with Global Tuners radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-listening-to-baseball-online-with-global-tuners-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 12:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-listening-to-baseball-online-with-global-tuners-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not easy to do, but with a little bit of perseverance and a little bit of luck you may be able to listen to your favorite baseball team online without an MLB subscription by way of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globaltuners.com&#34;&gt;Global Tuners&lt;/a&gt;. Here&#39;s how it works (and why it&#39;s hard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you&#39;ll need a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globaltuners.com&#34;&gt;Global Tuners&lt;/a&gt; account. This service provides you access to dozens of AM, FM, and short wave receivers around the world. The way it works is that the receivers are hooked up to a digital front end that lets you tune them remotely and that plays back the audio through the net. In general only one person can tune in at a time, so it&#39;s first come first served. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, you&#39;ll need to have some idea of which AM and FM stations your favorite team&#39;s radio network covers. For example, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroit.tigers.mlb.com/det/schedule/radioaffiliates.jsp&#34;&gt;Detroit Tigers radio network&lt;/a&gt; has AM and FM station ranging from Houghton in the U.P. to Toledo Ohio and Angola Indiana, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://houston.astros.mlb.com/hou/schedule/radio_affiliates.jsp&#34;&gt;Houston Astros radio network&lt;/a&gt; also covers San Antonio and Shreveport. If the Tigers play the Astros, you can possibly tune to either network&#39;s stations - you&#39;ll either get home or away team coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, and here&#39;s the tricky part, you&#39;ll want to figure out which of the tuners covers which of the stations you are interested in. As it happens none of the tuners cover any stations that the Tigers routinely broadcast on, but the Astros are on KTKR 760 AM &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ticket760.com/main.html&#34;&gt;Ticket 760&lt;/a&gt; in San Antonio, and there&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globaltuners.com/receiver/info.php?r=1155&#34;&gt;receiver in San Antonio&lt;/a&gt; that might be free to listen through to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out radio channels can be weird - some stations have higher power and transmit over clear channels for long distances, and others don&#39;t cover much more ground than the city they are based in. So the &#34;best&#34; channel to tune in might be for a station that&#39;s powerful but far away. When you search through the MLB.com site for stations, look for the &#34;flagship&#34; station listed, which often broadcasts with higher power and over a greater distance than the other stations in the network. As an example, here&#39;s a report of &lt;a href=&#34;http://globaltuners.blogspot.com/2011/10/knbr.html&#34;&gt;hearing the San Francisco Giants&lt;/a&gt; from a tuner in Phoenix, AZ more than 600 miles away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The signal was weak at a distance of over 650 miles, with little interference from other stations but some noise and fading.  Nonetheless, the content was usable and the station IDs clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hobby of DXing gets an extra boost when you can tune in to radios that are far away. It&#39;s fun to scan the dial and hear what&#39;s out there. Most tuners have a band scan listing that you can see what&#39;s there. I listen to remote radio stations on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunein.com&#34;&gt;Tunein&lt;/a&gt; as well, but there&#39;s not the same sense of being there when the reception is too perfect, and the baseball powers that be block internet-based games over regular radio channels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TuneIn: listen to broadcast radio from all over the world</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Tunein-appicon-free&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019103316b58970c-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Tunein-appicon-free&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&amp;#39;m fond of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tunein.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;TuneIn&lt;/a&gt;, a free service that lets you tune in to radio broadcasts from all over the world. I used it last night to listen to Pacific Coast League AAA baseball, and I&amp;#39;ve previously tuned in hockey games, news stations from far-away places when there&amp;#39;s breaking news, and the occasional music channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the remarkable things about TuneIn is that they have program schedules for the stations they are following, and so you can get real time updates for what&amp;#39;s playing now and who&amp;#39;s playing whom. The front page rotates new songs that if you&amp;#39;re a quick click you can hear more or less in their entirety as they are being broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particularly useful part of TuneIn is its &amp;quot;trending&amp;quot; tab, where it gives you real time feedback on which channels have the most activity. When people are listening primarily to music, it&amp;#39;s a slow news day; when the top station is an all-news local channel, there&amp;#39;s breaking news.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=tunein.player&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;TuneIn Android app&lt;/a&gt; has nearly all of the features of the web site, and it takes advantage of knowing where you are to offer up local stations. In addition there&amp;#39;s a &amp;quot;TuneIn Radio Pro&amp;quot;, which gives you record and rewind for $4.99. There has to be a monetization strategy in there somewhere; they also serve up ads as you connect to some channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended. For public safety scanner monitoring, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broadcastify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Broadcastify&lt;/a&gt; is a good complement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the W8UM net looks like in software defined radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-what-the-w8um-net-looks-like-in-software-defined-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-what-the-w8um-net-looks-like-in-software-defined-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sample screen grab from tonight&amp;#39;s W8UM net on 145.23. Please note that the radio I&amp;#39;m using looks like it&amp;#39;s out of tune a little bit, since I&amp;#39;m actually listening here on 145.217.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ce9139f970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot 2013-06-02 at 8.07.22 PM&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ce9139f970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ce9139f970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2013-06-02 at 8.07.22 PM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a good clear strong signal (the red/yellow line), even with the not very good antenna I have; it should be, since the transmitter is only about a mile from here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>