<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hazen Schumacher of Jazz Revisited</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-hazen-schumacher/</guid>
      <description>Hazen Schumacher was a radio broadcaster who hosted the popular &amp;ldquo;Jazz Revisited&amp;rdquo; show on NPR and Michigan Radio (WUOM) for 30 years. He died on July 18, 2015.
Arborwiki&amp;rsquo;s page on Hazen Schumacher has memories of him and his program. The jazz collection that he assembled and all of the master tapes for the show are now at the Jazz Museum Bix Eiben Hamburg, and 24 editions of the program are up online for your listening at http://bixrevisited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Midland G-227 GMRS/FRS radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 11:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-midland-g-227/</guid>
      <description>Midland G-227 GMRS radio, quantity two, a gift from the Wells-Becker Motorcycle Emporium in Dexter, Michigan.
I replaced batteries in both of them, they take 4xAAA.
Radio 1 successfully hears static when the (M) monitor button is depresssed; Radio 2 hears nothing.
A manual is at http://www.manualslib.com/manual/396326/Midland-G-225.html which describes the frequencies of the 22 channels it can transmit on. A reasonable next step is to get my NooElec SDR tuner out and see if I can monitor a transmission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two repaired shortwave receivers in one day !</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</guid>
      <description>From the fix-it-yourself department, two successful radio repairs in one day.
For my dad Lewis Peters&amp;rsquo;s old Kenwood R-2000, a replaced 100ma 5x20mm fuse brought it back to life. The antenna fuse search took a rather long time to get started, but the help of the UMARC club and Dean KD8VXR was enough to unearth the right part. For reference the Mouser part number is 693-0034.3107 for a Schurter fuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W8UM 145.23 repeater for Sunday night net, 19 April 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-19-w8um-14523-repeater-for-sunday-night-net-19-april-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 21:06:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-19-w8um-14523-repeater-for-sunday-night-net-19-april-2015/</guid>
      <description>As seen with gqrx on my Mac.

The readout on the radio says 145.2169 Mhz instead of 145.2300 Mhz, I think that means the receiver has drifted 16.1 KHz from peak, or perhaps the listed frequency is not what I&#39;m looking at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.
I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Radio Havana Cuba via shortwave</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-17-listening-to-radio-havana-cuba-via-shortwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 15:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-17-listening-to-radio-havana-cuba-via-shortwave/</guid>
      <description>Radio Havana Cuba was one of my cold war era shortwave radio presets. I don&#39;t have a working shortwave radio of my own any more, and the miracle of the Internet means that you can now tune in broadcasts directly from the broadcaster without the inconvenience of shortwave tuning.
The best way really to listen to a station like R Havana Cuba is via shortwave. Here are a couple of ways that you can do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on Echolink and websdr</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-09-some-notes-on-echolink-and-websdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 01:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-09-some-notes-on-echolink-and-websdr/</guid>
      <description>Echolink is a system that lets amateur radio operators transmit from their computer, through a relay at a suitable Echolink server. You have to be a licensed ham to get on the network, and typically there&#39;s a two-way repeater set up to some radio station so that you can hear what&#39;s being said on RF and vice versa.
websdr is a system that lets anyone listen to a slice of radio spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter:
In an emergency, call 911.
911 trunk lines can go down in storms. The Ann Arbor non-emergency police number is (734) 994-2911, put it in your cell phone.
Sirens: City sirens are tested on the second Tuesdays of the month at 1 pm. A small handful of us notice this and tweet SIRENS. Generally siren activation in any quantity will prompt twitter chatter. Hashtags: #miwx is primary, but I also watch or post to #annarbor and #skywarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Day Tech Class: Saturday, May 3, 2014 9a-3p at Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-25-one-day-tech-class-saturday-may-3-2014-9a-3p-at-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum/</guid>
      <description>From Dan Romanchik KB6NU &amp;#x63;&amp;#x77;&amp;#103;&amp;#x65;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#64;&amp;#x6B;&amp;#98;&amp;#x36;&amp;#x6E;&amp;#x75;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;m - lightly edited:
Dan Romanchik, KB6NU will be conducting the next One-Day Tech Class will be held on Saturday, May 3, 2014 from 9am to 3pm at the Ann Arbor Hands-On Museum, 220 E. Ann St. Ann Arbor, MI 48104. Immediately after the class, the Technician Class license exam will be administered. Pre-registration is required, and there is a $10 fee to take the class. We often fill the class and have to put people on the waiting list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to baseball online with Global Tuners radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-listening-to-baseball-online-with-global-tuners-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 12:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-listening-to-baseball-online-with-global-tuners-radio/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s not easy to do, but with a little bit of perseverance and a little bit of luck you may be able to listen to your favorite baseball team online without an MLB subscription by way of Global Tuners. Here&#39;s how it works (and why it&#39;s hard).
First, you&#39;ll need a Global Tuners account. This service provides you access to dozens of AM, FM, and short wave receivers around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TuneIn: listen to broadcast radio from all over the world</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m fond of TuneIn, a free service that lets you tune in to radio broadcasts from all over the world. I used it last night to listen to Pacific Coast League AAA baseball, and I&amp;#39;ve previously tuned in hockey games, news stations from far-away places when there&amp;#39;s breaking news, and the occasional music channel.
One of the remarkable things about TuneIn is that they have program schedules for the stations they are following, and so you can get real time updates for what&amp;#39;s playing now and who&amp;#39;s playing whom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strait, AM 1610 The Station, Detroit Electronic Vinyl on Saturday nights 10 pm to midnight</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-the-strait-am-1610-the-station-detroit-electronic-vinyl-on-saturday-nights-10-pm-to-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 22:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-the-strait-am-1610-the-station-detroit-electronic-vinyl-on-saturday-nights-10-pm-to-midnight/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite radio shows is from an utterly obscure low power AM radio station in Hamtramck, which puts out an ultra lofi low power over-the-air signal on AM 1610 and a digital broadcast on http://am1610.org . The show is &amp;quot;The Strait&amp;quot;, which features Detroit electronic vinyl. It&amp;#39;s on Saturday nights from 10:00 p.m. to midnight, and it&amp;#39;s always worth a listen.&amp;#0160;
Some day I&amp;#39;ll get to Hamtramck and do an air check and make sure I can actually tune this in - I don&amp;#39;t know if they cover the whole city or just a piece of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to (and participating in!) the W8UM net for Sunday, November 18, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-18-listening-to-and-participating-in-the-w8um-net-for-sunday-november-18-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 21:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-18-listening-to-and-participating-in-the-w8um-net-for-sunday-november-18-2012/</guid>
      <description>My friend Dan KB6NU&amp;#0160;was network control for the W8UM net tonight at 8:00 p.m. Eastern&amp;#0160;(145.230 MHz, -600 kHz shift, 100 Hz PL). This was my first try at being on for the net, and so I waited patiently until my radio started making noises other than static.
After most everyone else checked in, I hit the transmit button and gave my call sign (KD8OQG) and was acknowledged by Dan.&amp;#0160;
Among other things discussed tonight:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geek tour: WCBN-FM control room, Wednesday, November 14, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</guid>
      <description>a2geeks is hosting a tour of the WCBN-FM control room on Wednesday, November 14, 2012. Tours start at 5:30p, 6:30p, and 7:30p, and you should RSVP for your space. (I&amp;#39;ll be at the 5:30pm tour.)
WCBN is an amazing student-run radio station at the University of Michigan, founded in 1972 and broadcasting from the basement of the Student Activities Building. Listen live to WCBN at 88.3 FM (all the way to the left on your dial) or online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to five channels of CBC Radio 2</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-02-listening-to-five-channels-of-cbc-radio-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 14:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-02-listening-to-five-channels-of-cbc-radio-2/</guid>
      <description>CBC&amp;#39;s Radio 2 has 5 channels of online music going at any time, reflecting the need to provide programming from the Atlantic Time Zone to the Pacific Time Zone. Newfoundland, a half hour east of the Atlantic Time Zone, gets a shout out from time to time but not its own time slot.
It&amp;#39;s nice to have a choice of five channels, because sometimes you want to have mid-day classical music, and some days you want to have afternoon popular music, and in this way you can just time-shift your listening all from the same page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Tuners - listening to far-off radio stations</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-14-global-tuners-listening-to-far-off-radio-stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-14-global-tuners-listening-to-far-off-radio-stations/</guid>
      <description>Global Tuners is a worldwide project for people to share their shortwave radio receivers. There are about 50 tuners around the world, and once you create an account you can log in to each of them, change the tuning settings, and listen to the broadcasts that can be heard in that part of the world.

I have an old shortwave set that was my stepdad&amp;rsquo;s, and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to pull in stations from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing the elusive weather balloon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-08-chasing-the-elusive-weather-balloon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 08:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-08-chasing-the-elusive-weather-balloon/</guid>
      <description>Thursday&amp;#39;s adventure was George Albercook&amp;#39;s launch and successful retrieval of a weather balloon, with a payload of radios, cameras, and GPS telemetry.
Here&amp;#39;s a map of the telemetry that was visible through APRS.FI&amp;#0160;for the duration of the launch. The device is identified as KC8SBA. Note that for some reason tracking didn&amp;#39;t pick up until a few minutes after the launch, and the tracking was also silent for a while until just before the descent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area FM radio, scanning left to right on your radio dial</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</guid>
      <description>A band scan from Ann Arbor, with notes especially on how to get ahold of the station if you like the tunes being played. This list is incomplete, because you can always have a better radio with a better antenna that can pick out one more low power station at the edge of its range. It&#39;s also incomplete, because it only points to stations I&#39;m likely to listen to, and because it&#39;s starting at the left edge of the dial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you tune into during severe weather?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 22:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>I get all the news I need from the weather report. Here&amp;#39;s where I get the weather report from.
Twitter, to chat with people who are also in their basements. The local hash tag is #miwx for severe weather. I have a list @vielmetti/weather that I follow for the news.
Weather Underground for radar and forecasts and what not. I like the classic version of the user interface, which is busy and deep and which I know well enough to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spooky Talk on AM 1610 The Station</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-spooky-talk-on-am-1610-the-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 09:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-spooky-talk-on-am-1610-the-station/</guid>
      <description>Spooky Talk is the talk show that&amp;#39;s spooky. It&amp;#39;s on weekly on AM 1610 The Station in Hamtramck on Sunday at midnight, after the 10 p.m. The Strait show which plays Detroit electronic vinyl.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Gears, NPR project adding staff for Rustbelt local coverage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 00:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Award-winning journalists from public media, the Web and newspapers are now part of the Changing Gears team. via www.changinggears.info
National Public Radio launching local coverage out of Cleveland, Ann Arbor, and Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>study for the ham radio exam</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-08-study-for-the-ham-radio-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 02:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-08-study-for-the-ham-radio-exam/</guid>
      <description>An online study guide should help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do before the network goes down: emergency preparation for Michigan summer storms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-30-what-to-do-before-the-network-goes-down-emergency-preparation-for-michigan-summer-storms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-30-what-to-do-before-the-network-goes-down-emergency-preparation-for-michigan-summer-storms/</guid>
      <description>Every summer there are thunderstorms in southeastern Michigan, and every year some part of the networks (power, phone, cable, cell phone, traffic lights, twitter) go down.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a roundup of some things you can add to your emergency communications checklist so that when the weather goes sour you are prepared to be safe.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m leaving a few of them blank where I don&amp;#39;t know the answer, so check the comments on this for the fill in the blanks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Harvey (as played by Rich Hall), 1987</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-28-paul-harvey-as-played-by-rich-hall-1987/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 22:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-28-paul-harvey-as-played-by-rich-hall-1987/</guid>
      <description>Paul Harvey passed away today at the age of 90.
Rich Hall played him on Saturday Night Live - a clip I can&#39;t find right now - and also in this 1987 Showtime special I found on Youtube.   Time Magazine&#39;s obituary talks a bit about the Rich Hall piece on SNL: A salesman for himself and his vision of the American dream, he was also a master peddler of many products, whose makers were as loyal to Harvey as his listeners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>