<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sabra Briere on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/sabra-briere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sabra Briere on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/sabra-briere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I voted, summer 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-i-voted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor is one of three peculiar communities in the state of Michigan
to have partisan City Council elections; the other two are Ypsilanti and
Ionia. This has in recent years meant that the races that decide the makeup
of City Council happen in the summer when students are gone and when
voter turnout is very low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did vote, and I do plan to go to at least one of the parties celebrating
victory or acknowledging defeat by the candidates who have the remaining
funds from their campaign to put out a nice spread for supporters, hangers-on,
or the perpetually politically curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few rounds of picking up result tapes from Ward Four precincts, I ended up
at Arbor Brewing Company which was Council Party HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Sabra Briere&lt;/span&gt; over Will Leaf, handily with 70%+ of the vote,
though only 6% of registered voters actually voted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Ward: We&amp;rsquo;ll wait until the fall for this as Jane Lumm (I) meets
Sally Hart Petersen (D) in November.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Zachary Ackerman&lt;/span&gt; defeats Steve Kunselman by about 40 votes.
This was the surprise of the night. Ackerman&amp;rsquo;s entire margin of victory was
his strong showing in 3-3 (Burns Park) where he outpaced Kunselman 345-171.
Turnout was under 11%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fourth Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Jack Eaton&lt;/span&gt; defeats Jamie Magiera with about 60% of the vote.
Jack held his party at Wolverine Brewing; Jamie was at ABC, looking subdued.
Turnout was about 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifth Ward: &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Chip Smith&lt;/span&gt; defeated Mike Anglin with about 55% of the vote.
Voter turnout in the mighty Fifth Ward was strong compared to the other wards,
with a mighty 14% of the electorate turning out to vote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 85%+ of Ann Arbor voters who didn&amp;rsquo;t know enough or didn&amp;rsquo;t bother
to turn out to vote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://electionresults.ewashtenaw.org/electionreporting/aug2015/index.jsp&#34;&gt;UnOfficial Election Results, August 4, 2015 City Primary Election&lt;/a&gt;, Wasthenaw County&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Paid for by * for mayor of Ann Arbor&#34; - an analysis of campaign advertising &amp; disclosure</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 19:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After getting one too many political ads in my Facebook newsfeed, I started paying closer attention to the &#34;Paid for by&#34; language that I expect to see on every paid political campaign message. The mayoral candidates for the City of Ann Arbor all have some work ahead of them to get their disclosures in order for the 2014 campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked for campaign disclosures on Facebook pages, on Twitter feeds, and on event pages created by the campaign on Facebook. I also looked generally at Google, searching for the phrase in question. The four candidates for the Democratic side of the Ann Arbor mayoral ballot are Stephen Kunselman, Sally Hart Petersen, Sabra Briere and Christopher Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Kunselman: while I can find a &#34;Kunselman for Council&#34; web site, I can&#39;t locate a &#34;Kunselman for Mayor&#34; web site. The candidate&#39;s Facebook page doesn&#39;t mention the candidacy that I can see. I haven&#39;t seen any ads from the candidate yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sally Hart Petersen: No search results on Google for the mayoral campaign. A Facebook page for the candidate has 294 likes; in the header, it says &#34;Paid for by the Committee to Elect Sally Hart Petersen to Mayor&#34;, but that header omits the expected address of the committee. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sabra Briere: A search for &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for Mayor&#34; generates two pages. The http://sabrabriereformayor.org/ web page has &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for City Council&#34; at the bottom, in white type on a yellow background making it virtually unreadable; it also has bunches of Latin text where the real text should be, making me suspicious that it&#39;s not real. On Facebook, the page &#34;Vote for Sabra for Ann Arbor Mayor in the Democratic Primary on Tuesday August 5th 2014&#34; has invited 500 people, but has no &#34;Paid for by&#34; disclosure. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Sabra Briere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clearly, sabrabriereformayor.org is a non-working website.  A completely different set of pages should be up soon - but in the meantime, I changed the accent yellow to an accent blue - so the white lettering is now higher contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t at all ready to be published, and is just there as filler for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Taylor: A search for &#34;Paid for by Christopher Taylor for Mayor&#34; has 49 results, from the candidate&#39;s own web site and from &#34;ngpvanhost&#34;. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ngpvan.com/&#34;&gt;NGP VAN&lt;/a&gt; is a campaign website hosting platform for Democrats.) The &#34;Christopher Taylor for Ann Arbor&#34; Facebook page has 686 likes, with no &#34;Paid for by&#34; until you get to the &#34;Contribute&#34; page. Facebook ads for Taylor say &#34;Sponsored&#34;, but do not disclose who is paying for them in either the text of the ad or in the image associated with the ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Christopher Taylor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My understanding is that we included the proper disclosure language in the initial ad, but that for some reason it is not appearing. We&#39;re on it and will fix it pronto.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I appreciate the notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any of these clearcut campaign violations? Probably not. The relevant text of the law is &#34;Any other medium used for campaign purposes shall clearly and unequivocally include the identification or disclaimer, or both, provided in section 47 of the act.&#34; Michigan campaign finance law has not been updated to provide specific rules for Facebook (or Twitter), so you can&#39;t point to a specific line of text that says &#34;you did this wrong&#34;. Without specific guidance, there&#39;s wiggle room, and a wait for an opinion from the Attorney General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this &#34;flyspecking&#34;, as one candidate described my efforts, or mere &#34;piffle&#34; as another political operative chided me? It&#39;s still early in the race, but expectations are that this will be one of the most expensive political races in Ann Arbor mayoral history, with four primary campaigns going and an empty mayoral seat at stake. I fully expect my Facebook timeline and Google search results to be full of paid advertising, and that that advertising will get more and more political as the primary draws near. Close attention to who is paying how much for what is worthwhile, especially in the presence of &#34;free media&#34; like Facebook where you can sent out an unrelenting stream of updates and invites at no obvious direct cost to anyone except the poor reader who just wants to see funny cat videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>