<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Os X on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/os-x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Os X on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 16:53:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/os-x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker&#39;s new RunC doesn&#39;t (yet?) work on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-22-dockers-new-runc-doesnt-yet-work-on-mac-os-x-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 16:53:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-22-dockers-new-runc-doesnt-yet-work-on-mac-os-x-/</guid>
      <description>Docker has a new runtime environment that they are releasing called runC. It&#39;s a &#34;lightweight universal plumbing&#34; that tries to encapsulate all of the Docker dependencies and infrastructure.  To build Docker we have re-used large quantities of plumbing: Linux, Go, lxc, aufs, lvm, iptables, virtualbox, vxlan, mesos, etcd, consul, systemd… the list goes on.
 Because of Docker&#39;s start on Linux systems, it&#39;s been tricky to get it running under Mac OS X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Lag Monster a bit less laggy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-making-lag-monster-a-bit-less-laggy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 22:41:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-making-lag-monster-a-bit-less-laggy/</guid>
      <description>@tallervielmetti is using my old black Macbook. It&#39;s never been an exceptionally fast machine, but it&#39;s been super laggy of late, hence the name Lag Monster. I installed all kinds of crap on that machine to test it out, and never uninstalled a lot of it. It turns out that some judicious uninstalls seemed to help a lot to keep the load average down. Some hints to my future self if these ever re-emerge:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS 10.9.5 audio problems on MacBook Air</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-mac-os-1095-audio-problems-on-macbook-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 23:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-mac-os-1095-audio-problems-on-macbook-air/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms include no audio inputs when a headset is plugged in, but the built-in mic works fine when the headset is not plugged in.
sudo killall coreaudiod is one suggested fix.
This superuser.com article tells you how to reload Mac audio drivers without rebooting.
Thanks to Mohan Kartha for helping sort this out; still not convinced I can adequately fix it with these tools, or even that I have diagnosed the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I should have bought more memory for my Macbook sooner</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-i-should-have-bought-more-memory-for-my-macbook-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-i-should-have-bought-more-memory-for-my-macbook-sooner/</guid>
      <description>Ever since upgrading my Mac to 10.6.8 I&amp;#39;ve been running into memory problems, especially when I have a lot of Chrome windows open. I solved this problem - or I seem to have - by upgrading from 2G to 4G of memory, with memory from Crucial. Less than $100 spent, and the computer no longer starts to thrash when I have more than a few windows open.
Now of course it&amp;#39;s time to keep a lot more apps open to see what the new system limits are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce file size of PDFs on Macs with Preview&#39;s Quartz filter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-reduce-file-size-of-pdfs-on-macs-with-previews-quartz-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-reduce-file-size-of-pdfs-on-macs-with-previews-quartz-filter/</guid>
      <description>The screen capture should be self-explanatory; select &amp;quot;Save As&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PDF&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Reduce file size&amp;quot;.
 
Thanks to Marcy for the suggestion; she notes &amp;quot;I tell you, the cyber world is as finicky as we are.&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology upgrades are a tedious but necessary task</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-29-technology-upgrades-are-a-tedious-but-necessary-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 17:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-29-technology-upgrades-are-a-tedious-but-necessary-task/</guid>
      <description>Technology upgrades are a tedious but necessary task.  I&amp;#39;m going through this now, with an upgrade from Mac OS 10.5.8 to Mac OS 10.6.8 on my black MacBook. The world decided in its infinite wisdom that 10.5 was too old to keep supporting, and so quite a bit of software was starting to break. The promise is that 10.6.x will last a bit longer and keep my old 2008 vintage system running for a while longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spotty wifi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-04-the-problem-with-unreliablenetworks-is-that-you-have-to-engineer-extra-hard-to-be-able-to-make-use-of-them-and-you-still-ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 15:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-04-the-problem-with-unreliablenetworks-is-that-you-have-to-engineer-extra-hard-to-be-able-to-make-use-of-them-and-you-still-ca/</guid>
      <description>The problem with unreliable networks is that you have to engineer extra hard to be able to make use of them, and you still can&amp;#39;t rely on them even when you do.
Consider the network connection that&amp;#39;s randomly working and not working. If the network were actually down, you could work with that, knowing that eventually it would be a time and place that you could reconnect. Until then you stay offline in airplane mode and just chill and enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom, to go offline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-18-freedom-to-go-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 20:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-18-freedom-to-go-o/</guid>
      <description>Through some random chance encounter on the net - that is to say,
I don&#39;t remember why I found it - I&#39;m offline right now.
The tool of choice for going offline is a little Mac application
called Freedom, which disables your Internet access for a specified
period of time so that you can get things done. Written by Fred Stutzman at UNC.
 Freedom enforces freedom; a reboot is the only circumvention of the Freedom time limit you specify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook flickery pixels - diagnosing and fixing a screen hardware problem</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-05-macbook-flicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 11:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-05-macbook-flicker/</guid>
      <description>I have a Macbook, it&amp;rsquo;s partially broken right now.  There is a stripe of pixels top to bottom on the screen, about 1&amp;frasl;8 of the screen, running top to bottom that is flickering. It&amp;rsquo;s not what Apple calls a &amp;ldquo;pixel anomaly&amp;rdquo;, since it&amp;rsquo;s not a single isolated spot; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s a big stripe. It starts at the middle of the screen, and goes to the right from there.  I have Applecare (whew).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>