<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No Email on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/no-email/</link>
    <description>Recent content in No Email on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/no-email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to sending electronic mail; alternatives to receiving electronic mail</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>The weekend is a low email diet, but somehow that&amp;#39;s difficult to do without explaining myself a little bit. Here&amp;#39;s some thoughts as to how I might do things the next time that I work through the world of weekend time, how I can get some more effective communications rather than just more frequent.
Short asynchronous private message. A Twitter direct message works nicely for this, as does an SMS message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from a spell of no email, and starting a new one</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-recovery/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Sisyphus had it easy.&amp;quot;
I&amp;#39;ll be off email starting Friday night and continuing to Sunday night; the second weekend in a row of a &amp;quot;no email&amp;quot; weekend. It wasn&amp;#39;t quite 100% offline the first weekend, since I&amp;#39;m so addicted, but I made a point of not clicking on any messages in my inbox and not sending any mail.
Part of the plan for not doing email is making sure that at the end of the time you can recover gracefully and not feel overwhelmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No email for the weekend</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-03-no-email-for-the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-03-no-email-for-the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve updated my email vacation message to inform my correspondents that I&amp;#39;m taking the weekend off from electronic mail. If you get some message to that effect, you know how to get ahold of me.
I envy those with enough status to completely exit electronic mail, but at the very least I expect that an occasional weekend could be email-free.
Some background:
Paul Jones has given up on email, in his #noemail project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>