<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Github private repositories</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-06-01-github-private-repos/</guid>
      <description>Github has changed their pricing strategy to allow individual accounts to have more private repositories. This is a welcome change for accounts like mine.
As part of their change, enterprise pricing has increased. I&amp;rsquo;m told that this will multiply the bills that some companies will see.
This post tests a new private repo, and links to Github pricing for future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am eating a sandwich, with a recipe in Github</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-14-i-am-eating-a-sandwich-github-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-14-i-am-eating-a-sandwich-github-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is, of course, for telling people that you are eating a sandwich. That&amp;rsquo;s been the point of the system the whole time - long before selfies, even long before it took pictures at all, you might get a proper narrative of what people are eating for lunch or a snack.
Using the net to keep track of food is an old tradition; I need only point you at the Usenet Cookbook, developed from 1985 to 1987 by Brian Reid, as an archetype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The productivity oscillator</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Github issues for a long time as a todo list tracking and general productivity tool. It works well enough that I&amp;rsquo;ve opened over 4000 issues and have closed most of them.
The perpetual management challenge is in deciding how many issues is OK to leave open. Put too few in, and it feels like you have things to do that are not written down; put in too many, and you&amp;rsquo;re likely to have duplication and you forget what it is that you were trying to do in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing from Hugo to Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-publishing-from-hugo-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 17:20:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-publishing-from-hugo-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges in getting things started is figuring out where the end product is going to live. Hugo has its own web server which is pretty nice, but since it generates static pages, the results can really go anywhere.
This tutorial goes through the process in excruciating detail
http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/
but somehow fails to make it easy. What I&amp;rsquo;d like is a publishing workflow that just like the normal Hugo workflow puts things online instantly once they are built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gogs, a self-hosted Git server</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-27-gogs-a-self-hosted-git-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 23:06:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-27-gogs-a-self-hosted-git-server/</guid>
      <description>Gogs is a self-hosted Git server, an alternative to using Github as a for-pay hosted service or Gitlab as another self-hosted system. It&#39;s written in the Go language, and is said to be sparing of system resources.

I&#39;m building it using Docker on a Raspberry Pi 2, thanks to the folks at Hypriot; the writeup is Run your own GitHub-like service with the help of Docker, and the file on Dockerhub is at hypriot/rpi-gogs-raspbian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>