<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aviation on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/aviation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aviation on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:44:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/aviation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The mysterious crash of</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-the-mysterious-crash-of-4u9525-germanwings-flight-9525-in-the-french-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:44:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-the-mysterious-crash-of-4u9525-germanwings-flight-9525-in-the-french-alps/</guid>
      <description>My Twitter feed was full of air crash news this morning. Germanwings flight 9525 crashed in the French Alps, killing all passengers aboard. Wikipedia has a good summary, perhaps as good as any.
What was unusual about the crash was that there was no distress call, and that the plane descended rapidly and steadily into the ground without veering once from its course.
Of note in this regard is another European flight on a similar aircraft some months earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mystery of flight MH370</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-the-mystery-of-flight-mh370/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-the-mystery-of-flight-mh370/</guid>
      <description>I was up late the other night when the news that Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 was missing came out. There was a flurry of speculation as to its whereabouts, but no hard news. I went to bed figuring that by morning the mystery would be resolved.
That was four days ago, and the plane is still missing and the mystery has only deepened. Short of going on a search and rescue mission yourself, the closest that anyone can do to chip in on the search is to join in on Tomnod which has a crowd-sourced digital image recognition system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asiana Airlines Flight 214, a Boeing 777, crash lands at San Francisco Airport with 307 on board</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-06-asiana-airlines-flight-214-a-boeing-777-crash-lands-at-san-francisco-airport-with-303-on-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 16:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-06-asiana-airlines-flight-214-a-boeing-777-crash-lands-at-san-francisco-airport-with-303-on-board/</guid>
      <description>Asiana Airlines Flight 214, a Boeing 777, crash landed at San Francisco Airport on Saturday, July, 2013 with 307 passengers and crew on board. As of this writing (1:19 PM PT) there are no confirmed fatalities, but it&amp;#39;s too early yet to give a final accounting. The plane did not report any problems before landing, and caught fire on the ground.
SFO airport was closed for several hours, and flights were diverted to other area airports.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>