<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autofocus on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/autofocus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autofocus on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 17:45:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/autofocus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>autofocus - yet another productivity algorithm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-15-autofocus-yet-another-productivity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 17:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-15-autofocus-yet-another-productivity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markforster.net/blog/&#34;&gt;Mark Forster has a new productivity system which he calls Autofocus.&amp;#0160;&lt;/a&gt; There&amp;#39;s the obligatory blog, video, twitter account, glowing Lifehacker review etc etc.&amp;#0160; If you care, you&amp;#39;ll look them up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many systems, this one relies on making one list and then working your way through it.&amp;#0160; The twist on this system vs. some others is that for the most part there is very little attempt to produce metadata about the parts of your list that you&amp;#39;re working on.&amp;#0160; Rather that giving tasks tags, categories, priorities, precedence, importance, geographic location, or anything else, you simply step through your list one page at a time.&amp;#0160; To decide what to do next you contemplate all of the unsolved tasks on that page, and when one of them jumps out at you, you do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The page at a time approach ensures that you don&amp;#39;t spend all your time in contemplation and that there&amp;#39;s a finite and shrinking list of things to contemplate.&amp;#0160; The lack of explicit sorting means that you can engage in constructive procrastination to do something that needs to be done without feeling bad that the thing that has to be done is delayed.&amp;#0160; And the lack of tags etc. means that the cognitive overhead of keeping track of how you make a decision goes away - you just pick something and do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(One more piece of this that I haven&amp;#39;t done yet is the algorithm for deciding what not to do; apparently if you look at a page and nothing jumps out at you, you are to cross off everything on the page and not do them.&amp;#0160; And doing something partially is OK, you mark it off on the old page and re-enter it on the new page.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a weakness for new systems, if only because learning a new system means that you apply a new filter to the same old things that have been postponed for too long and you get a new way to handle a burst of attention.&amp;#0160; This one works well on paper and works with the reporter-style pocket notebook I&amp;#39;m using.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve used similar approaches before to exploring big problem sets - if you divide the whole set into small and manageable pieces, and do something useful with each of those pieces, then you can get through a lot without trying to optimize every decision.&amp;#0160; It works, for instance, as the strategy for picking out some new books to read from a library new bookshelf, just go one shelf at a time and pick something that catches your eye from each shelf.&amp;#0160; You can get through a lot that way - it won&amp;#39;t be everything, and it won&amp;#39;t be exhaustive, but the throughput in a system where lots of decisions are easy and lots of alternatives are exposed can be good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>