<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salad on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/salad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salad on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/salad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rice: prepare 1.5 cups rice according to your taste. Do this first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the broccoli: Preheat oven to 425 degrees F. Cut a few heads of broccoli into bite sized florets. Mix in a bowl with olive oil, then place on a cookie sheet. Sprinkle sea salt on top. Roast 12-15 minutes until the broccoli is every so slightly browned on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the garbanzos: Drain and rinse a can of garbanzos. Put in a small pot and cover with water. Heat until hot, then rinse again under cool water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the red peppers: Cut a red pepper into pieces about the size of a garbanzo bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Make a lemon vinaigrette with a little mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Some sweet chili paste, or gochujang, or your favorite spicy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the feta: crumble some feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve in individual bowls on the table, for people to mix their own salads. If your family is like mine, someone will eat just rice and peppers and beans, someone else will prefer the salad without feta, someone will want a vinaigrette and someone else (me) will douse the whole thing with chili sauce. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radish salad with soy and sesame dressing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-26-radish-salad-with-soy-and-sesame-dressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-26-radish-salad-with-soy-and-sesame-dressing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the simplest possible thing to make with a bunch of radishes fresh from farmers market ($1.25 this week).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;one bunch radishes&lt;br /&gt;vinegar&lt;br /&gt;soy sauce&lt;br /&gt;sesame oil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wash and trim the radishes.&amp;#0160; Slice thin, put in a bowl.&amp;#0160; Add vinegar (I used white vinegar, but rice vinegar would do well), soy sauce, and a little sesame oil; you&amp;#39;re after enough to moisten, not to cover.&amp;#0160; Let sit a few minutes before eating.&amp;#0160; Put the leftovers, if there are any, in the fridge; eat them while writing at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original recipe had sesame seeds, but I didn&amp;#39;t bother this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It should work with all kinds of radishes, and next time I have a daikon I&amp;#39;ll use this same recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slice the radishes thin; this didn&amp;#39;t work as well one time when I made them chunks.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve seen recipes where you do matchstick style slices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you insist on measuring the ingredients for this, you should tell me the proportions you use; I&amp;#39;ve done it enough times that I just pour in whatever seems reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>