<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 14:01:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The weak ties of your social network are its greatest strength</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 14:01:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-weak-ties-of-your-social-network/</guid>
      <description>Lior Zoref has a new book out called Mindsharing: the art of crowdsourcing everything (Portfolio / Penguin, 2015). I have a copy of it from the Ann Arbor District Library which was on the new shelf at Mallett&amp;rsquo;s Creek on a sunny and hot summer Sunday afternoon. Mallett&amp;rsquo;s has good air conditioning, a very good spot to be on a warm day.
 The challenge of a book like this is picking out the good bits without repeating the author&amp;rsquo;s technique of using the word &amp;ldquo;Mindsharing&amp;rdquo; (capitalized) at every opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I&#39;ve requested for the Ann Arbor District Library</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-books-ive-requested-for-the-ann-arbor-district-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 23:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-books-ive-requested-for-the-ann-arbor-district-library/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor District Library is really quite good about getting copies of new books for its bookshelves. You can request a title online, and very few reasonable requests for in-print materials available from publishers are turned down. (I haven&#39;t tried the equivalent for self-published books, but I suspect it&#39;s harder; that would be a good question.)
Alas, requesting a book does not immediately add you to the request list for the book, so you need to keep a task alive to search for the title or author in the hopes that it shows up soon enough (with &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United America, divided media?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-16-united-america-divided-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 12:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-16-united-america-divided-media/</guid>
      <description>If you look at American media you can see a sharp ideological divide. Television networks show notorious political biases, and book-buying habits show a schism between what those on the left read vs those on the right. If you looked only at media, you&#39;d think that we lived in two countries, red and blue, with hardly anything shared between the two sides.
Wayne Baker&#39;s new book United America looks at survey data from citizens across the country and comes to a different conclusions: that there are core American values that are common across the entirety of the political spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of Social Physics: How Good Ideas Spread — The Lessons from a New Science, Alex Pentland</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-09-a-review-of-social-physics-how-good-ideas-spread-the-lessons-from-a-new-science-alex-pentland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 18:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-09-a-review-of-social-physics-how-good-ideas-spread-the-lessons-from-a-new-science-alex-pentland/</guid>
      <description>A review of Social Physics: How Good Ideas Spread — The Lessons from a New Science, Alex Pentland, 2014.
Pentland and his research group have appeared to have discovered a simple model of human behavior with great predictive power. By snooping on people&#39;s cell phones, they can reduce typical human interactions into a set of interacting finite state machines, and by noticing just how regular those behavioral patterns are they think they understand ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having read a passage from a book, I then .... Rereading Benedikt&#39;s &#34;Cyberspace&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-28-having-read-a-passage-from-a-book-i-then-rereading-benedikts-cyberspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 20:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-28-having-read-a-passage-from-a-book-i-then-rereading-benedikts-cyberspace/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m rereading some books from my bookshelf, on the theory that it&#39;s easier to make sense of the static texts that I own than to try to dip into the infinite stream of the internet and be enlightened or entertained by it.
So far, so good; I pulled out a copy of Polya&#39;s &#34;How to Solve It&#34; (1945), David Sucher&#39;s &#34;City Comforts&#34; (2003), and Michael Benedikt&#39;s anthology &#34;Cyberspace: First Steps&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11th Kerrytown Bookfest, September 8, 2013, Ann Arbor Farmers Market</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-11th-kerrytown-bookfest-september-8-2013-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-11th-kerrytown-bookfest-september-8-2013-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</guid>
      <description>From the official Kerrytown Bookfest web site:
 The 11th Kerrytown BookFest will celebrate Detroit and its writers with three panel discussions featuring celebrated auto executive Bob Lutz (“Icons and Idiots”), rock ‘n’ roll writers Steve Miller (“Detroit Rock City”) and Peter Benjaminson (“Mary Wells”) and urban observers Edward McClelland (“Nothin’ But Blue Skies: The Heydey”), Gordon Young (“Teardown”), June Thomas (“Redevelopment and Race”) and John Gallagher (“Revolution Detroit”) of the Detroit Free Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Grant, Give and Take; on being &#34;otherish&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</guid>
      <description>A brief review of Give and Take, which I checked out from the Ann Arbor District Library.
Grant writes about a number of people he calls givers, who are generous to a fault when sharing their time and expertise, even when there is not a sure bet that the generosity will be repaid. He contrasts this with the matchers, who always keep track of favors, and the takers who seek to exploit every circumstance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Karl Pohrt, 65, owner of Ann Arbor&#39;s Shaman Drum Bookshop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-12-obituary-karl-pohrt-65-owner-of-ann-arbors-shaman-drum-bookshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 13:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-12-obituary-karl-pohrt-65-owner-of-ann-arbors-shaman-drum-bookshop/</guid>
      <description>Karl Pohrt died Wednesday, July 10, 2013, after a battle with anaplastic thyroid cancer. He wrote about books and life on his weblog &amp;quot;there is no gap&amp;quot;. Karl was the owner of the Shaman Drum Bookshop, an independent bookstore on Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s State Street which closed in 2009 after a 29 year run.
Some obituaries from the net:
Publisher&amp;#39;s Weekly:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;quot;Karl Pohrt was a true bookman: a bookseller, compulsive reader, and a publisher as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookgate in Urbana, Illinois at the Urbana Free Library</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-bookgate-in-urbana-illinois-at-the-urbana-free-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 22:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-bookgate-in-urbana-illinois-at-the-urbana-free-library/</guid>
      <description>People in Urbana Illinois are up in arms that the Urbana Free Library director decided to discard a large portion of the library&amp;#39;s non fiction collection. Shelves were left bare after books older than 10 years old were summarily discarded. Citizens, up in arms after their library collection was decimated, packed a library board meeting to demand answers.
Every library weeds old books from their shelves, partly to make room for new ones, partly to remove surplus copies of no longer popular titles, and partly to get rid of texts that are no longer accurate or true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocity, give and take a little bit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 16:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading&amp;#0160;Adam Grant&amp;#39;s book&amp;#0160;Give and Take&amp;#0160;(aadl). &amp;#0160;Look in the March 31 NY Times Magazine for a preview, featuring a quote from the U of Michigan&amp;#39;s Jerry Davis. At the moment I&amp;#39;m&amp;#0160;33d on a list of 53 holds at the library for the book; if you&amp;#39;re generous, and have finished your copy, please lend it to me!
The table of contents and blurb, from the AADL catalog:
 Good returns: the dangers and rewards of giving more than you get -- The peacock and the panda: how givers, takers, and matchers build networks -- The ripple effect: collaboration and the dynamics of giving and taking credit -- Finding the diamond in the rough: the fact and fiction of recognizing potential -- The power of powerless communication: how to be modest and influence people -- The art of motivation maintenance: why some givers burn out but others are on fire -- Chump change: overcoming the doormat effect -- The scrooge shift: why a soccer team, a fingerprint, and a name can tilt us in the other direction -- Out of the shadows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual bookplates</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-10-virtual-bookplates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 10:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-10-virtual-bookplates/</guid>
      <description>You run a library; it gets donations, from time to time, of books or other materials. Some of the donations are substantial and the donor is recognized. How to best recognize a donor in the digital age?
One approach is the &amp;quot;virtual bookplate&amp;quot;, described in this ACRL article written by folks at the U of Florida. The catalog is extended to include graphics that honor the donor of the materials, and the search is extended to make it easy to look up all of the works that were donated by a particular individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet - Finn Brunton - MIT Press - 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</guid>
      <description>Finn Brunton has a new book out, called &amp;quot;Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet&amp;quot;, published by the MIT Press. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading it this summer.
Some radio interviews about the book:
An interview with NPR&amp;#39;s Scott Simon on Weekend Edition.
CBC&amp;#39;s Spark, in 2010.
and some print:
Roar so wildly: spam, technology and language. From Radical Philosophy 2010.
This is the raw text output of a chat session with a bot I modified to act as an interlocutor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing release notes for a new version of my Michigan FOIA book, using Leanpub</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-09-writing-release-notes-for-a-new-version-of-my-michigan-foia-book-using-leanpub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 11:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-09-writing-release-notes-for-a-new-version-of-my-michigan-foia-book-using-leanpub/</guid>
      <description>The book is my&amp;#0160;No-Nonsense Guide to the Michigan Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), which I&amp;#39;m publishing (early) and updating (as its written) using Leanpub. Here&amp;#39;s what I sent out to subscribers - all four of them! - this morning.
I&amp;#39;m happy to have a chance to keep working on this, since even the smallest amount of money from new sales covers the direct costs &amp;#0160;of coffee to do the writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibraryThing as a shadow catalog for books</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-23-librarything-as-a-shadow-catalog-for-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-23-librarything-as-a-shadow-catalog-for-books/</guid>
      <description>350 words about LibraryThing as a shadow catalog for books.
The bookshelf in my bedroom is full of books, thanks to LibraryThing. It&amp;#39;s been a reliable source for recommendations for works that are the next one to read after I&amp;#39;ve enjoyed a book. Hopefully I&amp;#39;ll be able to read a lot of them before they need to go back to the library.
Unlike some other libraries, the Ann Arbor District Library doesn&amp;#39;t have a direct connection to LibraryThing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Red Plenty&#34;, Francis Spufford</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-09-red-plenty-francis-spufford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 23:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-09-red-plenty-francis-spufford/</guid>
      <description>I just got done reading Francis Spufford&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Red Plenty&amp;quot;. In one modestly thick volume, it gave me insights into the Soviet economy of the 1950s and 1960s that an entire semester of college failed to give - the failures of central planning, the strange prices that led to strange decision making, and (most importantly) the optimism of the late 1950s when everything was humming along nicely.
Some other reviews of the work, so that I don&amp;#39;t miss them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Click clack moo: cows that type</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-29-click-clack-moo-cows-that-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 23:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-29-click-clack-moo-cows-that-type/</guid>
      <description>By Doreen Cronin, as read by Youtube&amp;rsquo;s Ginger12691
&amp;ldquo;Duck was a neutral party.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>there was hardly a page of the work that didn&#39;t echo someone else&#39;s thoughts</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-22-digitalvertigo-by-ajkeen-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-22-digitalvertigo-by-ajkeen-/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Keen&amp;#39;s Digital Vertigo is a follow-on to his earlier The Cult of the Amateur. Where his first work took on Wikipedia as the scourge of knowledge, the current work aims its sights at Facebook and LinkedIn, and is reflectively critical of the online social networks that Keen sees as more harmful than useful.
With a lead-in like this, you might expect that this is one of those books that fits in a long history of media criticism - from Marshall McLuhan to Umberto Eco to Michel Foucault, you&amp;#39;ll find a series of quips and quotes from dozens of thinkers littering the pages of Digital Vertigo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anti-internet texts from the 1990s</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-29-cyberspace-is-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 13:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-29-cyberspace-is-gone/</guid>
      <description>A collection of anti-Internet texts from the mid-1990s. Each of these were written at the point just as the net was unquestionably entering its stage of hyper-growth, absorbing more and more personal time as well as gobbling up independent networks into its own.
The Internet As Hyper-Liberalism&amp;#0160;(1996) argues against interconnectivity of networks.
 Net-ism is wrong because it is coercively expansionist. There is no inherent or inevitable technical or historical trend to a single communication network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The House Was Quiet and the World Was Calm, Wallace Stevens</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-31-the-house-was-quiet-and-the-world-was-calm-wallace-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 01:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-31-the-house-was-quiet-and-the-world-was-calm-wallace-stevens/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

The House Was Quiet and the World Was Calm
The house was quiet and the world was calm.
The reader became the book; and summer night
Was like the conscious being of the book. The house was quiet and the world was calm.
The words were spoken as if there was no book,
Except that the reader leaned above the page,
Wanted to lean, wanted much most to be</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for midsummer 2010: paperback swap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-discardia-for-midsummer-2010-paperback-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-discardia-for-midsummer-2010-paperback-swap/</guid>
      <description>The challenge is to get rid of some set of books that have accumulated, while simultaneously fulfilling the need to always have some kind of new reading in the house. &amp;#0160;
A new (to me) way to do this is Paperback Swap, a system which works as a trading board for books. &amp;#0160;You are entitled to books in the proportion that you send books to others, and every book you request is free to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathan Schneider defends the memory theater</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</guid>
      <description>An essay published in Open Letters Monthly.
What concerns me about the literary apocalypse that everybody now expects—the at least partial elimination of paper books in favor of digital alternatives—is not chiefly the books themselves, but the bookshelf. My fear is for the eclectic, personal collections that we bookish people assemble over the course of our lives, as well as for their grander, public step-siblings. I fear for our memory theaters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand County Almanac, June: &#34;The Alder Fork - A Fishing Idyl&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-sand-county-almanac-june-the-alder-fork-a-fishing-idyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 14:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-sand-county-almanac-june-the-alder-fork-a-fishing-idyl/</guid>
      <description>We found the main stream to law that the teeter-snipe pattered about in what last year were trout riffles, and so warm that we could duck in its deepest pool without a shout. Even after our cooling swim, waders felt like hot tar paper in the sun. Aldo Leopold, A Sand County Almanac. This 1989 Oxford Paperbacks edition, ISBN 0-19-505928-X, as an introductory essay from Robert Finch commemorating the 100th anniversary of Leopold&#39;s birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a delicious torpor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-15-a-delicious-torpor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2010 20:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-15-a-delicious-torpor/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s a great word; I was looking for some great people who used it.
Google Books is my first search for this stuff, but I wanted to give the query narrowing &#34;search only fiction&#34;. &amp;nbsp;Can&#39;t do that; ah, perhaps I can; &#34;subject:fiction torpor&#34; looks pretty good. &amp;nbsp;From The Count of Monte-Cristo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uninterruptability, reading, and attention</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-08-uninterruptability-reading-and-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-08-uninterruptability-reading-and-attention/</guid>
      <description>from &amp;quot;ruined by reading&amp;quot; -
I envied my older sister her uninterruptability. While I looked up immediately from my book when my name was called, she had the uncanny ability not to hear. I would test her as she read. It was like addressing a stone, except that with a stone, if we are imaginative enough, we can infer some kind of response albeit in stone language. My sister appeared to be present, but she was in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ebooks for kids, via the Cult of the Dead Cow</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-09-ebooks-for-kids-via-the-cult-of-the-dead-cow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 15:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-09-ebooks-for-kids-via-the-cult-of-the-dead-cow/</guid>
      <description>I want an ebook reader on my phone, so that I can read stories to my kids with the lights out. &amp;#0160;Better yet if the ebooks have just enough pictures to satisfy the need for pictures.
 I have a bootlegged ASCII text from 1987 published by The Cult of the Dead Cow of Dr. Seuss&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Cat In The Hat&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;s perfect to read on my Blackberry. &amp;#0160;I don&amp;#39;t read the preface to the three year old, which reads as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index Cards, Anne Lamott, from Bird By Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>I have an index card stuck in my copy of Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird By Bird. In that essay, she exhorts the reader to write down the ideas and thoughts and clever lines of dialog and whatever else they want to remember on a handy index card (carry one, folded, in your back pocket so you don&amp;rsquo;t look bulky). I just reread it out loud to myself, and now I kick myself for not having recorded myself to listen to it again (not for you all mind you, just for me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aldo Leopold, A Sand County Almanac - grandfather of the Leopold Bros.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-aldo-leopold-a-sand-county-almanac---grandfather-of-the-leopold-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 16:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-aldo-leopold-a-sand-county-almanac---grandfather-of-the-leopold-bros/</guid>
      <description>This 1948 collection of essays about the changing of the seasons in Wisconsin was on my parents bookshelf, and sits on mine in the dining room where various bits of natural history live.
 There is an essay or three for each month.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s some part of November captured in words as &amp;quot;If I Were The Wind&amp;quot;
The wind that makes music in November corn is in a hurry.&amp;#0160; The stalks hum, the loose husks whisk skyward in half-playful whirls, and the wind hurries on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 18, 2008: Used book sale at Burns Park Elementary, Ann Arbor MI, 9am-1pm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-17-october-18-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 10:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-17-october-18-2008/</guid>
      <description>a note from the organizers  There will be a large selection of adult and children’s fiction and non-fiction books for sale at GREAT prices!&amp;nbsp; Additionally, there will be silent auction of rare and first edition titles including: Roald Dahl, Dr. Seuss, Maurice Sendak, Dick and Jane and many more!&amp;nbsp; Please visit www.burnsparkpto.org to read more about the silent auction items and to place a bid on-line.&amp;nbsp; A portion of the proceeds will support the BP Media Center, the rest will go the Karen Thomas Memorial Fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One inch picture frame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 01:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m rereading Anne Lamott&#39;s bird by bird, and am inspired by the chapter on short assignments and on shitty first drafts to write some code.
Crontab: 00,20,40 * * * * getoutagemap
Getoutagemap: #!/bin/sh curl $map  $map.$now pdf2png $map.$now  $png.$now For where in $(ziplist) Do
Getpixel.$png.$now $(pixeldata $where) |
Pixdata2csv  outages.csv Done
Much better to have dte report the table of areas with power outages directly as a csv than to have to reconstruct it from pixel color values on a map, but we cope with the civic infrastructure we have, not the civic infrastructure we want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olive, the other reindeer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-olive-the-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 21:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-olive-the-other/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Olive the Other Reindeer Deluxe Edition: Deluxe Edition!&amp;rdquo; (Vivian Walsh) Technorati Tags: olive, reindeer, olivetti-vielmetti, dogs, woof-woof-woof</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Tech 2006 online - call for Best of Tech 2007</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-best-of-tech-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 08:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-best-of-tech-20/</guid>
      <description>Nominate your favorite for Best of Tech 2007 today.  from Steven Levy:   As I’ve mentioned earlier, I had the honor and pleasure of editing The Best of Technology Writing, 2007, an anthology published by the digitalculture imprint of the University of Michigan Press. For those who want to dip in and sample, the contents are available online. Or you can get it sent to you, piece by piece to read on your iPhone or Blackberry or on email, via DailyLit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>