<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-daily-telegraph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 11:25:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-daily-telegraph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph for 18 September 2012: Groceries, libraries, and sidewalks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-18-daily-telegraph-18-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 11:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-18-daily-telegraph-18-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>This is the Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph for Tuesday, 18 September 2012.&amp;#0160;
Groceries
Patel Brothers is &amp;quot;coming soon&amp;quot; to 3426 Washtenaw Avenue (at Pittsfield), the former home of Once Upon A Child. &amp;quot;Patel Brothers is the largest Indian&amp;#0160;Grocery chain in America, with over 35 stores nationwide and still growing.&amp;quot; The store is about 3400 square feet in total. [Loopnet] [Twitter: @pbrosfan] Yelp readers are very happy (4.5 stars) about their store in their home town of Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph for September 17, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-17-daily-telegraph-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 10:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-17-daily-telegraph-17/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve made an effort to cull stories from other college towns around the country and to feature former Ann Arborites who have left town to make their mark on the world. Without further ado....&amp;#0160;
Beirut, Lebanon: Former Ann Arborite Bilal Ghalib is now in Beirut raising money for an international network of hacker spaces. His Kickstarter campaign would bring this campaign to Baghdad, Iraq. [Kickstarter] [GEMSI] Bilal has been affiliated with Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s AHA All Hands Active makerspace, which hosts weekly build nights and after-school programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor daily telegraph for September 14, 2012: Belle Isle, Busch&#39;s recall, Guatemala eruption, Detroit Free Press exodus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-14-ann-arbor-daily-telegraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 09:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-14-ann-arbor-daily-telegraph/</guid>
      <description>Please note that the name of this newsletter has changed from the &amp;quot;Daily Telegram&amp;quot; to the &amp;quot;Daily Telegraph&amp;quot;, to avoid confusion with the Adrian, Michigan &amp;quot;Daily Telegram&amp;quot; newspaper.
Apples, cheese, sticks, lava, speeding bicycles, noise-making devices and old VHS tapes with&amp;#0160;big 1970s hair all feature prominently in the Friday edition of the Ann Arbor Daily Telegraph. To subscribe via email, fill out the form at http://eepurl.com/ppAPX or send a note to edward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor daily telegram for 9/13/2012: iPhone 5, &#34;Sam Bacile&#34;, Penny Stamps, Ann Arbor downtown construction update</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-13-ann-arbor-daily-telegram-for-9132012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-13-ann-arbor-daily-telegram-for-9132012/</guid>
      <description>Volume 1, no. 4 of the Ann Arbor daily telegram. If you&amp;#39;re interested in an email subscription, follow the subscription link. This is still an experimental project.&amp;#0160;
San Francisco: the iPhone 5 is out; it&amp;#39;s faster, lighter (112 grams), thinner (7.6 mm), and has a slightly bigger screen (4&amp;quot;, 176 extra vertical rows of pixels) than previous iPhones. [Techmeme] [The Next Web] But wait, there&amp;#39;s more: there&amp;#39;s a new dock connector, so all of your old iPhone peripherals are incompatible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor daily telegram for 9/12/2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-12-daily-telegram-for-9122012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-12-daily-telegram-for-9122012/</guid>
      <description>News from around the network and around Ann Arbor for Wednesday, September 12, 2012. This is an experimental production! Let me know if you&amp;#39;re interested in being on a mailing list for the daily telegram.
Volume 1, Number 3.
Benghazi, Libya: Four American embassy officers, including Ambassador J. Christopher Stevens, are dead and others are injured after a mob attacks and sets fire to the US consulate office. [BBC]&amp;#0160;[New York Times]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>