<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio Havana Cuba on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/radio-havana-cuba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio Havana Cuba on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 22:45:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/radio-havana-cuba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Radio Havana Cuba via a shortwave software defined radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-radio-havana-cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 22:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-radio-havana-cuba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m listening to Radio Havana Cuba via a shortwave listening post set up
with a software defined radio. The system, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blerp2.dyndns.org:8901/&#34;&gt;Great Lakes Listening Post&lt;/a&gt;,
has four separate radios covering the 80, 40, 30, and 20 meter bands, all
fed into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.websdr.org&#34;&gt;WebSDR&lt;/a&gt; software from PA3FWM. It&amp;rsquo;s
located in Michigan, and thus approximates the radio reception I&amp;rsquo;d get from
my own receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R Havana Cuba is a good station to listen to. There&amp;rsquo;s interesting political
commentary, fun music, and the occasional show about shortwave listening.
The signal is usually strong and the frequency (6000 kHz) is easy to remember.
Most international braodcasters have refocused their attention on Internet
based broadcasts, but R Havana Cuba continues on with its shortwave service.
My Sony ICF-2010 set from the 1980s still has a Cold War era present to that
frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage to web-based software radio is the ability to pick up
stations from listening posts around the world. The WebSDR platform has stations
with good antennas around the world, and they each allow multiple listeners
to tune in to different stations without any of them monopolizing the receiver.
Most web-based SDR systems focus on shortwave and HF amateur bands, but every
so often you find a system that can tune domestic medium wave (AM) and
long wave bands, which gives you a chance to hear programs that were
never anticipated to be listened to from half way around the world.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/images/R-Havana-Cuba-WebSDR.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Radio Havana Cuba on Great Lakes Listening Post WebSDR&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Discussion on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/edward.vielmetti/posts/10105619636684853&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>