<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip report, Tectonic 2016.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-19-tectonic-2016-trip-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-19-tectonic-2016-trip-report/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://tectonic.com/summit/&#34;&gt;Tectonic Summit&lt;/a&gt; was a conference in New York City in December 2016, hosted
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/&#34;&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;, with the theme &lt;em&gt;Enterprise Kubernetes&lt;/em&gt;. Mohan Kartha and
Edward Vielmetti went there as a guest of &lt;a href=&#34;http://packet.net&#34;&gt;Packet&lt;/a&gt;, a bare-metal hosting
provider in the city. This report details highlights of the presentations
at the event as well as accounts from attendees of what they thought
was missing from the presentation and discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is an orchestration system that runs on top of a container
system like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It allows an enterprise or service provider to
define a system that can scale up and down according to need. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kubernetes.io/2016/12/kubernetes-1.5-supporting-production-workloads.html&#34;&gt;Version 1.5 of Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;
was announced during the event, and it has extended
beyond the previous version by speeding up operations so that it can
support larger clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kubernetes project is relatively young, but it draws from
the experience of Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Borg&amp;rdquo; program. Version 1.0 came
out about two years ago, and there have been tens of thousands
of contributions to the codebase since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes-project-management-openstack-docker-comparison&#34;&gt;Kubernetes project management; OpenStack, Docker comparison&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kubernetes project is run by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Foundation&lt;/a&gt;,
which is about 50% by weight Google and the rest other cloud providers
like Amazon. There was some political discussion at the event where it
was clear that Kubernetes proponents made an effort to distance themselves
from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org/foundation&#34;&gt;OpenStack Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstack.org&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; was what people were doing
a few years ago to solve a similar set of problems, and that project
has floundered because of a combination of vendor-induced complexity
and a set of designs that did not reflect actual operation practice.
While the Kubernetes folks were all polite to OpenStack, they were
clear that they did not want to be tarred with the same brush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other product positioning and political interest at the event was
how various organizations were dealing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. That company
controls the container system that is being orchestrated by Kubernetes,
but also has been clawing its way up the stack acquiring other organizations
that do container management and monitoring and developing additional
capacities beyond the container core.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-swarm&#34;&gt;Docker Swarm&lt;/a&gt; competes with
Kubernetes, in the same way that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/rkt/&#34;&gt;rkt&lt;/a&gt; container engine competes
with [containerd] provided by Docker. The Kubernetes
team would really rather have a vendor-neutral, stable, drama free
container engine, rather than one that mutates all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-driving-kubernetes-tectonic-from-coreos&#34;&gt;Self-driving Kubernetes: Tectonic from CoreOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major product announcement at the event was from CoreOS, their
namesake &lt;a href=&#34;https://tectonic.com/&#34;&gt;Tectonic&lt;/a&gt; product. The latest release of Tectonic is said to
be &amp;ldquo;self-driving&amp;rdquo;, i.e. will upgrade the version of Kubernetes on
a cluster automatically. Their observation was that people who
run Kubernetes spend an inordinate amount of time outside of Kubernetes
upgrading systems when a new version comes out, and that there was
an opportunity to remove that burden by automatically handling
upgrades using a strategy much like CoreOS&amp;rsquo;s own &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/os/docs/latest/&#34;&gt;Container Linux&lt;/a&gt;
which automagically installs new versions when they are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tectonic is now available with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/press/tectonic-self-driving.html&#34;&gt;free 10-node license&lt;/a&gt;. This is
a new pricing strategy aimed at capturing the trial and test user
market and offering an easier self-service onramp to getting started
with the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sysdig-kubernetes-monitoring-and-debugging-tool&#34;&gt;Sysdig, Kubernetes monitoring and debugging tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes monitoring was demonstrated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sysdig.org/&#34;&gt;Sysdig&lt;/a&gt;, which has a product
both for individual system monitoring and for container monitoring
of Kubernetes and Docker systems. There is lots of complexity in the container
world, with processes moving here and there and logical systems
dispersed across physical machines. sysdig starts with a robust
monitoring and introspection technology that can replace lots of
one-shot Linux monitoring tools (ps, top, sysstat etc) and extends
that tool function all the way up into Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided for a fee is &lt;a href=&#34;https://sysdig.com/sysdig/&#34;&gt;Sysdig Cloud&lt;/a&gt; which puts a point-and-click GUI interface on
Kubernetes networking so that you get the whole picture at whatever
level of detail you want. Sysdig&amp;rsquo;s CEO also presented in Chicago at Docker Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;helm-kubernetes-provisioning-tool&#34;&gt;Helm, Kubernetes provisioning tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh&#34;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; was described as &amp;ldquo;like apt-get for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo;; it promises to make
deployment of systems easier by allowing a prepackaged set of commands
and configurations to be distributed through a central registry or
produced for your own private use. Every system needs a package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-studies-ticketmaster-planet&#34;&gt;Case studies: Ticketmaster, Planet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rossdakin/status/808323710381920256&#34;&gt;Ticketmaster&lt;/a&gt; was the main customer case study provided. Their system
architecture support a very large, complex, heterogeneous workload
with very old legacy stuff in the core of it (an old Vax, with its
brain pickled into an emulator). The ticketing business model is
a &amp;ldquo;self-induced DDOS attack&amp;rdquo; with very bursty loads when tickets
go on sale. They use Kubernetes to schedule containers so as to
handle peak loads better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.planet.com/&#34;&gt;Planet&lt;/a&gt; was a second case study, which does global daily hi res
satellite imagery.  Their previous operations environment deployed
VMs with Ansible, which led to a relatively slow deployment process
in which every image had crazy dependencies. Docker helps contain
dependency interactions.  Kubernetes helps scheduling and deployment
of resources as they are needed, so they can spin up and spin down
resources specific to a task and not have to guess what part of the
world their users are interested in today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-the-missing-link&#34;&gt;Storage, the missing link&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably missing from the discussion was a comprehensive look at
storage. People had seemed to have sorted out at least the basics
of networking and compute distribution over these large workloads,
but anyone who had large storage needs had worked out something
specific and purpose-built to their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation with the CTO of Quantum who is
the project lead for &lt;a href=&#34;https://rook.io/&#34;&gt;Rook&lt;/a&gt; which uses an embedded &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mail-archive.com/ceph-users@lists.ceph.com/msg34143.html&#34;&gt;Ceph&lt;/a&gt; filesystem.
Ceph is one of the file systems that has come out of the
cluster world, and Rook is an attempt to cut it down to
size and simplify it so that it can be easily embedded
as container storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one really wants to write a file system from scratch and use it
in production that same year. The most mature file systems are decades
old and have a long history of correctness and performance tweaks.
Of all things to worry about people are largely unwilling to put
production loads on untested storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kubernetes-progress-development-testing-deployment&#34;&gt;Kubernetes progress: development, testing, deployment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What people are using Kubernetes for: mostly for testing. The average
size of a cluster is less than 3 nodes, according to a Gartner
analyst.  &lt;a href=&#34;bare metal hosting&#34;&gt;Packet&lt;/a&gt; has seen uptake as a Kubernetes
test environment - it&amp;rsquo;s cheaper to provision bare metal than AWS or VMs
for Kubernetes, and performant enough for the test environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;arm-in-the-data-center&#34;&gt;ARM in the data center.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a good lunch discussion of ARM processors in the data center. Question:
is there any way to displace Intel&amp;rsquo;s dominance of data center
computing?  ARM has advantages at very low end due to low power
consumption, and the 4-core ARM Raspberry Pi 3 is a popular testbed for home clustering
but not suitable for data center use. Packet has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.packet.net/bare-metal/servers/type-2a/&#34;&gt;96-core ARMv8 server&lt;/a&gt;
that we have been involved in testing, and there was lots of interest in
stories around that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges of ARM in the data center: Intel dominance on software
side, some small amount of fragmentation in Unix flavors, immaturity
of software ports to ARMv8 (even as compared to ARMv7), unconvincing
economics. One ex-Transmeta guy was very pessimistic about displacing
Intel because of Intel&amp;rsquo;s manufacturing lead. On the other hand a Khosla Ventures
exec was bullish on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cavium.com&#34;&gt;Cavium&lt;/a&gt;, an ARM server core vendor, and thought they
had a long way to grow. He was interested in a call back in 30 - 90
days with report on uptake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-visit-packet-net&#34;&gt;Site visit: Packet.net&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://packet.net&#34;&gt;Packet&lt;/a&gt; provides bare metal as a service, either in your data
center or their own. The office was very busy and bursting at the
seams, with people sitting everywhere and a steady stream of vendors and
partners in evidence. Packet are very nice, prompt, pleasant people to deal
with, and they are expanding to new markets (Japan) with new
investment (Softbank) on new servers (ARMv8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hosting market was explained to me this way: some companies have OpEx to
spend, so they spend it on AWS; others have CapEx to spend, so they
are trying to build a data center operating platform that&amp;rsquo;s friendly
to using on premises. Can you run your system on other people&amp;rsquo;s
capital? The Packet founders have been through this before and seem to have
built a culture that knows its market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good conference, and thanks to CoreOS for organizing the event
and to Packet for inviting us to participate!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>