<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discardia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/discardia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Discardia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 17:05:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/discardia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discardia is September 22 and 23, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-discardia-is-september-22-and-23-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 17:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-discardia-is-september-22-and-23-2014/</guid>
      <description>Discardia is a quarterly holiday that helps you get rid of things. This year&#39;s fall season dates are September 22 (the equinox) to September 23 (the new moon), 2014. I&#39;m looking forward at the very least to a cleanout of the basement, which as my son points out is full of &#39;crap from the 1990s&#39;.
See www.discardia.com for details; the origin of the event is due to Dinah Sanders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forgetting as a feature, not a bug&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-forgetting-as-a-feature-not-a-bug/</guid>
      <description>[New] technologies are currently being viewed as either substitutes for, or possible augmentations of, human faculties. I argue that the proffered scenarios of computerized ‘help’ for human activities evident in the ubiquitous computing world tends to focus on augmentation of human remembering, with sensors and computer networks archiving vast amounts of data, but neglects to consider what augmentation might mean when it comes to that other human activity, namely, forgetting. (5) via www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discardia for Spring 2011 runs from March 20 to April 3</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-20-discardia-spring-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-20-discardia-spring-2011/</guid>
      <description>Discardia is a holiday to celebrate and teach letting go of what doesn’t add value to your life – whether a physical object, habit, or emotional baggage – and replacing it with what makes your world more awesome. (Dinah Sanders)   Each quarter I celebrate the modern holiday of&amp;#0160;Discardia.&amp;#0160;This quarter&amp;#39;s Discardia runs from&amp;#0160;March 20 (the vernal equinox) to April 3 (the new moon).&amp;#0160;Here&amp;#39;s some of the things I did with my kids this Discardia season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia runs 20 Mar 2010 - 14 Apr 2010</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-discardia-runs-20-mar-2010-14-apr-2010-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-discardia-runs-20-mar-2010-14-apr-2010-/</guid>
      <description>The season of discardia is upon us again. &amp;#0160;
It&amp;#39;s time to unsubscribe from mailing lists, take out the trash, empty out your pockets, weigh your inbox and reduce its weight, clean out the cupboards and more.
It&amp;#39;s also time for me to stop even pretending that I can follow everything that have at one time been interested in and let some things that fascinate me slip by the wayside for a while, so that in some future I can come back to them and be surprised by how much progress has been made since I was gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discardia is the new discardage; or, um, BBQ</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-26-discardia-is-the-new-discardage-or-um-bbq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 10:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-26-discardia-is-the-new-discardage-or-um-bbq/</guid>
      <description>While waiting for the page to load, please enjoy this brief televised interlude, previously recorded for your enjoyment; 0:24 in if you are impatient.
    Thanks to Peter Honeyman for the heads up.
For the summer discardia, look for plans for the first ever OMG WTF BBQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for spring 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-discardia-for-spring-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-discardia-for-spring-2009/</guid>
      <description>Discardia is a four times a year holiday that celebrates letting go, getting rid of, and removing unneeded things from your life.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s one of my favorite modern holidays, one of those repeated reminders that there are sometimes things that you have gathered into your life that need to be scattered around instead.
Priority one is a book purge; I&amp;#39;ll be filling up a few bags with books to get out of the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for winter 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-21-discardia-for-winter-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 12:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-21-discardia-for-winter-2008/</guid>
      <description>Discardia is a four times a year holiday that celebrates letting go, getting rid of, and removing unneeded things from your life.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s one of my favorite modern holidays, one of those repeated reminders that there are sometimes things that you have gathered into your life that need to be scattered around instead.
Priority one is a book purge; I&amp;#39;ll be filling up a few bags with books to get out of the house.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>