<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 09:05:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How does this system even work?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-21-how-does-this-system-even-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 09:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-21-how-does-this-system-even-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some questions to ask while you&#39;re trying to sort this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Draw a diagram of the entire system, from one end
to the other. Label the parts. Identify especially the
parts that &#34;just work&#34;, because undoubtably there are 
unexpected cases that won&#39;t work just when you need them 
to work. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identify the message flows through the system.
Where do signals get generated, where do they get
retransmitted, where do they get changed and when
does a human interpret them? Look for feedback loops,
where messages oscillate between two parts of a system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure out what kind of time scale you need to operate
on, and understand the characteristics of delays within
the system. Identify the cycle time of critical components,
how often they can be queried and especially how long it
takes to return an accurate reading. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Form follows funding. Understand the financial flows
through the system that constrain the data flows. If a
process costs money, sort out the planning and
budgeting implications of making a change. Systems that
are subject to external regulation may have unexpected
constraints on operations and reporting, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Complex working systems are in a perpetual state of
partial failure, and often the resolution of partial failures
involves human inputs. Consider the human element in
the systems design, and draw that into your functional
design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s possible to overthink all of these, and some of the
parts decompose into smaller parts that are in turn rather
complex. Inside every complex working system is a simpler
system that works, and you are looking to identify that at
the core of your efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 23, 2014: Metro-North computer &#34;glitch&#34; strands NYC commuters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-january-23-2014-metro-north-computer-glitch-strands-nyc-commuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-january-23-2014-metro-north-computer-glitch-strands-nyc-commuters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABC News reports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Metro-North, the nation&#39;s second-busiest commuter railroad, was brought to a standstill for nearly two hours on Thursday night after computer problems caused signal issues system-wide, railroad officials said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://newyork.cbslocal.com/2014/01/23/metro-north-service-suspended-on-hudson-harlem-and-new-haven-lines/&#34;&gt;CBS&lt;/a&gt; has this diagnosis of what went wrong, and why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The cause of the outage remained under investigation Thursday night. “We can’t say what the cause of it is. We’re still trying to figure that out,” Daniels told 1010 WINS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a good read on after-incident reporting, I always refer people to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/115136140203018391796&#34;&gt;Postmortems&lt;/a&gt; group on Google+ - it&#39;s an excellent source of descriptions of what happened when computers &#34;glitch&#34; (because they rarely glitch all by themselves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/AP3e0d4e92f5dd41a09b091619239c819a.html&#34;&gt;AP/WSJ&lt;/a&gt; The Metro-North computer &#34;glitch&#34; described as human error, AP story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MTA head Thomas Prendergast said Friday that computers that run Metro-North&#39;s signal system lost power at 7:45 p.m. Thursday when one of two main power supply units was taken out of service for replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;He said technicians performing the work did not realize that a wire was disconnected on the other main power supply unit.﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>