<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 09:05:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How does this system even work?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-21-how-does-this-system-even-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 09:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-21-how-does-this-system-even-work/</guid>
      <description>Some questions to ask while you&#39;re trying to sort this out.
 Draw a diagram of the entire system, from one end to the other. Label the parts. Identify especially the parts that &#34;just work&#34;, because undoubtably there are unexpected cases that won&#39;t work just when you need them to work.  Identify the message flows through the system. Where do signals get generated, where do they get retransmitted, where do they get changed and when does a human interpret them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 23, 2014: Metro-North computer &#34;glitch&#34; strands NYC commuters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-january-23-2014-metro-north-computer-glitch-strands-nyc-commuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-january-23-2014-metro-north-computer-glitch-strands-nyc-commuters/</guid>
      <description>ABC News reports:
 Metro-North, the nation&#39;s second-busiest commuter railroad, was brought to a standstill for nearly two hours on Thursday night after computer problems caused signal issues system-wide, railroad officials said.
 CBS has this diagnosis of what went wrong, and why
 The cause of the outage remained under investigation Thursday night. “We can’t say what the cause of it is. We’re still trying to figure that out,” Daniels told 1010 WINS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems attract systems people</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-systems-attract-systems-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-systems-attract-systems-people/</guid>
      <description>From Systemantics, the systems bible:
 While Systems-people share certain attributes in common, each specific system tends to attract people with specific sets of attributes. For example, people who are attracted to auto racing are likely to be people who enjoy driving fast, tinkering with high-powered cars, and beating other people in fierce competition. The System calls forth those attributes in its members and rewards the extreme degrees of them. But a word of warning is in order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outages, cable failures, and postmortems: sources for information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-outages-cable-failures-and-postmortems-sources-for-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-outages-cable-failures-and-postmortems-sources-for-information/</guid>
      <description>If you, like me, are interested in how systems work and when they fail, here are three good sources to look at from the internet persective on global network behavior.
The outages mailing list (outages at outages.org) describes itself as follows:
 The primary goal of this mailing list (&amp;quot;outages&amp;quot;) is for outages-reporting that would apply to failures of major communications infrastructure components having significant traffic-carrying capacity, similar to what FCC provided prior to 9/11 days but they seem to have pulled back due to terrorism concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction markets are too easy to game, so let&#39;s play games instead</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-prediction-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-prediction-markets/</guid>
      <description>Prediction markets provide a nice, idealized way to use market mechanisms to predict the future. They are a slightly idealized version of an office betting pool and allow small scale bets (real or virtual) on future events. Unlike a real futures market, where you can get guarantees of future performance on things like delivery of gasoline or frozen orange juice, there&amp;#39;s no way that betting on some prospective GOP hopeful will lift your candidate to office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s always good to collect a lot of examples as you look to map out a system. For that you want to have generative tools that suggest the kinds of examples that you want to look for.
The power outage maps I have been collecting started with the generative system of making a blank entry for each of 50 states, and looking to collect one in each state. I&amp;#39;ve done similar exercises where the generator is the first letter of the alphabet collecting examples A-Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guthery&#39;s Law: &#34;In an evolving man-machine system, the man will get dumber faster than the machine gets smarter.&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-gutherys-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 14:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-gutherys-law/</guid>
      <description>I quoted Guthery&amp;#39;s Law in a 1986 contribution to Risks Digest&amp;#0160;about fast-food computing; here&amp;#39;s the original citation from Scott Guthery, who was at ASCVX6 at the time.
He&amp;#39;s now contributing a column to TMCnet, looking particularly at risks to the public from smart medical devices operated by less-smart humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 7-9, 2008: Language as a Complex Adaptive System, Ann Arbor, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-november-7-9-2008-language-as-a-complex-adaptive-system-ann-arbor-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 12:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-november-7-9-2008-language-as-a-complex-adaptive-system-ann-arbor-mi/</guid>
      <description>The theme builds upon foundations laid by colleagues from different branches of linguistics, psychology, and complex systems. The speakers are active in their recognition of complexity in their respective areas, ranging from language usage, structure, and change, sociolinguistics, cognitive linguistics, anthropology, language evolution, first language acquisition, second language acquisition, psycholinguistics and language processing, language education, individual differences, and language testing.
Conference Schedule is available at http://elicorpora.info/LLC/schedule
(Free) Registration required
Dates: November 7-9, 2008</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>