<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kanban on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/kanban/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kanban on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 09:14:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/kanban/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Github-based kanban boards: Zenhub, Waffle, Huboard, Blossom et al</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-24-github-based-kanban-boards-zenhub-waffle-huboard-blossom-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-24-github-based-kanban-boards-zenhub-waffle-huboard-blossom-et-al/</guid>
      <description>A kanban board is simply a two-dimensional view of a series of work queues. By moving a piece of work from one column to another, you update its status. This gives you a quick way to visualize your current priorities, as well as making it very clear when one or more of your queues are too full.
I&#39;ve been using Github issues as a personal issue tracker for a while, using its milestones feature to track categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Personal Kanban with Boardthing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</guid>
      <description>I change productivity tools from time to time. Here&#39;s a latest try.
There are only two real rules with Personal Kanban: 1. Visualize your work 2. Limit your work-in-progress
I wrote about Personal Kanban before back in 2010, but I didn&#39;t try to put it into practice as such.
Boardthing is an invention of Dave Gray. There&#39;s a review of Boardthing from Chuck Frey which goes into a few more details, but the short summary of it is that it&#39;s a suitable way to rearrange little rectangles on a board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting work in progress vs. the endless todo list</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 10:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been using a todo system based on Github issues for the better part of a year. It&#39;s been an interesting exercise in trying to corral the things that aren&#39;t done yet but that need to be.
When I started out, I dumped every last thing that I might do into the system, everything from major tasks to &#34;do laundry&#34; (which can seem like a major task at times). The count of undone things oscillated from 60 to 100 things to be done, which made it seem like an infinite list because it took too long to review the whole list and it was on 3 or 4 screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we can learn from procrastination : James Surowiecki The New Yorker</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-17-what-we-can-learn-from-procrastination-the-new-yorker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 18:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-17-what-we-can-learn-from-procrastination-the-new-yorker/</guid>
      <description>Academics, who work for long periods in a self-directed fashion, may be especially prone to putting things off: surveys suggest that the vast majority of college students procrastinate, and articles in the literature of procrastination often allude to the author’s own problems with finishing the piece. (This article will be no exception.) But the academic buzz around the subject isn’t just a case of eggheads rationalizing their slothfulness. As various scholars argue in “The Thief of Time,” edited by Chrisoula Andreou and Mark D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban; or, management by post-it note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 21:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a few years back about a mini-kanban that John Hritz had put together to remember to refill washer fluid. There are a lot of colorful sticky notes around my workplace these days, so I thought I&#39;d read up on how kanban-inspired systems are being used for process management in the software development and other non-manufacturing worlds.  Some inspiring examples (with post-its to illustrate):  Corey Ladas on Kanban systems for software engineering:  A perfect state of flow may be very difficult, or at least uneconomical, to achieve in a robust product development process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>