<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grand Marais Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/grand-marais-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grand Marais Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/grand-marais-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>