<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 22:37:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2014 Web Analytics Wednesday at Enlighten, a meeting non-summary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-02-april-2014-web-analytics-wednesday-at-enlighten-a-meeting-non-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 22:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-02-april-2014-web-analytics-wednesday-at-enlighten-a-meeting-non-summary/</guid>
      <description>We had 11 in attendance for the April 2014 edition of the Ann Arbor Web Analytics Wednesday group, which meets roughly monthly at Enlighten on the west side of Ann Arbor. This month&#39;s meeting was sponsored by Tealium, a tag management vendor. Thanks to Chris Grant for being my co-organizer for the event. I won&#39;t try to summarize what was said by whom in what order, because discussion went around and around the table a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis paralysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>I have a bunch of tools that tell me what people have looked at on the net, including Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools, Clicky, and some Twitter tools. It&#39;s fascinating to see people&#39;s attention move around and occasionally reanimate something that I wrote months or years ago.
What these tools don&#39;t easily do is tell me what to write about next. Yes, sometimes they suggest missing things that should be expanded on, and looking at Twitter stats is endlessly fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>