<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Events on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Events on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 22:19:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All Hands Active open house, September 19, 2014, 7:00 p.m - 10:00 p.m., 525 E Liberty St Ann Arbor MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 22:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-13-9x-all-hands-active-open-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Post the poster! &lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Openhouse-20140919-e1410474571147&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e158762970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Openhouse-20140919-e1410474571147&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A design for an an Ann Arbor events channel, @a2events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a design for a low overhead way to post about events coming up in Ann Arbor. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2events&#34;&gt;@a2events on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you want to play along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule of business is that every event has to have a URL, and the more simple and direct the URL is the more likely it is that it&#39;s authoritative for the event. If an event doesn&#39;t have a URL yet, I&#39;ll blog about it here if I need to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second rule of business is that I&#39;m not keeping a calendar, just a feed, and the feed is not going to be a 100% comprehensive feed; you have to be prepared to get events info from multiple sources and I&#39;m just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third rule of business of course is that if you want to pay for this service we&#39;ll find a way to let you pay, though the specifics are TBD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic idea for technology is to use a tag on my Pinboard account to feed a specific tag, and to use that tag to feed IFTTT to feed Twitter so that events get pushed out. I&#39;ll probably also use a Node-RED page to help construct something that does the right thing, and there will be a Slack channel on the a2b3 slack to do - something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Brian Kerr for having the foresight to reserve the name a2events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U of Michigan to announce &#34;historic event&#34; at Michigan Stadium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: Special Event Press Conference today @ Noon (EDT). Historic event to be held at Michigan Stadium. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23BigHouse&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#BigHouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Michigan Tix Office (@umichtix) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/umichtix/statuses/452084506975952896&#34;&gt;April 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working assumption is that this is the long-rumored summer soccer game between Manchester United and Real Madrid in August. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crainsdetroit.com/article/20140403/NEWS/140409938/soccer-headed-to-big-house-manchester-united-real-madrid-to-play-in&#34;&gt;Crain&#39;s Detroit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Global soccer powerhouses Manchester United — wearing its new Chevrolet-sponsored jerseys — and Real Madrid will square off at Michigan Stadium in Ann Arbor at 4 p.m. Aug. 2, two sources with direct knowledge of the situation told Crain’s this week.
  The University of Michigan has scheduled a press conference for noon Friday to announce the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23mufc&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#mufc&lt;/a&gt; face Real Madrid in the International Champions Cup, presented by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChevroletFC&#34;&gt;@ChevroletFC&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23mutour&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#mutour&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/6bTkIaqdoJ&#34;&gt;http://t.co/6bTkIaqdoJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/3DVqUwFD8q&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3DVqUwFD8q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Manchester United (@ManUtd) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ManUtd/statuses/452113689621966848&#34;&gt;April 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire, May 10, 2014, Washtenaw Community College</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-24-ann-arbor-mini-maker-faire-may-10-2014-washtenaw-community-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 22:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-24-ann-arbor-mini-maker-faire-may-10-2014-washtenaw-community-college/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5118dc189970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5118dc189970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;AnnArbor_MMF_logos_Wordpress&#34; title=&#34;AnnArbor_MMF_logos_Wordpress&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5118dc189970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please share this Save the Date with your friends, family, neighbors, and colleagues across the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in its sixth year, the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire features dozens of makers from across the region and draws over three thousand members of the community for the day’s free events. Metalworkers, inventors, papermakers, artists, students, robot designers, enthusiasts and professional alike teach the public how they make their work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many participants come away with more than just inspiration, but new skills they can use to fuel their own creations and lasting connections to other makers and resources in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 10, 2014 marks the second time the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire will be hosted by Washtenaw Community College. This free, all-ages event features community members of all types who come together to display their ideas, projects, and inventions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be seeking applications from people and groups with engaging, inspiring, and just plain cool projects.  Projects should have a focus on the process of creating, designing, and making - not just displaying a final product.  Makers of all ages and experience levels are encouraged to submit applications. We will begin seeking applications for makers in the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Info&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our website (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2makerfaire.com&#34;&gt;http://www.a2makerfaire.com&lt;/a&gt;) or our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ann-Arbor-Mini-Maker-Faire/185228104678&#34;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for more information, applications, and dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organized by members of the Ann Arbor tech and arts communities such as a2geeks (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2geeks.com&#34;&gt;http://www.a2geeks.com&lt;/a&gt;) and GO-Tech (&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/notbago/&#34;&gt;http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/notbago/&lt;/a&gt;), the Ann Arbor Mini Maker Faire is a small, local version of the huge Bay-area Maker Faire, and is one of many faires across the country that happen year around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about participating in or attending the Mini Maker Faire, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2makerfaire.com&#34;&gt;http://www.a2makerfaire.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Needs point of contact for questions via email)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feburary 6, 2014, 7:00 p.m. at Crazy Wisdom: Sunday School: Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-29-feburary-6-2014-700-pm-at-crazy-wisdom-sunday-school-yesterday-today-and-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 23:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-29-feburary-6-2014-700-pm-at-crazy-wisdom-sunday-school-yesterday-today-and-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join interfaith minister [Lauren Zinn] at SUNDAY SCHOOL: YESTERDAY, TODAY &amp;amp; TOMORROW for an interesting and energizing conversation about what&#39;s happening, not happening and will be happening in Sunday Schools, and why you might want to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encourage religious school teachers, clergy, intermarried friends, parents of young children, students, etc. to attend this open conversation initiated by several local Sunday School teachers involved in interfaith education for youth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you there, with a cup of hot tea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crazy Wisdom SALON: Inspiring Talks in the Tea Room, February 6, 2014 at 7:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crazy Wisdom Bookstore and Tea Room, 114 S Main St, Ann Arbor, MI 48104&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store phone number: (734) 665-2757&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greg Briggs is Associate Pastor at Bethlehem United Church of Christ in Ann Arbor where he directs the youth programming. He is interested in using pop culture to promote social justice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kellie Love has been co-teaching for the Youth Ed program at the Interfaith Center for Spiritual Growth for 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heide Kaminski taught the Youth Ed program for 10 years at Unity of Ann Arbor and for the past 12 years at the Interfaith Center. She considers herself eclectic with a family of agnostics, atheists, and traditional Christians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lauren Zinn of ZinnHouse, Educational Planning PhD &amp;amp; Interfaith Minister, runs an independent Interfaith Orientation and Hebrew program for all ages, and trains future teachers in Teaching Interfaith to Youth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2geeks 2013 annual meeting, Thursday May 16 2013, 5:30 p.m. at Ann Arbor SPARK</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-05-07-a2geeks-2013-annual-meeting-thursday-may-16-2013-530-pm-at-ann-arbor-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-05-07-a2geeks-2013-annual-meeting-thursday-may-16-2013-530-pm-at-ann-arbor-spark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/519632611427608/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901beb0df5970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Jpeg&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901beb0df5970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901beb0df5970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From the Facebook event announcement:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a2geeks&amp;#39; third annual meeting is a gathering-of-the-geeks - inventors and innovators, makers and hackers, students and grandparents, town and gown. This event will also kick-off the A2Geeks Civic Apps Contest. Food and fun galore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event starts at 5:30 p.m. I&amp;#39;ll be there pitching the Civic Apps contest, which I&amp;#39;ve been working on for a while now to organize. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Nerd Nite, Wednesday April 17, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-15-ann-arbor-nerd-nite-wednesday-april-17-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-15-ann-arbor-nerd-nite-wednesday-april-17-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s monthly Nerd Nite is coming Wednesday, April 17; doors open at 6:30pm for a 7:00pm event. Here&amp;#39;s a bit from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.nerdnite.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Nerd Nite web site&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;which also has more in the way of details about the speakers and the format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.nerdnite.com/2013/04/05/wham-w00t-wednesday/&#34; rel=&#34;bookmark&#34; title=&#34;Permanent Link to Wham! W00t! Wednesday!&#34;&gt;Wham! W00t! Wednesday!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What up, A2nerds? We’re mixing things up a bit this month by bringing the nerdery to Wednesday. For those of you that are new to the fold,&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.nerdnite.com/&#34;&gt;Nerd Nite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is a monthly social event where nerds of all disciplines give 18-21 minute funny and informative talks while the audience drinks along and asks questions. We’ve heard&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/nerdniteannarbor&#34;&gt;good things&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;about this shindig. So, what will we be learning about this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W is for Water:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;David Trossman will channel his inner Steve Zissou and guide us through Voyages of the Neo-Voyeurs: How They Observe Motion in the Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W is for Writing:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Amy Wilson&amp;#0160;would Do Anything for Love and she’ll explain to us Why, in fact, Good Pop Music is Good Writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W is for Whiskey:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Michelle Kydd, in Eau Whiskey, will help us see that whiskey isn’t just for drinking, but for smelling, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Wednesday, April 17 Doors at 6:30 Event at 7&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;The Last Word,&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.com/maps?q=301+W+Huron+St,+Ann+Arbor,+MI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sll=45.00109,-86.270553&amp;amp;sspn=7.814605,19.709473&amp;amp;oq=301&amp;amp;hnear=301+W+Huron+St,+Ann+Arbor,+Washtenaw,+Michigan+48103&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;z=16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Map of 301 W. Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI&#34;&gt;301 W. Huron St.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wage:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;$5&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/17hm4K8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Buy Tickets to Nerd Nite Ann Arbor&#34;&gt;Buy online&lt;/a&gt;! or at the door (cash/credit)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Healthcare Decisions Day is April 16, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-13-national-healthcare-decisions-day-is-april-16-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-13-national-healthcare-decisions-day-is-april-16-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Merilynne Rush for notice of this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Healthcare Decisions Day is April 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join with other Americans across the country completing Advance Directives documents at an
Advanced Directives Party
at the Center for the Childbearing Year, 722 Brooks St., Ann Arbor
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
6:30     Drinks and hors d’oeuvres&lt;br /&gt;
7:00     Presentation and Q &amp;amp; A&lt;br /&gt;
8:00     Small Group discussion and filling out documents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cost:   $15 per person or $20 per family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information and to RSVP, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://afterdeathhomecare.com&#34;&gt;After Death Home Care (dot) com&lt;/a&gt; or call
734-395-9660
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now that the taxes are done, do the other paperwork you’ve been putting off!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
National Healthcare Decisions Day highlights the importance of advance healthcare decision-making.  As a participating organization, After Death Home Care is providing information and tools for the public to talk about their wishes with family, friends and healthcare providers, and execute written advance directives in accordance with Michigan laws.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Specifically, on April 16, from 6:30 – 8:30 pm, After Death Home Care is welcoming the public with information about advance care planning and advance directive forms. Merilynne Rush, RN, Natural Burial Specialist is joined by Patricia Lyndale, UM Hospital Chaplain, and John Erdevig, Attorney, to answer questions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
National Healthcare Decisions Day encourages people in our community to have thoughtful conversations about their healthcare decisions and to complete reliable advance directives to make their wishes known.  As a result, more people will plan ahead before a health crisis, fewer families and healthcare providers will have to struggle with making difficult decisions when a patient can no longer do so, and more families will be able to honor their loved ones wishes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For more information about the party, please visit After Death Home Care (dot) com.  For more information about National Healthcare Decisions Day, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhdd.org&#34;&gt;www.nhdd.org&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Media Contact:  Merilynne Rush, After Death Home Care, 734-395-9660, mrush@afterdeathhomecare.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;fieldset class=&#34;zemanta-related&#34;&gt;&lt;legend class=&#34;zemanta-related-title&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://queencityhospice.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/national-healthcare-decisions-day/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/157511645_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://queencityhospice.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/national-healthcare-decisions-day/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Healthcare Decisions Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://managedcarecontracting.typepad.com/managed_care_contracting_/2011/04/guest-post-national-healthcare-decisions-day.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/57341982_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://managedcarecontracting.typepad.com/managed_care_contracting_/2011/04/guest-post-national-healthcare-decisions-day.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guest Post: National Healthcare Decisions Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thetimesnews.com/opinion/guest-columns/take-control-of-health-care-decisions-1.125370&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/159801352_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thetimesnews.com/opinion/guest-columns/take-control-of-health-care-decisions-1.125370&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Take control of health care decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jacksonville.com/opinion/blog/407800/beth-cravey/2013-04-10/advance-healthcare-directives-community-hospice-pushes&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/159140059_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jacksonville.com/opinion/blog/407800/beth-cravey/2013-04-10/advance-healthcare-directives-community-hospice-pushes&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Advance healthcare directives: Community Hospice pushes &amp;#39;important conversation&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.star-telegram.com/2013/04/08/4759091/a-good-death-requires-honest-conversation.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/158485340_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.star-telegram.com/2013/04/08/4759091/a-good-death-requires-honest-conversation.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A &amp;#39;good&amp;#39; death requires honest conversation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuri&#39;s Night in Ann Arbor, Friday April 12, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-11-yuris-night-in-ann-arbor-friday-april-12-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 14:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-11-yuris-night-in-ann-arbor-friday-april-12-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the a2geeks mailing list - added links are mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday April 12th is&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yurisnight.net/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Yuri&amp;#39;s Night&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;- celebrating spaceflight on the anniversary of&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuri_Gagarin&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Yuri Gagarin&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;flight in 1961, and the first space shuttle flight in 1981. The&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is bringing laptops running&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kerbalspaceprogram.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Kerbal Space Program&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(an awesomely fun space exploration sandbox game) to&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/327-Braun-Court/120577181379049&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Bar at 327 Braun Court&lt;/a&gt;. Come celebrate space exploration!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d42b811c6970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot 2013-04-11 at 2.34.02 PM&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d42b811c6970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d42b811c6970c-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2013-04-11 at 2.34.02 PM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penny Stamps: Arduino creator Massimo Banzi, “Opensourcing Imagination,” Thursday, April 11, 2013 at Michigan Theater</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-10-penny-stamps-arduino-creator-massimo-banzi-opensourcing-imagination-thursday-april-11-2013-at-michig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 11:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-04-10-penny-stamps-arduino-creator-massimo-banzi-opensourcing-imagination-thursday-april-11-2013-at-michig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a press release from ORCI; added hyperlinks are mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Posted on&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://orci.research.umich.edu/2013/04/09/arduino-creator-massimo-banzi-opensourcing-imagination-thursday-april-11/&#34; rel=&#34;bookmark&#34; style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34; title=&#34;10:37 am&#34;&gt;April 9, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;by&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://orci.research.umich.edu/author/dmeisler/&#34; rel=&#34;author&#34; style=&#34;font-size: 14px;&#34; title=&#34;View all posts by Dan Meisler&#34;&gt;Dan Meisler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Penny Stamps College of Art and Design Distinguished Speaker Series featuring Massimo Banzi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Thursday, April 11, 5:10 p.m.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;Michigan Theater, 603 E. Liberty, Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;: Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interaction designer &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.massimobanzi.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Massimo Banzi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(@&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mbanzi&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;mbanzi&lt;/a&gt;) helped invent the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny, easy-to-use open-source microcontroller that has inspired people around the world to make the coolest things they can imagine. With a variety of sensors, the Arduino is versatile and easy to use for projects as diverse as an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/17/arts/design/arduinos-provide-interactive-exhibits-for-about-30.html?_r=0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;exhibit on brains&lt;/a&gt; at the American Museum of Natural History in New York, to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.makezine.com/2008/02/25/how-to-make-plants-talk-t/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;DIY kit that sends a Tweet&lt;/a&gt; when your houseplant needs water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massimo has consulted for Prada, Artemide, Persol, Whirlpool, the V&amp;amp;A Museum and Adidas. He is also the author of&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Getting Started with Arduino&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;and&amp;#0160;a regular contributor to both the italian edition of&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Wired Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;and the online innovation magazine&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chefuturo.it/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Che Futuro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#0160; Massimo currently teaches Interaction Design at SUPSI Lugano in Switzerland and is a visiting professor at CIID in Copenhagen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With support from ArtsEngine, the Urban Institute for Contemporary Arts, the School of Information and the Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Spring CSA (Community Supported Agriculture) Fair, Sunday, March 24, 2013 at Pittsfield Grange</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-03-18-ann-arbor-spring-csa-community-supported-agriculture-fair-sunday-march-24-2013-at-pittsfield-grange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 10:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-03-18-ann-arbor-spring-csa-community-supported-agriculture-fair-sunday-march-24-2013-at-pittsfield-grange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kim Bayer asked me to pass this event along, which sounds like a great time if you are considering getting a CSA farm share for 2013 in the Ann Arbor area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greetings&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slowfoodhuronvalley.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Slow Food Huron Valley&lt;/a&gt; invites you to the first annual CSA Fair on Sunday, March 24, 2013 from 2-4pm at the Pittsfield Grange. It is free to attend, and more than 20 CSAs will be represented. Meet CSA farmers, find out which option works for you and sign up for the perfect CSA match - whether it&amp;#39;s vegetables, humanely raised meat, whole grains, prepared meals, frozen fruits and vegetables, and more! &amp;#0160;A CSA membership is the most affordable way to get local, sustainable food into your diet AND it gives a vote of confidence to our farmers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In addition to the CSA farms, Packard Health Clinic will be on hand with information about their free health insurance programs. And the Great Lakes CSA Coalition will be there talking about establishing insurance wellness rebates for CSA members. &amp;#0160;The Pittsfield Grange will also have information about Grange programs!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;PS: sign up for a CSA on the 24th and enter our drawing...if your name is drawn you get reimbursed so your CSA share is FREE!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SPRING CSA FAIR&lt;br /&gt;When: Sunday, March 24, 2013 from 2-4pm&lt;br /&gt;Where: Pittsfield Grange, 3337 Ann Arbor-Saline Rd., Ann Arbor, MI&lt;br /&gt;More info:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:slowfoodhuronvalley@gmail.com&#34;&gt;slowfoodhuronvalley@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee97d7fb7970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Spring CSA Fair flyer (1)&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee97d7fb7970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee97d7fb7970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Spring CSA Fair flyer (1)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor District Library to circulate electronic music tools; Moog Foundation event August 1, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-07-30-ann-arbor-district-library-to-circulate-electronic-music-tools-moog-foundation-event-august-1-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-07-30-ann-arbor-district-library-to-circulate-electronic-music-tools-moog-foundation-event-august-1-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Eli Neiburger for the heads up for this event -&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor District Library is launching a new circulating collection of&amp;#0160;electronic music tools, and they are brining &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://moogfoundation.org/tag/dr-bobs-sound-school/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Dr. Bob&amp;#39;s Sound School&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, a&amp;#0160;program of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://moogfoundation.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Robert Moog Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, to AADL this Wednesday August 1, 2012.&amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s an introduction to the principles of electronic sound synthesis,&amp;#0160;a little history of Moog, and a chance to get your hands on some&amp;#0160;seriously cool and unusual music tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instrument collection will feature musical gear that you can check out from the Library, from such noted manufacturers as Moog, Korg, Maywa Denki, Bleep Labs, Chamber of Sounds, Folktek, Critter &amp;amp; Guitari and more! Participants in the workshop will get a chance to get their hands on these instruments before they go into general circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One event is&amp;#0160;intended for grades K-5 and their adults from 2-3:30 PM, and another&amp;#0160;for grades 6 - Adult from 7 - 8:30 PM. &amp;#0160;Details here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=15787&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=15787&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=16246&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=16246&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>