<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Providence Rhode Island on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cities/providence-rhode-island/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Providence Rhode Island on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 13:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cities/providence-rhode-island/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretending to be on an airplane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-06-02-pretending-to-be-on-an-airplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-06-02-pretending-to-be-on-an-airplane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on a trip to Rhode Island last week for a conference (RILA09).&amp;#0160; That gave me a chance to enter &amp;quot;airplane mode&amp;quot;, that rare time in my life when I have lots of time to spend in contemplation but very little network connectivity. And I have to say, I enjoy that time immensely, perhaps more than I enjoy any individual hour trying to be engaged with the net.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airplane mode is a very distinctive time and place to be in.&amp;#0160; You are typically either in an airplane terminal with time to wait for your flight, or sitting buckled into a seat.&amp;#0160; Each experience is essentially the same each time you go, with little meaningful distinction between individual flights; the seat might be a bit noisier or more comfortable, and the terminal a bit more or less dingy, but it&amp;#39;s all of a piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result then is that I am transported into a new place with this effort, a place where I can write a postcard, read a long-forgotten book, or work within the confines&amp;#0160;of my laptop without the infinite global distraction of the Internet.&amp;#0160; Frankly, the infinite global distraction of the Internet is not conducive to reasonable thought - it demands attention, reply, responsiveness, and engagement, 24/7, whether you want it or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard, but not impossible, to reconstruct airplane mode in the rest of the day.&amp;#0160; The appropriate cafe can be a part of it, at least for the ritual coffee experience. It helps a lot to have a tool like Freedom (Mac OS X) that enforces a bit of network downtime for you by shutting down all Internet links for a period of time.&amp;#0160; The telephone is&amp;#0160;harder, but almost every call can be made to wait if you plan carefully enough to create a signal for what is actually urgent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m offline, I write with different tools, and thus my thinking is different.&amp;#0160; Entering text into &amp;quot;vim&amp;quot;, my old standby favorite text mode editor, triggers different brainwaves that does keying things carefully into a web form.&amp;#0160; Not feeling like I have to hyperlink every third word frees up the brain for internal connections instead of external&amp;#0160;connections.&amp;#0160; There&amp;#39;s rarely a need to hide from flashing distracting advertising or to spend time deleting spam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, being online was the exception rather than the rule - some part of my far away brain remembers that and wants to get back to that earlier, simpler day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;notes afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/05/freedom-to-go-o.html&#34;&gt;Freedom: previously described here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a possible answer for using &lt;a href=&#34;http://labnol.blogspot.com/2007/06/use-notepad-vim-or-any-text-editor-with.html&#34;&gt;vim as an alternative text editor in firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;once upon a time&amp;quot; is roughly the UUCP era, when there was email and netnews but no web and hardly ever any real time communications unless you were all logged into the same machine.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>