<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weather on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/weather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weather on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 16:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Small multiples</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-02-small-multiples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-02-small-multiples/</guid>
      <description>James Corriea, Jr. has this nice illustration of the use of small multiples in weather forecasting to show the progression of forecasts as they change.
Day 1 outlook progression #wiwx #miwx #ilwx #ohwx #inwx pic.twitter.com/HtLJQ6lOq0
&amp;mdash; james correia jr (@jimmyc42) August 2, 2015 
Better Know a Visualization: Small Multiples from Juice Analytics has some more examples - the original goes back to the work of Edward Tufte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blitzortung.org and lightningmaps.org to watch lightning roll in</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-using-blitzortungorg-and-lightningmapsorg-to-watch-lightning-roll-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 10:39:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-using-blitzortungorg-and-lightningmapsorg-to-watch-lightning-roll-in/</guid>
      <description>A brief note on two pages I refer to during severe weather, like the storms that rolled through the area on Monday night and Tuesday early morning that led to tornado damage in Manchester on the morning of June 23, 2015.
LightningMaps.org has a zoomable near real time map of lightning strikes. You can zoom and pan around looking at locations of lightning strikes, with a small (less than 10 seconds) delay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor flooding on Sunday, June 14, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</guid>
      <description>A severe storm dumped a bunch of water on Ann Arbor on Sunday, June 14, 2015. Here are reports of flood locations as monitored on Twitter. All times Eastern.
6:09 p.m. Huron River well down from its crest at 14.95 feet; flood stage is 16 feet, last observation is 13.57 feet at 5:15 P.M.

4:28 p.m. Huron River downstream from Allen Creek surged from about 700 cfs to over 2200 cfs in the span of less than an hour at about 2:00 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>super cold (but sunny; don&#39;t forget that it was sunny)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-20-super-cold-but-sunny-dont-forget-that-it-was-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-20-super-cold-but-sunny-dont-forget-that-it-was-sunny/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite weather forecasts comes from forecast.io. This screen shows the ensemble set of forecasts they have for temperature for tomorrow (February 20, 2015), highlighting the 8:00 a.m. reading.

You&#39;ll note from this graph that there are several weather models they are pulling from. The one of them that has the coldest predicted weather is RAP from the National Center for Atmospheric Research in Boulder, Colorado. Looking at their set of pages they have a nice cold temperature forecast map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-traditional maps to monitor severe weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-22-non-traditional-maps-to-monitor-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 13:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-22-non-traditional-maps-to-monitor-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>When ordinary weather maps don&#39;t tell you what the worst of the weather is like out there, I turn to these sources for information.
 Twitter, especially. A search this morning for &#34;ann arbor ice&#34; gave plenty of illustrations why it was not suitable to be out walking around. Streets and highways were bad, and a Delta flight slid off the runway at DTW. For Michigan weather follow the #miwx hashtag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-05-essential-components-of-ann-arbor-weather-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Essential components of Ann Arbor Weather Twitter:
In an emergency, call 911.
911 trunk lines can go down in storms. The Ann Arbor non-emergency police number is (734) 994-2911, put it in your cell phone.
Sirens: City sirens are tested on the second Tuesdays of the month at 1 pm. A small handful of us notice this and tweet SIRENS. Generally siren activation in any quantity will prompt twitter chatter. Hashtags: #miwx is primary, but I also watch or post to #annarbor and #skywarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snowedoutatlanta - January 28, 2014 Atlanta snowstorm paralyzes city</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-29-january-28-2014-atlanta-snowstorm-paralyzes-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-29-january-28-2014-atlanta-snowstorm-paralyzes-city/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s cold here in Ann Arbor, but we more or less know how to deal with it. Not so in Atlanta, where slippery roads led to gridlock on the highways and midnight traffic jams.

From the Atlanta Journal-Constitution:
 It was a day when a 10-mile commute could take you at least six hours. For those heading from downtown to the burbs, it was even worse. The interstates were a gridlocked mess long before the snow finished falling Tuesday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Snow Emergency Ordinance, 10:143</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 16:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</guid>
      <description>This is current as of January 4, 2014. Check on the Municode web site for the absolute latest information, though it&#39;s unlikely that the ordinance will change.
Note that as of 9:30pm January 5, 2014, there is no snow emergency declared for the City of Ann Arbor, but Washtenaw County has declared a &#34;Snow Condition Yellow&#34;. From the City of Ann Arbor Facebook:
 The City of Ann Arbor is not declaring a snow emergency at this point, but we are recommending residents move their cars off the streets, if possible, to make it easier for city trucks to plow the full width of streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HE WENT OUT WITHOUT A HAT. WHAT HAPPENS NEXT WILL CHILL YOU TO THE BONE</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-upworthy-wx-wind-chill-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-upworthy-wx-wind-chill-advisory/</guid>
      <description>Or, Upworthy does weather in the imitable National Weather Service style.
For January 2-3 2014 we are looking at a wind chill advisory for the Ann Arbor area with wind chills going all the way past 15 below F. From the NWS Detroit:  Cold overnight temperatures in the single digits below zero will combine with 10 to 15 mph winds to cause dangerous Wind Chill Values of -17 to -23 across all of southeast Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice storm of December 21-22, 2013 and the Sperry-Piltz Ice Accumulation Index</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-21-ice-storm-of-december-21-22-2013-and-the-sperry-piltz-ice-accumulation-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 16:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-21-ice-storm-of-december-21-22-2013-and-the-sperry-piltz-ice-accumulation-index/</guid>
      <description>On the Sperry-Piltz Ice Accumulation Index:
 The Sperry–Piltz Ice Accumulation Index, or SPIA Index, is a forward-looking, ice accumulation and ice damage prediction index that uses an algorithm of researched parameters that, when combined with National Weather Service forecast data, predicts the projected footprint, total ice accumulation, and resulting potential damage from approaching ice storms. It is a tool to be used for risk management and/or winter weather preparedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area closings for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>High winds took down trees and knocked out power to thousands in Washtenaw County the night of 17 November 2013, and the next morning a number of schools and government offices closed because of lack of power.
From various sources including email and twitter; this is surely incomplete.
Ann Arbor Public Schools: Tappan and King are closed today due to power outages at both schools. Tonight&#39;s Listen and Learn at Tappan will be rescheduled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live blog: November 17, 2013 tornadoes in Illinois and Indiana, severe weather in Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-17-live-blog-november-17-2013-tornado-outbreak-in-central-illinois/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 22:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-17-live-blog-november-17-2013-tornado-outbreak-in-central-illinois/</guid>
      <description>Live blog of tornado and severe weather outbreak on Sunday, 17 November 2013. Worst affected were several towns in central and southern Illinois and in central Indiana.
12:15pm Monday. USA Today reports the death toll as 6 in Illinois, and 2 in Michigan. I don&#39;t have details on the Michigan deaths. The report includes 1 minute 30 of tornado videos.
11:45am Monday. DTE Energy has a storm damage in Michigan photo set on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe weather forecast for Ann Arbor and Detroit area for Sunday, November 17, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-severe-weather-forecast-for-ann-arbor-and-detroit-area-for-sunday-november-17-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 10:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-severe-weather-forecast-for-ann-arbor-and-detroit-area-for-sunday-november-17-2013/</guid>
      <description>The National Weather Service in Detroit forecasts a moderate risk of severe weather for the Ann Arbor and Detroit area as well as for the rest of southern Michigan for Sunday afternoon, November 17, 2013. The risk is of high winds with a chance of tornadoes. Winds will be from the south at about 25 mph with gusts of up to 70 mph.
UPDATED 12:45 p.m. EST: Tornado watch (Particularly Dangerous Sitation) WW 562</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semi overturns on Mackinac Bridge in storms of July 18, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-18-semi-overturns-on-mackinac-bridge-in-storms-of-july-18-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 22:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-18-semi-overturns-on-mackinac-bridge-in-storms-of-july-18-2013/</guid>
      <description>The photo below of an overturned semi-tractor trailer on the Mackinac Bridge is from Lora Brown, as posted to Facebook, and as reposted to Twitter by Kristi Steffen (@Upsilky66). The driver was not hurt, and the bridge has reopened.
MT @Upsilky66: Photo of overturned semi on #MackinacBridge. Bridge is closed to all traffic. pic.twitter.com/dAJO81YjiV #Breaking #WCMU
&amp;mdash; CMU Public Radio (@WCMUNews) July 19, 2013  Apparently a semi tipped over on the bridge and almost went over the railing #mackinacbridge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2013 Calgary, Alberta floods yycflood</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-june-2013-calgary-alberta-floods-yycflood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 22:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-june-2013-calgary-alberta-floods-yycflood/</guid>
      <description>Flooding of the Bow and Elbow Rivers inundated downtown Calgary, Alberta on June 21, 2013. Flooding and flash flooding has affected large parts of southern Alberta, due in part to a slow-moving storm front that is dumping a lot of rain on the area, up to 7.5 inches in 2.5 days. Three people have died from the flooding.
If you&#39;re in Calgary, Alberta reading this, you should know that it&#39;s likely to be out of date and incomplete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brrr! Cold overnight temperatures on Tuesday, January 22, 2013 in the Ann Arbor area.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-22-brrr-cold-overnight-temperatures-on-tuesday-january-22-2013-in-the-ann-arbor-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-22-brrr-cold-overnight-temperatures-on-tuesday-january-22-2013-in-the-ann-arbor-area/</guid>
      <description>The cold overnight temperatures in the Ann Arbor area are illustrated nicely by the Weather Underground&amp;#39;s Wundermap for the area - here&amp;#39;s a snapshot from 12:30 a.m. Brrr!
Assuming that school is on tomorrow (and not called off because of bitter cold), this should be one of the few days of the year I don&amp;#39;t just send my second grader off to make it to school on his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy - bookmarks and apps for your mobile phone</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-26-hurricane-sandy-bookmarks-for-your-mobile-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-26-hurricane-sandy-bookmarks-for-your-mobile-phone/</guid>
      <description>My twitter feed is blowing up with people discussing Hurricane Sandy and its likely impact on the East Coast. In the interests of having somewhere useful to drop things that come up along the way, here&amp;#39;s a live blog of sorts of the event. I&amp;#39;ll put all of my Sandy stuff here, rather than have it go over multiple other entries. The top of this is collected info; the bottom is the blog collecting things without much sorting except chronological.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-25-hurricane-sandy-is-being-called-a-snoreastercane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-25-hurricane-sandy-is-being-called-a-snoreastercane/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s a bit of a stretch, but the word &amp;quot;snor&amp;#39;eastercane&amp;quot; is supposedly a portmanteau of &amp;quot;snow&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;nor&amp;#39;easter&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;hurricane&amp;quot;. Credit to the Wall Street Journal for the name.
 Odds are increasing that a hybrid “snor’eastercane” could make landfall near Greater New York early next week, with wide-ranging impacts affecting nearly the entire East Coast.
 The Twitter hashtag is #snoreastercane and is in use already, with comments like this from @LoriG: &amp;quot;Unexpected consequence of global warming: having to learn the names of a bunch of new types of storms&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Isaac flood maps and flooding predictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-hurricane-isaac-flood-maps-and-flooding-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-hurricane-isaac-flood-maps-and-flooding-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Isaac brought with it high winds and a substantial amount of rain, and both of those combined has led to a lot of flooding. Here are some maps I&amp;#39;ve collected while the storm is still underway. You should know that for each of them I&amp;#39;ll also give a link to the underlying mapping source so that you can get current information.
If you are in the affected area and need details about flooded roads or the risk of dams or levees bursting or anything else, do not trust this weblog for current information; seek out official and up to date sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane season, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-hurricane-season-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 22:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-hurricane-season-2012/</guid>
      <description>Each year is a new hurricane season, and each year the internet is a little different. Here&amp;#39;s some things that are new that I&amp;#39;ve noticed.
Every single meteorologist is on Twitter (or close enough), and there&amp;#39;s an ample supply of both local weather reporting and national weather forecasting to satisfy anyone&amp;#39;s need to look at weather models for hurricanes to come. The word of the year is &amp;quot;spaghetti model&amp;quot;, illustrated below, showing a whole series of separate tracks from different atmospheric models to predict a set of possible futures for the storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derecho of June 29, 2012, with time lapse radar video</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-29-derecho-of-june-29-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 23:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-29-derecho-of-june-29-2012/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (June 29, 2012) An intense storm called a derecho with long lived straight line winds passed to the south of the area today. The Disaster Mapping weblog entry 6/29/2012 Derecho has a good summary of the impact to the power grid from storm, which had knocked out power to over 3 million people as of 11:45 p.m from Illinois all the way to DC. Wind gusts of over 90 miles per hour were clocked in some areas as the storm blew through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe weather expected Sunday, April 15, 2012 for</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-15-severe-weather-expected-sunday-april-15-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 02:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-15-severe-weather-expected-sunday-april-15-2012/</guid>
      <description>The 2:40am map from Wunderground is a good marker of things to come for the Ann Arbor area.

As always, for DTE power outage information, the DTE Power Outage map is a place to go. Our old analog meter was replaced by a digital one, so there&amp;#39;s one additional point of non-mechanical failure to watch for. The page onDTE outage claims is worth noting.
The 3am forecast from NWS:&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit to Dexter after the Dexter tornado</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-18-a-visit-to-dexter-after-the-dexter-tornado/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 02:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-18-a-visit-to-dexter-after-the-dexter-tornado/</guid>
      <description>Photo: Hudson Mills Metropark golf course,&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Some rights reserved&amp;#0160;by&amp;#0160;Andy Fowler.
DEXTER, Michigan. As much as possible, I tried not to be the tornado gawker. I probably failed.
Update: photo from Andy Fowler, map from National Weather Service.
Busch&amp;#39;s was giving away water that had been donated, and cookies, to affected residents. Their store was very close to one of the neighborhoods that was worst hit (Huron Farms). With police blocking the entrance to that neighborhood, you had the feeling that the store was being exceptionally kind to its neighbors and that it was exceptionally lucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix tape music for hurricanes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-08-26-mix-tape-music-for-hurricanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 11:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-08-26-mix-tape-music-for-hurricanes/</guid>
      <description>WNYC has put together the Dark and Stormy mix tape, featuring Lena Horne&amp;#39;s Stormy Weather and Prince&amp;#39;s Purple Rain on side A, and Nanci Griffith&amp;#39;s cover of Wasn&amp;#39;t That a Mighty Storm on side B.&amp;#0160;
Galveston had a seawall&amp;#0160;
To keep the water down,&amp;#0160;
But the high tide from the ocean&amp;#0160;
Washed water over the town.&amp;#0160;
The New Yorker has&amp;#0160;The iPod of the Hurricane, songs for a windy weekend, leading with&amp;#0160;Wynonie Harris, “She’s Gone with the Wind”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 10/11 2011 Lake Michigan storms: Mesoscale Discussion 402</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-10-april-1011-2011-lake-michigan-storms-mesoscale-discussion-402/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 23:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-10-april-1011-2011-lake-michigan-storms-mesoscale-discussion-402/</guid>
      <description>Severe storms and damaging winds are possible across the upper Great Lakes from the storm on April 10/April 11 2011. This map is from Mesoscale Discussion 402.

Edward Vielmetti watches for severe storms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather forecast for Tubilustrium: Wednesday, March 23, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-21-tubilistrium-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 19:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-21-tubilistrium-weather/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a storm coming, which may bring some mix of rain, snow, sleet, freezing rain, and ice pellets to Ann Arbor. The worst of it will be on Wednesday, March 23 2011, &amp;#0160;the date of the Roman festival of Tubilustrium. This event was&amp;#0160;held in honor of Vulcan, the god of fire and metal working.
Some charts, graphs, maps etc.
The Weatherspark forecast&amp;#0160;has a nice spark-line style chart interface; this is an excerpt from the full page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play list for an ice storm (or, Wintry Mix Tape)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-20-play-list-for-an-ice-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 10:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-20-play-list-for-an-ice-storm/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla Ice - Ice Ice Baby
Foreigner - Cold As Ice
Britney Spears - Break the Ice
Viva Valdy - Hard Rain
Hurricane Bells - Freezing Rain
Albert Collins - Iceman:&amp;#0160;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ihvvf1R_vWo
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tremors come, the tremors go, they love the wintry weather: frost quakes in Ohio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-10-the-tremors-come-the-tremors-go-they-love-the-wintry-weather-frost-quakes-in-ohio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-10-the-tremors-come-the-tremors-go-they-love-the-wintry-weather-frost-quakes-in-ohio/</guid>
      <description>The Dayton Daily News notes an overnight frost quake centered around Darke County, Ohio&amp;#0160;on February 10, 2011.
 The quake, or cryoseism as it’s known in scientific circles, occurs when moisture soaks into the soil and a quick freeze causes a sudden, even violent expansion and contraction. Darke County’s 911 director Brandon Redmond said the quakes erupted for eight hours Thursday, starting at 1 a.m. The heaviest reports were between 5:30-7:30 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It pours, man it pours</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-21-it-pours-man-it-pours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 00:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-21-it-pours-man-it-pours/</guid>
      <description>It never rains in Southern California.
&amp;nbsp;
 It pours, man it pours.
 Image: National Weather Service Advanced Hydrological Prediction Service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes wave forecast: 20&#43; foot waves on Lake Superior on Wednesday, October 27</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-25-great-lakes-wave-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 22:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-25-great-lakes-wave-forecast/</guid>
      <description>The Great Lakes Coastal Forecasting System&amp;#0160;has recent history, current conditions, and near term forecasts for wind, waves and temperatures across the Great Lakes. &amp;#0160;There&amp;#39;s a windstorm coming which is predicted to create serious waves; look at the 24+ foot predictions on Lake Superior near where the Edmund Fitzgerald went down in 1975.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2009 strawberry season delayed by cold weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s some reports from around the state of the strawberry crop.&amp;#0160; (We&amp;#39;re planning a trip to Rowe&amp;#39;s in Rawsonville for Father&amp;#39;s Day).
From the Detroit Free Press via FreshPlaza:
At DeGroot&amp;#39;s Strawberries in Gregory, 16 acres of lush plants are close to ripening.
&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s not too hot and could be a little warmer,&amp;quot; says Marsha DeGroot, who with her family has owned the Livingston County farm since 1978. &amp;quot;But the lovely winter with lots of snow made for a nice insulating blanket for the plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do before the network goes down: emergency preparation for Michigan summer storms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-30-what-to-do-before-the-network-goes-down-emergency-preparation-for-michigan-summer-storms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-30-what-to-do-before-the-network-goes-down-emergency-preparation-for-michigan-summer-storms/</guid>
      <description>Every summer there are thunderstorms in southeastern Michigan, and every year some part of the networks (power, phone, cable, cell phone, traffic lights, twitter) go down.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a roundup of some things you can add to your emergency communications checklist so that when the weather goes sour you are prepared to be safe.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m leaving a few of them blank where I don&amp;#39;t know the answer, so check the comments on this for the fill in the blanks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools closed 16 January 2009 because of cold weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-16-ann-arbor-public-schools-closed-16-january-2009-because-of-cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 08:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-16-ann-arbor-public-schools-closed-16-january-2009-because-of-cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>Schools closed; it&amp;#39;s too cold.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ll update this page as I find stuff to keep me warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new TDWR - Thermal Dopplr Weather Radar - at Detroit via Weather Underground</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-new-tdwr-thermal-dopplr-weather-radar-at-detroit-via-weather-underground/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 17:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-new-tdwr-thermal-dopplr-weather-radar-at-detroit-via-weather-underground/</guid>
      <description>Detroit has a new weather radar offering what the Weather Underground calls &amp;quot;high def radar&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s the link to the TDWR Radar for Detroit.
The vendor&amp;#39;s web site, TSC, says
The Federal Aviation Administration&amp;#39;s (FAA) Terminal Doppler Weather Radar (TDWR) system detects and reports hazardous weather in and around airport terminal approach and departure zones. The TDWR identifies and warns air traffic controllers (ATCs) of low altitude wind shear hazards caused by microbursts and their associated gust fronts, in addition to reporting on precipitation intensities and providing advanced warning of wind shifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sayre Fire, Los Angeles</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-sayre-fire-los-angeles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 10:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-sayre-fire-los-angeles/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of the Tea Fire comes word of another big fire in Los Angeles, the Sayre Fire. Here&#39;s the news sources I was able to round up quickly; no doubt this will be changing fast.
LAFD suggests these social media tags and channels:
 Twitter hashtag: #LAFIRE Flickr tags: &#34;SayreFire&#34; and &#34;LAFD&#34; and add to LAFD Photo Pool YouTube tags: &#34;SayreFire&#34; and &#34;LAFD&#34;   Los Angeles Fire Department: Fire update 6am Sat PST; Fire evacuation map; Los Angeles DWP: Major power lines taken out of service Blog: LAist - power shut off by DWP;&amp;nbsp; freeway closure map; Newspaper: LA Times - overview with map and videos  Television: KABC 7 live video Radio: KNX 1070 CBS news radio Hospital: Olive View Hospital in path of fire (LA Times) Metrolink: Antelope Valley Saturday service cancelled Twitter: following LAist, Metrolink, LAFD  I&#39;m particularly looking for news about Reseda (family in the area).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald, November 10, 1975</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-november-10-1975/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 11:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-november-10-1975/</guid>
      <description>November 10, 1975.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; I was 10, and I had a paper route delivering the Marquette MIning Journal, which means I was out delivering newspapers to the Marquette Harbor Lighthouse the day the Edmund Fitzgerald went down.&amp;#0160; Television news in those days was black and white, and there&amp;#39;s a clip of Harry Reasoner that plays at the Great Lakes Shipwreck Museum from the news the next day that I must have seen two dozen times which brings me back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasn&#39;t that a mighty storm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-15-wasnt-that-a-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 09:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-15-wasnt-that-a-mi/</guid>
      <description>as seen in this excellent NY Daily News article -
Galveston had a seawall To keep the water down, But the high tide from the ocean Washed water over the town. Wasn&#39;t that a mighty storm! Oh, wasn&#39;t that a mighty storm with water!
Wasn&#39;t that a mighty storm That blew all the people away! Their trumpets gave them warning, &amp;quot;You&#39;d better leave this place.&amp;quot; They never thought of leaving Till death looked them in the face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gustav: social media lessons being learned</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-02-gustav-social-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 14:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-02-gustav-social-m/</guid>
      <description>While it&#39;s still fresh, here are some lessons being learned in the middle of watching (and being a small part of) the net&#39;s response to Hurricane Gustav.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m not putting a lot of links in this post.
--
Decision to evacuate: It was clear while following Twitter - both directly from the handful of NOLA folks I follow and generally from looking at the net - that people went through a huge amount of decision-making about when and whether to leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compact weather forecast in RSS?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-compact-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 07:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-compact-weather/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m looking for a weather forecast in RSS which packs as much information into the subject line as possible.
By point of comparison, here are a few examples of things that could be better. The weather underground&#39;s feed looks like this: Current Conditions - 49.8F / 9.9C | Partly Cloudy - 6:50 AM EDT Apr. 23 Today as of Apr. 23 3:45 AM EDT which is OK for current information (albeit wordy) but useless for the forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>