<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geology on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/geology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geology on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 03:55:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/geology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Calbuco volcano in Chile has erupted; 23 April 2015, early a.m. update</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-23-the-calbuco-volcano-in-chile-has-erupted-23-april-2015-early-am-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 03:55:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-23-the-calbuco-volcano-in-chile-has-erupted-23-april-2015-early-am-update/</guid>
      <description>The pictures coming out of Calbuco are stunning, let me find a few to save them here. Local coverage is from biobiochile.cl:
Volcán Calbuco retoma proceso eruptivo con expulsión de material incandescente
 Una densa columna de lava y material incandescente comenzó a desprenderse desde el cráter del volcán Calbuco pasada la 1:00 de la madrugada de este jueves, en lo que fue calificado como una reactivación abrupta del macizo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association a public body under Michigan FOIA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</guid>
      <description>The question from a story in the Marquette Mining Journal:
 MARQUETTE - Marquette County Circuit Court Judge Thomas Solka heard oral arguments Thursday on a case involving whether the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association is a public body subject to producing financial information under the Freedom of Information Act.
The association is important to plaintiffs in the case because it was created under state law requirements by the Michigan Department of Environmental Quality, which makes it a public body by extension, the plaintiffs contend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power outages follow Christchurch, New Zealand earthquake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-22-eqnz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 23:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-22-eqnz/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor, December 22, 2011 - Three strong earthquakes of more than magnitude 5 hit Christchurch, New Zealand today, disrupting the power and telecommunications networks in the area and damaging roads and structures because of liquefaction of the soil. Damage and injury estimates are incomplete as of this writing.
 According to USGS, three earthquake hits christchurch today , 5.8 at 01:58:36 PM, 5.3 at 02:06:25 PM and 5.8 at 03:18:02 PM&amp;nbsp;#eqnz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George F. Kay, Frank Leverett, and Paul MacClintock examining gumbotil in Iowa, 1925</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-10-gumbotil-kay-leverett-macclintock-1925/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 22:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-10-gumbotil-kay-leverett-macclintock-1925/</guid>
      <description>George F. Kay, Frank Leverett, and Paul MacClintock, 4 miles NE of Ricketts, IA, at the Nebraskan gumbotil outcrop. &amp;#0160;Photo Calvin Photographic Collection. From George Frederick Kay 1873-1943, University of Iowa.&amp;#0160;Photographed by: Earl T. Apfel, July 1925.&amp;#0160;
Frank Leverett did extensive field work in Michigan; this Michigan Digital Geology Library&amp;#0160;has many of his notebooks.
George F. Kay was my great-grandfather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soil texture triangle</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-10-soil-texture-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-10-soil-texture-triangle/</guid>
      <description>from Soil Textural Triangle, in Plantfacts, a wiki at Ohio State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska volcano maps - Mt. Redoubt, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-31-alaska-volcano-maps-mt-redoubt-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-31-alaska-volcano-maps-mt-redoubt-2009/</guid>
      <description>There are active volcanoes in Alaska, especially now including Mt. Redoubt.&amp;#0160; It appears likely to erupt as of this writing, and I&amp;#39;m not expecting to be on the top of things when it does.&amp;#0160; The Alaska Volcano Observatory is the best source of current information, and they are using twitter at @alaska_avo for updates.
Here are some sources for Alaska volcano maps - so you know where things are, how far apart the various places are, and what might be downwind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>