<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Weird Ideas on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/great-weird-ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Weird Ideas on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 18:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/great-weird-ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>That bright idea of yours might cost you $25,000</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-14-that-bright-idea-of-yours-might-cost-you-25000/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 18:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-14-that-bright-idea-of-yours-might-cost-you-25000/</guid>
      <description>A cautionary tale.
What&#39;s the value of an idea? Consider that some ideas might have a negative value; indeed that most of them might. It may take you some substantial investment to test out your idea, to prove it, to build something minimal to show people that it was real. And then when you&#39;re ready with it there might be a net result that you finally have talked to enough people that you know that you need to scrap it and start over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are you going to keep them down on the farm, after they&#39;ve seen 5D?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-07-how-are-you-going-to-keep-them-down-on-the-farm-after-theyve-seen-5d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-07-how-are-you-going-to-keep-them-down-on-the-farm-after-theyve-seen-5d/</guid>
      <description>I spent some quality time playing the dreadfully addictive game &#34;2048&#34;. (No, I won&#39;t link to it.) After beating it a few times, I went looking for higher dimensional versions and found a 2048 3D, 4D, and 5D version. And, after playing and beating 2048 5D I am no longer satisfied with most of the user interfaces that I see. 5 dimensional thinking on a 2x2x2x2x2 board is really not all that hard, once you bend your mind to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you have no idea what to write, use randomness in your favor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-when-you-have-no-idea-what-to-write-use-randomness-in-your-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 16:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-when-you-have-no-idea-what-to-write-use-randomness-in-your-favor/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve been trying to keep up a daily pace to blogging here; that&amp;#39;s been my habit for almost ten years. The problem is that it&amp;#39;s not always easy to know what to write about.
I&amp;#39;ve taken to using a few prompting tricks to help sort through some ideas about what to write about. The simplest one is one I haven&amp;#39;t heard of before: use the day of the month as a key into the letters of the alphabet, and thus write about something appropriate for that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket Twitter - a suitable replacement for the Internet when offline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-pocket-twitter-a-suitable-replacement-for-the-internet-when-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-pocket-twitter-a-suitable-replacement-for-the-internet-when-offline/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;#39;t had a working smart phone in months, and so the times when I find myself needing to write down short messages to the world don&amp;#39;t always coincide with the times that I&amp;#39;m on the net. Hence this version of &amp;quot;pocket twitter&amp;quot;, writing down things that you want to share (or to remember) on paper, and saving that paper away until the next time it&amp;#39;s possible to share a photograph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new phone to test out for a while.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-new-phone-to-test-out-for-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-new-phone-to-test-out-for-a-while/</guid>
      <description>I am going to be able to see if I can get the intended recipient please do you have any questions. Automatic arrangement of the intended recipient please notify us to the sender immediately and then you have to be able to see the resulting directly with a lot of this message. It does not quite as well as I have to be able to be but it is still working with some reservations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great weird ideas vs. slow accretion of interesting things</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-01-great-weird-ideas-vs-slow-accretion-of-interesting-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 15:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-01-great-weird-ideas-vs-slow-accretion-of-interesting-things/</guid>
      <description>From time to time I have great weird ideas, but those don&amp;#39;t happen every day. So instead of using this weblog just to catch the brainstorms I have to be also prepared to have it slowly collect the ordinary things that catch my eye long enough to be worth saving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top of mind vs. top of page vs Top Of The Park</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-26-top-of-mind-vs-top-of-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 10:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-26-top-of-mind-vs-top-of-page/</guid>
      <description>At what point did &amp;quot;top of mind&amp;quot; get replaced by &amp;quot;top of page&amp;quot; ? For people like me who spend a lot of time online, it&amp;#39;s easy for social network systems like Twitter and Facebook to be a steady stream of distractions, especially when the usual clues for what is important get replaced simply by cues for what is new.
Some background for context.
The earliest use of the phrase &amp;quot;top of mind&amp;quot; that I can find in a modern context is Alin Gruber&amp;#39;s Top of Mind Awareness and Share of Families (1969), a discussion in the Journal of Marketing Research on how closely the snap judgments that consumers make about brand recogition map to market share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dial by name, using the Twitter name space?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-dial-by-name-using-the-twitter-name-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-dial-by-name-using-the-twitter-name-space/</guid>
      <description>I find myself wanting to call people once in a while, and I also find that I know people&amp;#39;s twitter names pretty well.
What is disappointing is that none of the tools I have let me &amp;quot;dial by twitter name&amp;quot; in the sense that there&amp;#39;s no command line prompt that has a &amp;quot;call&amp;quot; verb which takes the twitter username as an object.
 % call @vielmetti
 Actually, I&amp;#39;m at even a worse spot; I don&amp;#39;t even have a &amp;quot;call&amp;quot; command to start from at the shell script prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknowledge management</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</guid>
      <description>From The Unknowledge Pattern Language, on Nooron:
 Unknowledge Patterns describe ways of talking about that which is unknown. For example, the discovery of the periodic table of the elements created a pattern of information about what we didn&amp;#39;t know about the elements, until we &amp;quot;filled in the blanks.&amp;quot; These &amp;quot;named voids&amp;quot; in our knowledge were powerful attractors, and shaped the discourse of science. Are there other ways of naming voids which shape our discovery?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My great weird ideas don&#39;t fit in 140 characters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-09-my-great-weird-ideas-dont-fit-in-140-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 09:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-09-my-great-weird-ideas-dont-fit-in-140-characters/</guid>
      <description>I have a brainstorm and want to capture it in a bottle before it dissipates. It&amp;#39;s impossible to fit it into a box that allows too few words. A suitably complex thought asks for at least a couple of paragraphs to stretch out its feelers and see if it grabs ahold of anything.&amp;#0160;
The Twitter input box doesn&amp;#39;t give the thought enough room to spark. It too quickly fizzles out, bumping into traffic and weather reports that ground it or pop culture that doesn&amp;#39;t pop for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I wish I had written: May 2011 edition, A-G</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-may-2011-edition-a-g/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-may-2011-edition-a-g/</guid>
      <description>May is almost over, and as always there is more I wish I would have done than was actually done. Some notes on things not written, in the hopes next year will bring another May (chances are good) and that I&amp;#39;ll have some of these May stories written before then.
a2b3. I would have loved to have written meeting non-summaries for every lunch meeting, capturing at least who was there, what the question was, how long it took to introduce everyone, how many people where there, and who the new people were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocomplete, letter A; as seen, somewhat edited, in my browser tonight</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-22-autocomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 23:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-22-autocomplete/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: if you are going to name a new site, think about when you autocomplete it what sites you&amp;#39;re competing with for autocomplete space.&amp;#0160;
AA - Ann Arbor District Library
AB - about:memory, Chrome diagnostic
AC - Accuweather for Ann Arbor 48104, city weather forecast
AD - Advertising Age, trade publication for the advertising industry
AE - (not used)
AF - (not used)
AG - (not used)
AH - (not used)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s hard to have great weird ideas when you&#39;re busy closing trouble tickets.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-17-its-hard-to-have-great-weird-ideas-when-youre-busy-closing-trouble-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 16:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-17-its-hard-to-have-great-weird-ideas-when-youre-busy-closing-trouble-tickets/</guid>
      <description>Conversely, it&amp;#39;s hard to close trouble tickets when you are having great weird ideas; those ideas tend to create trouble in and of themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathan Schneider defends the memory theater</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</guid>
      <description>An essay published in Open Letters Monthly.
What concerns me about the literary apocalypse that everybody now expects—the at least partial elimination of paper books in favor of digital alternatives—is not chiefly the books themselves, but the bookshelf. My fear is for the eclectic, personal collections that we bookish people assemble over the course of our lives, as well as for their grander, public step-siblings. I fear for our memory theaters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>assisted synesthesia as augmented reality</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-11-assisted-synesthesia-as-augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-11-assisted-synesthesia-as-augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>A comment I wrote on Ethan Hein&amp;#39;s account of color-coding sequencer tracks:
When you say “color coding improved your ears”, the first thing that comes to mind is that you are doing some kind of machine-assisted synesthesia. very cool, that. another enticing pice from oblong industries
It&amp;#39;s true that one of the elements is a blue ball that bounces in time to the music and touches down on the notes that are playing just then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>