<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan Football on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan Football on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>September 30, 2014 University of Michigan campus football protest</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;This is so much better than a home game&amp;quot; -protestor
&amp;mdash; mgoblog (@mgoblog) September 30, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thanks Dave Brandon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 21:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</guid>
      <description>A brisk torch and pitchfork business offsets diminished football parking revenues.
(As noted on Twitter tonight. Michigan fans have loyalty to the school, even if they are not particularly fond of this season&#39;s athletic director.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a blow to the head, but back in the game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</guid>
      <description>The tone of Michigan football blogs has changed since the loss to Minnesota on Saturday. Before the game there was a lot of grumbling, but it was varied; no one single issue stood out. After the game, it was much more clear.
A series of plays saw the second string Michigan quarterback, Shane Morris, get hit hard on his head. Morris is seen exhibiting signs of a concussion. Yet in an unfortunate sequence he goes back into the game after sitting out one play on the sidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the risk of misplaced enthusiasm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>At some point in the life of a project it is inevitable that an obstacle comes up that makes you wonder whether your enthusiasm for the effort is well placed.
Do you redouble your efforts, or do you take a break, or do you simply refocus and find something else to zero in on for the moment?
Sometimes a bit of distance can help, at least temporarily. Rather than exit in flames with a tattered manifesto flapping on the door in your wake, just go quiet for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan vs Virginia Tech (Hoke vs Hokies) in Sugar Bowl, January 3, 2012 in New Orleans; also, sandwiches</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 22:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Follow the coverage from all sides.
National coverage: ESPN&#39;s WolverineNation coverage from beat writer Michael Rothstein. Michigan Wolverines Land Sugar Bowl.
 It almost didn&#39;t happen, however. After finishing the regular season 10-2, the Wolverines needed help from other teams around the country on Saturday and from the pollsters on Sunday morning in order to be in this position -- and they received it.  On Virginia Tech, the Washington Post writes &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Muppet Glee Club&#39;s version of Temptation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-13-the-muppet-glee-clubs-version-of-temptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 11:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-13-the-muppet-glee-clubs-version-of-temptation/</guid>
      <description>After every Michigan football win, the band plays Temptation.&amp;nbsp; Here&amp;rsquo;s a version from practice.

And, after every Michigan win, the blog MGoBlog posts the Muppet Glee Club&amp;rsquo;s version of Temptation.. Alas, MGoBlog usually gives you the abbreviated version minus the first half of the sketch.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the whole thing. &amp;ldquo;It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what song you&amp;rsquo;re going to sing, as long as we all agree the song we&amp;rsquo;re going to sing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Brown Jug, and other Michigan - Minnesota connections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 14:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</guid>
      <description>Since it&amp;#39;s game day (Michigan at Minnesota) I thought I&amp;#39;d link to at least a few connections between Michigan and Minnesota.
1.&amp;#0160; The Little Brown Jug is the trophy that goes back and forth between the two schools depending on which one wins the game.&amp;#0160; It was originally purchased as a water jug for the Michigan team on an away game to Minnesota in 1903, it was left behind after the game (a 6-6 tie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst season ever? - Michigan 2008 football not as bad as 1934</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-worst-season-ever---michigan-2008-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-worst-season-ever---michigan-2008-football/</guid>
      <description>Along with all of the other t-shirts (Michigan Beer Pong, Michigan Undecided) for sale on State Street before football games, a new one has appeared this year:&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;2008 Worst Season Ever&amp;rdquo;.
Not being one to quarrel with a t-shirt, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go back through history and see just how bad this year&amp;rsquo;s team is compared to teams of the past.
1.&amp;nbsp; Rich Rodriguez has the worst lifetime record (2-7) of any Michigan football coach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Toledo War, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-notes-on-the-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 15:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-notes-on-the-to/</guid>
      <description>1.&amp;nbsp; Holy Toledo!
2.&amp;nbsp; Two Stickney, younger brother of One Stickney.
3.&amp;nbsp; 13-10.
4.&amp;nbsp; Parking prices due to drop for the rest of the season.
5.&amp;nbsp; The Michigan-Ohio boundary was resurveyed in 1915, and it&#39;s not straight.
6.&amp;nbsp; Seen on the way to the game: &amp;quot;Michigan Undecided&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Michigan Beer Pong&amp;quot; t-shirts.
7.&amp;nbsp; Their mascot is &amp;quot;Rocky the Rocket&amp;quot;.
8.&amp;nbsp; Their home field is the &amp;quot;Glass Bowl&amp;quot;.
I watched the game on Twitter with the radio on, listening to Barefoot Jerry on WCBN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Football blogs 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-20-michigan-foot-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 15:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-20-michigan-foot-1/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s getting to be that time of year when the streets are crowded with eager fans looking for a place to park for Michigan football.&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s a list of blogs covering the 2008 season - not complete and not in any order - for reference.
mgoblog starts preseason blogging in earnest next week.
Stadium and Main has notes about Comcast and the Big Ten Network in other cities.
Michigan Football Saturdays was at Media Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Football Parking 2008 map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-19-michigan-footba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 14:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-19-michigan-footba/</guid>
      <description>These are projected, estimated, possible, or likely prices for Michigan football parking for 2008.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s based on the dataset I collected from the 2007 football season, which as you might recall had an unfortunate start (which definitely impacted prices).

View Larger Map

It needs better icons so you don&#39;t have to decode the color chart.&amp;nbsp; Typically prices can vary $5 from week to week depending on the game, and if all goes well it will rain on a Thursday so that the golf course is closed and thus neighborhood parking is at a premium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>