<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan Football on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan Football on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>September 30, 2014 University of Michigan campus football protest</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is so much better than a home game&amp;quot; -protestor&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; mgoblog (@mgoblog) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mgoblog/status/517079310965178368&#34;&gt;September 30, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thanks Dave Brandon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 21:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brisk torch and pitchfork business offsets diminished football parking revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As noted on Twitter tonight. Michigan fans have loyalty to the school, even if they are not particularly fond of this season&#39;s athletic director.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a blow to the head, but back in the game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tone of Michigan football blogs has changed since the loss to Minnesota on Saturday. Before the game there was a lot of grumbling, but it was varied; no one single issue stood out. After the game, it was much more clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of plays saw the second string Michigan quarterback, Shane Morris, get hit hard on his head. Morris is seen exhibiting signs of a concussion. Yet in an unfortunate sequence he goes back into the game after sitting out one play on the sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fans now have a pinpoint spot to point their anger at coach Brady Hoke. The team lost, but it&#39;s not all about winning and losing. What matters now is the understanding of the coaching staff and their inability to protect an obviously injured student from further harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michigan has gotten funding to reduce the risk of concussions in sports. It appears that all that effort was for naught in this particular instance of not protecting a player whose judgment was impaired because of a head injury. Coach Hoke is under fire and for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the risk of misplaced enthusiasm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in the life of a project it is inevitable that an obstacle comes up that makes you wonder whether your enthusiasm for the effort is well placed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you redouble your efforts, or do you take a break, or do you simply refocus and find something else to zero in on for the moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a bit of distance can help, at least temporarily. Rather than exit in flames with a tattered manifesto flapping on the door in your wake, just go quiet for a while. If no one notices that you are no longer present so much, then you can free up that unrequited love and apply it to something else for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Written for all those unhappy Michigan football fans.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan vs Virginia Tech (Hoke vs Hokies) in Sugar Bowl, January 3, 2012 in New Orleans; also, sandwiches</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 22:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-sugar-bowl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Follow the coverage from all sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National coverage: ESPN&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://espn.go.com/colleges/michigan/&#34;&gt;WolverineNation&lt;/a&gt; coverage from beat writer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikerothstein&#34;&gt;Michael Rothstein&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://espn.go.com/colleges/michigan/football/story/_/id/7316280/michigan-wolverines-land-sugar-bowl&#34;&gt;Michigan Wolverines Land Sugar Bowl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It almost didn&#39;t happen, however. After finishing the regular season 10-2, the Wolverines needed help from other teams around the country on Saturday and from the pollsters on Sunday morning in order to be in this position -- and they received it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Virginia Tech, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/colleges/virginia-tech-hokies-a-surprise-pick-for-sugar-bowl/2011/12/04/gIQAghsCUO_story.html&#34;&gt;Washington Post writes&lt;/a&gt; &#34;one of the most surprising Bowl Championship Series at-large picks ever&#34;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virginia Tech’s BCS at-large hopes appeared to evaporate after its 38-10 loss to Clemson in the ACC championship game Saturday. While the Hokies have been ranked all season, they have not defeated a team currently in the Associated Press top 25 poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is in New Orleans, and Michigan&#39;s ever-efficient alumni association has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://alumni.umich.edu/sports/athletic-tours-and-travel-packages/official-bowl-tours&#34;&gt;official bowl tour package&lt;/a&gt; complete with chartered flights. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Orleans is a great place to eat a sandwich. &lt;a href=&#34;http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/686440&#34;&gt;Chowhound has a best sandwiches&lt;/a&gt; thread that&#39;s got a lot of great suggestions; I&#39;d pick a banh mi (in its role as a Vietnamese po&#39;boy). In Ann Arbor the blog &#34;Meg Goes Nom Nom&#34; has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://meggoesnomnom.wordpress.com/2011/02/10/meggoesnomnoms-one-year-birthday-banh-mi/&#34;&gt;glowing review of the banh mi from Zingerman&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And a few months after this occurred, I discovered that the featured sandwich at local favorite Zingerman’s Delicatessen was the Banh Mi. It was time! And not only get to try the sandwich, I got to meet the talented creator of this legit sandwich while I was there. Awesome! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zing sandwich was done by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/sanstreetfood&#34;&gt;San Street&lt;/a&gt;, a food cart which alas I have not checked out myself yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Viet World Kitchen blog has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vietworldkitchen.com/blog/2009/06/banh-mi-sandwich-recipe.html&#34;&gt;master banh mi recipe&lt;/a&gt; which pretty much sums up what you&#39;d need to put together your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is essentially one sandwich in Vietnamese cooking and it is quite a tour de force. It started out very simply, with baguette smeared with liver pate and that was it. That&#39;s how my mom knew it in the 1940s when she was growing up in Northern Vietnam. What we know today as banh mi is a light, crispy small baguette that is split and hollowed before it is invariably filled with homemade mayonnaise or butter (which I don&#39;t like), sliced chili pepper, cilantro leaves, cucumber, a tangy-sweet daikon and carrot pickle (do chua), and a drizzle of soy sauce. The variation comes in when you choose what protein component(s) will be center stage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recipe action gets you a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stickygooeycreamychewy.com/2010/08/13/do-chua-vietnamese-carrot-and-daikon-pickle/&#34;&gt;do chua recipe from the blog Sticky Gooey Creamy Chewy&lt;/a&gt;, which sounds easy enough to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do chua is so incredibly easy to make. Since it is a “fresh” pickle, there is no boiling or cooking involved. All you do is julienne the carrots and daikon, and soak them in a brine made with white vinegar, rice wine vinegar, a little water, sugar and a pinch of salt. That’s it!  Plus, the pickles only need to marinate in their brine for about an hour before they’re ready to devour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you are ready for some football.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Muppet Glee Club&#39;s version of Temptation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-13-the-muppet-glee-clubs-version-of-temptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 11:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-13-the-muppet-glee-clubs-version-of-temptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After every Michigan football win, the band plays Temptation.&amp;nbsp; Here&amp;rsquo;s a version from practice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/wG8s4QmK1bM&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/wG8s4QmK1bM&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, after every Michigan win, the blog MGoBlog posts &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/content/muppets-glorious-muppets&#34;&gt;the Muppet Glee Club&amp;rsquo;s version of Temptation.&lt;/a&gt;.  Alas, MGoBlog usually gives you the abbreviated version minus the first half of the sketch.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the whole thing.  &amp;ldquo;It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what song you&amp;rsquo;re going to sing, as long as we all agree the song we&amp;rsquo;re going to sing.&amp;rdquo; (Alas, that was an embedded Youtube video that&amp;rsquo;s gone; here&amp;rsquo;s another one.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;405&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/SnI2dMuiAv0?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Brown Jug, and other Michigan - Minnesota connections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 14:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535e32c60970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Gopher&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535e32c60970c &#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535e32c60970c-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;&#34; title=&#34;Gopher&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 Since it&amp;#39;s game day (Michigan at Minnesota) I thought I&amp;#39;d link to at least a few connections between Michigan and Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;#0160; The Little Brown Jug is the trophy that goes back and forth between the two schools depending on which one wins the game.&amp;#0160; It was originally purchased as a water jug for the Michigan team on an away game to Minnesota in 1903, it was left behind after the game (a 6-6 tie).&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailygopher.com/2008/11/6/655570/the-little-brown-jug&#34;&gt;The Daily Gopher has an excellent roundup of the story (warning: Minnesota point of view) quoting from several Michigan football blogs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Days later when Yost sent a letter requesting his water jug back, Cook replied saying &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;We have your little brown jug; if you want it, you’ll have to win it.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;More on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Little_Brown_Jug&#34;&gt;Little Brown Jug&lt;/a&gt;, and on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Brown_Jug&#34;&gt;Brown Jug&lt;/a&gt; (a South University campus bar and restaurant) at Arborwiki.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.&amp;#0160; Michigan shares a border with Minnesota along Lake Superior, and there is public transportation by ferry from Houghton, Michigan to Grand Portage, Minnesota via a stop at the Isle Royale National Park.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isleroyaleboats.com/&#34;&gt;Minnesota to Isle Royale ferry information:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Grand Portage Isle Royale Transportation Line began as a way for the
    Sivertson family of Lake Superior&amp;#39;s north shore to transport their catch of
    freshwater fish from Isle Royale to Minnesota. It gradually expanded to include
    passenger service. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/isro&#34;&gt;Michigan to Isle Royale ferry information:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Unlike other Isle Royale ferry services, the Ranger III was designed by
the National Park Service specifically to bridge the gap between the
mainland and the Island. It was built to withstand the Lake’s fierce
storms and its ice breaking capabilities assist in opening the park in
the spring. An experienced nine-member crew take great pride in not
only maintaining the vessel, but in serving its passengers. The Ranger
III’s Captain, Bill Hanrahan, a graduate of the Great Lakes Maritime
Academy, has over&amp;#0160;30 years of experience; the crews combined experience
is just under 200 years.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.&amp;#0160; Ann Arbor, MI was the site of GopherCon &amp;#39;92, a 50 person workshop for developers and users of the Gopher information system, a pioneering Internet publishing system that was for some brief furry moment the hot new thing on MTV and bigger than that super-complicated World Wide Web hypertext thing.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://iubio.bio.indiana.edu/soft/util/gopher/gophercon1.txt&#34;&gt;Prentiss Riddle wrote up the trip report for it,&lt;/a&gt; and here&amp;#39;s his writeup on my presentation at the time:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;RELATED TECHNOLOGIES: Ed Vielmetti of CICnet gave a talk on &amp;quot;what we would be gathering to discuss if UMinn had never developed Gopher&amp;quot;, meaning primarily World-Wide Web (WWW). WWW was developed for the high-energy physics community and serves as a model of what Gopher could do if a discipline-oriented virtual community invested in it&lt;br /&gt;heavily. WWW is based on SGML (Standard General Markup Language&amp;quot;), an ISO standard for marking up text which WWW uses to implement hypertext. SGML is a bear and it is a significant investment of effort to properly add a document to WWW, but the result is quite powerful (for instance, WWW handles footnotes in hypertext). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet periodically notices that Gopher is not dead; here are a survey of the current Gopher infrastructure from &lt;a href=&#34;http://kottke.org/06/08/gopher-still-going&#34;&gt;Jason Kottke&lt;/a&gt;, some April development from &lt;a href=&#34;http://george.hotelling.net/90percent/geekery/howto_make_a_weblog_a_gopherlog.php&#34;&gt;George Hotelling&lt;/a&gt;, and a manifesto from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scn.org/%7Ebkarger/gopher-manifesto&#34;&gt;Bjorn Karger&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worst season ever? - Michigan 2008 football not as bad as 1934</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-worst-season-ever---michigan-2008-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-worst-season-ever---michigan-2008-football/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;float: left;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535f82055970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535f82055970c&#34; alt=&#34;51-04189-B&#34; title=&#34;51-04189-B&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef010535f82055970c-800wi&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with all of the other t-shirts (Michigan Beer Pong, Michigan Undecided) for sale on State Street before football games, a new one has appeared this year:&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;2008 Worst Season Ever&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not being one to quarrel with a t-shirt, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go back through history and see just how bad this year&amp;rsquo;s team is compared to teams of the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; Rich Rodriguez has the worst lifetime record (2-7) of any Michigan football coach.&amp;nbsp; The nearest benchmark is the 1891 team, coached by Mike Murphy and Frank Crawford, who coached for one season with a 4-5 mark.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; The last years in modern times to have a two win season are 1962 (Bump Elliot) and 1958 (Bennie Oosterbann&amp;rsquo;s last year).&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.&amp;nbsp; In &lt;a href=&#34;http://bentley.umich.edu/athdept/football/fbteam/1934fbt.htm&#34;&gt;1934&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://bentley.umich.edu/athdept/football/fbteam/1936fbt.htm&#34;&gt;1936&lt;/a&gt;, Harry Kipke coached to a 1-7 record.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hooverstreetrag.blogspot.com/2007/11/harry-kipke-has-street-named-after-him.html&#34;&gt;Harry Kipke has a street named after him&lt;/a&gt;, notes the Hoover Street Rag, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/reader/1572436611/ref=sib_fs_top?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;p=S00P&amp;amp;checkSum=GoXlC%2BSVJfrhGaPTmGnsh3HniGYNsTaS19keqemvgqE%3D#reader-link&#34;&gt;the late Gerald Ford was MVP of the 1934 team.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/a&gt;   Ford wrote a chapter in What It Means To Be A Wolverine which is worth a read about just how difficult a year that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=1572436611&amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_blank&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, not quite the worst season ever, but pretty close - &#34;worst coach ever&#34; is too soon to tell, but RichRod still needs to live up to the Bump Elliot benchmark of winning the Rose Bowl (with the 1964 team vs Oregon State).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/08/michigan-footba.html&#34;&gt;The other football benchmark is of course is Michigan football (see the season map):&lt;/a&gt; look for a report on how the season compares to previous years next week.&amp;nbsp; The reports I have gathered from people with parking near the stadium who always fill up is that prices don&#39;t vary much by the success of the team, but the time to sell out the lot is a lot less on a busy day.&amp;nbsp; As you get farther from the Big House, even lower prices won&#39;t necessarily fill all the spaces.  Ann Arbor taxpayers depend on the rents from their 7x/year lawns to pay the property taxes, so we&#39;re all pulling for the team. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Toledo War, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-notes-on-the-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 15:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-notes-on-the-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; Holy Toledo!&lt;br /&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Two Stickney, younger brother of One Stickney.&lt;br /&gt;3.&amp;nbsp; 13-10.&lt;br /&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Parking prices due to drop for the rest of the season.&lt;br /&gt;5.&amp;nbsp; The Michigan-Ohio boundary was resurveyed in 1915, and it&#39;s not straight.&lt;br /&gt;6.&amp;nbsp; Seen on the way to the game: &amp;quot;Michigan Undecided&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Michigan Beer Pong&amp;quot; t-shirts.&lt;br /&gt;7.&amp;nbsp; Their mascot is &amp;quot;Rocky the Rocket&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;8.&amp;nbsp; Their home field is the &amp;quot;Glass Bowl&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched the game on Twitter with the radio on, listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.last.fm/music/Barefoot+Jerry&#34;&gt;Barefoot Jerry&lt;/a&gt; on WCBN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;POSTGAME UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/content/preview-toledo&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss will cause me to...&lt;/strong&gt; zombie apocalypse&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; (mgoblog)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2008/10/12/sunday-funnies-totter-toons/&#34;&gt;Bail for the conquering zeros&lt;/a&gt; (Totter Toons)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Football blogs 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-20-michigan-foot-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 15:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-20-michigan-foot-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s getting to be that time of year when the streets are crowded with eager fans looking for a place to park for Michigan football.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a list of blogs covering the 2008 season - not complete and not in any order - for reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/&#34;&gt;mgoblog&lt;/a&gt; starts preseason blogging in earnest next week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stadiumandmain.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Stadium and Main&lt;/a&gt; has notes about Comcast and the Big Ten Network in other cities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thosewhostaywillbechampions.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Michigan Football Saturdays&lt;/a&gt; was at Media Day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hooverstreetrag.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;The Hoover Street Rag&lt;/a&gt; has the band program schedule for the year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mvictors.com/&#34;&gt;MVictors&lt;/a&gt; regularly picks up old school Michigan memoriabilia from eBay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and of course I will remind you of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/08/michigan-footba.html&#34;&gt;Michigan Football Parking Map 2008&lt;/a&gt; with as much pregame parking pricing info as I can find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The season schedule from &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp&#34;&gt;michigan.rivals.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width=&#34;100%&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;2&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;stattable&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Aug. 30, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=UTAH&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 0.6em;&#34;&gt;(ABC)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;3:30 pm ET&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Sept. 6, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=MIAMIOH&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miami-OH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;12:00 pm ET&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Sept. 13, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=NOTREDAME&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notre Dame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 0.6em;&#34;&gt;(NBC)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;3:30 pm ET&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Sept. 27, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=WISCONSIN&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wisconsin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Oct. 4, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=ILLINOIS&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illinois&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 0.6em;&#34;&gt;(ABC)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;3:30 pm ET&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Oct. 11, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=TOLEDO&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toledo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Oct. 18, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=PENNST&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Penn State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;4:30 pm ET&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Oct. 25, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=MICHIGANST&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michigan State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Nov. 1, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=PURDUE&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purdue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Nov. 8, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=MINNESOTA&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minnesota&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#dddddd&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Nov. 15, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=NORTHWSTRN&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northwestern&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;Nov. 22, 2008&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34;&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.rivals.com/schedule.asp?Year=2008&amp;amp;Team=OHIOST&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ohio State&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td valign=&#34;bottom&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Football Parking 2008 map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-19-michigan-footba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 14:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-19-michigan-footba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are projected, estimated, possible, or likely prices for Michigan football parking for 2008.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://spreadsheets.google.com/ccc?key=pqZp74nNK6ZunQusNTgfKfA&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;the dataset I collected from the 2007 football season&lt;/a&gt;, which as you might recall had an unfortunate start (which definitely impacted prices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;s=AARTsJqbwUJ7RJr518l8IcBlS2jagebNSg&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=113932165856461159137.000454d3a8fd470f3f78f&amp;amp;ll=42.268671,-83.744402&amp;amp;spn=0.04446,0.072956&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;output=embed&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=113932165856461159137.000454d3a8fd470f3f78f&amp;amp;ll=42.268671,-83.744402&amp;amp;spn=0.04446,0.072956&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;source=embed&#34; style=&#34;color:#0000FF;text-align:left&#34;&gt;View Larger Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It needs better icons so you don&#39;t have to decode the color chart.&amp;nbsp; Typically prices can vary $5 from week to week depending on the game, and if all goes well it will rain on a Thursday so that the golf course is closed and thus neighborhood parking is at a premium.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>