<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan Football on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/michigan-football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan Football on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/michigan-football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>September 30, 2014 University of Michigan campus football protest</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 10:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-01-september-30-2014-university-of-michigan-campus-football-protest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is so much better than a home game&amp;quot; -protestor&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; mgoblog (@mgoblog) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mgoblog/status/517079310965178368&#34;&gt;September 30, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thanks Dave Brandon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 21:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-29-thanks-dave-brandon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brisk torch and pitchfork business offsets diminished football parking revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As noted on Twitter tonight. Michigan fans have loyalty to the school, even if they are not particularly fond of this season&#39;s athletic director.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a blow to the head, but back in the game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-28-a-blow-to-the-head-but-back-in-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tone of Michigan football blogs has changed since the loss to Minnesota on Saturday. Before the game there was a lot of grumbling, but it was varied; no one single issue stood out. After the game, it was much more clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of plays saw the second string Michigan quarterback, Shane Morris, get hit hard on his head. Morris is seen exhibiting signs of a concussion. Yet in an unfortunate sequence he goes back into the game after sitting out one play on the sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fans now have a pinpoint spot to point their anger at coach Brady Hoke. The team lost, but it&#39;s not all about winning and losing. What matters now is the understanding of the coaching staff and their inability to protect an obviously injured student from further harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michigan has gotten funding to reduce the risk of concussions in sports. It appears that all that effort was for naught in this particular instance of not protecting a player whose judgment was impaired because of a head injury. Coach Hoke is under fire and for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the risk of misplaced enthusiasm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-27-the-risk-of-misplaced-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in the life of a project it is inevitable that an obstacle comes up that makes you wonder whether your enthusiasm for the effort is well placed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you redouble your efforts, or do you take a break, or do you simply refocus and find something else to zero in on for the moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a bit of distance can help, at least temporarily. Rather than exit in flames with a tattered manifesto flapping on the door in your wake, just go quiet for a while. If no one notices that you are no longer present so much, then you can free up that unrequited love and apply it to something else for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Written for all those unhappy Michigan football fans.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>