<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathy Sample on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/kathy-sample/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kathy Sample on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:59:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/kathy-sample/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily telegraph: A new routine with the Argus Farm Stop and the Ann Arbor Y</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:59:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-13-daily-telegraph-a-new-routine-with-the-argus-farm-stop-and-the-ann-arbor-y/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was spring break, so my routines were completely upended. The boys didn&#39;t have school and so I didn&#39;t actually have to be anywhere in the morning. Yet I was up and out of bed and awake by 7:00 a.m. and the weather was nice. Perfect weather to try out a new spring routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first piece of the new routine is getting to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarborymca.org/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor YMCA&lt;/a&gt;. If the weather is nice and I don&#39;t have anything else going on, it&#39;s a nice bike ride; if I&#39;m making a car trip into town for school, it&#39;s close enough to be a good next stop. The only slight problem with the Y during the day is parking, not that I&#39;d spend money on parking, but that everyone knows to park on West Washington St. There&#39;s nothing quite like a sauna in the morning to get you going, and there&#39;s a lovely little library by the pool with a very fast wifi and good power outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second piece of the new routine is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.argusfarmstop.com/&#34;&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/a&gt;. I had been in here when it first opened, but now the routine has settled down a bit, and after the 8:00 a.m - 9:00 a.m. coffee rush it&#39;s a pretty reasonable spot to sit and type. There&#39;s delicious day-old bread to be had at reasonable prices and they will lop off an end for you to chew on while you drink your coffee. As a bonus the parking on Second St usually has a free space on one side or another at 8:00 a.m. so I can walk to the Y, do my thing, walk back, sit for a bit and type some more, and be good to go by 10:00 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation at the Farm Stop is sparkling - talked to a fellow named Granger who&#39;s moving here from Colorado about food, where to get a good bi bim bap, and his plans with his friends to open up a glass shop in town. 
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Kathy Sample&lt;/span&gt;
was behind the counter sorting out the morning flow and talking about the farmers bringing in their produce and their meats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between those two changes I now can pretty much count on being bathed, fed, watered, and have a little bit of shopping done by 10:00 a.m. If the weather is nice, I get a bike ride in to start the day, and I haven&#39;t spent any pennies on parking, and it also works to take the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>