<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food And Drink on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/food-and-drink/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food And Drink on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:25:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/food-and-drink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gin and rhubarb</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-02-gin-and-rhubarb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-02-gin-and-rhubarb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As noted elsewhere, gin and rhubarb are said to go well together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://boozedandinfused.com/2012/05/30/a-tale-of-two-rhubarbs-and-some-gin/&#34;&gt;Boozed and Infused&lt;/a&gt; has two recipes, one for Rhubarb Gin and one for Rhubarb Orange Gin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://theyearinfood.com/2011/05/the-tippler-rhubarb-fennel-fizz.html&#34;&gt;Rhubarb Fennel Fizz&lt;/a&gt; is from The Year in Food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am promised that if I provide the rhubarb, that gin will be provided to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&#39;t talk about rhubarb without Rhabarberbarbara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gG62zay3kck?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasty Green Cafe at Ann Arbor City Hall</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-tasty-green-cafe-at-ann-arbor-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-tasty-green-cafe-at-ann-arbor-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re looking to bump into city employees and talk shop, there&#39;s no better place to stop in than at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Tasty_Green_Cafe&#34;&gt;Tasty Green Cafe&lt;/a&gt; inside Ann Arbor City Hall. The menu includes the usual coffee drinks plus lunchtime choices like meat and spinach pies. There are three tables inside and a few more outside on the patio, and you get a nice view of the city hall fountain (which isn&#39;t running at the moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch (a meat pie and a coke) was $5.01. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked briefly with City Attorney &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Stephen_Postema&#34;&gt;Stephen Postema&lt;/a&gt; and his thoughts on proposed FOIA legislation coming from Lansing (he&#39;s skeptical). I told him about my new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2013/11/welcome-to-foia-friday.html&#34;&gt;FOIA Friday column on Damn Arbor&lt;/a&gt;, and he recognized Damn Arbor because it once wrote about his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2011/04/what-if-anything-is-hipster.html&#34;&gt;status as a hipster&lt;/a&gt; (he&#39;s not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental Coordinator &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Matt_Naud&#34;&gt;Matt Naud&lt;/a&gt; and I talked about the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/a2civictech&#34;&gt;a2civictech meetup&lt;/a&gt;, and he referred me to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wegowise.com/&#34;&gt;WeGoWise&lt;/a&gt; program in Boston that&#39;s reducing people&#39;s energy and water bills - similar, in spirit at least, to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dteenergy.mediaroom.com/index.php?s=26817&amp;amp;item=72330&#34;&gt;OPower insert&lt;/a&gt; in my recent DTE bill that told us we used a lot of electricity compared to our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmonella Heidelberg outbreak from raw chicken from Foster Farms - and the CDC and the USDA are at reduced capacity because of the government shutdown</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-08-salmonella-heidelberg-outbreak-from-raw-chicken-from-foster-farms-and-the-cdc-and-the-usda-are-at-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 21:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-08-salmonella-heidelberg-outbreak-from-raw-chicken-from-foster-farms-and-the-cdc-and-the-usda-are-at-re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affdf04b5970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affdf04b5970d&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;100813-map&#34; title=&#34;100813-map&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affdf04b5970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start with the lead of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/thesalt/2013/10/08/230486409/amidst-big-salmonella-outbreak-usda-says-it-s-on-the-job?sc=tw&amp;amp;cc=share&#34;&gt;NPR story&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Agriculture has issued a health alert warning that an estimated 278 illnesses caused by Salmonella Heidelberg are associated with raw chicken produced by Foster Farms at three facilities in California.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention says illnesses have been reported in 17 states, with the vast majority — 78 percent — in California. The outbreak is ongoing, so it&#39;s possible that people are still being sickened by the chicken.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The CDC says about 42 percent of the people who&#39;ve gotten sick (among those for whom information is available) have been hospitalized. The strains of Salmonella Heidelberg that have made people sick are resistant to several commonly prescribed antibiotics. And according to the CDC, the resistance may increase the risk of hospitalization or make the illness tougher to treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsis.usda.gov/wps/portal/fsis/newsroom/news-releases-statements-transcripts/news-release-archives-by-year/archive/2013/pha-100713&#34;&gt;USDA FSIS press release&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This public health alert is being issued after an estimated 278 illnesses were recently reported in 18 states, predominantly in California.  The outbreak is continuing. The investigations indicate that consumption of Foster Farms brand chicken and other brand chicken produced at Foster Farms plants are the likely source of this outbreak of Salmonella Heidelberg infections. Illnesses were linked to Foster Farms brand chicken through epidemiologic, laboratory and traceback investigations conducted by local, state, and federal officials. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is partnering with state health departments to monitor the outbreak while FSIS continues its investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdc.gov/salmonella/heidelberg-10-13/index.html&#34;&gt;CDC&#39;s MMWR report&lt;/a&gt;, a case count and map -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As of October 7, 2013, a total of 278 individuals infected with the outbreak strains of Salmonella Heidelberg have been reported from 17 states. Most of the ill persons (77%) have been reported from California. The number of ill persons identified in each state is as follows: Alaska (2), Arkansas (1), Arizona (11), California (213), Colorado (4), Connecticut (1), Florida (1), Hawaii (1), Idaho (2), Michigan (2), North Carolina (1), Nevada (8), Oregon (8), Texas (5), Utah (2), Washington (15) and Wisconsin (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wzzm13.com/news/article/270175/2/Salmonella-outbreak-in-18-states-including-Michigan&#34;&gt;WZZM / USA Today&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CDC has been hampered in tracing the outbreak because the government shutdown meant the agency had to shut down PulseNet, a national network of public health laboratories that looks for trends and matches reports to spot food-borne illness outbreaks. It&#39;s one of the agency&#39;s most important tools in detecting such problems.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;We were trying to do this without the automatic system, and it was nearly impossible,&#34; Reynolds said. Seven of the eight staffers who run the system were furloughed. &#34;We were doing it by hand, and it just become untenable.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;CDC director Thomas Frieden determined that not having PulseNet was resulting in &#34;an imminent threat to health and safety,&#34; a finding that allowed the agency to bring back the seven staffers, Reynolds said Tuesday. &#34;It&#39;s back up and running as of today.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdc.gov/pulsenet/&#34;&gt;PulseNet&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PulseNet compares the &#39;DNA fingerprints&#39; of bacteria from patients to find clusters of disease that might represent unrecognized outbreaks. Health officials can&#39;t stop an outbreak, and industry and regulatory agencies can&#39;t make changes to our food and water delivery systems, if they don&#39;t know that outbreaks are occurring. That&#39;s where PulseNet comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosterfarms.com/faq/faqfoodsafety.asp&#34;&gt;Foster Farms have to say&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Salmonella is naturally occurring in poultry and can be fully eradicated if raw product is properly handled and fully cooked,” said Dr. Robert O’Connor, the company’s food safety chief and head veterinarian. “All poultry producers strive to reduce bacterial presence, including Salmonella. We take food safety very seriously. When the incidence of illnesses linked to Salmonella increased, we wanted to know why and we have worked quickly to identify and implement additional controls. It is also important to reassure the public that the FSIS process has not been affected by the recent government shutdown.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably they also emphasize, in red:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No Recall is in Effect. Products are Safe to Consume if Properly Handled and Fully Cooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blimpy Burger is closing, it&#39;s closing, it&#39;s closing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-blimpy-burger-is-closing-its-closing-its-closing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 17:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-blimpy-burger-is-closing-its-closing-its-closing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Blimpy Burger is closing; three stories in the dotcom should convince you of that. Read about how it was - and how it might be in the future - on &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Blimpy_Burger&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&amp;#39;s Blimpy Burger page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ecb37e2970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot 2013-08-14 at 4.58.07 PM&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ecb37e2970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901ecb37e2970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2013-08-14 at 4.58.07 PM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Asparagus with mushrooms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-recipe-asparagus-with-mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-recipe-asparagus-with-mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This simple asparagus with mushrooms dish is served with pasta. J doesn&amp;#39;t like linguini, so we made it with rotini. This comes together in a hurry - you can cook the whole thing up in the time it takes to boil the pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two or three cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asparagus, about a pound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Button mushrooms, about a pound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basil, dried or fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boil water for pasta. When it&amp;#39;s hot, cook the pasta. There should be time to drain it after you&amp;#39;ve done the cooking of the asparagus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash the asparagus, snap the tough ends, and slice on the bias into 1.5&amp;quot; pieces. Clean the mushrooms and cut each one in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in a large frying pan on high. Fry the garlic until it&amp;#39;s light brown and smells great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the asparagus to the frying pan and cook, stirring frequently, until the asparagus is bright green. Add the mushrooms and keep stirring. When the mushrooms are hot, add the white wine, stir, and cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe called for basil, but I didn&amp;#39;t put it in because I was hurrying to get everything together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wine will deglaze the pan and make a nice sauce. Serve with pasta and white wine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Kale with corn and green onions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe for kale with corn and green onions works well enough with frozen corn, but I&amp;#39;m sure it would be better with fresh. You cook with the ingredients you have, not the ingredients you want to have. We&amp;#39;re lucky to have fresh kale at the farmers market!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bag kale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;corn - frozen, if you must, but fresh would be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green onions - chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash and spin-dry the kale, being careful to get dirt out of the center rib. We had a very nice bag of small kale from market that didn&amp;#39;t require much more than this, but if you have older, tougher kales, trim them of their tough bits and cut them into pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in a large pot on medium high to high. Chop some garlic into big pieces. Fry the garlic until light brown and it smells good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the kale and cook, stirring frequently, until the kale has cooked down to a fraction of its original size. Add some corn and the chopped green onions; stir. Cook until the corn is warmed through, then add some soy sauce and cover and turn down the heat to low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bag of kale served the family, with one person not eating it; there were a few leftovers. This recipe would multiply quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more kale recipes, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.365daysofkale.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;365 Days of Kale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweetwaters Ginger-Lemon Tea recipe (or at least something close)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-sweetwaters-ginger-lemon-tea-recipe-or-at-least-something-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 17:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-sweetwaters-ginger-lemon-tea-recipe-or-at-least-something-close/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a few sources for recipes that are similar to what you get at Sweetwaters when you order a Ginger-Lemon Tea (one of my favorites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Coppertop Kitchen (a blog by someone who was a Sweetwaters barista): &lt;a href=&#34;http://coppertopkitchen.blogspot.com/2012/01/ginger-lemon-tea.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ginger Lemon Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;2 cups fresh lemon juice&lt;br /&gt;1 3- by 1-inch piece of fresh ginger, peeled and sliced thinly&lt;br /&gt;10 cups water&lt;br /&gt;1 cup honey&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Place lemon juice, ginger, and water in a large saucepan over medium heat, and bring to a boil.&amp;#0160; Boil for a couple of minutes, cover and remove from heat, and steep at least 30 minutes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Food Network, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/lemon-ginger-tea-recipe/index.html?oc=linkback&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Lemon Ginger Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 quart water&lt;br /&gt;Juice of 1 lemon&lt;br /&gt;1/4 cup freshly grated ginger&lt;br /&gt;1/4 cup honey&lt;br /&gt;Thin slices of lemon and lime for garnish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a saucepan bring water to a boil. Add lemon juice, the squeezed lemon, and ginger. Let steep about 20 minutes. Stir in honey. Line a strainer with a thin wet cloth and strain tea into a pitcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From The Ginger People&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.constantcontact.com/fs087/1101564793691/archive/1102619855670.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, writing about Sweetwaters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;They initially juiced their own ginger for the Ginger Lemon Tea but its increasing popularity eventually caused them to look for a commercially available ginger ingredient. After considering several options, they decided on The Ginger People&amp;#39;s ginger juice because of its high quality and intensely true ginger flavor. Their secret recipe, which now includes our ginger juice, is served either hot or cold, and is one of their top selling drinks.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you go, the secret ingredient - you&amp;#39;ll have to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gingerpeople.com/ingredients&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;buy it in industrial quantities&lt;/a&gt;, or juice your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semolina Pudding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-31-semolina-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 10:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-31-semolina-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;(originally posted January 26, 2003&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEMOLINA PUDDING&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ingredients:&lt;br /&gt;1 cup sugar&lt;br /&gt;1 cup milk&lt;br /&gt;4 cups water&lt;br /&gt;grated peel of 1 lemon (pref. organic)&lt;br /&gt;1 cup semolina flour&lt;br /&gt;cinnamon&lt;br /&gt;raspberries or other berries&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Directions:&lt;br /&gt;Mix sugar, milk, water and lemon peel in a pot or big saucepan. Heat until just about to boil, then gradually sprinkle in semolina flour, whisking the whole time to prevent lumps from forming. Allow mixture to thicken considerably. Remove from heat and pour into bowl, mold, or cupcake pan. Refrigerate for at least two hours. Pudding should be somewhat firmer than chocolate pudding, but less firm than jello.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When ready to serve, unmold pudding or leave in bowl and sprinkle with cinnamon. Top with raspberries or other fruit. Sugared raspberries are particularly nice when a little bit of sauce is formed and can be poured over the pudding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The pudding has a texture that is somehow both agreeably grainy and smooth and is very cooling in the summertime. You can vary the milk:water ratio in the recipe, even to the point of omitting one or the other entirely.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(thanks to puddingmeister Deb for the recipe)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta with leeks, cashews, and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-pasta-with-leeks-cashews-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-pasta-with-leeks-cashews-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dinner tonight was surprisingly good, especially because I didn&amp;#39;t have a recipe. All measurements approximate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one leek, white parts only, cleaned and cut into thin strips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rice wine&amp;#0160;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cashews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feta, cubed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pasta (we used farfalle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat the olive oil. Add the leeks to the pan, with a sprinkling of oregano on top. Cook the leeks until just browned. Deglaze the pan with a little rice wine. Add cashews and feta, return to the heat, and cook until the feta is warm and just starting to melt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve over pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yum! Serves 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The challenge of dinner</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-23-the-challenge-of-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 19:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-23-the-challenge-of-dinner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cooking dinner while I&amp;#39;m hungry just makes me hungrier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The daily sandwich: Serious Eats on sandwiches</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-the-daily-sandwich-serious-eats-on-sandwiches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 01:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-the-daily-sandwich-serious-eats-on-sandwiches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Serious Eats has a blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seriouseats.com/a_sandwich_a_day/&#34;&gt;A Sandwich A Day&lt;/a&gt;, with a nicely illustrated and well researched sandwich every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this great country of ours, one could eat a different sandwich every day of the year—so that&#39;s what we&#39;ll do. Here&#39;s A Sandwich a Day, our daily look at sandwiches around the country. Got a sandwich we should check out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a a part of this they note the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seriouseats.com/2011/08/the-grandwich-sandwich-competition-in-grand-rapids-michigan.html&#34;&gt;Grandwich competition in Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;, where 10 sandwich vendors competed for the best sandwich in town prize. The winner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;The G-Wrap&#34; from BOB-Bobarinos restaurant in downtown Grand Rapids, which featured crisp seared Big B Farms pulled pork, spiced barbecue sauce, locally-made Andouille sausage, and spicy pickle slaw on spiced naan. &#34;It wraps Grand Rapids up!&#34; said executive chef Jared Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love me some sammiches, and I&#39;m sure there&#39;s at least one Ann Arbor area sandwich worth mentioning in A Sandwich A Day. (I&#39;ll bet you could eat a different sandwich every day without leaving downtown Ann Arbor.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 13:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And, if I am able to rectify the situation, I will &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com/business-review/long-awaited-subway-on-the-corner-of-packard-and-platt-opens/?cmpid=NL_DH_topicbox_headline&#34;&gt;share my profits with Jordan Miller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I agree! There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this website. I, for one, love sandwiches. What if all the pet stories were sandwich stories instead? Everyone isn&#39;t into pets, but who doesn&#39;t like sandwiches? Not anyone I want living in my town. PS if [redacted] puts this advice into action, I expect a share of what is sure to be a tremendous surge in profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For who does not love sandwiches? They are compact, and amiable, and easy to pack for lunch. If you have a generous lunch budget, you have have someone else make you a sandwich of wide variety on the spot and enjoy it at your leisure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous sandwich coverage here and elsewhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/eat-well-at-any-deli-by-making-your-own-sandwich-1/&#34;&gt;Eat well at any deli by making your own sandwich&lt;/a&gt;, written for AnnArbor.com; please excuse the random punctuation marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/monday-lunch-links-fried-egg-sandwich/&#34;&gt;Fried egg sandwich&lt;/a&gt;, also written for AnnArbor.com; please excuse the lack of photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/06/lack-of-discretion-is-the-better-part-of-twitter.html&#34;&gt;Lack of discretion is the better part of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, on this blog: &#34;Your indiscretions make up for the rest of us who are content to describe where we are eating a sandwich.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancakes? Take our poll.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-12-pancakes-take-our-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 11:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-12-pancakes-take-our-poll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;http://widget.allourideas.org/pancakes?width=450&amp;amp;height=410&#34; height=&#34;410&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recipes follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic pancake recipe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers call &lt;a href=&#34;http://dinersjournal.blogs.nytimes.com/2008/12/24/recipe-of-the-day-everyday-pancakes/&#34;&gt;Mark Bittman&#39;s basic Everyday Pancakes recipe&lt;/a&gt;, from Christmas Eve in 2008, &#34;uninspired&#34;; that creates the necessary fermentation in the comments to generate 27 earnest responses with variations on a theme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rhubarb syrup, and what to make with it; and, conversely, how to avoid it</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-02-rhubarb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 01:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-02-rhubarb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working my way through the rhubarb recipe set, I find variations on what I made tonight, which was stewed rhubarb. If you were to separate the juice from the fruit, you&amp;#39;d get &lt;strong&gt;Rhubarb Syrup&lt;/strong&gt;, as seen in &lt;a href=&#34;http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/07/01/case-study-rhubarb-syrup/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(water, vanilla pod, no sugar), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thekitchn.com/thekitchn/ingredients-fruit/homemade-pantry-rhubarb-syrup-084304&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(4c rhubarb, 1c sugar, 1c water, ginger root), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodinjars.com/2009/05/rhubarb-syrup-recipe/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Food in Jars&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(more sugar). Use as a flavoring in fizzy water, or in a fizzy drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhubarb Daisy&lt;/strong&gt;, a drink made with this syrup (gin, lemon juice, soda, syrup) is seen in &lt;a href=&#34;http://thepauperedchef.com/article/homemade-rhubarb-syrup-and-rhubarb-daisy&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Paupered Chef&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use both parts of the straining operation when you&amp;#39;re done with stewed rhubarb. &amp;#0160;Take the now no longer fibrous bits and use as a &amp;quot;rustic jam&amp;quot;; add pectin to the syrup, and you get &lt;strong&gt;Rhubarb Jelly,&lt;/strong&gt; a la &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tasteofhome.com/Recipes/Rhubarb-Jelly&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Taste of Home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you won&amp;#39;t want to stew the rhubarb down entirely, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peoplesfood.coop/recipes/rhubarb.php&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;People&amp;#39;s Food Coop&lt;/a&gt; has this recipe for &lt;strong&gt;Rhubarb Poached in Red Wine&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thebittenword.typepad.com/thebittenword/2009/05/rice-pudding-with-poached-rhubarb.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Bitten Word&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;has a similar recipe pairing the rhubarb with rice pudding. To avoid stewing the rhubarb down entirely, aim for &lt;strong&gt;Roasted Rhubarb&lt;/strong&gt;, a la &lt;a href=&#34;http://wednesdaychef.typepad.com/the_wednesday_chef/2007/06/rose_grays_and_.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Wednesday Chef&lt;/a&gt;, or a simple recipe from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doriegreenspan.com/2009/06/-tomorrow-ill-be-going.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Dorie Greenspan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Coconut-potato curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is good for those days when you have dinner that might be postponed for a long time. The curry can be served quickly, but if you leave it on the stove longer the potatoes turn into a kind of delicious curry gravy for the garbanzos. We served it with greens, and it would have been good with a side of cauliflower as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coconut-potato curry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 lbs potatoes, boiled, with 1 cup cooking water reserved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curry powder, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cans garbanzo beans, cooked and drained and rinsed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare potatoes by boiling them until done. Reserve some cooking water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the potatoes are boiling, fry a chopped onion in some oil on low heat. When the onion smells nice but is not brown, add the curry powder and cook, stirring, until fragrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the coconut milk to the curry mixture and stir until well mixed. Then add the garbanzoes, and cook covered on low heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the potatoes are ready, add them to the garbanzo curry. Cut the potatoes into smaller pieces if they are too large. Keep covered, and add up to 1 cup potato water if the mixture gets too dry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>