<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karl Weick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/karl-weick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Karl Weick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/karl-weick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Small wins</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-w08-1-small-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-w08-1-small-wins/</guid>
      <description>I am reminded again of Karl Weick&amp;rsquo;s work on &amp;ldquo;small wins&amp;rdquo;, the observation that large problems are so large that we are overwhelmed just in thinking about them. It can be incredibly powerful to have a series of small wins that provide some momentum and that set you up for increasing confidence and capability to tackle bigger issues.
My small win of the moment is getting this blog post up, reminding myself that once upon a time I met a writing deadline every day for publication, and knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary for every single post to be a big thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small wins and writing productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 15:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m intrigued of late by the notion of &#34;small wins&#34;. This is prompted by reading Wayne Baker&#39;s book on social networks in which he quotes Karl Weick. Rather than try to solve big problems all at once, you attack them by making progress on a series of smaller more attainable goals. This keeps morale up and shows you that you&#39;re really getting somewhere, even if on the grand scale it doesn&#39;t register yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breeding black swans</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-01-breeding-black-swans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-01-breeding-black-swans/</guid>
      <description>I had a disturbing thought while rereading Malcolm Gladwell&amp;#39;s piece on Nassim Taleb in his latest book which collects his New Yorker essays. What if Taleb is not only profiting from unknownable random adverse events, but also encouraging their proliferation?
The logic runs like this. You place a series of bets, where if you lose you lose $1 and if you win you win $1000000. The bets are on some implausible condition, one which (at the outset) there is no chance of happening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>