<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karl Weick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/karl-weick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Karl Weick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 15:47:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/karl-weick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Breeding black swans</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-01-breeding-black-swans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-01-breeding-black-swans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a disturbing thought while rereading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gladwell.com/2002/2002_04_29_a_blowingup.htm&#34;&gt;Malcolm Gladwell&amp;#39;s piece on Nassim Taleb&lt;/a&gt; in his latest book which collects his New Yorker essays. What if Taleb is not only profiting from unknownable random adverse events, but also encouraging their proliferation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logic runs like this. You place a series of bets, where if you lose you lose $1 and if you win you win $1000000. The bets are on some implausible condition, one which (at the outset) there is no chance of happening. You bet the first time, you lose; the counterparty is $1 richer and one iota more confident. You bet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there really is a one in a million chance of winning, in the long run you will break even. The scary notion, though is the thought that by losing over and over again you can change the probabilities of the game, so that once you have lost 1000 times your opponent - who is $1000 richer - will start making decisions about how they conduct their business that increases the chance that you will win this long-shot bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your series of losses are funding the adversary&amp;#39;s bad behavior. They are up $1000, haven&amp;#39;t lost in 3 years, have an unbroken string of fiscal quarters where each and every quarter they beat the analysts estimates by a penny. Management becomes bolder, knowing that their track record demands that they confidently take on risks that 3 or 6 or 12 years ago whey would have shunned. After a long interrupted run of good fortune misinterpreted as careful skill they seek out the next incrementally more risky and profitable opportunity in order to pursue the growth that you have funded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m challenged to reconcile the strategy of &amp;quot;small wins&amp;quot;, where you look to succeed in small ways over and over again to build confidence, with the Taleb style strategy of &amp;quot;small losses&amp;quot; where you take lots and lots of calibrated long shot bets that often lose. It&amp;#39;s discouraging to think that the confidence that you are building with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=karl+weick+small+wins&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0&amp;amp;as_vis=1&amp;amp;oi=scholart&#34;&gt;Karl Weick style small win strategy&lt;/a&gt; of building upon small incremental gains might be deliberately funded by someone who is set up to profit big time if you grow for a long time and then lose it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small wins and writing productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 15:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m intrigued of late by the notion of &#34;small wins&#34;. This is prompted by reading Wayne Baker&#39;s book on social networks in which he quotes Karl Weick. Rather than try to solve big problems all at once, you attack them by making progress on a series of smaller more attainable goals. This keeps morale up and shows you that you&#39;re really getting somewhere, even if on the grand scale it doesn&#39;t register yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A small win is a concrete, complete outcome of moderate importance. By itself, one small win may seem unimportant. A series of small wins at small but significant tasks, however, reveals a pattern that may attract allies, deter opponents, and lower resistance to subsequent proposals. A series of small wins is also more structurally sound than a large win because small wins are stable building blocks. Small wins are controllable opportunities that produce visible results. Once a small win has been accomplished, forces are set in motion that favor another small win. When a solution is put into place, the next solvable problem often becomes more visible. Additional resources flow toward winners, which means that slightly larger wins can be attempted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, rather than think about how hard it would be to produce a book of 80,000 words all in one sitting, it gets a lot easier to think how easy it would be to produce 400 words per day (on a topic of your choice naturally) for 200 days over the course of a year. I can bat out 100 words without thinking about it to answer an email message a dozen times a day. So capturing 80,000 words is simply a matter of doing that in some sensible order and not getting sidetracked by the need for everything to make 100% sense at the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(originally published Monday, August 07, 2000)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>