<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gadgets on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/gadgets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gadgets on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 11:14:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/gadgets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acer C720 Chromebook as a Minecraft machine?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-29-acer-c720-chromebook-as-a-minecraft-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 11:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-29-acer-c720-chromebook-as-a-minecraft-machine/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m looking into getting an Acer C720 Chromebook as a next computer.
Shopping sources:
 Google via Amazon Newegg  Prices vary; I had seen less than $175, but now (late July 2014) it&#39;s running about $200. Of particular interest is the ability of this system to run Linux. Your choices are
 Crouton Chrubuntu  Of especially particular interest is Minecraft on a Chromebook. Here&#39;s a walk through of Minecraft on an Acer C720 with Crouton, which reports that &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on bringing the laptop into the shop for repairs</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-01-on-bringing-the-laptop-into-the-shop-for-repairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-01-on-bringing-the-laptop-into-the-shop-for-repairs/</guid>
      <description>My Mac is in the shop. It&amp;#39;s getting a new wifi card, and while they are at it they&amp;#39;ll replace the chipped case. The chip fixing means that labor is free for the wifi fixing so it&amp;#39;s a very reasonable cost.
The last time I had any kind of extended computer downtime I remember it being a strain, since I then had so much of my personal computing stuff actually on my computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>art on a shovel, some sources: metalworking</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-07-art-on-a-shovel-some-sources-metalworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 23:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-07-art-on-a-shovel-some-sources-metalworking/</guid>
      <description>Getting ready for a February art on a shovel project (&#34;shovel ready!&#34;). Here&#39;s some sources of inspiration.
Masks from recycled shovel blades, John T. Unger.
Plasma cut steel shovels, Cal Lane.
Shovel art, Texas Lone Star, Iron Signs and Designs.
Each of these involve some serious metalworking, generally with round point dirt shovel as the starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>