<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Honeyman on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-honeyman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peter Honeyman on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-honeyman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or
is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage
everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging
environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have
my computer with me. On the other hand doing live-blogging from a phone is
not possible, not that it ever really was very practical with any previous setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your UMARC shack access code is &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Achievement unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The todo list right now for the shack is very short - &amp;ldquo;get in&amp;rdquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m
in I should have a longer list. There is a lot of gear in that room
to get familiar with, not least of which is HF equipment with tunable
and movable antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/twitter-marius-eriksen-finagle/&#34;&gt;Why Twitter Has More Freedom To Innovate Than Google&lt;/a&gt; is a 2013 Wired Magazine writeup.
Prominently featured are Marius Eriksen, Niels Provos, and Peter Honeyman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the early aughts, when Eriksen was an undergrad at
Michigan, studying computer science under a professor and lovable
eccentric named Peter Honeyman. Known as “Dr. Honey” among the
undergrads and PhD students at his Center for Information Technology
Integration, Honeyman was famous for making assignments without
really making assignments. “He would develop a particular obsession,
and he would give you random hints about it, but he wouldn’t actually
tell you what to do,” Eriksen remembers. “You would end up collaborating
with people on whatever it was, in this freeform way, without much
direction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to one of Peter&amp;rsquo;s current students. Evan is looking at ways to
direct RF energy at devices to make them fail in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan are working on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://it.slashdot.org/story/15/06/30/1917207/stanford-starts-the-secure-internet-of-things-project&#34;&gt;Secure Internet of Things Project (slashdot)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan have now started
the Secure Internet of Things Project, which aims to promote security
and transparency for IoT devices. They hope to unite regulators,
researchers, and manufacturers to ensure nascent internet-connected
tech is developed in a way that respects customer privacy and choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web site has more details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu&#34;&gt;http://iot.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the presentations at the Secure Internet of Things Project Retreat
in Half Moon Bay on June 5, 2015 was this by U of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Prabal Dutta,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu/retreat15/sitp15-swhw.pdf&#34;&gt;State of the Field: Hardware and Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(embed deck here, if I can)
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LP0965 Antenna is a Log Periodic PCB directional antenna, at 5-6dBi Gain.
The design is from Kent Britain WA5VJB, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wa5vjb.com/pcb-pdfs/LP8565.pdf&#34;&gt;data sheet for the antenna&lt;/a&gt; describes its
utility for signals from 850 Mhz to 6500 Mhz. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://wa5vjb.com&#34;&gt;http://wa5vjb.com&lt;/a&gt; for more
circuit board antennas for use for hobby, wifi, microwave and cellular use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic jam on Fuller on the return trip, backed up all the way to the river.
It took about 15 minutes to get through because of construction on westbound
Fuller taking traffic to one lane. It would have been faster to take the Route 1
AAATA bus via Pontiac Trail, even though it would have been a considerable detour,
or to walk to Plymouth Road and take the 2 in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fire at the Michigan League this afternoon. No sign of any issues
as I pass by this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question when taking Commuter South is always where to get off the bus. Today
I&amp;rsquo;ll take it all the way to the end of its route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No email for the weekend</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-03-no-email-for-the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-03-no-email-for-the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve updated my email vacation message to inform my correspondents that I&amp;#39;m taking the weekend off from electronic mail. If you get some message to that effect, you know how to get ahold of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I envy those with enough status to completely exit electronic mail, but at the very least I expect that an occasional weekend could be email-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Jones&lt;/strong&gt; has given up on email, in his &lt;a href=&#34;http://ibiblio.org/pjones/blog/category/noemail/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;#noemail&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://peter.honeyman.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Peter Honeyman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is behind on reading his email. Aren&amp;#39;t we all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr CEO &lt;strong&gt;David Karp&lt;/strong&gt; notices that &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inc.com/magazine/201106/the-way-i-work-david-karp-of-tumblr.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;if you&amp;#39;re not responsive to e-mail&lt;/a&gt;, it trains people to leave you alone.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Freeman&lt;/strong&gt; rants against &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.simonandschuster.com/Tyranny-of-E-mail/John-Freeman/9781416576730&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;the tyranny of email&lt;/a&gt;, in book length form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, &lt;strong&gt;Nathaniel Borenstein&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cio.co.uk/debate/3232906/nathaniel-borenstein-on-why-email-isnt-dead/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;told CIO magazine that email was not dead&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dir.salon.com/tech/feature/2003/10/02/e_mail/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;E-mail is broken&lt;/a&gt; was a Salon.com headline. &lt;strong&gt;Jacob Nielsen &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;stopped using e-mail and hired staff to do it for me.&amp;quot; It was a bad year for spam, and &lt;strong&gt;Joi Ito&lt;/strong&gt; pronounced email &lt;a href=&#34;http://joi.ito.com/weblog/2003/08/14/email-is-offici.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;officially broken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu/~uno/email.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don Knuth&lt;/strong&gt; has been happy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;since he gave up email in 1990 after 15 years of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>