<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Malletts Creek Branch Library on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/malletts-creek-branch-library/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Malletts Creek Branch Library on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/malletts-creek-branch-library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of BBQ at Ricewood.
 One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and manual file transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lunch with jonathan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:30:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</guid>
      <description>Jonathan and I went to Paradise, a Vietnamese place in the Colonade that also serves Chinese food. He got Mongolian Beef, and I got pho deluxe. It was perfectly adequate if not spectacular. The topic of conversation was an elaborate storyline in a game that involved animatronics in a creepy Chuck E. Cheese type abandoned pizza parlor.
We then went to the Malletts Creek library, until about 4:00 p.m. I worked on Hugo and constructed a theme from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>