<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supermemo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/supermemo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supermemo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/supermemo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermemo, spaced repetition and time-structured randomness</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-06-supermemo-spaced-repetition-and-structured-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-06-supermemo-spaced-repetition-and-structured-randomness/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve written about Supermemo before, a system for focusing your attention on things that you have previously learned in such a way that you reinforce long term memory. Given a set of items which you were confident in at a stage in the past, identify a way to re-test yourself on that confidence. Space out those retest intervals so that you keep the learning from decaying into nothingness. Repetition is the very soul of the net, and if you are careful you can repeat at intervals that don&amp;#39;t overwhelm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermemo: repetition is the very soul of the net</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-12-supermemo-repet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 14:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-12-supermemo-repet/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about SuperMemo some months back, but if I&#39;ve told you once, I&#39;ve told you 146 times: repetition is the very soul of the net.
SuperMemo is a piece of software from P A Wozniak, originally developed in 1987 as a DOS program for learning languages.&amp;nbsp; Wozniak, a student of molecular biology, was frustrated by the amount of knowledge he lost after cramming for an exam, and worked to develop methods for improving long term memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>supermemo and morning coffee ritual memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</guid>
      <description>An important piece of having coffee in the morning is making it part of a routine. If you&#39;re predictable in your habits, you start to see the same people in the same space at the same time, and you get to be something of a regular.
If you&#39;re careful, and switch your morning allegiances from time to time but still visit the old haunts often enough, you can be what passes for a regular long after you stopped coming every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>