<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vrml on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/vrml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vrml on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/vrml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink.
Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong
iced latte, just add a little half and half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending
postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite
images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence
of mind seven years ago to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-29-image-processing-on-the-mac-with-sips-imagemagick-watching-dte-restore-power-slowly/&#34;&gt;write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick&lt;/a&gt;
for image manipulation and that helped. In this case the magic incantation
was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sips -z 1275 1875 original.jpg --out new.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Mac, or want to do this on a server or container
somewhere, you&amp;rsquo;ll want Imagemagick. That venerable program has a
bazillion options, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find the image geometry options at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imagemagick.org/script/command-line-processing.php#geometry&#34;&gt;http://www.imagemagick.org/script/command-line-processing.php#geometry&lt;/a&gt; .
Recreating this exact sips command is left as an exercise for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bit of image processing taken care of, the next iteration is to
launch a few actual postcards into the ether. After having confirmed
that everything goes OK on the test key, I sent out four cards. Estimated
delivery date is July 30, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting about a two week turnaround
for feedback that I got everything right. Lob has card tracking so I guess
the next step is to write the simple tools to know when things were
delivered so that I can plan some phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr  /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin Zorba has perhaps the best bio in the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has, in the course of his endeavors: been shot at by Navajos
in Utah; seized and threatened at knifepoint by rednecks in Arkansas;
chased by AK-47-toting soldiers in Hungary; run out of town by the
Penitentes in Truchas; shaken down by the Federales in Baja, and
forced to be rude to secure a cab in Rome. He has hung out of and
over: planes, balloons, helicopters, boats, rafts, race cars,
elevator shafts, too tall cliffs, and real deep canyons- and yet,
he still has enthusiasm and a good attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerry Davis asks why we still have academic journals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web has greatly reduced the barriers to entry for new journals
and other platforms for communicating scientific output, and the
number of journals continues to multiply. This leaves readers and
authors with the daunting cognitive challenge of navigating the
literature and discerning contributions that are both relevant and
significant. Meanwhile, measures of journal impact that might guide
the use of the literature have become more visible and consequential,
leading to “impact gamesmanship” that renders the measures increasingly
suspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay, published in &lt;a href=&#34;http://asq.sagepub.com/content/59/2/193&#34;&gt;Administrative Science Quarterly&lt;/a&gt; in June 2014, has the seeds of its own answer. Journals
exist to enrich academic publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay per Article - You may purchase this article for US$32.00. You
must download your purchase, which is yours to keep, within 24
hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just ask Jerry for a preprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously (1995!) I get quoted in the Times Higher Education Supplement.
The debate then centered around Stevan Harnad, an open access journal
advocate who saw clearly the trend towards low cost electronic publications,
thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It remains only to tally up these PostGutenberg values: If the
world&amp;rsquo;s esoteric scholarly/scientific literature were available to
everyone for free in electronic form, the first benefit to the
author would be the great increase in the visibility, accessibility
and hence the potential impact of his work (1). This would of course
also be a benefit to all scholars when they are wearing their
readers&amp;rsquo; rather than their authors&amp;rsquo; hats (2). Some fear that such
a literature would be overwhelming and un-navigable, but stop and
think: How do we currently manage it in paper? If the entire corpus
were transferred to the Net, instead of our eyes and fingers and
feet doing the walking to get to the papers or to get the papers
to us, electronic directories containing everything could be searched
using the kinds of keyword search already used today in searching
electronic databases that contain the titles and abstracts (but not
the articles) in the paper literature. Then, one more click, and
you have the paper itself! Or clever &amp;ldquo;knowbots&amp;rdquo; (automatic search
programmes) could be designed to go out instead of us and look for
papers fitting our profile of interests, leaving us even more time
to actually read what we want and to do our research, rather than
running after the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reply, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.timeshighereducation.co.uk/features/harnad-versus-fuller-round-2/98502.article&#34;&gt;immortalized from the past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Vielmetti (bottom) uncontroversially points out that there
is a lot of rubbish on the Internet; but he is sceptical of peer
review as a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original commentary is lost in the mists of time, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two institutions that went by the name of GopherCon.
(No, it&amp;rsquo;s not a furry convention; that&amp;rsquo;s Anthrocon.) One was
from the early 1990s surrounding the Gopher internet browsing
protocol; the other is for enthusiasts and programmers of the
Go programming language. I am not aware of anyone who can claim
to have gone to both events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.databaseteam.org/10-database/0722cf77b51ab4ba.htm&#34;&gt;GopherCon 1995&lt;/a&gt;
featured discussion of GopherVR and VRML for virtual reality in Gopher,
the Hyper-G Information System for hypertext authoring, and an
early morning session on Integrating Gopher and WWW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GopherCon 2015 was in early July in Colorado. Of the items on
the agenda this talk by Barak Michener was perhaps the most interesting
to follow through on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written in Go, Cayley is a graph database based on technology
behind Freebase.com. Starting with a short history of the inspirations
behind Cayley, this talk will deep-dive into the moving parts of
building a graph database, between the various query languages, the
storage engines, and the iterator trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course this blog is now powered by Hugo which is written in Go
so I&amp;rsquo;m learning a little about the Go template language as a side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>