<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food And Drink Juneberry Strawberries on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/food-and-drink-juneberry-strawberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food And Drink Juneberry Strawberries on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:50:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/food-and-drink-juneberry-strawberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>making fruit liqueurs, (or) how to prepare for the holidays well in advance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s fruit season (or nearly so) and so it&#39;s time to start thinking about what we&#39;re going to do for making holiday gifts.  One staple in our house is a simple fruit liqueur of some sort, which turns sugar + fruit + vodka + time into something yummy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not generally a cocktails household, so part of the corresponding challenge is giving people some sense of what do to with the jar to help them enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some minimal collection of things to help for this year, one fruit at a time; not exhaustive, but maybe it will help jump start next year.  Ordered in rough order of appearance of the fruit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strawberry liqueur.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cottagesmallholder.com/?p=750&#34;&gt;Irene&#39;s Strawberry liqueur&lt;/a&gt; from The Cottage Smallholder; noting that &#34;There’s nothing like the distraction of homemade grog when times are getting tough.&#34;
&lt;li&gt;Juneberry liqueur.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.farm-garden.com/viewtopic.php?id=1056&#34;&gt;Saskatoons go with gin&lt;/a&gt;, says contributor &#34;prairiemaid&#34; from Manitoba.
&lt;li&gt;Gooseberry liqueur.  In the 1930s, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bedfordshire.gov.uk/CommunityAndLiving/ArchivesAndRecordOffice/GuidesToCollections/MeltisofBedford.aspx&#34;&gt;Meltis of Bedford&lt;/a&gt; introduced a gooseberry liqueur sweet to the UK market which was a big success, so they say.    Read Anton Chekov&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eldritchpress.org/ac/gooseb.html&#34;&gt;Gooseberries&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&#39;t have a recipe.
&lt;li&gt;Currants.  Make cassis; here&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.ibiblio.org/pipermail/labruscagrape/2005-June/000296.html&#34;&gt;cassis recipe&lt;/a&gt;, from &#34; The Cook and the Gardener&#34; by Amanda Hesser, A Year of Recipes and Writings from the French Countryside.
&lt;li&gt;Blueberries.  Freeze the berries first, then make &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guntheranderson.com/liqueurs/blueber0.htm&#34;&gt;blueberry liqueur.&lt;/a&gt;.  Ex-Michigander &lt;a href=&#34;http://culinariaeugenius.wordpress.com/2008/02/28/my-staples-summer-blueberry-liqueur/&#34;&gt;Culinaria Eugenius&lt;/a&gt; has a photo of the red-purple liquid that results.  
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>