<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:14:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Griefnet, support for grief, death, and major loss</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-griefnet-support-for-grief-death-and-major-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-griefnet-support-for-grief-death-and-major-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.griefnet.org/&#34;&gt;GriefNet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is an Internet community approach to on line grief support, providing support to people working through loss and grief issues of all kinds. Cendra Lynn is the leader of the organization, and I had some small technological part in starting it back in 1993 when the appropriate technology of the day was Gopher, not the World Wide Web. The system hosts dozens of moderated mailing lists for people who share a common loss like the death of a spouse or the loss of a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a nice conversation with Cendra last night about how hard it is to build a community where people who are going through a lot can have a place where they can trust each other enough to share what are not easy feelings to share. It takes active moderation, careful planning, and a constant attention to the details of online identity. The technology is not fancy - they are using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/mailman/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Mailman&lt;/a&gt; mailer, which is now 15 years in development - and the key community insight is that it&amp;#39;s utterly crucial to keep people&amp;#39;s identity pseudonomous (first name only) so that people can focus on working through grief and not get distracted by the rest of people&amp;#39;s real lives. This is so completely unlike the over-sharing Google Plus and overtly commercialized Facebook as to be worthy of note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration and community leadership</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-12-collaboration-and-community-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 13:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-12-collaboration-and-community-leadership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about collaboration and community leadership, since it seems to be something that I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples that come to mind share some common traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a mix of online and in person communications, and not solely one or the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for routine everyday communications you use whatever everyone is using in your field; be that email or facebook or twitter or phone or sms, you adapt to the existing norms to start at least.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the successful communicator is good at more than one network and can move between them, pulling ideas and people along for the ride.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somewhere at the center of the network there&amp;#39;s a culturally appropriate publication process that generates an external memory of what has been communicated, whether that&amp;#39;s a ritual behavior, a database, something like a wiki, or some book or printed artifact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that if you can manage to satisfy all four of these factors that you can get alongwith a wide range of technologies. The working amateur radio clubs that I know fit the bill,&amp;#0160;as do some networks that are coordinated by prolific bloggers or that have sprung up&amp;#0160;around civic wikis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that emerged from writing this was realizing that ritual behavior could be the&amp;#0160;external memory that you get from community leadership, and that doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily&amp;#0160;need to be written down. Just knowing that there&amp;#39;s some component of a community that&amp;#0160;gathers in an orderly way regularly and that follows a pattern that&amp;#39;s not much different&amp;#0160;from the time before, that&amp;#39;s a powerful synchronizing pulse that can feed all sorts of&amp;#0160;other informal collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
Thanks to Kevin Doyle Jones for the conversation that led to this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to watch on CTN, April 1-7, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What to watch on CTN is the City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s weekly programming guide to public access cable. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/educationstation/Documents/CTN_WTW_2011-04-01.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Download this week&amp;#39;s flyer as a PDF.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;Here&amp;#39;s show listings for April 1-7, 2011. Note that several of these are also available on demand over the Internet at &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.org/ctn&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://a2gov.org/ctn&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3a9a380970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;CTN_WTW_2011-04-01&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3a9a380970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3a9a380970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;CTN_WTW_2011-04-01&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti is certain to make it big in television if he ever gets a chance to break in to the big time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing questions with Aardvark</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-practicing-questions-with-aardvark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-practicing-questions-with-aardvark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aardvark is &lt;a href=&#34;http://vark.com/&#34;&gt;vark.com&lt;/a&gt; - as of February 2010 they are owned by the Google. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s part of a genre of question asking sites where the answer comes back partly from &amp;quot;your network&amp;quot; and partly from the random parts of the net that you don&amp;#39;t know very much about. If you think you have an interesting question, you can ask it on Aardvark and see what you get. &amp;#0160;My practice efforts have been pretty dismal, but I might be asking for things outside of what it&amp;#39;s capable of doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It might simply be that I&amp;#39;ve been at it too long and my non-random sources for answers to random questions are just better. &amp;#0160;If you&amp;#39;ve collected enough mailing lists full of &lt;a href=&#34;http://group.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;local people&lt;/a&gt; or topical experts or &lt;a href=&#34;http://listserv2.michigan.gov/wa.exe?A0=michlib-l&#34;&gt;reference librarians&lt;/a&gt;, the appeal of asking an unspecified audience is limited. &amp;#0160;Ditto the comparison with asking the same question to Twitter where it might ping-pong into someone&amp;#39;s news stream, or asking a network full of PR people on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.helpareporter.com/&#34;&gt;HARO&lt;/a&gt; in the hopes of luring in someone&amp;#39;s publicist who is happy to answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the frailty of human memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-25-the-frailty-of-human-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-25-the-frailty-of-human-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m trying to figure out how to retell stories about a place that I only know a little about. &amp;#0160;The particular spot is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Clague&amp;#39;s_Grocery&#34;&gt;one time grocery store&lt;/a&gt;, now a bicycle shop, that I am guessing was a center of a neighborhood in its time. If there ever was a lore around it, it circulates among a group of people who I don&amp;#39;t know. &amp;#0160;The owner of the store was notable in his day, but that day is about 60 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My usual routine is to find an interesting idea, do searches in unexpected locations that get uncommon results, and assemble a story from clippings of things already written. &amp;#0160;This can be a fast way of going from scattered and fragmentary information about something to a composed account that makes sense. Clippings are easy to assemble, someone else has done the work, and you can sit down and be done when you&amp;#39;re done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s harder for me is to write about something that no one else has written down, especially something which you in turn have only limited knowledge of. &amp;#0160;The quotable information from print sources may be locked up in materials that are not scanned in, and perhaps never scanned in unless you scan them in yourself - that is, if you can find anything at all. &amp;#0160;The real stories of how things were might only be tellable if you can locate someone to tell them to you and if you write the stories down carefully for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in something and want to publish something about it to mark that interest, you might end up with only a fragment to start. &amp;#0160;There are some media where it&amp;#39;s acceptable to tell a piece of a story that&amp;#39;s an incomplete image, but only a very few. &amp;#0160;&amp;quot;That&amp;#39;s not news&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;what&amp;#39;s your point&amp;quot; are typical reactions when a newspaper behaves that way. &amp;#0160;The encyclopedia&amp;#39;s defense mechanism says &amp;quot;that&amp;#39;s not notable&amp;quot;. &amp;quot;Too long, didn&amp;#39;t read&amp;quot; is the reaction in the blog world. &amp;#0160;So you need some place to dump fragments that don&amp;#39;t have to be complete that&amp;#39;s safe so when it comes time to tell a story you can extend your memory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing gets around the problem that the real stories can only be told by people. &amp;#0160;That&amp;#39;s an opportunity and a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of Metblogs</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-23-the-end-of-metblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 22:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-23-the-end-of-metblogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.metblogs.com/sanjose/files/2008/11/metblogs-logo.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image from img.metblogs.com&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0134817d871b970c selected &#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0134817d871b970c-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;&#34; title=&#34;image from img.metblogs.com&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metblogs.com&#34;&gt;Metblogs&lt;/a&gt; was a national network of local blogs. The idea was that in each of many metro regions, someone or some set of people would be recruited to write local content, largely for free. The whole network would be run on advertising revenue, and user generated content would fill pages with fresh, relevant, hyperlocal content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://jpd.me/2010/05/21/metblogs-series-finale/&#34;&gt;Metblogs series finale&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;[U]ltimately the downturns in advertising and dwindling interest in blogs in favor of social networks and twitter have made the business unsustainable and we’re closing the doors at the end of May.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The metblogs network never intersected with my world, so I don&amp;#39;t know whether this is just the passing of time or some kind of deep-seated, widely felt loss. Their stats:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://detroit.metblogs.com/&#34;&gt;Detroit Metblogs&lt;/a&gt;: 2,218 posts / 3,722 comments
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
which I have to compare with Vacuum, just to give some sense of scale and scope (since 2003 when I started on Typepad):
&lt;blockquote&gt;
2229 Total Posts, 2033 Total Comments
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s all kinds of business models that have to change with time. I can only say that because I lived through the era when modems ruled the Internet, and then after that when they didn&amp;#39;t. So it&amp;#39;s no failing to have started something that was a good idea at the time and then discover that times have changed and your idea doesn&amp;#39;t have a neat transition to the current day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some parts of the Metblogs network died a bit earlier. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://morehockeylesswar.org/blog/archive/2008/06/18/the_death_of_portland_metblogs/&#34;&gt;2008 post on the situation in Portland&lt;/a&gt; signals what happens when founders intent, advertiser interest, and core contributor passions don&amp;#39;t line up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
There could still be hope for Metblogs. My suggestions of public journalism, open comments and revenue sharing to attract quality writers were met with hostility when I floated them before. Metblogs could be a voice in the Portland digital media milieu. But most likely it will quietly fade further into irrelevance.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metblogs.com/news/2010/05/21/well-that-just-happened/&#34;&gt;official going out of business notice&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;Here&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/showcase/metblogs/&#34;&gt;a feature about them from Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, the platform that they had used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noted on Twitter by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thenetworkthinker.com/&#34;&gt;Valdis Krebs&lt;/a&gt;, who asks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;starting to see the end of the &amp;quot;blog phase&amp;quot; of the Web? Or just the assimilation of another &amp;quot;form&amp;quot; into the whole?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If blogs are being assimilated, what are they being assimilated into? &amp;#0160;If they go into newspapers, you get editors and deadlines and a hesitance to be interested in everything in favor of something narrower and more marketable. If the blogger becomes a diarist, then the novelty is writing for the world but not the form itself. Perhaps some bloggers are just frustrated talk radio hosts? &amp;#0160;There are lots of possibilities to be assimilated into another established media form and not to create some new art form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another relevant touchpoint is the end of &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborupdate.com&#34;&gt;Arbor Update&lt;/a&gt;, which closed down after a 6 year run. &amp;#0160;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/links-arbor-update-blogroll/&#34;&gt;requiem for Arbor Update&lt;/a&gt;, I note that it gave up the ghost after many of its contributors who were also regular bloggers stopped blogging regularly. &amp;#0160;This suggests a life cycle for blogging that matches what used to happen on Usenet; a cadre would form, start writing together, and then at some point their lives got busy or they got out of grad school or their public writing style needed to be formal and they left en masse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure there&amp;#39;s some epidemic model of when blogging stops, which would say something similar to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://content.nejm.org/cgi/content/full/357/4/370&#34;&gt;Framingham obesity study&lt;/a&gt; - when your friends stop blogging, you are likely to stop blogging. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s not that any one thing got in the way; it&amp;#39;s just that the cool kids had a million followers on Twitter, and the eyeballs of the media buyers were diverted toward how you could be more like them. &amp;#0160;Or it may be as simple as not seeing eye to eye with a handful of people who are core to your effort and not being able to restart once they leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>collaboration superpowers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-01-collaboration-superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 02:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-01-collaboration-superpowers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://snarkmarket.com/2010/5462&#34;&gt;Robin Sloan on Snarkmarket&lt;/a&gt; describing tools for large scale, real time collaboration, using Twitter, Google Forms, and Dropbox.  Jane McGonigal gets called out for noticing and naming three collaboration superpowers and the tools and attitudes and interpersonal skills that matter.  Note that these three are part of a list coming from a world of multiplayer gaming; if you were wondering why your CEO was spending time leveling up in some MMO, now you can see why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mobbability&lt;/strong&gt;: the ability to do real-time work in very large groups; a tal­ent for coordinating with many people simultaneously.
&lt;strong&gt;Cooperation radar&lt;/strong&gt;: the ability to sense, almost intuitively, who would make the best collaborators on a particular task.
&lt;strong&gt;Ping quotient&lt;/strong&gt;: measures your responsiveness to other people’s requests for engagement.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avantgame.com/&#34;&gt;Jane McGonigal from AvantGame&lt;/a&gt; on collaboration, from 2007, here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width:425px&#34; id=&#34;__ss_214907&#34;&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;display:block;margin:12px 0 4px&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/avantgame/10-collaboration-superpowers&#34; title=&#34;10 Collaboration Superpowers&#34;&gt;10 Collaboration Superpowers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;object id=&#34;__sse214907&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=10-collaboration-superpowers-1198984701588013-4&amp;stripped_title=10-collaboration-superpowers&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed name=&#34;__sse214907&#34; src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=10-collaboration-superpowers-1198984701588013-4&amp;stripped_title=10-collaboration-superpowers&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:5px 0 12px&#34;&gt;View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/avantgame&#34;&gt;avantgame&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crisis informatics, or the study of community emergency response</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search?q=crisis+informatics&#34;&gt;crisis informatics&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (Google search) term is new to me, but the research I&amp;#39;ve been able to find under that term is familiar.&amp;#0160; Faced with an unexpected crisis situation that is bigger than what the mainstream media and existing government organizations can easily manage the news flow from, how do communities response in emergency situations with social media and with ad hoc emergency response systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into lots of detail I do want to share one recent paper that caught my eye, via Leysia Palen: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.colorado.edu/%7Epalen/Papers/iscram08/BackchannelsISCRAM08.pdf&#34;&gt;Backchannels on the Front Lines: Emergent Uses of Social Media in the 2007 Southern California Wildfires.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Opportunities for participation by members of the public are expanding the information arena of disaster.&amp;#0160; Social media supports “backchannel” communications, allowing for wide-scale interaction that can be collectively resourceful, self-policing, and generative of information that is otherwise hard to obtain. Results from our study of information practices by members of the public during the October 2007 Southern California Wildfires suggest that community information resources and other backchannel communications activity enabled by social media are gaining prominence in the disaster arena, despite concern by officials about the legitimacy of information shared through such means. We argue that these emergent uses of social media are pre-cursors of broader future changes to the institutional and organizational arrangements of disaster response. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The term &amp;quot;crisis informatics&amp;quot; is credited to Christine Hagar (2006).&amp;#0160; If you do a proper retrospective look at the phenomenon without that term, you unearth previous discussion of the use of the net for responses in the Kobe and Northridge earthquakes, hurricanes Katrina and Rita, and various power outages and ice storms.&amp;#0160; A proper retrospective bibliography awaits someone else&amp;#39;s project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;fieldset class=&#34;zemanta-related&#34;&gt;&lt;legend class=&#34;zemanta-related-title&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://anewdomain.net/2013/04/11/social-media-in-emergency-management/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/159424244_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://anewdomain.net/2013/04/11/social-media-in-emergency-management/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Social Media in Emergency Management: The Digital Public Information Officer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Wall of Panera: what do corporate cafe wifi networks block?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-great-wall-of-panera-what-do-corporate-cafe-wifi-networks-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 11:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-great-wall-of-panera-what-do-corporate-cafe-wifi-networks-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a few cafe networks have filters set up to block various kinds of use.&amp;#0160; My usual failure modes with these are that they mark perfectly reasonable internet services as inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a litany of Panera complaints, to give you a feel for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinotopia.com/wordpress/archive/bycategory/panera/&#34;&gt;Tinotopia was blocked for a while, which got the author riled up enough to document some of the failures.&amp;#0160; &lt;/a&gt;No entries since April 2005:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;In this case, &lt;em&gt;Tino&lt;/em&gt; of all people is the loser: for he has once
again been suckered into coming into Panera only to find that the
network is kaput. The network here is now well and truly down more than
it’s up, at least when I’m here. It’s even more kaput than usual today,
too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technologyevangelist.com/2008/04/tinyurlcom_blocked_b.html&#34;&gt;TinyURL.com is blocked by Panera Bread, notes Technology Evangelist :&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;I can understand Panera choosing to block porn sites, since it could
be disturbing for customers to glance over to see a neighboring table
watching porn while they&amp;#39;re trying to enjoy some bread bowl chowder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;But why is TinyURL.com banned? Why not just block inappropriate
sites that people may be trying to access after being redirected from
TinyURL.com?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookofjoe.com/2006/01/panera_blocked_.html&#34;&gt;BookOfJoe documents the Panera Blocked Site Hack:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookofjoe.com/2006/01/panera_cinnamon.html&#34;&gt;remarked&lt;/a&gt; Saturday on the fact that I couldn&amp;#39;t access bookofjoe on my local Panera&amp;#39;s WiFi because it was blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Reader Benjamin Tung of the great state of Michigan confirmed
shortly thereafter that the Italian–American corporate version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookofjoe.com/2004/09/the_great_firew.html&#34;&gt;Chinese firewall&lt;/a&gt; is up and functioning in a similar fashion at his local branch of the sandwich/bakery chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Benjamin wrote, &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t make me choose between the cinnamon raisin bread and reading your blog.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution is as simple as it is perfect, and should work nearly anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/translate?langpair=en%7Cen&amp;amp;u=http://www.bookofjoe.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/translate?langpair=en|en&amp;amp;u=http://www.bookofjoe.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;translates bookofjoe.com from english to english via $GOOG.&amp;#0160; hey presto.&amp;#0160; Replace the URL as needed, and bonus points for the next step of turning this into Greasemonkey or your favorite bookmark tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dave Sommerness, GovDelivery COO</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-interview-with-dave-sommerness-govdelivery-coo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-interview-with-dave-sommerness-govdelivery-coo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/10/ann-arbor-fire.html&#34;&gt;The City of Ann Arbor has started an email-based delivery service for changes and updates to the city&amp;#39;s web site run by GovDelivery.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160; I contacted Dave Sommerness, a University of Michigan graduate and their COO, to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
How did your organization get started, and who was your first customer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.govdelivery.com&#34;&gt;GovDelivery&lt;/a&gt;, Inc. was started in 1999 by our two co-founders, CEO Scott Burns and EVP of Sales Zach Stabenow. &amp;#0160;We developed the GovDelivery Digital Subscription Management system in 2000 in collaboration with the City of St. Paul, who had a need for reliable communication with its residents. &amp;#0160;We found this need to be pervasive across public sector organizations, and it&amp;#39;s taken off quite well from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;Ih2E3d&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Government web sites are built with all kinds of technologies. &amp;#0160;How do you manage the process so that it all looks the same to the user?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We integrate with client sites by simple links on their web pages. &amp;#0160;The effect is seamless because we customize our web and email templates to match the look-and-feel of each client. &amp;#0160;Behind the scenes GovDelivery is deployed as a multi-tenant, SaaS system, so Ann Arbor is using the same basic application as our other clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;Ih2E3d&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
The service I signed up for was an email based one. &amp;#0160;What are your plans for looking at web 2.0 technologies for notification, e.g. using something like Twitter to do messaging?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re always looking forward to new technologies and applications to our system/market. &amp;#0160;A couple years ago we added RSS capability, so our clients can publish their messages as RSS feeds in addition to sending them out through email. &amp;#0160;We&amp;#39;ve seen a lot of excitement in our market over Web 2.0 technologies, so we&amp;#39;re developing functionality to take advantage of that and promote more options for communication and collaboration between government and citizens. &amp;#0160;A few examples of Web&lt;br /&gt;
2.0 notification that we already support include automatically posting messages to blogs, updating a Facebook page, and using public RSS feeds to publish bulletins to widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;Ih2E3d&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Do you work with libraries as part of your business, and if so, can you share some good stories from those implementations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The majority of our experience has been with government bodies - from small cities and counties up to the largest federal departments - and transit authorities, though we have some experience with education,&lt;br /&gt;
non-profits, and other organizations. &amp;#0160;We work with a number of libraries, mainly through city accounts, but the most notable stand-alone library account is the Library of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;Ih2E3d&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
What makes St. Paul a good place to run this business from, and not Silicon Valley or Washington, DC?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good business is about good people, and there&amp;#39;s a great pool of talent in the Minneapolis/St. Paul area. We&amp;#39;re one of the fastest growing software companies in the area, which attracts talented people and helps us to retain and keep them challenged. &amp;#0160;We don&amp;#39;t have the issues that Silicon Valley has where folks are more apt to jump to the next flavor of the day. &amp;#0160;Because of the density of clients in D.C., we do maintain a sales office and staff there, which we plan to grow as the business does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Who do you root for when Michigan plays Minnesota?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I grew up a Bulldog hockey fan in Duluth - the Gophers were big rivals, so it&amp;#39;s been tough for me to become a fan of any of their teams. &amp;#0160;The real dilemma for me would be if Michigan ever played UMD in hockey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks Dave!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 8, 2008: Podcamp Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-16-november-8-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 23:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-16-november-8-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now you know just about as much as I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://podcampmichigan.org/&#34;&gt;Podcamp Michigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Twitter feed: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/podcampmichigan&#34;&gt;Podcamp Michigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;140 characters or less: &lt;span class=&#34;bio&#34;&gt;Saturday, Nov 8, Free Unconference for bloggers, podcasters, and all fans of new media.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Venue: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 8th , 2008&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, 9-4 at Embassy Suites Hotel, &lt;span dir=&#34;ltr&#34; class=&#34;adr&#34; id=&#34;sxaddr&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;extended-address&#34;&gt;28100 Franklin Road&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;locality&#34;&gt;Southfield&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;region&#34;&gt;MI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hotel phone: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;tel&#34; id=&#34;sxphone&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;248) 350-7007&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DISCLAIM ANY WARRANTIES OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, TITLE, OR QUIET ENJOYMENT</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-08-disclaim-any-wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-08-disclaim-any-wa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;yes, yes, yes, just let me in.&amp;nbsp; now what exactly did I agree to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=Terms of Use=&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Lotsa Helping Hands, LLC* (&amp;quot;Lotsa Helping Hands&amp;quot;) welcomes you to its web site&lt;br /&gt;(the &amp;quot;web site&amp;quot;). On this web site, Lotsa Helping Hands makes available to you&lt;br /&gt;its Internet service for helping others along with information, software,&lt;br /&gt;documents, communications, files, text, graphics, publications, content, tools,&lt;br /&gt;forums, resources and links to other web sites. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the particular bizarre clause is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IN ADDITION, EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED OTHERWISE, LOTSA HELPING HANDS AND ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS AND SPONSORS DISCLAIM ANY WARRANTIES OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, TITLE, OR QUIET ENJOYMENT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;quiet enjoyment&amp;quot; clause refers roughly to your right to live in an apartment undisturbed; I have no clue what it&#39;s doing inside an online services agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://law.jrank.org/pages/9614/Quiet-Enjoyment.html&#34;&gt;Quiet Enjoyment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(more after the jump)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Privacy Policy==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands respects your desire for privacy. Your information may be&lt;br /&gt;
stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Lotsa&lt;br /&gt;
Helping Hands or Lotsa Helping Hands representatives and affiliates maintain&lt;br /&gt;
facilities. This information is highly protected and is stored in a secure and&lt;br /&gt;
controlled environment. By using this site, you consent to any such transfer of&lt;br /&gt;
information outside of your country and you consent to the terms of our Privacy&lt;br /&gt;
Policy. Lotsa Helping Hands abides by the principles set forth in the Safe&lt;br /&gt;
Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the&lt;br /&gt;
collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==How Lotsa Helping Hands will protect your personal information==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands will always protect the personal information that you share&lt;br /&gt;
with us. Lotsa Helping Hands stores information internally in a controlled,&lt;br /&gt;
secure environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands requests general demographic information in the sign-up&lt;br /&gt;
process. This information is limited to reporting purposes only. Phone numbers,&lt;br /&gt;
email addresses, and postal addresses are not shared for demographic reports&lt;br /&gt;
with outside entities. If you join a community that was created from the web&lt;br /&gt;
site service of one of our Partner organizations, the Partner&#39;s name is&lt;br /&gt;
prominently displayed on each page of the web site. In such case, we may share&lt;br /&gt;
your name and email address with that Partner only, and the Partner may&lt;br /&gt;
communicate with you about activities associated only with it, but you will have&lt;br /&gt;
the opportunity to opt-out of receiving further communications from the Partner&lt;br /&gt;
if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose&lt;br /&gt;
personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief&lt;br /&gt;
that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a&lt;br /&gt;
court order or legal process served on our web site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Acceptance of Terms==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
PLEASE READ THESE *TERMS OF USE* CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS WEB SITE. By&lt;br /&gt;
accessing and using this web site in any way, including, without limitation,&lt;br /&gt;
browsing the web site, using any information, using any content, using any&lt;br /&gt;
services, downloading any materials, and/or placing an order for products or&lt;br /&gt;
services, you agree to and are bound by the terms of use described in this&lt;br /&gt;
document (&amp;quot;Terms of Use&amp;quot;). IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ALL OF THE TERMS AND&lt;br /&gt;
CONDITIONS CONTAINED IN THE TERMS OF USE, DO NOT USE THIS WEB SITE IN ANY&lt;br /&gt;
MANNER. The Terms of Use are entered into by and between Lotsa Helping Hands and&lt;br /&gt;
you. If you are using the web site on behalf of your employer, you represent&lt;br /&gt;
that you are authorized to accept these Terms of Use on your employer&#39;s behalf. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands reserves the right, at Lotsa Helping Hands&#39; sole discretion,&lt;br /&gt;
to change, modify, update, add, or remove portions of the Terms of Use at any&lt;br /&gt;
time without notice to you. Please check these Terms of Use for changes. Your&lt;br /&gt;
continued use of this web site following the posting of changes to the Terms of&lt;br /&gt;
Use will mean you accept those changes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Use of Materials Limitations==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
All materials contained in the web site are the copyrighted property of Lotsa&lt;br /&gt;
Helping Hands, its subsidiaries, affiliated companies and/or third-party&lt;br /&gt;
licensors. All trademarks, service marks, and trade names are proprietary to&lt;br /&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands, or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies and/or&lt;br /&gt;
third-party licensors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Unless otherwise specified, the materials and services on this web site are for&lt;br /&gt;
your personal and non-commercial use, and you may not modify, copy, distribute,&lt;br /&gt;
transmit, display, perform, reproduce, publish, license, create derivative works&lt;br /&gt;
from, transfer, or sell any information, software, products or services obtained&lt;br /&gt;
from the web site without the written permission from Lotsa Helping Hands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==No Unlawful or Prohibited Use==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As a condition of your use of the web site, you will not use the web site for&lt;br /&gt;
any purpose that is unlawful or prohibited by these terms, conditions, and&lt;br /&gt;
notices. You may not use the Services in any manner that could damage, disable,&lt;br /&gt;
overburden, or impair any Lotsa Helping Hands server, or the network(s)&lt;br /&gt;
connected to any Lotsa Helping Hands server, or interfere with any other party&#39;s&lt;br /&gt;
use and enjoyment of the web site. You may not attempt to gain unauthorized&lt;br /&gt;
access to services, materials, other accounts, computer systems or networks&lt;br /&gt;
connected to any Lotsa Helping Hands server or to the web site, through hacking,&lt;br /&gt;
password mining or any other means. You may not obtain or attempt to obtain any&lt;br /&gt;
materials or information through any means not intentionally made available&lt;br /&gt;
through the web site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Use of Services on the Web Site==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The web site provides its users (called members) access to a private community,&lt;br /&gt;
created by the coordinator, designed to provide for communication amongst the&lt;br /&gt;
members of the community. The web site may contain email services, communities,&lt;br /&gt;
calendars, news groups, forums, and/or other message or communication facilities&lt;br /&gt;
designed to enable you to communicate with others within your community (each a&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;quot;Communication Service&amp;quot; and collectively &amp;quot;Communication Services&amp;quot;). You agree to&lt;br /&gt;
use the Communication Services only to post, send and receive messages and&lt;br /&gt;
material that are proper and, when applicable, related to the particular&lt;br /&gt;
Communication Service. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands reserves the right at all times to disclose any information&lt;br /&gt;
as Lotsa Helping Hands deems necessary to satisfy any applicable law,&lt;br /&gt;
regulation, legal process or governmental request, or to edit, refuse to post or&lt;br /&gt;
to remove any information or materials, in whole or in part, in Lotsa Helping&lt;br /&gt;
Hands&#39; sole discretion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Always use caution when giving out any personally identifiable information about&lt;br /&gt;
yourself or your children in any Communication Services. Lotsa Helping Hands&lt;br /&gt;
does not control or endorse the content, messages or information found in any&lt;br /&gt;
Communication Services and, therefore, Lotsa Helping Hands specifically&lt;br /&gt;
disclaims any liability with regard to the Communication Services and any&lt;br /&gt;
actions resulting from your participation in any Communication Services.&lt;br /&gt;
Coordinators and members are not authorized Lotsa Helping Hands spokespersons,&lt;br /&gt;
and their views do not necessarily reflect those of Lotsa Helping Hands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Spam Email and Postings==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You agree that Lotsa Helping Hands would be irreparably harmed by the use, by&lt;br /&gt;
you or others, of the web site or facilities in connection with the transmission&lt;br /&gt;
of spam newsgroup postings or unsolicited email in violation of these Terms of&lt;br /&gt;
Use, and that Lotsa Helping Hands is entitled to obtain injunctive relief&lt;br /&gt;
against any such transmission (in addition to all other remedies available at&lt;br /&gt;
law or in equity). Lotsa Helping Hands reserves the right to block, filter or&lt;br /&gt;
delete unsolicited email. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Indemnity==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You agree to indemnify, defend and hold Lotsa Helping Hands, and its&lt;br /&gt;
subsidiaries, affiliates, officers, agents, co-branders, partners, and&lt;br /&gt;
employees, harmless from any claim or demand, including reasonable attorneys&#39;&lt;br /&gt;
fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of your submissions, your&lt;br /&gt;
use of the web site, including any use by your employees, your connection to the&lt;br /&gt;
web site, your violation of the Terms of Use, or your violation of any rights of&lt;br /&gt;
another. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Advertisements and Promotions==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Lotsa Helping Hands may run advertisements and promotions from third parties on&lt;br /&gt;
the web site. The manner, mode and extent of advertising by Lotsa Helping Hands&lt;br /&gt;
is subject to change. Your correspondence or business dealings with, or&lt;br /&gt;
participation in promotions of, advertisers other than Lotsa Helping Hands found&lt;br /&gt;
on or through the web site, including payment and delivery of related goods or&lt;br /&gt;
services, and any other terms, conditions, warranties or representations&lt;br /&gt;
associated with such dealings, are solely between you and such advertiser. Lotsa&lt;br /&gt;
Helping Hands is not responsible or liable for any loss or damage of any kind&lt;br /&gt;
incurred as the result of any such dealings or as the result of the presence of&lt;br /&gt;
such non-Lotsa Helping Hands advertisers on the web site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
==Disclaimers and Other Notices on the User of the Web Site==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED OTHERWISE, ALL INFORMATION, SOFTWARE,&lt;br /&gt;
DOCUMENTATION, MATERIALS, SERVICES AND PUBLICATION ARE PROVIDED &amp;quot;AS-IS&amp;quot; WITHOUT&lt;br /&gt;
WARRANTY OF ANY KIND AND LOTSA HELPING HANDS AND ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS AND&lt;br /&gt;
SPONSORS HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING&lt;br /&gt;
BUT NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A&lt;br /&gt;
PARTICULAR PURPOSE. IN ADDITION, EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED OTHERWISE, LOTSA&lt;br /&gt;
HELPING HANDS AND ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS AND SPONSORS DISCLAIM ANY WARRANTIES&lt;br /&gt;
OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, TITLE, OR QUIET ENJOYMENT. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
LOTSA HELPING HANDS, ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS AND SPONSORS, AND THE OFFICERS,&lt;br /&gt;
MANAGERS, EMPLOYEES, SUBCONTRACTORS, AGENTS, SUCCESSORS AND ASSIGNS OF LOTSA&lt;br /&gt;
HELPING HANDS AND ITS AFFILIATES PARTNERS AND SPONSORS (COLLECTIVELY REFERRED TO&lt;br /&gt;
AS &amp;quot;COVERED PARTIES&amp;quot;) WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS, INJURY, CLAIM, LIABILITY,&lt;br /&gt;
OR DAMAGE OF ANY KIND RESULTING IN ANY WAY FROM (A) ANY DEFICIENCY IN THE WEB&lt;br /&gt;
SITE OR THE SERVICE PROVIDED VIA THE WEB SITE (COLLECTIVELY, THE &amp;quot;SERVICE&amp;quot;) OR&lt;br /&gt;
ANY ERRORS IN THE SOFTWARE OR OTHER MATERIALS ON WHICH IT IS BASED OR ANY&lt;br /&gt;
INSTRUCTION OR OTHER MATERIALS DESCRIBING THE SERVICE OR ITS USE, (B) THE&lt;br /&gt;
UNAVAILABILITY OR INTERRUPTION OF THE SERVICE (OR ANY PART THEREOF), (C) ANY USE&lt;br /&gt;
OF THE SERVICE BY YOU (REGARDLESS OF WHETHER YOU RECEIVED ANY ASSISTANCE FROM A&lt;br /&gt;
COVERED PARTY IN USING THE SERVICE), (D) YOUR USE OF ANY EQUIPMENT IN CONNECTION&lt;br /&gt;
WITH THE SERVICE, (E) THE LOTSA HELPING HANDS WEB SITE OR THE CONTENT THEREOF,&lt;br /&gt;
OR (F) ANY DELAY OR FAILURE IN PERFORMANCE BEYOND THE REASONABLE CONTROL OF A&lt;br /&gt;
COVERED PARTY. THE AGGREGATE LIABILITY OF THE COVERED PARTIES IN CONNECTION WITH&lt;br /&gt;
ANY CLAIM ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THE SERVICE OR ANY MATTER RELATED TO THE&lt;br /&gt;
WEB SITE SHALL NOT EXCEED ONE THOUSAND DOLLARS. YOUR RIGHT TO MONETARY DAMAGES&lt;br /&gt;
IN THAT AMOUNT SHALL BE IN LIEU OF ALL OTHER REMEDIES WHICH YOU MAY HAVE AGAINST&lt;br /&gt;
ANY COVERED PARTY. THE COVERED PARTIES SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL,&lt;br /&gt;
INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER&lt;br /&gt;
(INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, ATTORNEYS&#39; FEES) IN ANY WAY DUE TO, RESULTING&lt;br /&gt;
FROM, OR ARISING IN CONNECTION WITH THE SERVICE OR ANY MATTER RELATED TO THE WEB&lt;br /&gt;
SITE. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED OTHERWISE, YOU ASSUME ALL RISKS CONCERNING THE&lt;br /&gt;
SUITABILITY AND ACCURACY OF THE INFORMATION WITHIN THE WEB SITE, MATERIALS,&lt;br /&gt;
PUBLICATIONS AND DOCUMENTS. THE WEB SITE, MATERIALS, PUBLICATIONS AND DOCUMENTS&lt;br /&gt;
MAY CONTAIN TECHNICAL INACCURACIES OR TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS. LOTSA HELPING HANDS&lt;br /&gt;
AND ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS AND SPONSORS ASSUME NO RESPONSIBILITY FOR AND&lt;br /&gt;
DISCLAIM ALL LIABILITY FOR ANY SUCH INACCURACIES, ERRORS OR OMISSIONS IN THE WEB&lt;br /&gt;
SITE, MATERIALS, PUBLICATIONS AND DOCUMENTS AND IN ANY OTHER REFERENCE. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
LOTSA HELPING HANDS MAY MAKE CHANGES TO THE WEB SITE, SERVICES ON THE WEB SITE,&lt;br /&gt;
INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, DOCUMENTS, PUBLICATIONS, PRICES, TECHNICAL&lt;br /&gt;
SPECIFICATIONS, PRODUCT OFFERINGS AND ANY OTHER INFORMATION AND MATERIALS ON THE&lt;br /&gt;
WEB SITE AT ANY TIME AND WITHOUT NOTICE. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
THE WEB SITE, DOCUMENTS AND PUBLICATIONS ARE DISTRIBUTED INTERNATIONALLY AND MAY&lt;br /&gt;
CONTAIN REFERENCES OR CROSS-REFERENCES TO LOTSA HELPING HANDS PRODUCTS,&lt;br /&gt;
PROGRAMS, AND SERVICES THAT HAVE NOT BEEN ANNOUNCED OR AVAILABLE IN YOUR&lt;br /&gt;
COUNTRY. SUCH REFERENCES DO NOT IMPLY THAT LOTSA HELPING HANDS INTENDS TO&lt;br /&gt;
ANNOUNCE SUCH PRODUCTS, PROGRAMS, OR SERVICES IN YOUR COUNTRY. CONSULT YOUR&lt;br /&gt;
LOCAL LOTSA HELPING HANDS BUSINESS CONTACT FOR INFORMATION REGARDING THE&lt;br /&gt;
PRODUCTS, PROGRAMS AND SERVICES WHICH MAY BE AVAILABLE TO YOU. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
THE WEB SITE CONTAINS LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SITES WHICH ARE NOT UNDER THE CONTROL&lt;br /&gt;
OF LOTSA HELPING HANDS AND LOTSA HELPING HANDS IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE&lt;br /&gt;
CONTENTS ON ANY LINKED SITE OR ANY LINK CONTAINED IN A LINKED SITE, OR ANY&lt;br /&gt;
CHANGES OR UPDATES TO SUCH SITES. LOTSA HELPING HANDS IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR&lt;br /&gt;
WEBCASTING OR ANY OTHER FORM OF TRANSMISSION RECEIVED FROM ANY LINKED SITE.&lt;br /&gt;
LOTSA HELPING HANDS IS PROVIDING THESE LINKS TO YOU ONLY AS A CONVENIENCE, AND&lt;br /&gt;
THE INCLUSION OF ANY LINK DOES NOT IMPLY THAT LOTSA HELPING HANDS ENDORSES OR&lt;br /&gt;
ACCEPTS ANY RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE CONTENT ON SUCH THIRD-PARTY SITES. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coping with community growth</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-coping-with-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 21:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-coping-with-com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/a2b3&#34;&gt;The a2b3 meeting today at Eastern Accents&lt;/a&gt; had 26 or so, again filling as many tables as we could manage to reasonably fill.&amp;nbsp; I asked the question &amp;quot;How do you keep your calendar&amp;quot; and got a full round of answers, as many as you would ever need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting is at the edge of what the venue can handle, but I want to keep inviting new people to it (every Thursday; you&#39;re invited).&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;So somehow there needs to be a growth strategy that absorbs new people in but that doesn&#39;t expect all 280 people on the email list to show up weekly because I know that they never would fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you cope with community growth?&amp;nbsp; In particular, if you have an organization that has regular meetings and it outstrips the capabilities of its venue, what do you do to keep it going?&amp;nbsp; Some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;nbsp; Hold the meeting more frequently.&amp;nbsp; If the monthly meeting is full every time, do a second event on alternate weeks.&amp;nbsp; This is what movie theaters do with popular films (matinees, midnight films, 10a showings) or what busy religious congregations do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.&amp;nbsp; Move the meeting from place to place.&amp;nbsp; Some people will come if it&#39;s convenient enough, so if you move from place to place you&#39;ll get a variety of people attending who wouldn&#39;t otherwise because it&#39;s incrementally less convenient.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://motorcityconnect.collectivex.com/main/summary&#34;&gt;Motor City Connect has ten meetings in eight cities around the Detroit area every month,&lt;/a&gt; with the idea that it&#39;s going to be somewhere close to you some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Let the group subdivide laterally, with some part of the original collection of people doing something related at a different place and a different time.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microcoworking.com&#34;&gt;The a2b3 group spawned (in some sense) the microcoworking group&lt;/a&gt;, which started with one day and has expanded to three days at three different locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.&amp;nbsp; Raise the bar for participation, so that your community grows more slowly.&amp;nbsp; At an extreme, you get new member initiation rituals that approach hazing, and so anyone who wants to stick around really wants to stick around; at the extreme, this coupled with no new member recruitment gives you groups that stop growing and start to grow old with the same people there every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Grow into different forms, e.g. take an offline group and put it online, or take an online group on one community platform and add it to another community platform.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 has a very strong and functional mailing list,&lt;/a&gt; so people don&#39;t have to be at the meetings to post a job offering or get bike repair recommendations or locate a trusted network security auditor (to give but three examples).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.&amp;nbsp; Use one group to bootstrap the creation of a new group, and then pull your energy out of the first group.&amp;nbsp; In a religious setting this would be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joyfulheart.com/plant/splinter.htm&#34;&gt;splinter church&lt;/a&gt;, and just by that very name you get some sense at some possible social friction that would result.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.&amp;nbsp; Move your focus from local groups to national or global ones, and grow a community of practice globally rather than just locally.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialtext.net/wikiwed/index.cgi?wiki_wednesdays&#34;&gt;Wiki Wednesday meets on the first Wednesday of the month worldwide&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webanalyticsdemystified.com/wednesday/&#34;&gt;Web Analytics Wednesday group&lt;/a&gt; coordinates Wednesday meetings worldwide.&amp;nbsp; The local meeting is probably still local, but it&#39;s part of a bigger world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these growth strategies yield more managable growth; others recognize that groups might just reach a happy steady state where you don&#39;t really want to multiply your size.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE power outage mobile phone reporting interface</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-dte-energy-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 19:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-dte-energy-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://finance.google.com/finance?q=NYSE:DTE&#34;&gt;DTE Energy&lt;/a&gt;, the power provider for SE Michigan, now has a mobile web based trouble reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Now you can report power outages on line using a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.dteenergy.com&#34;&gt;mobile.dteenergy.com&lt;/a&gt; with your web-based cell phone or PDA. In moments you can report an outage or get a repair estimate on a previously reported outage.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is reporting only, not mapping, and the mobile interface has the most pessimistic assumptions about mobile phone capacity.  If you have a cell phone capable of displaying a PDF file, you can get the &lt;a href=&#34;http://my.dteenergy.com/map/zipCodeOutageMap.pdf&#34;&gt;DTE power outage map&lt;/a&gt; directly.  Oddly, the mobile phone interface does not include a regular phone number (1-800-477-4747) on it if you happen to have a problem with the web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few problems with incoming phone calls to that phone number in the past few days; they were attributed to problems they were working on with the help of Verizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freep.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080612/BLOG01/80612021/1007/NEWS&#34;&gt;Mike Wendland from the Free Press&lt;/a&gt; has been without power for a week, and relates this trouble report:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In my area of Oakland Township, said James, there were still six downed wires that needed to be fixed, a blown transformer, problems with an underground connection and still unknown issues at a nearby substation. He said crews were working 24 hours a day but there was still much to be done.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are plenty of comments on his post regarding the untrustworthiness of DTE estimated time to repair numbers that are being given out, and unwillingness to believe the counts of houses without power:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ve been in a hotel for 3 nights, but...late yesterday, I got my hopes up. Our status was &#39;power restored&#39;!!! My husband went to the house today at noon, and no...no power, and it hadn&#39;t been on in the neighborhood at all. I have to believe they&#39;re just closing some work tickets to make things look better, then reopening them when the get the 2nd, or 3rd or 4th call. This has happened to several people I work with as well. One got through to a warm body at DTE and they said &#34;You don&#39;t have power? We show you do!!!&#34; That whole neighborhood was and is &#34;down&#34;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More bad weather expected Friday, of course it&#39;s too soon to know if this will trigger more outages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Mining Journal removes reader comments from newspaper web site</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 20:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/506528.html?nav=5003&#34;&gt;The Marquette Mining Journal recently ran this editorial regarding taking interactive comments off of the internet version of their newspaper, reading in part:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
The comments were posted, without prior screening, in order to make it as easy as possible for Journal readers to submit their input directly. Unfortunately, a handful of participants abused the system. While most comments were astute and relevant, some relentless individuals decided to turn the comments section into a chat room that ventured, frankly, into the realm of inappropriate, sophomoric  idiocy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The roots of The Mining Journal’s editorial ethical standards go back some 163 years. In order for a letter to the editor to be considered for publication in our print edition, a name and other verifiable information must be included. Not so, however, with the Internet comments. Subsequently, on our Web site a small but persistent group of people threatened to tarnish The Mining Journal’s reputation for responsible journalism. A few Web comment submissions even consisted of cowardly anonymous personal attacks on local citizens. That could not be allowed to continue.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The New Orleans online newspaper, nola.com, also has unmoderated comments.  Alan Gutierrez notes what this does to the discussion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thinknola.com/post/coldcock/&#34;&gt;quoting Mayor Ray Nagin:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Your news cast and the local newspapers are feeding these awful, ugly talk shows, that are feeding these blogs. You go look at these some of these blogs out there and some of the stories that come from the paper and you read the comments, it’s the most vile angry people that I’ve ever seen in this community.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Alan notes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is a common misconception in New Orleans, that the bloggers are the rabble. The city newspaper’s website, NOLA.com, is entirely unmoderated. NOLA.com calls these free-for-alls blogs.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Newspapers always run letters to the editor after verifying the identity of the writer.  Should online newspapers be any different?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>