<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:14:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Griefnet, support for grief, death, and major loss</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-griefnet-support-for-grief-death-and-major-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-16-griefnet-support-for-grief-death-and-major-loss/</guid>
      <description>GriefNet&amp;#0160;is an Internet community approach to on line grief support, providing support to people working through loss and grief issues of all kinds. Cendra Lynn is the leader of the organization, and I had some small technological part in starting it back in 1993 when the appropriate technology of the day was Gopher, not the World Wide Web. The system hosts dozens of moderated mailing lists for people who share a common loss like the death of a spouse or the loss of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration and community leadership</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-12-collaboration-and-community-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 13:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-12-collaboration-and-community-leadership/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;
Thinking about collaboration and community leadership, since it seems to be something that I do.
The examples that come to mind share some common traits.
 there is a mix of online and in person communications, and not solely one or the other for routine everyday communications you use whatever everyone is using in your field; be that email or facebook or twitter or phone or sms, you adapt to the existing norms to start at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing questions with Aardvark</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-practicing-questions-with-aardvark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-practicing-questions-with-aardvark/</guid>
      <description>Aardvark is vark.com - as of February 2010 they are owned by the Google. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s part of a genre of question asking sites where the answer comes back partly from &amp;quot;your network&amp;quot; and partly from the random parts of the net that you don&amp;#39;t know very much about. If you think you have an interesting question, you can ask it on Aardvark and see what you get. &amp;#0160;My practice efforts have been pretty dismal, but I might be asking for things outside of what it&amp;#39;s capable of doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the frailty of human memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-25-the-frailty-of-human-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-25-the-frailty-of-human-memory/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m trying to figure out how to retell stories about a place that I only know a little about. &amp;#0160;The particular spot is a one time grocery store, now a bicycle shop, that I am guessing was a center of a neighborhood in its time. If there ever was a lore around it, it circulates among a group of people who I don&amp;#39;t know. &amp;#0160;The owner of the store was notable in his day, but that day is about 60 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of Metblogs</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-23-the-end-of-metblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 22:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-23-the-end-of-metblogs/</guid>
      <description>Metblogs was a national network of local blogs. The idea was that in each of many metro regions, someone or some set of people would be recruited to write local content, largely for free. The whole network would be run on advertising revenue, and user generated content would fill pages with fresh, relevant, hyperlocal content.
From Metblogs series finale:
[U]ltimately the downturns in advertising and dwindling interest in blogs in favor of social networks and twitter have made the business unsustainable and we’re closing the doors at the end of May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>collaboration superpowers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-01-collaboration-superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 02:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-01-collaboration-superpowers/</guid>
      <description>Robin Sloan on Snarkmarket describing tools for large scale, real time collaboration, using Twitter, Google Forms, and Dropbox. Jane McGonigal gets called out for noticing and naming three collaboration superpowers and the tools and attitudes and interpersonal skills that matter. Note that these three are part of a list coming from a world of multiplayer gaming; if you were wondering why your CEO was spending time leveling up in some MMO, now you can see why:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crisis informatics, or the study of community emergency response</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;quot;crisis informatics&amp;quot; (Google search) term is new to me, but the research I&amp;#39;ve been able to find under that term is familiar.&amp;#0160; Faced with an unexpected crisis situation that is bigger than what the mainstream media and existing government organizations can easily manage the news flow from, how do communities response in emergency situations with social media and with ad hoc emergency response systems?
Without going into lots of detail I do want to share one recent paper that caught my eye, via Leysia Palen: Backchannels on the Front Lines: Emergent Uses of Social Media in the 2007 Southern California Wildfires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Wall of Panera: what do corporate cafe wifi networks block?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-great-wall-of-panera-what-do-corporate-cafe-wifi-networks-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 11:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-10-great-wall-of-panera-what-do-corporate-cafe-wifi-networks-block/</guid>
      <description>Quite a few cafe networks have filters set up to block various kinds of use.&amp;#0160; My usual failure modes with these are that they mark perfectly reasonable internet services as inappropriate.
Here&amp;#39;s a litany of Panera complaints, to give you a feel for it.
Tinotopia was blocked for a while, which got the author riled up enough to document some of the failures.&amp;#0160; No entries since April 2005:
In this case, Tino of all people is the loser: for he has once again been suckered into coming into Panera only to find that the network is kaput.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Dave Sommerness, GovDelivery COO</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-interview-with-dave-sommerness-govdelivery-coo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-interview-with-dave-sommerness-govdelivery-coo/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor has started an email-based delivery service for changes and updates to the city&amp;#39;s web site run by GovDelivery.&amp;#0160; I contacted Dave Sommerness, a University of Michigan graduate and their COO, to find out more.
 How did your organization get started, and who was your first customer?
GovDelivery, Inc. was started in 1999 by our two co-founders, CEO Scott Burns and EVP of Sales Zach Stabenow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 8, 2008: Podcamp Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-16-november-8-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 23:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-16-november-8-2008/</guid>
      <description>Now you know just about as much as I know.
Web site: Podcamp Michigan
Twitter feed: Podcamp Michigan
140 characters or less: Saturday, Nov 8, Free Unconference for bloggers, podcasters, and all fans of new media.
Venue: November 8th , 2008, 9-4 at Embassy Suites Hotel, 28100 Franklin Road, Southfield, MI
Hotel phone: (248) 350-7007</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DISCLAIM ANY WARRANTIES OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, TITLE, OR QUIET ENJOYMENT</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-08-disclaim-any-wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-08-disclaim-any-wa/</guid>
      <description>yes, yes, yes, just let me in.&amp;nbsp; now what exactly did I agree to?
=Terms of Use=
*Lotsa Helping Hands, LLC* (&amp;quot;Lotsa Helping Hands&amp;quot;) welcomes you to its web site
(the &amp;quot;web site&amp;quot;). On this web site, Lotsa Helping Hands makes available to you
its Internet service for helping others along with information, software,
documents, communications, files, text, graphics, publications, content, tools,
forums, resources and links to other web sites. the particular bizarre clause is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coping with community growth</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-coping-with-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 21:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-coping-with-com/</guid>
      <description>The a2b3 meeting today at Eastern Accents had 26 or so, again filling as many tables as we could manage to reasonably fill.&amp;nbsp; I asked the question &amp;quot;How do you keep your calendar&amp;quot; and got a full round of answers, as many as you would ever need.
The meeting is at the edge of what the venue can handle, but I want to keep inviting new people to it (every Thursday; you&#39;re invited).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE power outage mobile phone reporting interface</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-dte-energy-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 19:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-dte-energy-the/</guid>
      <description>DTE Energy, the power provider for SE Michigan, now has a mobile web based trouble reporting interface:
Now you can report power outages on line using a mobile device.
Just go to mobile.dteenergy.com with your web-based cell phone or PDA. In moments you can report an outage or get a repair estimate on a previously reported outage.

This is reporting only, not mapping, and the mobile interface has the most pessimistic assumptions about mobile phone capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Mining Journal removes reader comments from newspaper web site</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 20:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</guid>
      <description>The Marquette Mining Journal recently ran this editorial regarding taking interactive comments off of the internet version of their newspaper, reading in part:  The comments were posted, without prior screening, in order to make it as easy as possible for Journal readers to submit their input directly. Unfortunately, a handful of participants abused the system. While most comments were astute and relevant, some relentless individuals decided to turn the comments section into a chat room that ventured, frankly, into the realm of inappropriate, sophomoric idiocy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Day - Billy Collins</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-snow-day---bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 23:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-snow-day---bill/</guid>
      <description>As always, we will be tuning in to see if the Ann Arbor schools are closed tomorrow; it&amp;rsquo;s bitterly cold, there are wind chill warnings, and a few area schools have already cancelled. AAPS snow day phone 734-994-8684 - WWJ SE Michigan snow day page - WZZM Grand Rapids MI school closings - WSYM Lansing MI school closings - WLUC Marquette MI / Upper Peninsula school closings  SNOW DAY by Billy Collins  Originally from The Atlantic, February 2000  Hear Billy Collins read this poem (in RealAudio).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snow poetry, school closing, paczki, Kindergarten, NAAPID</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-31-snow-poetry-sch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-31-snow-poetry-sch/</guid>
      <description>Since the storm is coming, I&#39;d remind you of this page I&#39;m collecting snow poetry on. ORD was showing 5 hour delays a few minutes ago and there are expectations of 6-10 inches.  UPDATE: Wednesday, March 5 2008. Ann Arbor Public Schools closed. Check the Arborwiki sledding page for your favorite place to slide.  UPDATE: Thursday, February 7 2008. WWJ Radio has a comprehensive schools closed list for SE Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo leadership - nature abhors a vacuum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-22-yahoo-leadershi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 16:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-22-yahoo-leadershi/</guid>
      <description>As GigaOM notes in Yahoo Please Put Up A Fight
Yahoo has a staggering 500 million users. However, it does a rather poor job of monetization. The vision that Yang shared at CES last week (“At Yahoo we want to be the most essential starting point for your life”) can come true if the key activities that we perform online are channeled through its My Yahoo service. And on the financial side, each of those activities needs to be backed up by a monetization model that takes full advantage of the traffic that Yahoo consistently manages to generate and preserve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor (Jones Drive) murder - suspect information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-ann-arbor-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 17:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-ann-arbor-jones/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 1&amp;frasl;18: Two arrested in Ann Arbor shooting (Freep)  from theAnn Arbor Police Department account on Youtube.  Wanted for Questioning in a Fatal Shooting in the City of Ann Arbor, Michigan. If you know the whereabouts of Myrick, please call our Anonymous Tipline 734-996-3199. Refer to Case Number 08-457. Local news reporting pull quotes -  Your best narrow search results show up for the Google searches for Ann Arbor Jones Drive murder  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan primary results - 2008 presidential primary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-16-michigan-primar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 01:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-16-michigan-primar/</guid>
      <description>2008 Unofficial Michigan Primary Election Results from http://miboecfr.nicusa.com - who are these people, are they really part of michigan.gov ? Something is being outsourced, very badly.
The short story: Dem: Clinton 55, Uncommitted 40, Kucinich 4 Rep: Romney 39, McCain 30, Huckabee 16, Paul 6, Thompson 4, Guiliani 3
Best counties (overnight approx, data from NY Times, where is my spreadsheet full of numbers?)
Democrats: Kucinich: 9% in Washtenaw Clinton: 88% in Houghton, 64% in Macomb, 66% in Chippewa Uncommitted: 49% in Emmet, 46% in Washtenaw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoop house basil?  Some early research</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-14-hoop-house-basi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 01:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-14-hoop-house-basi/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s January, which means no farmer&amp;rsquo;s market basil until July or August. Not too early to start thinking about it, though, especially thinking about how to grow your own - perhaps using ahoop house to speed the process along. Here&amp;rsquo;s some preliminary research to share.  http://mdmintake.blogspot.com/2006/08/basil-anyone.html  Brooke and I had a great time at the farm this afternoon. And by great, I mean I now know why Tricia is always wearing carhartts, a straw hat, gloves and boots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Snow Removal Information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-18-ann-arbor-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 09:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-18-ann-arbor-snow/</guid>
      <description>This is a copy of http://www.a2gov.org/government/publicservices/fieldoperations/Pages/SnowRemoval.aspx as of December 2007, with markup and annotations noted.  The City of Ann Arbor performs a variety of street maintenance depending upon the amount of snow that falls. Generally, the categories are described as &amp;ldquo;light snow,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;snow emergency.&amp;rdquo; In addition, the city is dependent upon its citizens for sidewalk snow removal.  For up to date snow information please watch Cable Television Network (CTN) Channel 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedal powered washing machine</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-13-pedal-powered-w/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-13-pedal-powered-w/</guid>
      <description>Homeless Dave has this video documenting his design, implementation, and real world daily use of a dual use pedal power system, with a pedal powered washing machine spinning clothes dry, and a separate belt going to a generator for electricity.   We talked on Teeter Talk back in September, and you&amp;rsquo;ll catch a piece of the washing machine discussion there. Naturally there&amp;rsquo;s a sticker.
 go urgently, and find some mechanical engineer while you&amp;rsquo;re at it who has powertrain or appliance experience to look at the design and source parts for an improved version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood resources vs. cash resources</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had good experiences with sharing of surplus resources at a neighborhood level. The folks on my block regularly borrow ladders, save up canning jars, pick each others surplus tomatoes, take care of cats etc as needed. Sometimes token amounts of cash change hands - mostly to pay kids - but often not.
 I look at the kinds of businesses and business plans aimed at monetizing neighborliness with a bit of skepticism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>