<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peoples Food Coop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/peoples-food-coop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peoples Food Coop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/peoples-food-coop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>