<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiki Writing on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/wiki-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiki Writing on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:54:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/wiki-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jay Gatsby - the Wikipedia page from 2009, as edited by Dan Murphy, before the wikivandals took over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csmonitor.com/About/Staff/Dan-Murphy&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Dan Murphy&lt;/a&gt; wrote this biography of the fictional character Jay Gatsby for Wikipedia in 2009. Since then, the anonymous hordes of Wikipedia editors &lt;a href=&#34;http://wikipediocracy.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=14&amp;amp;t=2285&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;have not improved&lt;/a&gt; upon the page. Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;23 October 2009&lt;/a&gt; version of &amp;quot;Jay Gatsby&amp;quot;, which is much better written than the current edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jay Gatsby&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;is the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Title_role#Title_character&#34; title=&#34;Title role&#34;&gt;titular character&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;of&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F._Scott_Fitzgerald&#34; title=&#34;F. Scott Fitzgerald&#34;&gt;F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s 1925 novel&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Great_Gatsby&#34; title=&#34;The Great Gatsby&#34;&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/a&gt;. The character has become an archetype of self-made American men seeking to join&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upper_class&#34; title=&#34;Upper class&#34;&gt;High society&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and the name has become synonymous with successful businessmen with shady pasts in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Character biography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James &amp;quot;Jimmy&amp;quot; Gatz, a bright young man from a poor family in North Dakota, despised the imprecations of poverty so much he dropped out of&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Olaf_College&#34; title=&#34;St. Olaf College&#34;&gt;St. Olaf College&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;in Minnesota after only a few weeks because of his shame at the janitorial job he had to take to pay his way. While training in 1917 to join the infantry and fight in&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_War_I&#34; title=&#34;World War I&#34;&gt;World War I&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;he meets and promptly falls in love with the beautiful Daisy, who represents everything he is not: she is rich, from a patrician East Coast family and born with the proverbial silver spoon in her mouth. After the war, from which he emerged as a hero for his participation in the bloody battles of&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Marne&#34; title=&#34;Battle of the Marne&#34;&gt;Marne&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Argonne&#34; title=&#34;Battle of Argonne&#34;&gt;Argonne&lt;/a&gt;, he attends&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_College,_Oxford&#34; title=&#34;Trinity College, Oxford&#34;&gt;Trinity College&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Oxford&#34; title=&#34;University of Oxford&#34;&gt;Oxford&lt;/a&gt;. While there he receives a letter from Daisy telling him she has married the equally aristocratic Tom Buchanan. Rather than admit defeat, he commits his life to becoming a man of the sort of wealth and stature he imagines could win her love.&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatz returned home to an America transformed by&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prohibition_in_the_United_States&#34; title=&#34;Prohibition in the United States&#34;&gt;prohibition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;in 1919, a period in American history in which gangsters earned the sort of vast wealth previously the domain of the connected upper classes, an era in which &amp;quot;all the old boundaries that separated the classes were being broken, and a new wave of instant millionaires, like Gatsby himself&amp;hellip; mingled with the polo-players who inhabited the stiff enclaves of the established rich of Long Island&amp;#39;s gold coast.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;#0160;This era later came to be known as the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jazz_Age&#34; title=&#34;Jazz Age&#34;&gt;Jazz Age&lt;/a&gt;, after Fitzgerald&amp;#39;s own coinage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatz, who renamed himself Jay Gatsby, made a fortune in bootlegging thanks to his association with gangsters like Meyer Wolfsheim (patterned after real-life American gangster&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arnold_Rothstein&#34; title=&#34;Arnold Rothstein&#34;&gt;Arnold Rothstein&lt;/a&gt;) and sets himself up in a mansion in the fictional West Egg, Long Island, a haunt of the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nouveaux_riche&#34; title=&#34;Nouveaux riche&#34;&gt;nouveaux riche&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and across from the old-line money East Egg, where Tom and Daisy Buchanan live. Gatsby hosts wild parties, open to all comers, there every weekend, in the hopes that Daisy will attend and he can win her heart. He eventually catches up with Daisy, but fails to convince her to leave Tom. After his failure to change Daisy&amp;#39;s mind is clear to all but him, Daisy drives Gatsby&amp;#39;s car with Gatsby in the passenger seat and she accidentally strikes and kills Myrtle, the lover of her husband Tom, in a hit-and-run accident. Myrtle&amp;#39;s jealous husband George tracks the car back to the Buchanan home, where Tom lies and tells him that Gatsby was the driver of the car that killed his wife. George goes to Gatsby&amp;#39;s house, finds him floating in his lavish pool, and murders him before taking his own life. Almost none of Gatsby&amp;#39;s high society friends attend his funeral and in the meantime Gatsby&amp;#39;s underworld connections begin picking through his belongings in his mansion.&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gatsby as a reference point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure of Jay Gatsby became a cultural touchstone in 20th century America.&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Mathews&#34; title=&#34;Chris Mathews&#34;&gt;Chris Mathews&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;in his book&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;American&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;even forgives Gatsby his serial lies. When the poor native son Gatsby tells Nick Carraway, his only true friend and a relative of Daisy&amp;#39;s, he was brought up wealthy and that he attended Oxford because &amp;quot;all my ancestors have been educated there&amp;quot; Mathews sees him as the eternal American striver. &amp;quot;Gatsby needed more than money: he needed to be someone who had&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;had it&amp;hellip; this blind faith that he can retrofit his very existence to Daisy&amp;#39;s specifications is the heart and soul of the&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s the classic story of the fresh start, the second chance.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Jay Gatsby&amp;hellip; appears to be the quintessential American male hero. He is a powerful businessman with shady connections, drives a glamorous car&amp;hellip; and pursues the beautiful, privileged Daisy,&amp;quot; Michael Kimmel and Amy Aronson write.&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-5&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;#0160;In the Handbook of American Folklore, Richard Dorson sees Gatsby as a new American archetype who made a decision to transform himself after his first chance encounter with his mentor Dan Cody, who opens the door to riches in boot-legging. &amp;quot;The ragged youth who some months later (after Gatsby drops out of St. Olaf) introduces himself to a degenerate yachtsman as Jay Gatsby has explicitly rejected the Protestant ethic&amp;hellip; in favor of a much more extravagant form of ambition.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-6&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referring to real life figures as&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;has been common in the United States, usually in reference to rich men whose rise to prominence involved an element of deception. In a story on&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R._Foster_Winans&#34; title=&#34;R. Foster Winans&#34;&gt;R. Foster Winans&lt;/a&gt;, a reporter for the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wall_Street_Journal&#34; title=&#34;Wall Street Journal&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Heard on the Street&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;column who was fired after it was discovered he was giving advance knowledge of the columns&amp;#39; contents to Peter Brant, the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seattle_Post_Intelligencer&#34; title=&#34;Seattle Post Intelligencer&#34;&gt;Seattle Post Intelligencer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;described Brant as &amp;quot;Winan&amp;#39;s Gatsby.&amp;quot; The article noted that Brant had changed his name from Bornstein and said he was &amp;quot;a man who turned his back on his heritage and his family because he felt that being recognized as Jewish would be a detriment to his career.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-7&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;#0160;The&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Heard on the Street&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;column often effects the prices of the stocks it mentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The character is often used as a symbol of great wealth. Reporting in 2009 on the collapse of home prices and tourist spending in the exclusive&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hamptons&#34; title=&#34;Hamptons&#34;&gt;Hamptons&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;on Long Island, not far from the fictional setting of Gatsby&amp;#39;s home, the Wall Street Journal quoted a struggling hotelier as saying &amp;quot;Jay Gatsby is dead.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;cite_ref-8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jay_Gatsby&amp;amp;oldid=321578117#cite_note-8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletionism, or the grim reaper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-01-02-deletionism-or-the-grim-reaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 12:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-01-02-deletionism-or-the-grim-reaper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a tremendous appeal to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2008/06/15/Deletionist-Morons&#34;&gt;deletionist&lt;/a&gt; point of view.
&lt;p&gt;
I spent some time this evening improving Wikipedia by suggesting that some of its less well written articles be removed. The task was relatively simple; hit the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:Random&#34;&gt;random page&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; button, read the article, decide if it is so horrible as to be unencyclopedic, and if it is then paste in the &amp;quot;please delete this&amp;quot; template and hope for the best.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Combing through a series of random pages on Wikipedia is more grim than I had expected. Many of the articles were very short, to the typical tune of &amp;quot;X is a village with 42 inhabitants&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Y was an indifferent soccer player on a minor league team&amp;quot;. A surprising number of articles were years old and read &amp;quot;Z will be a television series on a minor television network&amp;quot; with no one bothering to follow up to see whether the series was kept or cancelled.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I haven&amp;#39;t always been a deletionist. There was a time when you&amp;#39;d find me in Wikipedia more often than not improving some minor but notable page to make it incrementally better in the hopes that it would not be deleted, or arguing to keep some minimally important article from being deleted. The experience of working through random pages was sufficiently enlightening about the general quality of the work there that it seemed more productive to argue instead to wipe out some of the less well considered contributions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com&#34;&gt;My weblog&lt;/a&gt; is similarly full of indifferent contributions, posts which seem to have been a good idea at the time but which don&amp;#39;t have much to argue for themselves now. For a long time I had a habit of writing very short and poorly edited posts just in order to get something out quickly, and I&amp;#39;d love to revisit those and improve them by taking them offline.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A help to solid improvement of a large body of work is some way to randomly index your way through the system and work on the next random piece that comes up in front of you. The standard Typepad system does not have any sort of &amp;quot;random post&amp;quot; structure, so I&amp;#39;ll need to somehow improvise. What I think I can do is &lt;a href=&#34;http://help.typepad.com/import_export.html&#34;&gt;export the entire contents of my blog&lt;/a&gt;, write a script to pull out just the titles and URLs of the posts, then generate something that pulls a random line from that list. If I can do that then I can go back randomly and be ruthless in pruning out things that don&amp;#39;t belong any more.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ideally there&amp;#39;s some basis for the notion that rather than writing new words all the time, I should be looking at ways of improving some of the old ones instead. That germ of a good idea, half explored in 150 words 5 years ago, might make a good 750 word essay now. That poorly executed quick post of 7 years ago might be deleted to make room for a better issue now. No one will miss the old words, and I might be able to free up space in my memory for something more positive.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The deletionist point of view, when applied too aggressively, can also be pretty grim. The grim reaper decides that one person&amp;#39;s hard work is unworthy of inclusion and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Please_do_not_bite_the_newcomers&#34;&gt;attacks everything they do&lt;/a&gt; until that contributor goes away. If you get hit by a deletionist of that type, your only best approach is to move your contributions to some other medium where you can contribute without attracting undue attention.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My randomized approach to editorial review is much more like the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techblog.netflix.com/2012/07/chaos-monkey-released-into-wild.html&#34;&gt;chaos monkey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; used by some cloud-based online services to ensure that their carefully constructed and complicated system is resilient in the case of failure. The chaos monkey takes down parts of a redundant system at random, forcing it to respond in the way that systems designers had planned for an outage. Because you are exercising the failures in a controlled way you can be prepared for uncontrolled failure at some future time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was able to download the entire blog corpus, and to write &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vielmetti/vielmetti-shelltools/blob/master/randomline&#34;&gt;the little script that pulled out a random title from the total&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s now also time to start doing other textual analysis on this word-hoard, looking for words that are used unusually frequently, or subjects that come up more often than I had imagined. With the right tool set there should be lots of good meta-information that I can reuse and turn into new ideas. After all, there&amp;#39;s more than a decade worth of stuff buried in almost 10 megabytes of text, and I&amp;#39;m sure that at least 10% of it is deletable without the slightest loss to anyone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>