<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marquette Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/marquette-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marquette Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/marquette-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.
He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivetti Programma 101</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 22:47:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</guid>
      <description>The first computer that I ever had all to myself was the Olivetti Programma 101. This was a 1965-era Italian machine that was just a little more than a programmable calculator. It used flexible magnetic cards for program storage, discrete logic for all of its computing functions, delay line memory (240 bytes), and it all sat in a 65 pound package. Output was on a humming little printer built into the machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowshoe race bridge</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 08:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on building the Marquette Park Cemetery finder app for Code Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 01:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working on a tool or a set of tools to assist people in finding grave sites in the Park Cemetery in Marquette, Michigan as a part of a project for Code Michigan. I&#39;m working with a team that&#39;s based in the U.P. to do this, and we&#39;re collaborating over Google Hangouts. Code Michigan is a hackathon, so this project timeline is compressed to a single weekend. The team is Edward Vielmetti, Jim Argeropoulos, Chris Marr, and Lynn Czarnecki Makela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Marquette Localwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 21:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</guid>
      <description>I visit Marquette Michigan every summer to see family and catch up with friends and visit the place I went to high school. Every so often there&#39;s a reunion, but often it&#39;s just a matter of going back to the home town and figuring out what&#39;s up and what&#39;s what.
Since I&#39;ve been working on Arborwiki for the better part of eight years, I thought last year that I&#39;d give a try to make a Localwiki for Marquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;An obituary for Greg Peters is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.
 
Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron money: economic isolation on the Upper Peninsula frontier</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>These are fragmentary notes - and a few links - regarding the introduction of &amp;quot;iron money&amp;quot; into the economy of Marquette County, Michigan, and the controversy surrounding it leading up to the 1876 Presidential election.
Timeline
Panic of 1857.
Panic of 1873.
Newspaper accounts
The New York Times was in 1876 a Republican newspaper, and did not have the reputation it maintains today as a &amp;quot;newspaper of record&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160;
Tilden&amp;#39;s Iron Currency, New York Times, July 19, 1876</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on a 30th high school reunion</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-some-notes-on-a-30th-high-school-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-some-notes-on-a-30th-high-school-reunion/</guid>
      <description>Some notes on a 30th high school reunion, written last summer but just now published.
There&amp;#39;s a certain ritual set of behavior you can safely engage in when you talk to someone who you vaguely remember from high school but have been completely out of touch with for 30 years.
Ask about where they are living now, and discovered that most of your classmates moved more than 200 miles away from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Alternative High School photo calendar for 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>Students and teachers from the photography class at Marquette Alternative High School (MAHS) create a calendar each year. The project showcases their work and funds a field trip for the students. This year&amp;#39;s 2013 calendar features pictures of Marquette, the butterfly house on Mackinac Island, and the DeYoung Family Zoo in Wallace. The cost is $20 and it&amp;#39;s available for sale online.
Proceeds from the sale of the calendar go to photo equipment and to a photo field trip - the butterfly museum photos are from last year&amp;#39;s trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For 906 day, some photos of Marquette, MI from Shorpy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</guid>
      <description>906 day (September 6) celebrates the area code of the Upper Peninsula of Michigan. First I&amp;#39;ve heard of this holiday, but I heartily approve.
In honor of this day a couple of nice photos of Marquette, MI came via Shorpy. The photos of the harbor and ore docks, Front Street, and a panorama of downtown Marquette&amp;#0160;date from 1908 and 1909 and are from glass negatives from the Detroit Publishing Company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My career in food service</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-my-career-in-food-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 14:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-my-career-in-food-service/</guid>
      <description>As published in the Association for Computing Machinery&#39;s Risks Digest, v4 n30, 1986:
&amp;nbsp;Fast-Food Computing &amp;lt;Edward_Vielmetti@um.cc.umich.edu&amp;gt; Tue, 16 Dec 86 16:15:04 EST
I must have been in the cycle early for McDonald&#39;s fast-food intelligent man-machine systems, according to Guthery&#39;s law: &amp;gt; In an evolving man-machine system, the man will get &amp;gt; dumber faster than the machine gets smarter. McDonald&#39;s fast food computers (i.e., cash registers) collect all sorts of data on the individual employee at the counter and on all counter sales as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch baby apple pancake; and a March 2009 maple report from the UP</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-18-here-is-the-penzeys-apple-pancake-recipea-morph-from-the-dutch-baby----14-cup-butter--34-cup-all-purpose-flour--34-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-18-here-is-the-penzeys-apple-pancake-recipea-morph-from-the-dutch-baby----14-cup-butter--34-cup-all-purpose-flour--34-cup/</guid>
      <description>Here is the Penzey&amp;#39;s Apple Pancake recipe&amp;hellip;a morph from the Dutch Baby. &amp;#0160; 1&amp;frasl;4 cup butter&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; 3&amp;frasl;4 cup all-purpose flour 3&amp;frasl;4 cup milk  1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 2 medium baking apples, peeled and thinly sliced&amp;#0160; (I used Braeburn apples) 3 Tbs sugar 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp ceylon cinnamon &amp;#0160; Preheat oven to 400.&amp;#0160; divide butter between two 9&amp;quot; pie plates and put them in the oven to melt the butter.&amp;#0160; Rotate to be sure that butter covers bottom and&amp;#0160; sides of pans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>