<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marquette Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/cities/marquette-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marquette Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/cities/marquette-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Doc&#34; title=&#34;Doc&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961. During his tenure, Lew served as department head from 1971 to 1975, taught Anatomy, Physiology and Parasitology, and in 1980 received a contract from the National Park Service to study parasites at Isle Royale. He retired in 1996 after 35 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew was a member of St. Michael Catholic Church and Marquette Rotary Club. He is survived by his wife, Kathy Peters of Marquette; children, Raymond (Velquis) Peters of Indianapolis, IN, Matthew (Elizabeth) Peters of Austin, TX, Dan (Jennifer) Peters of Tallahassee, FL, Edward (Deborah Fisch) Vielmetti of Ann Arbor, MI, Stephen (Paula) Vielmetti of Milwaukee, WI and Anne (Douglas) Moody of Vancouver, WA; grandchildren, Nicolette &amp;amp; Elizabeth Peters, Zack and Ava Peters, Garrett, Bryson &amp;amp; Reese Peters, Saul and Jonathan Vielmetti, Marshall, Nathan, Sophia and Zevon Vielmetti, Graham and Spencer Moody; sister, Robyn (David) Messner of Jensen Beach, FL; numerous nieces &amp;amp; nephews; and special family friend&#39;s, Tim Glover and his family. He was preceded in death by his parents, first wife, Oneita &#34;Beth&#34; Peters and a brother, Edward Peters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew&#39;s family would like to thank the staff of Brookridge Heights and Lake Superior Hospice for the wonderful care they provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A memorial service will be held on Monday, March 9, 2015 at 3:00 p.m. at the Canale-Tonella Funeral Home with Deacon David Adler officiating. Visitation will be held from 1:00 p.m. until the time of the service in the funeral home. Inurnment will take place at Park Cemetery. In lieu of flowers, memorials can be directed to the Biology Department at NMU in care of the NMU Foundation or the Lake Superior Land Conservancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canale-Tonella Funeral Home is assisting the family where memories may be shared at canalefuneral.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivetti Programma 101</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 22:47:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07d19a72970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first computer that I ever had all to myself was the Olivetti Programma 101. This was a 1965-era Italian machine that was just a little more than a programmable calculator. It used flexible magnetic cards for program storage, discrete logic for all of its computing functions, delay line memory (240 bytes), and it all sat in a 65 pound package. Output was on a humming little printer built into the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graveraet Middle School in Marquette had one of these, presumably discarded from its use in the school administration. By 1977 the machine was so completely obsolete that it sat idle, with no one knowing how it worked. I got plenty of time to spend with the system, and frankly I never really figured it out either. It was easy enough to use it as an adding and multiplying and dividing machine, but the mysteries of its program logic escaped me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several folks who have active projects to restore the old system, including a project at the DataMuseum in Denmark. &lt;a href=&#34;http://datamuseum.dk/wiki/Olivetti/Programma_101/Revive&#34;&gt;See their efforts here.&lt;/a&gt; There are quite a lot of mechanical parts in this old machine, including a set of 8 pulleys that drove the various bits of the card reader and the printer. Rubber rollers of course get old and decayed with time so every account of a restoration has some discussion of that repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photo at the top is from Michigan Tech, written by James D. Spain, who outlines the use of the Programma 101 &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.mtu.edu/biological/2012/03/origins-of-the-computer-simulation-program-in-biology-at-michigan-tech/&#34;&gt;in the biology program at Tech in 1969.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a video, &amp;ldquo;Quando Olivetti inventò il PC&amp;rdquo;, with a history showing the machine in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/oYB2oBc1BpA?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowshoe race bridge</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 08:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Showshoe-race-bridge&#34; title=&#34;Showshoe-race-bridge&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on building the Marquette Park Cemetery finder app for Code Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 01:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m working on a tool or a set of tools to assist people in finding grave sites in the Park Cemetery in Marquette, Michigan as a part of a project for Code Michigan. I&#39;m working with a team that&#39;s based in the U.P. to do this, and we&#39;re collaborating over Google Hangouts. Code Michigan is a hackathon, so this project timeline is compressed to a single weekend. The team is Edward Vielmetti, Jim Argeropoulos, Chris Marr, and Lynn Czarnecki Makela. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My motivation for picking the grave finder app is a personal one. My grandmother, Ada Burt Vielmetti, is buried in Park Cemetery, and I&#39;ve never visited the grave because I didn&#39;t know where it was. The cemetery covers over 100 acres so it&#39;s impractical to just wander around until you find what you&#39;re looking for, and there wasn&#39;t an online finder&#39;s aid. When the Code Michigan challenge came about it was an obvious task to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that providing detailed location data for individuals seeking to find people inside this cemetery is a common civic task. The role of the sexton, aside from care for the physical properties inside the cemetery, is to guide people to where they are looking for. This could be the grand burial grounds of famous and wealthy people with a beautiful mausoleum, or it could be a simple marker underfoot. In any case the challenge is to provide someone with enough guidance so that they can get close enough to the spot that they can locate exactly the one spot that is of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes on technology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maps problem for any geolocation task relies heavily on work that&#39;s been done before. Base maps of the city are available from Google, but the Google panopticar has not traversed all of the cemetery lanes and the Google map doesn&#39;t show the structure of the roads that you can walk or drive down. Open Street Map is better, in that it does have more detail within the cemetery, but it doesn&#39;t go down to the individual grave level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the base map with roads, there&#39;s a plat map showing the sections of the cemetery that&#39;s available in PDF format from the city. Our team took this plat map, field checked it, and encoded plat boundaries as GeoJSON files so that we had an accurate representation of the area within the cemetery that an individual could be located. This brings the task down to a range, rather than a specific point, but it&#39;s practical enough and a small and precise enough area to be a useful first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data about individual burial locations in Park Cemetery was provided to use using the Socrata SODA API. A challenge here was that the &#34;location&#34; field, a critical one for our use, was encoded in such a way that a simple download of the data would not yield an immediately usable result since the location (in latitude and longitude) of an individual grave is not known. We addressed that issue by using the API&#39;s JSON download function to return not only the valid fields in the data but also the ones marked invalid, and a post-processing step cleaned the data to extract a valid &#34;plat&#34; field from the provided data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON is a very easy to manipulate format, and I used two tools that are documented in the new book &lt;a href=&#34;http://datascienceatthecommandline.com/&#34;&gt;Data Science at the Command Line&lt;/a&gt; by Jeroen Jansens. &#34;jq&#34; is like sed for JSON data – you can use it to slice and filter and map and transform structured data with the same ease that sed, awk, grep and friends let you play with text. &#34;json&#34; offers powerful and flexible tools for taking JSON data and printing it in flexible formats. Between those two tools and a bit of other Unix command line efforts with &#34;sed&#34; and &#34;perl&#34;, it was possible to write a handful of one-line transformations that take the Socrata data and turn it into a more compact JSON and HTML format for use directly inside applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By running these transformations on the 12,000 plus record original dataset, I was able to pull out just the location information and basic personal details for everyone - including my Nana. This gets turned into a series of files, one per cemetery section, sorted by lot number so that there&#39;s a chance that you could walk a section methodically and have the data be your guide to whether you are close to what you&#39;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To publish the data in a format that is useful to the world, I turned to an old favorite, Localwiki. This comes with a number of useful tools right off the bat. At one file per cemetery section (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/marquettemi/Marquette_Park_Cemetery_-_Jenney_W&#34;&gt;Jenney W&lt;/a&gt; the sorted HTML list loads easily into the list. The GeoJSON we created can be imported using the Localwiki API, or cemetery areas or points can be hand-plotted on an OpenStreetMap based map. Names for which Localwiki has more information can be linked. (I resisted the temptation to link every name, though if you had more coverage it would be the obvious next step). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Localwiki is good for this effort for a few reasons. It has a local search tool that lets you type in a name and get something in return. While not as precise as a purpose-built search tool, it&#39;s easy to implement, and at 12,000 records spread out into a few dozen sections no individual file is too big to load. We know that Localwiki is good for local search, and eventually when the pages are indexed they will be reachable by Google search as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community aspect of civic data use with Localwiki is an important one. No municipal employee can ever hope to gather biographical data on 12,000 cemetery residents, but we want to support citizens in their interest to collect and refine as much detail as they need to memorialize or to research personal and community history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to loading Park Cemetery data into Localwiki, we also pursued a prototype of a purpose-built application designed specifically for mobile phone sized screens that would provide a name index and a plat finder for people who are on site. The goal is to reduce the complexity of the problem down to type in a name and get something back on a map that includes a dot saying where you are. This system uses Drupal as a back end, with maps provided through a responsive front end system specially adapted to look good on a mobile phone sized screen. Links are provided to Localwiki for reference data, and the design includes ways for individuals to quickly add to or verify location information so that you can pinpoint a spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some lessons learned from the effort, which isn&#39;t done yet but getting close!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s important to have a variety of skills on your team. We divvied up the problem into parts that were simple enough for each of us to tackle based on our own skills, and sorted through coordination issues via periodic Google Hangout calls. When you&#39;re working using tools you are good at and on things you find challenging but not impossible, there&#39;s a lot of room for making progress in a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools and standards help. We discovered GeoJSON mid-day through day 2, and were able to use it almost immediately to extend our data to be reusable without recoding on multiple platforms. Similarly, the combination of the Socrata SODA API and the powerful &#34;jq&#34; and &#34;json&#34; tools turned a complete data processing problem into a handful of lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there&#39;s a real problem to be solved, it&#39;s easier to see that you are successful. Two members of the team have family members buried in Park Cemetery. With the toolset we developed, we were able to find those graves, photograph the headstones, and decide how to incorporate that data into Localwiki. Knowing now that the problem is solvable with the data provided, it simply follows to extend that solution to a broader set of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usable prototypes are more valuable than pixel-perfect finished products. Localwiki let me test ideas almost immediately, without much more than a little bit of coding needed to get to a point where a search engine would return a useful result. The tooling we built for the mobile app got to a usable demo phase promptly. A handful of photographs from the field were enough to not only field-check the data that we had, but also to better understand what we could do when there was more time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A weekend is not a lot of time to get much beyond the prototype stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not done yet. The contest rules want a video, and we&#39;re working on the storyboard. The coding is done, but Localwiki is never really done, and there are some pages to make more spiffy and full of useful content. But in some sense I feel like we&#39;ve already succeeded, in that a completely hidden system got turned into something that I&#39;m starting to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proof, perhaps, is that we were able to put together a team that answered the question: where is Nana buried? The proof below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;WP_003205&#34; title=&#34;WP_003205&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 439px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-05 at 1.35.20 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-05 at 1.35.20 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d-450wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron money: economic isolation on the Upper Peninsula frontier</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are fragmentary notes - and a few links - regarding the introduction of &amp;quot;iron money&amp;quot; into the economy of Marquette County, Michigan, and the controversy surrounding it leading up to the 1876 Presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic of 1857.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic of 1873.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newspaper accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times was in 1876 a Republican newspaper, and did not have the reputation it maintains today as a &amp;quot;newspaper of record&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F60C12FE3E5B137B93CBA8178CD85F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden&amp;#39;s Iron Currency&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, July 19, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=FA081EFD395E137B93C1AB1783D85F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A Swindler of Labor&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, August 23, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F0061EFF3E5B137B93C1A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Sham Reformer&lt;/a&gt;. New York Times, October 3, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F70616FC3E5B137B93C6A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden and the Iron Money&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;Red Specular&amp;quot;, New York Times, October 4, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=FB0A15FC3E5B137B93C7A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Tilden Iron Money Question&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;Red Specular&amp;quot;, New York Times, October 5, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F40812F7345B127B93CBA8178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden&amp;#39;s Sharp Tricks&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, October 19, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magazine articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questia.com/library/1G1-166849379/the-legacy-of-peter-white&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Legacy of Peter White&lt;/a&gt;, George Merk,&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Michigan History Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 83, No. 3.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;May-June 1999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questia.com/library/1G1-163098143/iron-money&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Iron Money&lt;/a&gt;, William van Kosky, Michigan History Magazine v90 n2, March-April 2006
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=8mxTeVYKzMUC&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Honorable Peter White&lt;/a&gt;, Ralph Williams, 1907&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Fraud-Century-Rutherford-Samuel-Election/dp/0743255526&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Fraud of the Century: Rutherford B. Hayes, Samuel Tilden, and the Stolen Election of 1876&lt;/a&gt;, Roy Morris Jr., 2004&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GoXNi5gkTOgC&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Iron Will: Cleveland-Cliffs and the Mining of Iron Ore, 1847-2006&lt;/a&gt;, Reynolds and Dawson, 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://quod.lib.umich.edu/b/bhlead/umich-bhl-86396?rgn=main;view=text&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Peter White papers&lt;/a&gt;, Bentley Historical Library, Ann Arbor MI&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Alternative High School photo calendar for 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://marquette.revtrak.net/img/products/Thumbnaillarge.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image from marquette.revtrak.net&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d3ee5d119970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d3ee5d119970c-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;image from marquette.revtrak.net&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Students and teachers from the photography class at Marquette Alternative High School (MAHS) create a calendar each year. The project showcases their work and funds a field trip for the students. This year&amp;#39;s 2013 calendar features pictures of Marquette, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.originalbutterflyhouse.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;butterfly house on Mackinac Island&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeYoung_Family_Zoo&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;DeYoung Family Zoo&lt;/a&gt; in Wallace. The cost is $20 and it&amp;#39;s available &lt;a href=&#34;http://marquette.revtrak.net/tek9.asp?pg=products&amp;amp;specific=jnkqnoo0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;for sale online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeds from the sale of the calendar go to photo equipment and to a photo field trip - the butterfly museum photos are from last year&amp;#39;s trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Cindy DePetro from MAHS about the calendar and the responses they&amp;#39;ve gotten from it. She writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to get praised over the quality of the photos, but our biggest praise is that most people feel like they receive a little piece of home when they see our calendars. We get many repeat customers, and our calendars travel all over the world. Thus far, we know they are being sent to Iraq, Afghanistan, Germany and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For 906 day, some photos of Marquette, MI from Shorpy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;906 day (September 6) celebrates the area code of the Upper Peninsula of Michigan. First I&amp;#39;ve heard of this holiday, but I heartily approve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of this day a couple of nice photos of Marquette, MI came via Shorpy. The photos of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12492&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;harbor and ore docks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12489&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Front Street&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12493&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;panorama of downtown Marquette&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;date from 1908 and 1909 and are from glass negatives from the Detroit Publishing Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detail below shows the Hotel Janzen, with a train&amp;#39;s smoke just to the left of it and a piece of City Hall at the far left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 21&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 21&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>