<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marquette Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/marquette-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marquette Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/marquette-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Doc&#34; title=&#34;Doc&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961. During his tenure, Lew served as department head from 1971 to 1975, taught Anatomy, Physiology and Parasitology, and in 1980 received a contract from the National Park Service to study parasites at Isle Royale. He retired in 1996 after 35 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew was a member of St. Michael Catholic Church and Marquette Rotary Club. He is survived by his wife, Kathy Peters of Marquette; children, Raymond (Velquis) Peters of Indianapolis, IN, Matthew (Elizabeth) Peters of Austin, TX, Dan (Jennifer) Peters of Tallahassee, FL, Edward (Deborah Fisch) Vielmetti of Ann Arbor, MI, Stephen (Paula) Vielmetti of Milwaukee, WI and Anne (Douglas) Moody of Vancouver, WA; grandchildren, Nicolette &amp;amp; Elizabeth Peters, Zack and Ava Peters, Garrett, Bryson &amp;amp; Reese Peters, Saul and Jonathan Vielmetti, Marshall, Nathan, Sophia and Zevon Vielmetti, Graham and Spencer Moody; sister, Robyn (David) Messner of Jensen Beach, FL; numerous nieces &amp;amp; nephews; and special family friend&#39;s, Tim Glover and his family. He was preceded in death by his parents, first wife, Oneita &#34;Beth&#34; Peters and a brother, Edward Peters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew&#39;s family would like to thank the staff of Brookridge Heights and Lake Superior Hospice for the wonderful care they provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A memorial service will be held on Monday, March 9, 2015 at 3:00 p.m. at the Canale-Tonella Funeral Home with Deacon David Adler officiating. Visitation will be held from 1:00 p.m. until the time of the service in the funeral home. Inurnment will take place at Park Cemetery. In lieu of flowers, memorials can be directed to the Biology Department at NMU in care of the NMU Foundation or the Lake Superior Land Conservancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canale-Tonella Funeral Home is assisting the family where memories may be shared at canalefuneral.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivetti Programma 101</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 22:47:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-03-olivetti-programma-101/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07d19a72970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first computer that I ever had all to myself was the Olivetti
Programma 101. This was a 1965-era Italian machine that was just a
little more than a programmable calculator. It used flexible magnetic
cards for program storage, discrete logic for all of its computing
functions, delay line memory (240 bytes), and it all sat in a 65
pound package. Output was on a humming little printer built into
the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graveraet Middle School in Marquette had one of these, presumably
discarded from its use in the school administration. By 1977 the
machine was so completely obsolete that it sat idle, with no one
knowing how it worked. I got plenty of time to spend with the system,
and frankly I never really figured it out either. It was easy enough
to use it as an adding and multiplying and dividing machine, but
the mysteries of its program logic escaped me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several folks who have active projects to restore the old
system, including a project at the DataMuseum in Denmark. &lt;a
href=&#34;http://datamuseum.dk/wiki/Olivetti/Programma_101/Revive&#34;&gt;See their
efforts here.&lt;/a&gt; There are quite a lot of mechanical parts in this
old machine, including a set of 8 pulleys that drove the various
bits of the card reader and the printer. Rubber rollers of course
get old and decayed with time so every account of a restoration has
some discussion of that repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photo at the top is from Michigan Tech, written by James D.
Spain, who outlines the use of the Programma 101 &lt;a
href=&#34;http://blogs.mtu.edu/biological/2012/03/origins-of-the-computer-simulation-program-in-biology-at-michigan-tech/&#34;&gt;in
the biology program at Tech in 1969.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a video, &amp;ldquo;Quando Olivetti inventò il PC&amp;rdquo;, with a history showing the machine in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/oYB2oBc1BpA?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowshoe race bridge</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 08:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-26-snowshoe-race-bridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Showshoe-race-bridge&#34; title=&#34;Showshoe-race-bridge&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d084a268970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on building the Marquette Park Cemetery finder app for Code Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 01:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-notes-on-building-the-marquette-park-cemetery-finder-app-for-code-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m working on a tool or a set of tools to assist people in finding grave sites in the Park Cemetery in Marquette, Michigan as a part of a project for Code Michigan. I&#39;m working with a team that&#39;s based in the U.P. to do this, and we&#39;re collaborating over Google Hangouts. Code Michigan is a hackathon, so this project timeline is compressed to a single weekend. The team is Edward Vielmetti, Jim Argeropoulos, Chris Marr, and Lynn Czarnecki Makela. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My motivation for picking the grave finder app is a personal one. My grandmother, Ada Burt Vielmetti, is buried in Park Cemetery, and I&#39;ve never visited the grave because I didn&#39;t know where it was. The cemetery covers over 100 acres so it&#39;s impractical to just wander around until you find what you&#39;re looking for, and there wasn&#39;t an online finder&#39;s aid. When the Code Michigan challenge came about it was an obvious task to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that providing detailed location data for individuals seeking to find people inside this cemetery is a common civic task. The role of the sexton, aside from care for the physical properties inside the cemetery, is to guide people to where they are looking for. This could be the grand burial grounds of famous and wealthy people with a beautiful mausoleum, or it could be a simple marker underfoot. In any case the challenge is to provide someone with enough guidance so that they can get close enough to the spot that they can locate exactly the one spot that is of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes on technology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maps problem for any geolocation task relies heavily on work that&#39;s been done before. Base maps of the city are available from Google, but the Google panopticar has not traversed all of the cemetery lanes and the Google map doesn&#39;t show the structure of the roads that you can walk or drive down. Open Street Map is better, in that it does have more detail within the cemetery, but it doesn&#39;t go down to the individual grave level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the base map with roads, there&#39;s a plat map showing the sections of the cemetery that&#39;s available in PDF format from the city. Our team took this plat map, field checked it, and encoded plat boundaries as GeoJSON files so that we had an accurate representation of the area within the cemetery that an individual could be located. This brings the task down to a range, rather than a specific point, but it&#39;s practical enough and a small and precise enough area to be a useful first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data about individual burial locations in Park Cemetery was provided to use using the Socrata SODA API. A challenge here was that the &#34;location&#34; field, a critical one for our use, was encoded in such a way that a simple download of the data would not yield an immediately usable result since the location (in latitude and longitude) of an individual grave is not known. We addressed that issue by using the API&#39;s JSON download function to return not only the valid fields in the data but also the ones marked invalid, and a post-processing step cleaned the data to extract a valid &#34;plat&#34; field from the provided data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON is a very easy to manipulate format, and I used two tools that are documented in the new book &lt;a href=&#34;http://datascienceatthecommandline.com/&#34;&gt;Data Science at the Command Line&lt;/a&gt; by Jeroen Jansens. &#34;jq&#34; is like sed for JSON data – you can use it to slice and filter and map and transform structured data with the same ease that sed, awk, grep and friends let you play with text. &#34;json&#34; offers powerful and flexible tools for taking JSON data and printing it in flexible formats. Between those two tools and a bit of other Unix command line efforts with &#34;sed&#34; and &#34;perl&#34;, it was possible to write a handful of one-line transformations that take the Socrata data and turn it into a more compact JSON and HTML format for use directly inside applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By running these transformations on the 12,000 plus record original dataset, I was able to pull out just the location information and basic personal details for everyone - including my Nana. This gets turned into a series of files, one per cemetery section, sorted by lot number so that there&#39;s a chance that you could walk a section methodically and have the data be your guide to whether you are close to what you&#39;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To publish the data in a format that is useful to the world, I turned to an old favorite, Localwiki. This comes with a number of useful tools right off the bat. At one file per cemetery section (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/marquettemi/Marquette_Park_Cemetery_-_Jenney_W&#34;&gt;Jenney W&lt;/a&gt; the sorted HTML list loads easily into the list. The GeoJSON we created can be imported using the Localwiki API, or cemetery areas or points can be hand-plotted on an OpenStreetMap based map. Names for which Localwiki has more information can be linked. (I resisted the temptation to link every name, though if you had more coverage it would be the obvious next step). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Localwiki is good for this effort for a few reasons. It has a local search tool that lets you type in a name and get something in return. While not as precise as a purpose-built search tool, it&#39;s easy to implement, and at 12,000 records spread out into a few dozen sections no individual file is too big to load. We know that Localwiki is good for local search, and eventually when the pages are indexed they will be reachable by Google search as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community aspect of civic data use with Localwiki is an important one. No municipal employee can ever hope to gather biographical data on 12,000 cemetery residents, but we want to support citizens in their interest to collect and refine as much detail as they need to memorialize or to research personal and community history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to loading Park Cemetery data into Localwiki, we also pursued a prototype of a purpose-built application designed specifically for mobile phone sized screens that would provide a name index and a plat finder for people who are on site. The goal is to reduce the complexity of the problem down to type in a name and get something back on a map that includes a dot saying where you are. This system uses Drupal as a back end, with maps provided through a responsive front end system specially adapted to look good on a mobile phone sized screen. Links are provided to Localwiki for reference data, and the design includes ways for individuals to quickly add to or verify location information so that you can pinpoint a spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some lessons learned from the effort, which isn&#39;t done yet but getting close!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s important to have a variety of skills on your team. We divvied up the problem into parts that were simple enough for each of us to tackle based on our own skills, and sorted through coordination issues via periodic Google Hangout calls. When you&#39;re working using tools you are good at and on things you find challenging but not impossible, there&#39;s a lot of room for making progress in a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools and standards help. We discovered GeoJSON mid-day through day 2, and were able to use it almost immediately to extend our data to be reusable without recoding on multiple platforms. Similarly, the combination of the Socrata SODA API and the powerful &#34;jq&#34; and &#34;json&#34; tools turned a complete data processing problem into a handful of lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there&#39;s a real problem to be solved, it&#39;s easier to see that you are successful. Two members of the team have family members buried in Park Cemetery. With the toolset we developed, we were able to find those graves, photograph the headstones, and decide how to incorporate that data into Localwiki. Knowing now that the problem is solvable with the data provided, it simply follows to extend that solution to a broader set of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usable prototypes are more valuable than pixel-perfect finished products. Localwiki let me test ideas almost immediately, without much more than a little bit of coding needed to get to a point where a search engine would return a useful result. The tooling we built for the mobile app got to a usable demo phase promptly. A handful of photographs from the field were enough to not only field-check the data that we had, but also to better understand what we could do when there was more time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A weekend is not a lot of time to get much beyond the prototype stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not done yet. The contest rules want a video, and we&#39;re working on the storyboard. The coding is done, but Localwiki is never really done, and there are some pages to make more spiffy and full of useful content. But in some sense I feel like we&#39;ve already succeeded, in that a completely hidden system got turned into something that I&#39;m starting to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proof, perhaps, is that we were able to put together a team that answered the question: where is Nana buried? The proof below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;WP_003205&#34; title=&#34;WP_003205&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a943970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 439px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-05 at 1.35.20 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-05 at 1.35.20 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0792a95c970d-450wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Marquette Localwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 21:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I visit Marquette Michigan every summer to see family and catch up with friends and visit the place I went to high school. Every so often there&#39;s a reunion, but often it&#39;s just a matter of going back to the home town and figuring out what&#39;s up and what&#39;s what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I&#39;ve been working on Arborwiki for the better part of eight years, I thought last year that I&#39;d give a try to make a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi&#34;&gt;Localwiki for Marquette&lt;/a&gt;. Technologically it was easy to do - Localwiki makes adding new regions easy - but practically it&#39;s got some challenges. Here are notes on what it means to look at Localwiki for a rural area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first most obvious thing to note is that there often are places and locations that don&#39;t have a currently updated home page. If you want to document the area, you have to attach a lot of things to its history, and the places like closed mines, abandoned railroads, long-gone restaurants, shuttered gas stations, and the like have to be created from scratch and not simply replicated from existing content. This is typical of the history portion of any Localwiki effort, in that local histories of otherwise not notable enough for Wikipedia things demand a combination of original research and local knowledge. The page I started for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Red_Road&#34;&gt;Red Road&lt;/a&gt; is one example of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re doing a map of areas that are relatively rural, you find that the default street map used by Localwiki isn&#39;t that interesting. As much as I know it&#39;s difficult to do, I wish the system had easier ways of integrating other map sources into the effort. Street maps are really the wrong tool when you&#39;re looking at areas that are mostly woods; you&#39;d like a topo map, maybe, and a plat map that showed land ownership, and a geological surface map that gave some hint what the land looked like and a forest map that showed which lands were in commercial forest. None of these are likely to show up in Google Maps any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trails and non-motorized pathways are a big opportunity for Localwiki. My mom is working on a project for signage for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Iron_Ore_Heritage_Trail&#34;&gt;Iron Ore Heritage Trail&lt;/a&gt;, and I&#39;ve put the bug in her ear that it might be interesting to cross-link somehow the interpretive signs on the trail with the corresponding Localwiki pages. Even getting good photography and mapping of trail heads would be a big enough project that I can imagine spending a week scouting out locations and not being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a concern at the Wikipedia project that linking to Localwiki pages is somehow dicey because of advertising on Localwiki, or perhaps because not enough people on Wikipedia are familiar enough with Localwiki to know what to expect when they see a page. As a contrast, there are also concerns on a Facebook group I follow about &#34;wikishit&#34; when people see a years-old &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Marquette_Monster&amp;amp;oldid=622698099&#34;&gt;Marquette Monster&lt;/a&gt; page that was completely fabricated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll look for more ways to get more reliable information into the Marquette Localwiki. I&#39;m particularly happy with the start that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Gazetteer&#34;&gt;Gazetteer&lt;/a&gt; page has for listing location, and there&#39;s some long amount of work to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Mines&#34;&gt;Mines&lt;/a&gt; page its due to document the mining history of the area. I&#39;m not sure the system has a single goal, but I&#39;m always happy when other people pick up on it, add their piece, and make it useful to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/blogofneworleans/archives/2013/08/02/suspect-device-cartoonist-greg-peters-dies&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;obituary for Greg Peters&lt;/a&gt; is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-600wi&#34; alt=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obit as published in NOLA.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cartoonist and writer Greg Peters died Friday morning, Aug. 2, after emergency surgery at Ochsner Medical Center. Mr. Peters, who had suffered from a congenital heart condition throughout his life, was 50 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in Marquette, Mich., Peters arrived in Louisiana in 1990 to pursue a doctorate in English literature at the University of Louisiana at Lafayette. He became best known as the creator of “Suspect Device,” a starkly crafted, blackly funny Louisiana-themed political comic strip that made its debut in 1996, in the Times of Acadiana, and ran in New Orleans’&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/&#34;&gt;Gambit Weekly&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from 1999 to 2010. “Suspect Device” famously pulled no punches: In 1998, editor Harris Meyer resigned from the Times of Acadiana, when the paper’s publisher refused to run one of Mr. Peters’ strips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suspect Device” was recognized with awards from the Press Club of New Orleans and the Association of Alternative Newsweeklies, and in 2004 was anthologized in “&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=r18Or31mODcC&amp;amp;pg=PT95&amp;amp;dq=greg+peters+attitude+2&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=ih78UY3HG8iWqQHx7YFw&amp;amp;ved=0CC8Q6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=greg%20peters%20attitude%202&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Attitude 2: The New Subversive Alternative Cartoonists&lt;/a&gt;.” Mr. Peters’ work was displayed in exhibitions in conjunction with the book at New York City’s Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters was “one of the few alternative weekly political cartoonists whose mission is to skewer local and state politicians,&#34; anthology editor Ted Rall told Gambit’s Scott Jordan in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/gambit/unusual-suspect/Content?oid=1243221&#34;&gt;a 2004 profile of Mr. Peters&lt;/a&gt;. &#34;One would think that there would be such a cartoonist, or several, in every major city, but there just aren&#39;t,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Coupled with an over-the-top clip-art style and incredibly distinct cartooning personality, Greg&#39;s strip is everything that his readers and editors can hope for.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peters’ distinctive style involved the use of stock clip art images, arranged and annotated with wry, extensive text to skewer public figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The clip art thing was always a punk staple,&#34; Mr. Peters told Jordan. &#34;Like the cut-out letters and clip art that Jamie Reid, the Sex Pistols designer, did using Queen Elizabeth with the safety clip through her cheek picture. They&#39;re very much out of the DIY ethos. And the attitude simply of baseline mistrust for authority, and the demand that you be shown, not told.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters is survived by his parents, Reg and Kay Peters of Lafayette; his partner, Eileen Loh; his former wife, Saundra Scarce; and his two sons, Wilder, 12, and Magnus, 10. Plans for a memorial service in the New Orleans area are pending.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leveesnotwar.org/in-memoriam-greg-peters-suspect-device-artist-and-blogger-father-friend/&#34;&gt;Levees Not War&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron money: economic isolation on the Upper Peninsula frontier</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-iron-money-upper-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are fragmentary notes - and a few links - regarding the introduction of &amp;quot;iron money&amp;quot; into the economy of Marquette County, Michigan, and the controversy surrounding it leading up to the 1876 Presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic of 1857.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic of 1873.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newspaper accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times was in 1876 a Republican newspaper, and did not have the reputation it maintains today as a &amp;quot;newspaper of record&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F60C12FE3E5B137B93CBA8178CD85F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden&amp;#39;s Iron Currency&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, July 19, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=FA081EFD395E137B93C1AB1783D85F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A Swindler of Labor&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, August 23, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F0061EFF3E5B137B93C1A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Sham Reformer&lt;/a&gt;. New York Times, October 3, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F70616FC3E5B137B93C6A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden and the Iron Money&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;Red Specular&amp;quot;, New York Times, October 4, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=FB0A15FC3E5B137B93C7A9178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Tilden Iron Money Question&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;Red Specular&amp;quot;, New York Times, October 5, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=F40812F7345B127B93CBA8178BD95F428784F9&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tilden&amp;#39;s Sharp Tricks&lt;/a&gt;, New York Times, October 19, 1876&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magazine articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questia.com/library/1G1-166849379/the-legacy-of-peter-white&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Legacy of Peter White&lt;/a&gt;, George Merk,&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Michigan History Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 83, No. 3.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;May-June 1999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.questia.com/library/1G1-163098143/iron-money&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Iron Money&lt;/a&gt;, William van Kosky, Michigan History Magazine v90 n2, March-April 2006
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=8mxTeVYKzMUC&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Honorable Peter White&lt;/a&gt;, Ralph Williams, 1907&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Fraud-Century-Rutherford-Samuel-Election/dp/0743255526&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Fraud of the Century: Rutherford B. Hayes, Samuel Tilden, and the Stolen Election of 1876&lt;/a&gt;, Roy Morris Jr., 2004&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GoXNi5gkTOgC&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Iron Will: Cleveland-Cliffs and the Mining of Iron Ore, 1847-2006&lt;/a&gt;, Reynolds and Dawson, 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://quod.lib.umich.edu/b/bhlead/umich-bhl-86396?rgn=main;view=text&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Peter White papers&lt;/a&gt;, Bentley Historical Library, Ann Arbor MI&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on a 30th high school reunion</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-some-notes-on-a-30th-high-school-reunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-some-notes-on-a-30th-high-school-reunion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0192aae7e719970d-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;TheB-52&amp;#39;sTheB-52&amp;#39;s&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0192aae7e719970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0192aae7e719970d-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;TheB-52&amp;#39;sTheB-52&amp;#39;s&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Some notes on a 30th high school reunion, written last summer but just now published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a certain ritual set of behavior you can safely engage in when you talk to someone who you vaguely remember from high school but have been completely out of touch with for 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask about where they are living now, and discovered that most of your classmates moved more than 200 miles away from home. Some stayed in Marquette, or came back after college, or moved to even smaller towns nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask about their family, and you will find that some of your classmates are grandparents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask about what they are doing. &amp;#0160;I was surprised to find some of my classmates having had 25 or even 30 years of continuous career in the same field or even with the same employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself mostly talking to people who I talked to in high school - as my friend Tim put it we found the &amp;quot;geek table&amp;quot; and occupied that. Some things never change, and all we would have needed was a Rubik&amp;#39;s Cube and we could pick up where we left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do change a lot in 30 years. A small handful of folks look remarkably like what they looked like 30 years ago, plus or minus an 80s hairdo. Others changed a lot, not always in a direction I would have expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a small shrine to the classmates who had died, and it was sad and surprising to see young faces and realize that you wouldn&amp;#39;t be seeing them again, not here and not anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it was one of those parties that reminded me of the very few high school parties I went to - lots of people standing around drinking beer, a few people dancing, and the DJ playing the B-52s. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to the next event some 5 or 10 years from now to see how we&amp;#39;re still all holding up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Alternative High School photo calendar for 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-17-marquette-alternative-high-school-photo-calendar-for-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://marquette.revtrak.net/img/products/Thumbnaillarge.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image from marquette.revtrak.net&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d3ee5d119970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d3ee5d119970c-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;image from marquette.revtrak.net&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Students and teachers from the photography class at Marquette Alternative High School (MAHS) create a calendar each year. The project showcases their work and funds a field trip for the students. This year&amp;#39;s 2013 calendar features pictures of Marquette, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.originalbutterflyhouse.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;butterfly house on Mackinac Island&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeYoung_Family_Zoo&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;DeYoung Family Zoo&lt;/a&gt; in Wallace. The cost is $20 and it&amp;#39;s available &lt;a href=&#34;http://marquette.revtrak.net/tek9.asp?pg=products&amp;amp;specific=jnkqnoo0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;for sale online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeds from the sale of the calendar go to photo equipment and to a photo field trip - the butterfly museum photos are from last year&amp;#39;s trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Cindy DePetro from MAHS about the calendar and the responses they&amp;#39;ve gotten from it. She writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to get praised over the quality of the photos, but our biggest praise is that most people feel like they receive a little piece of home when they see our calendars. We get many repeat customers, and our calendars travel all over the world. Thus far, we know they are being sent to Iraq, Afghanistan, Germany and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For 906 day, some photos of Marquette, MI from Shorpy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-06-for-906-day-some-photos-of-marquette-mi-from-shorpy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;906 day (September 6) celebrates the area code of the Upper Peninsula of Michigan. First I&amp;#39;ve heard of this holiday, but I heartily approve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of this day a couple of nice photos of Marquette, MI came via Shorpy. The photos of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12492&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;harbor and ore docks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12489&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Front Street&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shorpy.com/node/12493&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;panorama of downtown Marquette&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;date from 1908 and 1909 and are from glass negatives from the Detroit Publishing Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detail below shows the Hotel Janzen, with a train&amp;#39;s smoke just to the left of it and a piece of City Hall at the far left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 21&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448e124d970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 21&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Faye Amo (1954-2011), high school French teacher</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MARQUETTE – Faye M. Amo, age 57, of 425 West Ridge Street, Marquette,
entered eternal life Wednesday evening, July 13, 2011, at her home
in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula
Home Health and Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born March 23, 1954 in Lima, Ohio, a daughter of Stephen J. and
Ethel (Salidas) Catel, Faye was raised in Ishpeming and graduated
from the Ishpeming High School as salutatorian of her class. From
her days in grade school, Faye held the desire to become a teacher.
She enrolled at Northern Michigan University, where she received
her baccalaureate degree summa cum laude (with highest honor) with
a double major in French and English. She continued at Northern,
obtaining a double masters degree in English and French in 1977 and
later studied at the University of the Sorbonne in Paris where she
earned highest honors in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye’s
lifelong dream of becoming a teacher began with her first teaching
assignment at the Ishpeming High School in 1977. In 1979, she started
teaching French at the Marquette Senior High School, a career that
would span 31 years. Teaching French was her passion in life and
she loved all her students and they loved her. Affectionately known
as Madame Amo, she was the consummate professional teacher, one who
truly cared about her students and was dedicated to their education
and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not enough that the
students learned the French language, she felt they needed to
experience what “French” meant. Heading the French Club at Marquette
Senior High School, Faye planned numerous trips for club members
to big city museums to view French art exhibits, eat at French
eateries, and learn about French culture. Over the years, several
trips were taken to Chicago and to France in her mission to educate.
These memorable events were always anticipated by Faye and greeted
with enthusiasm by her students. For a number of years, she served
as class advisor, particularly enjoying building and decorating
floats for homecoming and decorating the gym for junior prom
activities. Throughout her life, Faye maintained an untiring interest
in the students at MSHS, often asking parents about their children,
even through the children may never have been her students and she
kept in regular contact with students who were now living adult
lives, with families of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition
to her affiliations at MSHS as foreign language department head for
several years, class advisor for the MSHS graduating class of 2008,
and serving on numerous parent-teacher committees, Faye was also a
member of the Greek Orthodox Church of the Assumption and the Ladies
Philoptochos Society, and active in civic committees such as the
American Association of University Women and the Marquette
Beautification Committee. In her leisure, Faye loved walking her
dog, Mario, for the 13 years of his life, bicycling, running – even
participating in marathons in Detroit and France, and riding in her
boat on beautiful Lake Superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye is
survived by her husband, John; her cherished son, Bret; two sisters,
Stephanie (Bob) Trumm and Jayme (Rick) Iknoiah both of California;
her mother-in-law, Leone Amo of Ironwood; brothers-in-law, Tom Amo
of Philadelphia, PA, Jim (Brooke) Amo of Livonia, and Ken Amo of
Ft Worth, TX; and several nieces and nephews. Faye was preceded in
death by her father, the honorable judge, Stephen J. Catel, her
mother, Ethel Catel; brother-in-law, Andrew Walton; and father-in-law,
John M. Amo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family will receive friends
at the Swanson-Lundquist Funeral Home on Sunday from 4:00 pm until
7:00 pm. Trisagion will be held at 6:00 pm. The Funeral Liturgy
will be held on Monday, July 18, at 11:00 am at the Greek Orthodox
Church of the Assumption with Rev. Tom Michalos officiating. Burial
will be made in the Park Cemetery. Pallbearers will be Jimmy Pedakis,
Lou Roumanis, Paul Andronis, Paul Wainio, Gary Shaffer, and Craig
Cox. Memorials may be directed to the Greek Orthodox Church of the
Assumption, 235 W. Ridge Street, Marquette, MI 49855 or to the Faye
Amo Scholarship Fund, Wells Fargo Bank, 101 W. Washington Street,
Marquette, MI 49855. Condolences may be expressed online at
www.swansonlundquistfuneralhome.com Adieu Madame Amo. Repose en
paix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My career in food service</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-my-career-in-food-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 14:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-my-career-in-food-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As published in the Association for Computing Machinery&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/risks/4.30.html#subj7&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Risks Digest, v4 n30, 1986&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;subj7.1&#34; name=&#34;subj7.1&#34; href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/risks/4.30.html#subj7.1&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/Images/Misc/flash.gif&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;14&#34; height=&#34;14&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fast-Food Computing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&amp;lt;Edward_Vielmetti@um.cc.umich.edu&amp;gt;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tue, 16 Dec 86 16:15:04 EST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;I must have been in the cycle early for McDonald&#39;s 
fast-food intelligent man-machine systems, according to 
Guthery&#39;s law:
   &amp;gt;     In an evolving man-machine system, the man will get
   &amp;gt;     dumber faster than the machine gets smarter.

McDonald&#39;s fast food computers (i.e., cash registers) 
collect all sorts of data on the individual employee at 
the counter and on all counter sales as a whole.  They also 
do not have a &amp;lt;no sale&amp;gt; key that opens up the cash
register, probably to prevent theft.  That made it real hard to fix a
mistake without calling a manager to get a key to open the drawer.

Solution?  Well, the people I worked with at McD&#39;s had been 
around thesystem long enough to figure out how to get around 
it.  Without getting into too many details of why things were 
as they were, the easiest way to open the drawer without a 
manager was to ring up a sale that gave away a 
tub of barbecue sauce for McNuggets and nothing else.  
   (Hit &amp;lt;promo&amp;gt; &amp;lt;barbecue&amp;gt; &amp;lt;promo&amp;gt; &amp;lt;total&amp;gt; .)
Of course, that messed up the daily statistics some.

Edward Vielmetti, Ex-McDonalds employee, Computing Center 
Microgroup, U. Mich.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutch baby apple pancake; and a March 2009 maple report from the UP</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-18-here-is-the-penzeys-apple-pancake-recipea-morph-from-the-dutch-baby----14-cup-butter--34-cup-all-purpose-flour--34-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-18-here-is-the-penzeys-apple-pancake-recipea-morph-from-the-dutch-baby----14-cup-butter--34-cup-all-purpose-flour--34-cup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the Penzey&amp;#39;s Apple Pancake recipe&amp;hellip;a morph from the Dutch Baby.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup butter&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;wbr /&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup all-purpose flour&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup milk &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp salt&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;2 medium baking apples, peeled and thinly sliced&amp;#0160; (I used Braeburn apples)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;3 Tbs sugar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp ceylon cinnamon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Preheat oven to 400.&amp;#0160; divide butter between two 9&amp;quot; pie plates and
put them in the oven to melt the butter.&amp;#0160; Rotate to be sure that butter
covers bottom and&amp;#0160; sides of pans.&amp;#0160; Use a 4 cup measuring cup as a
mixing bowl (makes it easy to divide the batter).&amp;#0160; Beat eggs, flour,
milk and salt on medium speed for 1 minute.&amp;#0160; Divide the apple slices
between the pans and pour &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the egg mixture over each pan.&amp;#0160; Mix
the cinnamin and sugar and sprinkle over the batter.&amp;#0160; Bake until puffed
and folden brown&amp;#0160; 20-25 minutes.&amp;#0160; Serve right away, while still puffy,
with warm syrup.&amp;#0160; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Serves 4-6&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Prep time 10 minutes, baking time&amp;#0160; 20-25 minutes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and the report from up north from March 18, 2009:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Over the weekend we put 28 taps in our maple sugar trees.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; We
collected 8 gallons the first day but the next two nights were not
below freezing.&amp;#0160; We have only 17 gallons so far.&amp;#0160; It was cold last
night so the sap should run today.&amp;#0160; Snowshoes are very necessary as the
&lt;span class=&#34;il&#34;&gt;snow&lt;/span&gt; is &amp;quot;punky&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160; Even with snowshoes we
sometimes break through the crust and one leg goes down 1 foot...makes
for slow going.&amp;#0160; Hopefully we have a good wide track packed now.&amp;#0160; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy Yuill (1932-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 12:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/508946.html?nav=5007&#34;&gt;as printed in the Marquette Mining Journal, April 22 2008&lt;/a&gt;.  Joy and Baldy were neighbors of ours in Marquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REPUBLIC — Joy Elizabeth Yuill, 75, of 11676 River Road, Republic, and former Marquette resident, entered eternal life Tuesday afternoon, April 15, 2008, at her home in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula Home Health &amp; Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Born September 11, 1932, in Gaylord, the daughter of Stanley and Dorothy (Siegel) Yuill, Joy was raised in Vanderbilt and graduated from the Gaylord High School in 1949. She attended Hillsdale College for a year before transferring to Grinnell College in Grinnell, Iowa, where she received a bachelor of science degree in education in 1953. Joy taught in Detroit, while also taking classes at Wayne State University, which led to her receiving her master’s degree in special education in 1956, with special emphasis on blind and partially sighted clients. In 1957, Joy moved to Marquette, traveling extensively throughout the Upper Peninsula to serve sight-impaired students. In 1971, Joy received a nursing degree from Northern Michigan University, working at Marquette General Hospital mostly on weekends. She retired from her nursing career in 2000. For over 17 years, Joy worked summers at Bay Cliff Health Camp in Big Bay as a special education teacher and swimming instructor. She retired from this position in 2005 and then assisted with adult campers for one week each year. 1972 was to produce yet another degree for Joy, this time a master’s degree in music from Wayne State. Joy continued teaching full time until 2002 and thereafter taught on a part-time basis for the next two years. When not in the classroom, Joy was the piano accompanist for the Marquette Male Chorus for many years. She also assisted many students with their solo and ensemble pieces at the Negaunee and Westwood high schools for over 20 years. Known locally for her beautiful renditions on the harp, Joy was a participant in many concerts and musical programs over the years. She was a member of the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming. In June 1963, Joy married Vincent “Baldy” Bur, and he preceded her in death in 1999. Joy and Baldy were great animal lovers and took in all sorts of stray and unwanted animals over the years. In her leisure, she enjoyed baking bread, knitting, sewing, gardening, and being involved in anything musical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Joy is survived by her brother, Robert “Beezle” Yuill of Harvey; a brother-in-law, Leonard Bur of Marquette; sister-in-law, Amelia Kent of North Little Rock, Ark.; her niece, Martha Yuill of St. Paul, Minn.; and a nephew, Stephen Yuill of Ishpeming. In addition to her parents and husband, Joy was preceded in death by sisters-in-law, Christine Yuill and Verna Bur; and a nephew, Michael Bur. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The family will receive relatives and friends at the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming on Saturday, May 10, beginning at 1 p.m. A memorial service will follow at 2 p.m. Saturday with the Rev. James Robb officiating. Memorials may be directed to the Marquette County Humane Society, 84 Snowfield Road, Negaunee, MI 49866; or to the United Presbyterian Church, 112 E. Euclid St., Ishpeming, MI 49849.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Fassbender Funeral Home is serving the family, where condolences may be expressed online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&#34;&gt;www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>