<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-city-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:21:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-city-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council to consider restricting public comment time</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/06/15/council-mulls-speaking-rule-changes/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;As reported in the Ann Arbor Chronicle:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A June 13, 2013 meeting of the Ann Arbor city council’s rules committee has resulted in proposed revisions to the council’s rules, many of which affect speaking turns and time – for members of the public and for councilmembers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An across-the-board proposed change for city council meeting public speaking times is a reduction from three minutes to two minutes for each turn. The two councilmember speaking turns per question are proposed to be reduced from five to three minutes, and from three to two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revisions will be considered by the full council at its June 17 meeting, as agenda item&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com/LegislationDetail.aspx?ID=1446404&amp;amp;GUID=55CB03CF-7941-4008-B527-110AD78F2BC2&amp;amp;Options=&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;13-0767&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Council-Rules-2013-draft-changes.pdf&#34;&gt;.pdf of marked up rules for June 17, 2013 council meeting&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two obvious reasons why this might come up on the council rules agenda. One the presence of an individual (&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Thomas_Partridge&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tom Partridge&lt;/a&gt;) who generally uses every single public comment time available to him to speak his piece; in a single meeting, Partridge might account for 20+ minutes of public comment time. A second reason is the very effective &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Citizens_filibuster&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;citizens filibuster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; that several organized opposition groups have used to talk Council into the wee hours of the morning during public hearings. A well-organized group can bring forty or fifty people to the dais, accounting for two hours plus of a public hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing public comment time from 3 minutes to 2 minutes will slow down the frequent commenter, and additional rules to restrict individuals from commenting at successive sessions will further cut into their time and leave room for others to speak. Capping citizens participation time to 2 minutes during public hearings is less likely to have an impact on total meeting times, however. A group that&amp;#39;s capable of corralling 45 citizens to speak out will just have to get 68 in front of the cameras to make the same point. Never underestimate the number of issues where the irate citizenry will work as hard as they can to make an impact on their elected decisionmakers.&lt;/p&gt;
Having a robust public process can be mighty inconvenient at times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One reason why you, as a politician, should keep your domain registration current even if you are not running</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 16:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The web site is &lt;a href=&#34;http://higginsforcouncil.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://higginsforcouncil.com&lt;/a&gt; . It was once a campaign website; it&amp;#39;s now an anti-campaign site, with the (anonymous) person hosting it heaping invective and scorn upon a local politician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re running for office and have a web site set up to support your campaign, use some of your campaign money to buy a domain registration that lasts a long time. You&amp;#39;ll avoid problems like this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain was &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20111107082804/http://higginsforcouncil.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;previously parked&lt;/a&gt; at GoDaddy (internet archive) and was offered then for a measly $12.00.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor turns down request for meeting minutes, again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 19:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor has dozens of citizen boards and commissions, with members appointed by the mayor, that conduct some of the decision making parts of city government. Most of these boards toil in utter obscurity, with no one in attendance at meetings other than the minimum required board members and staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite (or perhaps because of) this obscurity, there are some interesting things to be discovered by reading board minutes and board packets from these groups. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Local Development Finance Authority is the city body that allocates economic development funds from tax capture to development organizations, primarily Ann Arbor SPARK. As of the latest board packet, there is no treasurer to this organization, as none of the existing board members were willing to serve in that role. There is one open position on that board as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sign Board of Appeals meets only when citizens or businesses have an appeal to decisions made under the city&amp;#39;s Sign Ordinance. This body only has 4 members seated, with 3 vacancies. As a result, that board did not elect officers and did not approve the most recent minutes of a previous meeting. The Sign Ordinance is said to be up for review, according to the draft minutes that I looked at, but the Sign Board had not seen that draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zoning Board of Appeals meetings to hear appeals to the city&amp;#39;s zoning laws. Here was the most unusual result that I had from a series of Freedom of Information Act requests: the draft minutes of the last meeting, in December, were not available when I asked for them, and the city turned down a FOIA request for those minutes. Under the Michigan Open Meetings Act, draft minutes are to be made available within 8 days of a public meeting being held. I appealed that decision - and it&amp;#39;s appalling that I should have to go through the FOIA appeals process just to read meeting minutes - and was given the minutes the day after my appeal. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2011/12/07/zba-turns-down-city-place-appeal/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle civic news ticker&lt;/a&gt; has the results of that meeting, which was controversial and resulted in the rejection of neighborhood appeals to the City Place development decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it unusual for a public body to turn down requests for meeting minutes? It&amp;#39;s happened to me before, when I had to go through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/on-asking-for-something-you-know-doesnt-exist/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;a protacted series of requests to get minutes from the Historic District Commission.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;The first time you do this, it&amp;#39;s an exciting process of delving into the fine points of carefully worded language to appeal a city decision. The second time, it&amp;#39;s just tedious and frustrating to have to go all the way to the city administrator just to get minutes to read. I suppose I&amp;#39;ll keep earning my title of &amp;quot;municipal irritant&amp;quot; one way or another, even without attending the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>