<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-city-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:08:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-city-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>410 Miller still stands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-11-410-miller-still-stands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is 410 Miller still standing, after the Building Board of Appeals issued an order for it to be demolished? In part, because the Notice and Order to demolish was never sent. From FOIA 15-210:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.11.33 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.11.33 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0840ca24970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further it is stated that the hearing at which the decision to demolish was made was recorded, yet a transcription of the hearing was not made available on account of the audio being illegible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.25.40 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-11 at 7.25.40 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c79ca086970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my FOIA I neglected to ask for this transcription, not knowing that it might exist. I&#39;ve filed a subsequent FOIA to figure out more, and plan to be at today&#39;s Building Board of Appeals meeting to share these findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When is Ann Arbor going to have a full time building official?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 21:44:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor does not have a full time building official, and the routine operations of the building department are suffering as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at a Building Board of Appeals meeting today, 14 May 2015. The group just barely met quorum and had just three members seated, with one member absent and one vacant position. The regular staff member who handles the meetings is on medical leave, and the building official who had been present at previous meetings (Ralph Welton) has left the city&#39;s employment under circumstances which have not been fully and adequately explained. The city has hired a contractor to handle the building official&#39;s role, but that contractor is not working on the day of this meeting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group&#39;s meetings are in Legistar, which I looked at at 8:30 a.m. today before a 1:30 p.m. meeting. Legistar should have details and staff reports for all of the items on the agenda, but as of 8:30 a.m. there was only the barest detail listed, with five parcels under review but no detail for any of those parcels and no information about old business to be reviewed. Several members of the board noted that they did not get any email from the building department reminding them that there was going to be a meeting, let alone informing them of the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to the meeting at 1:30 p.m. I find that one of the items was removed from the agenda (that&#39;s pretty typical) and there was a bare minimum of documentation for the other four items. Bare minimum in this case included photos but no writeup of the staff recommendation and no detail at all. There were also two surprise agenda items under old business, neither of which had any written supporting documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the meeting itself there was a fair amount of confusion. One unfortunate petitioner who was asking for a variance for basement apartment filled out his form asking for this as a Housing Board of Appeals request, but then someone (the petitioner or the city, not sure who) whited out the word &#34;Housing&#34; and replaced it with &#34;Building&#34;. Some substantial amount of time was spent sorting out which appeals board actually would address the appeal, and the petitioner felt that it should be the Housing Board of Appeals that would address a variance for occupancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course that discovers another problem. The Housing Board of Appeals, as currently constituted, has three members; but seven are specified by charter, and thus it does not have a quorum and cannot meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of Kafkaesque city do we live in where matters are best referred to a body that cannot meet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke up at public commentary at the end of the meeting, there being no opportunity to speak at the beginning, pointing out some of this sad state of affairs and especially encouraging the board to prepare more carefully for meetings in such a way that members of the public would be able to avail themselves of information about the matters coming before the board. Certainly there is public interest in some of the long-term dilapidated buildings that have come before the board - in particular 410 Miller, which has been a mess as long as I can recall - but there being no adequate agenda publicized there is no way for the public to be even aware that a discussion is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When is Ann Arbor going to have a full time building official? Without someone in an official position to make the department work, the city&#39;s systems for handling exceptional cases appears to be entirely and completely broken. I can only imagine that routine issues are under a similar sort of chaotic pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ann Arbor Chronicle, September 2, 2008 - September 2, 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-08-09-the-ann-arbor-chronicle-september-2-2008-september-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 21:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-08-09-the-ann-arbor-chronicle-september-2-2008-september-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 6 year run of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; is coming to a close. The end date will be Septmeber 2, 2014, which happens to be an Ann Arbor City Council night as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chronicle was noted for its relentless and exhausting coverage of civic meetings. You could get the feeling that you too had sat on the hard benches for hours as you read through a 15,000 word account of what transpired. Hey, you could even read 6,000 words from time to time about meetings that never got a quorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll miss the Chronicle, which was one beacon of honest (if quirky) journalism in a town that hasn&#39;t always had a newspaper that I&#39;ve looked forward to reading. It will become just a little harder to keep up with municipal government, and more people in government will get a free pass because they don&#39;t have a critical eye focused on what they do. I completely understand that six years of two people&#39;s lives is a lot to give for the cause of local journalism, and I wish Dave and Mary the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Note: The annual Bezonki award festivities will still take place – on Friday, Aug. 15  – and you’re invited. The open house will run from 6-8 p.m. at Zingerman’s Events on Fourth in Kerrytown. There will be teeter-tottering and general merriment. Publisher Mary Morgan will follow up with a final word on Sept. 2, after the city council meeting ends. That will be our final report filed from the hard benches of city hall.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;fieldset class=&#34;zemanta-related&#34;&gt;&lt;legend class=&#34;zemanta-related-title&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/legend&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34; class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size:11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34; class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34;&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/11/the-onion-leaves-ann-arbor-three-months-after-it-arrived.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/64640189_80_80.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/11/the-onion-leaves-ann-arbor-three-months-after-it-arrived.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow:hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34;&gt;The Onion leaves Ann Arbor, three months after it arrived&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size:11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34; class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34;&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2014/08/the_ann_arbor_chronicle_to_cea.html&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/290737885_80_80.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2014/08/the_ann_arbor_chronicle_to_cea.html&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow:hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34;&gt;The Ann Arbor Chronicle to cease publication after six years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size:11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34; class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34;&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://www.crainsdetroit.com/article/20140810/NEWS/308109965/exhausted-owners-to-halt-aa-news-site&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/291001629_80_80.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://www.crainsdetroit.com/article/20140810/NEWS/308109965/exhausted-owners-to-halt-aa-news-site&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow:hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34;&gt;Exhausted owners to halt AA news site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/fieldset&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Paid for by * for mayor of Ann Arbor&#34; - an analysis of campaign advertising &amp; disclosure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 19:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-04-20-paid-for-by-for-mayor-of-ann-arbor-an-analysis-of-campaign-advertising-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After getting one too many political ads in my Facebook newsfeed, I started paying closer attention to the &#34;Paid for by&#34; language that I expect to see on every paid political campaign message. The mayoral candidates for the City of Ann Arbor all have some work to do to get their disclosures in order for the 2014 campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked for campaign disclosures on Facebook pages, on Twitter feeds, and on event pages created by the campaign on Facebook. I also looked generally at Google, searching for the phrase in question. The four candidates for the Democratic side of the Ann Arbor mayoral ballot are Stephen Kunselman, Sally Hart Petersen, Sabra Briere and Christopher Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Kunselman: while I can find a &#34;Kunselman for Council&#34; web site, I can&#39;t locate a &#34;Kunselman for Mayor&#34; web site. The candidate&#39;s Facebook page doesn&#39;t mention the candidacy that I can see. I haven&#39;t seen any ads from the candidate yet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sally Hart Petersen: No search results on Google for the mayoral campaign. A Facebook page for the candidate has 294 likes; in the header, it says &#34;Paid for by the Committee to Elect Sally Hart Petersen to Mayor&#34;, but that header omits the expected address of the committee. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sabra Briere: A search for &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for Mayor&#34; generates two pages. The http://sabrabriereformayor.org/ web page has &#34;Paid for by Sabra Briere for City Council&#34; at the bottom, in white type on a yellow background making it virtually unreadable; it also has bunches of Latin text where the real text should be, making me suspicious that it&#39;s not real. On Facebook, the page &#34;Vote for Sabra for Ann Arbor Mayor in the Democratic Primary on Tuesday August 5th 2014&#34; has invited 500 people, but has no &#34;Paid for by&#34; disclosure. I haven&#39;t seen any ads for the candidate yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Sabra Briere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clearly, sabrabriereformayor.org is a non-working website.  A completely different set of pages should be up soon - but in the meantime, I changed the accent yellow to an accent blue - so the white lettering is now higher contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It isn&#39;t at all ready to be published, and is just there as filler for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Taylor: A search for &#34;Paid for by Christopher Taylor for Mayor&#34; has 49 results, from the candidate&#39;s own web site and from &#34;ngpvanhost&#34;. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ngpvan.com/&#34;&gt;NGP VAN&lt;/a&gt; is a campaign website hosting platform for Democrats.) The &#34;Christopher Taylor for Ann Arbor&#34; Facebook page has 686 likes, with no &#34;Paid for by&#34; until you get to the &#34;Contribute&#34; page. Facebook ads for Taylor say &#34;Sponsored&#34;, but do not disclose who is paying for them in either the text of the ad or in the image associated with the ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE from Christopher Taylor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My understanding is that we included the proper disclosure language in the initial ad, but that for some reason it is not appearing. We&#39;re on it and will fix it pronto.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I appreciate the notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any of these clearcut campaign violations? Probably not. The relevant text of the law is &#34;Any other medium used for campaign purposes shall clearly and unequivocally include the identification or disclaimer, or both, provided in section 47 of the act.&#34; Michigan campaign finance law has not been updated to provide specific rules for Facebook (or Twitter), so you can&#39;t point to a specific line of text that says &#34;you did this wrong&#34;. Without specific guidance, there&#39;s wiggle room, and a wait for an opinion from the Attorney General.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this &#34;flyspecking&#34;, as one candidate described my efforts, or mere &#34;piffle&#34; as another political operative chided me? It&#39;s still early in the race, but expectations are that this will be one of the most expensive political races in Ann Arbor mayoral history, with four primary campaigns going and an empty mayoral seat at stake. I fully expect my Facebook timeline and Google search results to be full of paid advertising, and that that advertising will get more and more political as the primary draws near. Close attention to who is paying how much for what is worthwhile, especially in the presence of &#34;free media&#34; like Facebook where you can sent out an unrelenting stream of updates and invites at no obvious direct cost to anyone except the poor reader who just wants to see funny cat videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsubscribing from a bitter local politics list (before I get kicked off)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve unsubscribed from a local politics mailing list that I&#39;ve been on for a while. Out of an abundance of not wanting to name names, I&#39;m not naming names; chances are there&#39;s one of these in your community too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ground rules of this list are almost certainly that of typical politics lists. There&#39;s a list owner, who sets the rules. One of the rules is that the list is a private list, with no reporters on it and no one is supposed to share anything they get from the list to anyone who&#39;s not on the list. Occasionally someone transgresses and they get visibly kicked off the list. A number of small-time politicians are on the mailing list, and it&#39;s run by a former elected official.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure how I ever got on the list, but I stayed on it. I didn&#39;t feel like I could contribute anything to it, because if I was outed as a blogger I&#39;m sure I&#39;d be kicked off. And I couldn&#39;t copy anything from it to anyone else (even though I did from time to time). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small town politics can be very small and very bitter. The straw that broke the camel&#39;s back was whining that there wasn&#39;t enough parking near Farmer&#39;s Market downtown, since apparently walking 5 minutes to an enormous structure nearby wasn&#39;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not my clowns, not my circus. My inbox is full enough as is. If I need to read this particular list, I&#39;ll just FOIA the contents of the inboxes of the elected officials that subscribe to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(shakes dust off shoes)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About sidewalks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-22-about-sidewalks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To the Editor: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question has been asked your correspondent by several citizens: Can the city legally compel the owners or occupants of property in this city to construct, at their own expense, sidewalks in front of their premises? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city certainly claims ownership of the street from fence to fence, and exercises absolute control thereof. Even if a man desires to plant shade trees on the street in front of his property, the city prescribes the exact distance at which they shall be placed from the property owner&#39;s street line; and notwithstanding the fact that the property owner pays for the trees himself and also for the planting and subsequent care of them until their growth is assured, yet he is denied by the city any ownership in them, and is forbidden to remove or even to trim them, should he at any time desire to do so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these people wish to know, then, is, if the city owns the streets and their shade trees and side walks, why the city should not itself build the sidewalks, do all grading and plant all shade trees? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that when a man builds his sidewalk it immediately becomes city property, and he has no more ownership of it than any other citizen. In fact, in a single day hundreds will use it when he uses it once. In short, it is built not for him, but for the public. Then why should not the public pay for it? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building of sidewalks under the existing ordinance is a heavy burden upon very many citizens, some of whom have been compelled by their circumstances to borrow the money at interest to enable them to comply with the order of the council. This seems to your correspondent to be a matter worthy of deliberate consideration by the city fathers. The claim of these people is that the city, owning the streets, should itself put down all sidewalks, and spread the expense upon he general tax. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may do no good to open up this question at this time; but the voice of the people should at least be heard in the matter, and this communication certainly expresses it in some degree. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SUMMIT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/node/103463&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Argus, August 28, 1891&lt;/a&gt;, via the Old News archive at the Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 5, 2014: City of Ann Arbor response to snow non-emergency (11&#34;&#43; of snow)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-05-january-5-2014-city-of-ann-arbor-response-to-snow-non-emergency-11-of-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 23:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-01-05-january-5-2014-city-of-ann-arbor-response-to-snow-non-emergency-11-of-snow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From email sent by Ann Arbor City Council member &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Christopher_Taylor&#34;&gt;Christopher Taylor&lt;/a&gt; (D-3d Ward).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick update for you about the snow and the City’s response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 9:00 pm, we have had 11+ inches of snow. We have not declared a formal snow emergency and street parking is unrestricted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All City facilities will be open Monday and trash collection will run on its ordinary schedule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Road crews are out working 12 – 14 hour shifts. The day shift had 14 trucks assigned to Major roadways until noon, then dropped down to 12 trucks to accommodate schedule changes necessary to bolster the night shift.  Our night shift began at 6pm with a regular staff of 14 trucks assigned to Majors. The Major road staff will start using sand/salt mix around midnight. Additional staff will be assigned to work on locals during the night.  Local plowing will begin with Monday and Tuesday trash collection routes, and then continue throughout the City.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Snow Desk (994-SNOW) will be staffed 7am - 11pm thru Wednesday to answer resident questions and to report concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ever, let me know if you have any questions or concerns.  Stay warm and if you must travel, drive carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Taylor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council to consider restricting public comment time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/06/15/council-mulls-speaking-rule-changes/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;As reported in the Ann Arbor Chronicle:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A June 13, 2013 meeting of the Ann Arbor city council’s rules committee has resulted in proposed revisions to the council’s rules, many of which affect speaking turns and time – for members of the public and for councilmembers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An across-the-board proposed change for city council meeting public speaking times is a reduction from three minutes to two minutes for each turn. The two councilmember speaking turns per question are proposed to be reduced from five to three minutes, and from three to two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revisions will be considered by the full council at its June 17 meeting, as agenda item&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com/LegislationDetail.aspx?ID=1446404&amp;amp;GUID=55CB03CF-7941-4008-B527-110AD78F2BC2&amp;amp;Options=&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;13-0767&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Council-Rules-2013-draft-changes.pdf&#34;&gt;.pdf of marked up rules for June 17, 2013 council meeting&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two obvious reasons why this might come up on the council rules agenda. One the presence of an individual (&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Thomas_Partridge&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tom Partridge&lt;/a&gt;) who generally uses every single public comment time available to him to speak his piece; in a single meeting, Partridge might account for 20+ minutes of public comment time. A second reason is the very effective &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Citizens_filibuster&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;citizens filibuster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; that several organized opposition groups have used to talk Council into the wee hours of the morning during public hearings. A well-organized group can bring forty or fifty people to the dais, accounting for two hours plus of a public hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing public comment time from 3 minutes to 2 minutes will slow down the frequent commenter, and additional rules to restrict individuals from commenting at successive sessions will further cut into their time and leave room for others to speak. Capping citizens participation time to 2 minutes during public hearings is less likely to have an impact on total meeting times, however. A group that&amp;#39;s capable of corralling 45 citizens to speak out will just have to get 68 in front of the cameras to make the same point. Never underestimate the number of issues where the irate citizenry will work as hard as they can to make an impact on their elected decisionmakers.&lt;/p&gt;
Having a robust public process can be mighty inconvenient at times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One reason why you, as a politician, should keep your domain registration current even if you are not running</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 16:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The web site is &lt;a href=&#34;http://higginsforcouncil.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://higginsforcouncil.com&lt;/a&gt; . It was once a campaign website; it&amp;#39;s now an anti-campaign site, with the (anonymous) person hosting it heaping invective and scorn upon a local politician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re running for office and have a web site set up to support your campaign, use some of your campaign money to buy a domain registration that lasts a long time. You&amp;#39;ll avoid problems like this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain was &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20111107082804/http://higginsforcouncil.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;previously parked&lt;/a&gt; at GoDaddy (internet archive) and was offered then for a measly $12.00.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor turns down request for meeting minutes, again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 19:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor has dozens of citizen boards and commissions, with members appointed by the mayor, that conduct some of the decision making parts of city government. Most of these boards toil in utter obscurity, with no one in attendance at meetings other than the minimum required board members and staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite (or perhaps because of) this obscurity, there are some interesting things to be discovered by reading board minutes and board packets from these groups. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Local Development Finance Authority is the city body that allocates economic development funds from tax capture to development organizations, primarily Ann Arbor SPARK. As of the latest board packet, there is no treasurer to this organization, as none of the existing board members were willing to serve in that role. There is one open position on that board as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sign Board of Appeals meets only when citizens or businesses have an appeal to decisions made under the city&amp;#39;s Sign Ordinance. This body only has 4 members seated, with 3 vacancies. As a result, that board did not elect officers and did not approve the most recent minutes of a previous meeting. The Sign Ordinance is said to be up for review, according to the draft minutes that I looked at, but the Sign Board had not seen that draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zoning Board of Appeals meetings to hear appeals to the city&amp;#39;s zoning laws. Here was the most unusual result that I had from a series of Freedom of Information Act requests: the draft minutes of the last meeting, in December, were not available when I asked for them, and the city turned down a FOIA request for those minutes. Under the Michigan Open Meetings Act, draft minutes are to be made available within 8 days of a public meeting being held. I appealed that decision - and it&amp;#39;s appalling that I should have to go through the FOIA appeals process just to read meeting minutes - and was given the minutes the day after my appeal. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2011/12/07/zba-turns-down-city-place-appeal/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle civic news ticker&lt;/a&gt; has the results of that meeting, which was controversial and resulted in the rejection of neighborhood appeals to the City Place development decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it unusual for a public body to turn down requests for meeting minutes? It&amp;#39;s happened to me before, when I had to go through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/on-asking-for-something-you-know-doesnt-exist/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;a protacted series of requests to get minutes from the Historic District Commission.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;The first time you do this, it&amp;#39;s an exciting process of delving into the fine points of carefully worded language to appeal a city decision. The second time, it&amp;#39;s just tedious and frustrating to have to go all the way to the city administrator just to get minutes to read. I suppose I&amp;#39;ll keep earning my title of &amp;quot;municipal irritant&amp;quot; one way or another, even without attending the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>