<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ann-arbor-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 16:57:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ann-arbor-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Coworking notes at Elixir Vitae</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 16:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-coworking-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A productive afternoon with Mohan Kartha in which I opened a great
many tabs in Chrome. This bit of writing to close those out. Elixir
Vitae is a great spot for writing - lots of quiet noise from the coolers
to keep a background hum, and close to the bus station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sorting out the simplest task that I&amp;rsquo;d like to do with Node-RED,
now that I have a Raspberry Pi 2 running it under Docker in a configuration
that&amp;rsquo;s reliable enough that it seems like it&amp;rsquo;s stable. The easiest
network test in the world is the ping test, and so my first stab at
a try for &amp;ldquo;run always&amp;rdquo; is a simple configuration to notice when the
network looks like it&amp;rsquo;s down and when it is to collect some more
detailed information and log it to a file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for that is this simple configuration from an idea
by Nathan Chantrell, implemented by Martin Harizanov in 2014.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://harizanov.com/2014/03/presence-detection-using-phones-wifi-and-node-red/&#34;&gt;Presence detection using phone’s WiFi and Node-RED&lt;/a&gt; relies on static
IP address assignments from DHCP, plus &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo;, to notice if
someone&amp;rsquo;s device is in the building, turned on, and listening to
wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough phones drain their battery to know that absence
of a wifi signal is not an unambiguous marker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantelope is doing a beta product launch at the final AFC Ann Arbor minor
league soccer game of the year, Saturday, July 25 at 6 PM at Hollway
Field (Pioneer High School, 601 W. Stadium, Ann Arbor). See
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fantelope.com/afc-ann-arbor-fantelope-beta-launch/&#34;&gt;the Fantelope web site&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at writing code to send postcards from Lob.com is
working. The note to self is that if you have a square bracket in
a URL, that you have to turn off curl&amp;rsquo;s globbing function, e.g.
with -g or &amp;ndash;globoff. &amp;ldquo;When you set this option, you can specify
URLs that contain the letters {}[] without having them being
interpreted by curl itself. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every card has a tracking code, so the next bit of reporting to write
is to see which cards are awaiting printing, which ones are in transit,
where they are going to and whether they have been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AAATA moved the endpoint URL for its old-school &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo;
mobile RideTrak application. To go to a particular route like
the 5, see e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org/classic/rideguide_m.asp?route=5&lt;/a&gt; .
The main &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.theride.org&#34;&gt;http://mobile.theride.org&lt;/a&gt; has a newer interface, but
alas my Windows Phone 8.1 with its Internet Explorer browser
doesn&amp;rsquo;t do that page justice. (That, and I prefer the old interface
because I managed to figure it out for the stop I&amp;rsquo;m always catching
the bus from.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getlittlebird.com/&#34;&gt;Little Bird&lt;/a&gt; promises to
&amp;ldquo;help businesses unlock the valuable information in structured social data&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve asked for a trial to see what they have in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m wondering what the best approach is to the task of
&amp;ldquo;download all of my email from Gmail&amp;rdquo;, since the storage I
now have available on my laptop would make it straightforward
to have an 18 GB personal mail spool and because I really actually
would love to search through it so that I can mark some messages
for permanent deletion. One possibility is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enkive.org&#34;&gt;Enkive&lt;/a&gt;
from The Linux Box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am reminded that I want to carry around a set of headphones with me
that plug into my Nokia 635 so that I can use the phone as a radio,
and also reminded that I want to try to construct a headphone dipole
as an antenna for my NooElec DVB-T tuner. The challenge will be remembering
those desires at the right time so that when I see the parts I need
in the junk pile at home that I can grab what I need for my every
day carry bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I need to track down an 8 GB USB stick to load a boot ISO on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A design for an an Ann Arbor events channel, @a2events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a design for a low overhead way to post about events coming up in Ann Arbor. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2events&#34;&gt;@a2events on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you want to play along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule of business is that every event has to have a URL, and the more simple and direct the URL is the more likely it is that it&#39;s authoritative for the event. If an event doesn&#39;t have a URL yet, I&#39;ll blog about it here if I need to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second rule of business is that I&#39;m not keeping a calendar, just a feed, and the feed is not going to be a 100% comprehensive feed; you have to be prepared to get events info from multiple sources and I&#39;m just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third rule of business of course is that if you want to pay for this service we&#39;ll find a way to let you pay, though the specifics are TBD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic idea for technology is to use a tag on my Pinboard account to feed a specific tag, and to use that tag to feed IFTTT to feed Twitter so that events get pushed out. I&#39;ll probably also use a Node-RED page to help construct something that does the right thing, and there will be a Slack channel on the a2b3 slack to do - something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Brian Kerr for having the foresight to reserve the name a2events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>