<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:26:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vellum, a downtown Ann Arbor restaurant, has closed</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</guid>
      <description>Vellum closed in January 2015. The Ann Arbor News story tells the part of the story of an innovative kitchen that was &#34;like a laboratory&#34;, and a subsequent format change to a more mainstream menu. The restaurant had a two year run.
What&#39;s missing from the narrative is the prompt from the county health department that forced the change. Vellum&#39;s menu at the outset used the &#34;sous vide&#34; cooking technique to produce its most innovative dishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council highlights for 5 January 2015, a preview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:33:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council is meeting tonight, 5 January 2015, at 7:00 p.m. the Washtenaw County Administration Building. Here are some highlights from the agenda.
Three public hearings are on the docket. The public will get a chance to weigh in on a proposed amendment to the chicken-keeping ordinance and two hearings on downtown zoning.
The chicken-keeping ordinance (Section 107) would be amended to allow people to keep 6 chickens instead of the current 4, and to allow people to keep chickens without getting the mandatory consent of the neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken coops in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-chicken-coops-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 08:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-chicken-coops-i/</guid>
      <description>from UPI in their &#34;quirks&#34; section:  ANN ARBOR, Mich., Dec. 3 (UPI) -- Officials in Ann Arbor, Mich., are working on a plan to allow residents of the college town to set up their own chicken coops. City Councilman Stephen Kunselman told his colleagues during the weekend there is support among residents who like the idea of having access to &#34;farm fresh&#34; eggs, which some foodies consider to be tastier and healthier than the store-bought variety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood resources vs. cash resources</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had good experiences with sharing of surplus resources at a neighborhood level. The folks on my block regularly borrow ladders, save up canning jars, pick each others surplus tomatoes, take care of cats etc as needed. Sometimes token amounts of cash change hands - mostly to pay kids - but often not.
 I look at the kinds of businesses and business plans aimed at monetizing neighborliness with a bit of skepticism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>