<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:26:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ann-arbor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council highlights for 5 January 2015, a preview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:33:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Council is meeting tonight, 5 January 2015, at 7:00 p.m. the Washtenaw County Administration Building. Here are some highlights from the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three public hearings are on the docket. The public will get a chance to weigh in on a proposed amendment to the chicken-keeping ordinance and two hearings on downtown zoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chicken-keeping ordinance (Section 107) would be amended to allow people to keep 6 chickens instead of the current 4, and to allow people to keep chickens without getting the mandatory consent of the neighbors. Expect the neighborliness issue to be a substantial point of discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downtown zoning plans revolve around the changes proposed to what&#39;s now a parking lot next to the DTE building on S Main St. The parcel abuts a residential neighborhood and the neighbors don&#39;t particularly want a giant building to the west looming over their back yards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the consent agenda is approval of an emergency repair to the city&#39;s tower truck in the sum of $64,464.93 which is to repair damage from an accident on October 31, 2014. The fire department has brought its 18 year old previous tower unit back into service in reserve, according to the city administrator&#39;s notes accompanying the purchase order approval request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council will take up the issue of rezoning of a parcel at 3601 Plymouth Road to allow the construction of a Plum Market on the land most recently occupied by Cleary University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be an early night at council.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken coops in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-chicken-coops-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 08:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-chicken-coops-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
from UPI in their &#34;quirks&#34; section:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
ANN ARBOR, Mich., Dec. 3 (UPI) -- Officials in Ann Arbor, Mich., are working on a plan to allow residents of the college town to set up their own chicken coops.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;City Councilman Stephen Kunselman told his colleagues during the weekend there is support among residents who like the idea of having access to &#34;farm fresh&#34; eggs, which some foodies consider to be tastier and healthier than the store-bought variety.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To the reader: a challenge to update the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Chicken_coops&#34;&gt;chicken coops&lt;/a&gt; page on Arborwiki, noting the urban history of residential avian husbandry, and to document in particular the tipping point at which eggs from your back yard went from being a sign of prosperity to something else.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood resources vs. cash resources</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 21:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-neighborhood-re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve had good experiences with sharing of surplus resources at a neighborhood level.  The folks on my block regularly borrow ladders, save up canning jars, pick each others surplus tomatoes, take care of cats etc as needed.  Sometimes token amounts of cash change hands - mostly to pay kids - but often not.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I look at the kinds of businesses and business plans aimed at monetizing neighborliness with a bit of skepticism.  You need only look at vast empty wastelands like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neighborhoodlink.com/&#34;&gt;NeighborhoodLink&lt;/a&gt; to see how grim things can look if you only believe what the people with a vested interest (real estate agents) have in providing local information.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are multiple reasonable goals for neighborhood infrastructure.  One is to use the exchange of small tokens of low value but useful stuff as a way of maintaining sociability and making sure that things don&amp;rsquo;t go undone just because something is needed that is
&lt;br /&gt;readily available.  A second, perhaps just as valuable, is to identify systematically how you could cooperate to generate something of substantial value - be that good real estate values, some kind of business opportunity, or some other cash equivalent.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In many ways, cash is the enemy of community and sociability at this level.  Consider the set of people who would be happy to cook you a meal when you&amp;rsquo;re in need of help; the fact that they can deliver a hot meal for your family is worth way more than whatever the nominal cash equivalent of that meal is.  What dollar value do you place on having good neighbors?  Is that even the right measure?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Deciding where to live is a big part of living.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vellum, a downtown Ann Arbor restaurant, has closed</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vellum closed in January 2015. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2015/01/downtown_ann_arbors_vellum_to.html&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor News story&lt;/a&gt; tells the part of the story of an innovative kitchen that was &#34;like a laboratory&#34;, and a subsequent format change to a more mainstream menu. The restaurant had a two year run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s missing from the narrative is the prompt from the county health department that forced the change. Vellum&#39;s menu at the outset used the &#34;sous vide&#34; cooking technique to produce its most innovative dishes. County health officials took a dim view of this, as seen in this excerpt from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.healthinspection.info/establishments/1364&#34;&gt;health inspection in February 2014&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(Critical) Found a package of meat in a vacuum sealed package, and found beef short rib in a vacuum sealed package in the basement meat walk in cooler. These packages were the same size as the vacuum package supply in facility, and did not appear to be commercial products as there were no labels and pic could not provide any statements or boxes indicating from a commercial licensed source. Pic corrected by discarding meats in vacuum sealed packages. Found a piece of meat in a vacuum sealed package with &#34; 140 degrees 4 and half hours&#34; written on package in the walk in cooler. Pic states he does not know what marking mean and where this came from. Pic corrected by discarding meat. Found several pieces of sous vide equipment in the basement and main kitchen areas. Found at least 5 boxes of packages for vacuum packaging on the shelf in the basement prep area, and was denied access to room/closet next to shelf with vacuum packaging. To correct verify that no one in facility is using vacuum sealer or preparing food using sous vide method as a variance is required. This violation has repeated and a risk control plan is required to be submitted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your innovative kitchen depends on methods that are in violation of regulations, it&#39;s going to be hard to keep up the buzz when you have to give them up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>