<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vivienne Armentrout on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/vivienne-armentrout/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vivienne Armentrout on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:56:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/vivienne-armentrout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsubscribing from a bitter local politics list (before I get kicked off)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-unsubscribing-from-a-bitter-local-politics-list-before-i-get-kicked-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve unsubscribed from a local politics mailing list that I&#39;ve been on for a while. Out of an abundance of not wanting to name names, I&#39;m not naming names; chances are there&#39;s one of these in your community too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ground rules of this list are almost certainly that of typical politics lists. There&#39;s a list owner, who sets the rules. One of the rules is that the list is a private list, with no reporters on it and no one is supposed to share anything they get from the list to anyone who&#39;s not on the list. Occasionally someone transgresses and they get visibly kicked off the list. A number of small-time politicians are on the mailing list, and it&#39;s run by a former elected official.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure how I ever got on the list, but I stayed on it. I didn&#39;t feel like I could contribute anything to it, because if I was outed as a blogger I&#39;m sure I&#39;d be kicked off. And I couldn&#39;t copy anything from it to anyone else (even though I did from time to time). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small town politics can be very small and very bitter. The straw that broke the camel&#39;s back was whining that there wasn&#39;t enough parking near Farmer&#39;s Market downtown, since apparently walking 5 minutes to an enormous structure nearby wasn&#39;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not my clowns, not my circus. My inbox is full enough as is. If I need to read this particular list, I&#39;ll just FOIA the contents of the inboxes of the elected officials that subscribe to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(shakes dust off shoes)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>