<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave Newton on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dave-newton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dave Newton on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dave-newton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of
BBQ at Ricewood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting
an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately
cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command
line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately
sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and
manual file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I know doesn&amp;rsquo;t work is upload via Twitter, because the series of
resizings generate visible compression artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can upload from the phone to OneDrive, which gives me a photo of size
2592 × 1456 pixels (1.78:1, 16:9). The target size is 1875 x 1275
(1.47:1, 25:17), which is postcard format. I can keep all of the pixels
in the image by letterboxing it, or I can crop off the edges. What I
can&amp;rsquo;t really do is stretch the image to fit because it&amp;rsquo;s too far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking further at my camera software (Lumia Camera) it appears
that I can also take photos at 4:3. There&amp;rsquo;s more experimenting to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more documentation, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/06/efficient-image-resizing-with-imagemagick/&#34;&gt;Efficient Image Resizing With ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt;,
Dave Newton in Smashing Magazine, June 25, 2015. Dave goes through a
professionally thorough view of resizing and resampling images for the web,
comparing his results against Photoshop. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested 31 different settings for &lt;code&gt;-filter&lt;/code&gt; and got the best results
with &lt;code&gt;Triangle&lt;/code&gt;. The Triangle resampling filter is also known as
bilinear interpolation, which I discussed above. It determines pixel
color by looking at a support area of neighboring pixels and produces
a weighted average of their colors. I found it best to specify this
support area at two pixels using the &lt;code&gt;-define filter:support=2&lt;/code&gt;
setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave uses DSSIM from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pornel.net/dssim&#34;&gt;https://pornel.net/dssim&lt;/a&gt; to test his results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool computes (dis)similarity between two PNG images using
(my approximation of) algorithms approximating human vision.
Comparison is done in L*a&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; color space using a multi-scale variant
of the SSIM algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are sites that have automatic crop algorithms, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet found a package that&amp;rsquo;s usable without licensing. The interactive
web site of &lt;a href=&#34;http://croppola.com/&#34;&gt;Croppola&lt;/a&gt; is one useful example of
this genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pittsburgh&amp;rsquo;s smallest jazz club is installed in a bus stop on Liberty
Avenue, across from 9th Street.  The shelter was installed on July
6 and will remain until late August 2015. From the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://newpittsburghcourieronline.com/2015/07/09/the-worlds-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;New Pittsburgh Courier Online&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://awesomepgh.com/2015/01/15/award-36-pittsburghs-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;Awesome Pittsburgh&lt;/a&gt;’s trustees smiled unanimously when they decided
to choose the proposal for one of 2014’s $1000 grants, envisioning
a bus patron who pushes a button, only to have an iPod play jazz
music from one of MCG Jazz’s Grammy Award winning recordings. The
interior walls of a bus shelter will feature images of Pittsburgh’s
jazz legends, and a blank “Your Face Here!” space to take a picture
of yourself at “Pittsburgh’s Smallest Jazz Club.” Lamar Outdoor,
owner of the bus shelters in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, is
already on board to help make the project happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was done by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcgjazz.org/&#34;&gt;MCG Jazz&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Amy_MCGJazz&#34;&gt;Amy Kline&lt;/a&gt; is their marketing manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network issues at Malletts Creek branch were a good reason to exit back
towards town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>