<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anne Lamott on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/anne-lamott/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anne Lamott on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:06:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/anne-lamott/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Index Cards, Anne Lamott, from Bird By Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>I have an index card stuck in my copy of Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird By Bird. In that essay, she exhorts the reader to write down the ideas and thoughts and clever lines of dialog and whatever else they want to remember on a handy index card (carry one, folded, in your back pocket so you don&amp;rsquo;t look bulky). I just reread it out loud to myself, and now I kick myself for not having recorded myself to listen to it again (not for you all mind you, just for me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become an expert by collecting other experts in your field or other fields</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 23:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</guid>
      <description>How do you become an expert in a field? By writing about that field, repeatedly, until you have mastered it to the level which people find you easily and draw on your expertise.
A big part of being able to write about something twice a day is to have a ready collection of other people to call on for ideas or to ask for details or referrals. By being ready to tap into other people&amp;rsquo;s expertise, you figure out what you need to know fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One inch picture frame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 01:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m rereading Anne Lamott&#39;s bird by bird, and am inspired by the chapter on short assignments and on shitty first drafts to write some code.
Crontab: 00,20,40 * * * * getoutagemap
Getoutagemap: #!/bin/sh curl $map  $map.$now pdf2png $map.$now  $png.$now For where in $(ziplist) Do
Getpixel.$png.$now $(pixeldata $where) |
Pixdata2csv  outages.csv Done
Much better to have dte report the table of areas with power outages directly as a csv than to have to reconstruct it from pixel color values on a map, but we cope with the civic infrastructure we have, not the civic infrastructure we want.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>