<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anne Lamott on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/anne-lamott/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anne Lamott on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:06:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/anne-lamott/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Become an expert by collecting other experts in your field or other fields</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 23:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you become an expert in a field?  By writing about that
field, repeatedly, until you have mastered it to the level which
people find you easily and draw on your expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of being able to write about something twice a day is
to have a ready collection of other people to call on for ideas or
to ask for details or referrals.   By being ready to tap into other
people&amp;rsquo;s expertise, you figure out what you need to know fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/12/bird_by_bird_an.html&#34;&gt;Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird by Bird&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are an enormous number of people out there with invaluable
information to share with you, and all you have to do is pick up
the phone.  They love it when you do, just as you love it when
people ask if they can pick your brain about something you happen
to know a great deal about &amp;ndash; or, as in my case, have a number of
impassioned opinions on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/expert/&#34;&gt;blogger&amp;rsquo;s secret&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index Cards, Anne Lamott, from Bird By Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-03-index-cards-anne-lamott-from-bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe align=&#34;left&#34; frameborder=&#34;100&#34; marginheight=&#34;20&#34; marginwidth=&#34;20&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;asins=0385480016&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;lt1=_blank&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have an index card stuck in my copy of Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird By
Bird. In that essay, she exhorts the reader to write down
the ideas and thoughts and clever lines of dialog and whatever else
they want to remember on a handy index card (carry one, folded, in
your back pocket so you don&amp;rsquo;t look bulky). I just reread
it out loud to myself, and now I kick myself for not having recorded
myself to listen to it again (not for you all mind you, just for
me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bird By Bird is one of my favorite books about writing, and it turns out that it reads really well too - marvelous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t carry index cards with me all the time - for a while I did,
and now I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped, more or less. That should be fixable,
and the completely inexcusable case where I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a
pen with me is fixable too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital equivalents I have for them are either pages in my
personal wiki (again, not for you, just for me) or posts like this
one in whichever blog seems the most relevant. In
both cases the Socialtext and Typepad support for Blackberry devices
are key to having some reasonable web-based system that&amp;rsquo;s always
available especially when I&amp;#39;m on the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most fun I&amp;#39;ve seen with index cards as a system has to be
&lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hawkexpress/sets/72157594200490122/&#34;&gt;hawkexpress&amp;#39;s PoIC (&amp;quot;Pile of Index Cards&amp;quot;) system&lt;/a&gt;, which combines
ideas and methods and rigor in a way that to me is distinctly
Japanese.
&lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/aki_oda/sets/72157606070587225/&#34;&gt;
Aki&amp;#39;s PoIC system&lt;/a&gt; is new to me, and you can read more about
it at &lt;a href=&#34;http://next-action.net/&#34;&gt;next-action.net&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160;&lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jazzmasterson/sets/72157609130689807/&#34;&gt;
jazzmasterson&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;notes to self&amp;quot; capture some of the
same ideas.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One inch picture frame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 01:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-07-one-inch-pictur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m rereading Anne Lamott&#39;s bird by bird, and am inspired by the chapter on short assignments and on shitty first drafts to write some code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crontab: 00,20,40 * * * * getoutagemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getoutagemap: #!/bin/sh curl  $map &gt; $map.$now pdf2png $map.$now &gt; $png.$now &lt;br /&gt;
For where in $(ziplist) &lt;br /&gt;
Do&lt;br /&gt;
    Getpixel.$png.$now $(pixeldata $where) |&lt;br /&gt;
    Pixdata2csv &gt;&gt; outages.csv Done&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much better to have dte report the table of areas with power outages directly as a csv than to have to reconstruct it from pixel color values on a map, but we cope with the civic infrastructure we have, not the civic infrastructure we want. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m guessing on the ability to render a pdf to a png from the command line, and the existence of a tool to extract the value of a pixel at a certain place from a png.  Everything else is a table look up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output goal looks like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 April 08 12:11am,48104,1500&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$now,$zip,$subscribers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitable for excel and then powerpoint and people with suits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed. &lt;br /&gt;
Sent wirelessly via BlackBerry from T-Mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>