<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 05:12:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 May 4 Ann Arbor City Council preview, in map form.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-04-2015-may-4-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-in-map-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 05:12:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-04-2015-may-4-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-in-map-form/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks in large part to the hard work of Dave Askins of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.civcity.org/&#34;&gt;Civ City&lt;/a&gt;, here&#39;s a preview map snapshot of the agenda for Ann Arbor City Council for May 4, 2015. Click through for detail which will take you to Arborwiki&#39;s accounts for each of those items tagged with the tag &#34;20150504ccmtg&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/tags/20150504ccmtg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c78461c9970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 400px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-05-04 at 5.08.00 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-05-04 at 5.08.00 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c78461c9970b-400wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This map reflects these agenda items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;590 W. Ellsworth Road&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;African American Downtown Festival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allmendinger Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Book Festival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Jaycees Fourth of July Parade: Routes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrowwood Hills Cooperative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barton Sidewalk Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinetopia: Maynard Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firecracker 5K&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire Station 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flagstar Bank: 3600 Plymouth Road&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-On Museum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunt Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scio Church Sidewalk Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traver Street Storm Sewer Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing City Council, it&#39;s likely that one or more issues will emerge at the last possible moment, but this at least gives you a shot at figuring out what council actions are happening in your back yard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments as presented to the Ann Arbor City Council: municipal maps, public records, closed captioning and the city web site.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-comments-as-presented-to-the-ann-arbor-city-council-municipal-maps-public-records-closed-captioning-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 23:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-comments-as-presented-to-the-ann-arbor-city-council-municipal-maps-public-records-closed-captioning-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0622c18970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0622c18970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;2014-09-02 22.49.49&#34; title=&#34;2014-09-02 22.49.49&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0622c18970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments as presented to the Ann Arbor City Council for the September 2, 2014 meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four very brief topics: municipal maps, public records, closed captioning and the city web site. These are my intended comments at the end of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding municipal maps, I would point out that any of the maps generated by the city in your packet have a very strict copyright on them prohibiting redistribution without the express written consent of the city. This is but one of several easily addressable flaws in the city mapping project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding public records, the current system of Legistar for publication of attachments to the agenda is very difficult in that it is impossible to search through the full text of attached items. Some municipal data activists in other cities have taken to wholesale downloading of the entire site to get around the problems with access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding closed captioning, it is my understanding that the Disability Commission is going to have closed captioning of its meetings, and I urge you to direct the city administrator to direct CTN to provide closed captioning of City Council meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally regarding the city web site. It is more of a thing of beauty than the previous version, but in the process several hundreds of pages have gone missing, either by renaming of previous URLs or removal of content, and I urge you to take action to remedy these failings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The City of Ann Arbor copyright on its maps is unreasonable</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-the-city-of-ann-arbor-copyright-on-its-maps-is-unreasonable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 20:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-02-the-city-of-ann-arbor-copyright-on-its-maps-is-unreasonable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This detail is from a document provided in the board packet for a recent
public meeting. According to the terms of the copyright, it&#39;s not legal for
me to post this excerpt (except under fair use claims).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e0e1749970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e0e1749970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-02 at 8.21.42 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-02 at 8.21.42 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73e0e1749970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City of Ann Arbor Map Disclaimer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No part of this product shall be reproduced or transmitted in any
form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, for any purpose,
without prior written permission from the City of Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This map complies with National Map Accuracy Standards for
mapping at 1 Inch = 100 Feet. The City of Ann Arbor and its
mapping contractors assume no legal representation for the content
and/or inappropriate use of information on this map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Map Created: 5/16/2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;h/t on Ann Arbor map nuttiness to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt;, a resident there who would like his city to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Derek Willis (@derekwillis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/derekwillis/status/506959365073825792&#34;&gt;September 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; tells city they need to make sure information they distribute has copyright notices appropriate for archiving. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/a2council?src=hash&#34;&gt;#a2council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Julie Weatherbee (@juliewbee) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/juliewbee/status/506954833845567488&#34;&gt;September 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Pedestrian Safety and Access Task Force meeting schedule, 2014-2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-25-ann-arbor-pedestrian-safety-and-access-task-force-meeting-schedule-2014-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-25-ann-arbor-pedestrian-safety-and-access-task-force-meeting-schedule-2014-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the Pedestrian Safety and Access Task Force meeting schedule for 2014-2015. It&#39;s presented here exactly as the notice is up at Ann Arbor City Hall. The public is invited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fd397919970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fd397919970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Ped Safety Task Force_Meeting Notice_complete schedule&#34; title=&#34;Ped Safety Task Force_Meeting Notice_complete schedule&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fd397919970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Council preview and Legistar search tutorial on Damn Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-13-city-council-preview-and-legistar-search-tutorial-on-damn-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 13:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-13-city-council-preview-and-legistar-search-tutorial-on-damn-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get on over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com&#34;&gt;Damn Arbor&lt;/a&gt; for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2013/12/ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for.html&#34;&gt;preview&lt;/a&gt; of the Monday 16 December 2013 City Council meeting and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2013/12/foia-friday-using-legistar-to-keep.html&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on how to search Legistar for council actions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hieftje Veto Preserves Crosswalk Law</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-03-hieftje-veto-preserves-crosswalk-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 01:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-03-hieftje-veto-preserves-crosswalk-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR - Mayor John Hieftje promised Monday night to exercise his mayoral veto powers to squash City Council&#39;s amendments to the city crosswalk law, which passed 6-4. The veto will mean that the crosswalk law will be unchanged. 36 people spoke up at a public hearing in favor of the law as written, with only 3 speaking in favor of a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details Tuesday as stories come in from local media outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every lame duck has his day.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Twenty Pound Carp (@TwentyPoundCarp) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TwentyPoundCarp/statuses/407722759784247296&#34;&gt;December 3, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor News: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2013/12/ann_arbor_mayor_using_veto_pow.html&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor mayor using veto power to block crosswalk law changes&lt;/a&gt;. Don&#39;t read the comments, which are the usual anonymous MLive drivel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle: &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/12/03/a2-crosswalk-repeal-to-be-vetoed/&#34;&gt;A2 Crosswalk Repeal: To Be Vetoed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WEMU News: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wemu.org/post/ann-arbor-mayor-veto-changes-crosswalk-law&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Mayor to Veto Changes to Crosswalk Law&lt;/a&gt;. &#34;City Council member Stephen Kunselman says the veto means the poorly crafted and implemented law remains in place. However, nearly 40 people spoke in favor of keeping the law during a public hearing.&#34; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Preview for December 2, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-29-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-december-2-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 18:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-29-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-december-2-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A preview of the Ann Arbor City Council meeting for Monday, December 2, 2013; based on the agenda printed on Friday, November 29, 2013 at 6:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hot issue for December 2, 2013 is the proposed repeal of the Ann Arbor pedestrian ordinance. If passed, city rules for pedestrians would revert to the Michigan state laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another preview, with a lot more words, is at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/12/01/dec-2-2013-ann-arbor-city-council-preview/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INT-1. We have new firefighters, let&#39;s meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INT-2. A review of Fiscal Year 2013 audit results from CFO Tom Crawford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INT-3. Philip Deletka is volunteer of the month for work on the CERT program. (Added late.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public commentary reserved time! 10 speakers at 3 minutes each. Speakers: Tom Partridge, Henry Herskovitz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC-1. Here&#39;s who&#39;s on various council committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briere to Planning Commission. (added late)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor to Greenbelt Advisory Commission.  (added late)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briere and Anglin to the Environmental Commission.  (added late)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council rep TBD to Disabilities Commission.  (added late)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone to LDFA (added late, not reflected in electronic agenda).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CC-2. Council rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MC-1. Mayoral appointments and confirmations. Nothing controversial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PH-2. An industrial development district at 1901 E Ellsworth, which would suit the needs of http://www.genze.com/ (Mahindra Genze), an electric scooter company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PH-3. Running Fit wants to build upwards at 121-123 E Liberty and at 220 S Fourth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PH-1. Repeal of the pedestrian ordinance, a public hearing. Expect a lot of speakers. Reorganized on the agenda to go third, not first. (39 speakers, 36 against)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A-1. Approve last month&#39;s minutes for council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CA-1. Approve a $58,000 annual maintenance license for ESRI GIS software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B-1. Repeal of the pedestrian ordinance, second reading. There are 5 sponsors for the ordinance, and it&#39;s expected to be repealed; but there may be last-minute negotiations that lead to some kind of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C-1. Traverwood Apartments rezoning, first reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-1. Council calendar for 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-2. Policy for removal of street parking spaces; it&#39;s proposed that a street parking space be valued at $45,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DB-1. Running Fit wants to build upwards at 121-123 E Liberty and at 220 S Fourth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DB-2. Donation of 2.2 acres from Bill Martin adjacent to the Traverwood Apartments proposed development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-1, DS-2. Asbestos abatement in floors 3, 4, and 5 of City Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-3. An industrial development district at 1901 E Ellsworth, see PH-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-4. City-University parking ticket processing contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-5. &#34;Resolution to Approve a Six Month Extension of the Existing Installment Purchase Agreement with Bank of Ann Arbor to Finance the Purchase of 350 S. Fifth Avenue ($3,500,000.00) (8 Votes Required) (Roll Call Vote Required)&#34;  This is a surprise. &#34;Whereas, it is in the best interest of the City to extend the maturity date of the Agreement by six months.&#34;  The Bank of Ann Arbor is extending the same terms and interest rate as currently held, with no prepayment penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meeting preview for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-13-ann-arbor-city-council-meeting-preview-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 21:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-13-ann-arbor-city-council-meeting-preview-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com/MeetingDetail.aspx?ID=222614&amp;amp;GUID=3890EFBC-18C0-4B89-A44B-B72A3143DAD5&amp;amp;Options=info|&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;meeting agenda&lt;/a&gt; for Ann Arbor City Council is up for the Monday, 18 November 2013 meeting. That means it&#39;s time to do a preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual this is done strictly in the order of the agenda, with item numbers. For a longer and more thematic look, I recommend the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/11/13/nov-18-2013-ann-arbor-city-council-preview/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle preview&lt;/a&gt;. For a preview of the pedestrian safety ordinance discussion, see this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2013/11/repeal_of_ann_arbors_controver.html&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor News story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: as of 4:40 p.m. it&#39;s not on the agenda, but Ann Arbor News reporter Ryan Stanton suggests on twitter that the disposition of the Old Y Lot may make it onto the agenda tonight, with council asked to accept the Dahlmann bid. 5:05 p.m. Now on the PDF agenda as &#34;DC-4 13-1467 Resolution to Approve Sale of City-Owned Property at 350 S. Fifth to Dennis A. Dahlmann (8 Votes Required)&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Word is that Dennis Dahlmann has accepted all of the city&amp;#39;s terms and Y Lot sales agreement could be voted on tonight &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23a2council&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#a2council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ryan Stanton (@ryanjstanton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ryanjstanton/statuses/402543766415757312&#34;&gt;November 18, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the first meeting for new City Council member Jack Eaton, who defeated Twenty Pound Carp in the general election in November 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council will appoint a Mayor Pro Tem, to serve as acting Mayor when there is no mayor available. Traditionally this has gone to the most senior member of council by tenure, and I think that might be Margie Teall; the Chronicle hints that Jane Lumm might have the nod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MC-1 Mayoral appointments look uncontroversial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PH-1, B-1 &#34;Pizza in the park&#34;, a waiver of fees for parks activities that provide basic human services, looks like it&#39;s likely to pass based on last week&#39;s discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PH-2, B-2 &#34;DDA Revisions&#34; is probably going to take a long time, as various members of council try to make political points regarding the relative balance of services between the downtown and the neighborhoods. Make popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CA-1 &#34;The Puck Drops Here&#34; is a 31 December 2013 event (details?) to be held just before the 1 January 2014 Winter Classic NHL hockey game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CA-2 &#34;Hockey is just like football&#34; as far as parking restrictions and street closings goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CA-3 Dawn Farm has agreed to acquire 618 N. Main from Avalon Housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-1 &#34;Ypsi Township on AAATA board&#34; Council gets to decide whether Ypsilanti Township has a seat on the AAATA transit authority board. It was a matter of controversy when it came up the first time; keep up with the popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-4 &#34;Dahlmann proposal for Old Y Lot&#34; This showed up on the agenda at the last possible moment, to the point where it&#39;s not clear that members of council will get a chance to read it before voting on it; certainly no one had a chance to put their name in for public commentary on this item. I&#39;m hopeful that this resolution will be postponed until next time for a vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-2, DS-3, DS-4 Easement swaps with the University of Michigan for a new conduit through the Arboretum, and a new survey to settle a disputed boundary between the city and the university. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G-1. The Greenbelt Advisory Commission has minutes to approve from 2011 (!!!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G-2. The Public Art Commission has minutes to approve from January and Feburary 2012 (!!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G-6, G-7, G-8, G-9 The Taxicab board has been very slow to produce minutes; these date back to January 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not on the agenda yet is a possible purchase agreement for the &#34;Old Y Lot&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council preview for Thursday 7 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-01-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-thursday-7-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 22:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-01-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-thursday-7-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because of the election on Tuesday 5 November 2013, the Ann Arbor City Council will be meeting on Thursday 7 November 2013. Here&#39;s a preview of sorts of the agenda. Note that the agenda is subject to change up until the very last minute, though in general it stabilizes well before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/11/04/nov-7-2013-ann-arbor-city-council-preview/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle preview&lt;/a&gt; is well worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda, in order, noting only interesting items. Your idea of what is interesting may differ. This posting may be updated from time to time as more details emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MC-1, Mayoral appointments. Nothing obviously controversial here. &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Cyndi_Clark&#34;&gt;Cyndi Clark&lt;/a&gt; is proposed to fill a vacancy on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Ann_Arbor_DDA&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor DDA&lt;/a&gt; board; she&#39;s the owner of &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Lily_Grace&#34;&gt;Lily Grace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B-1. DDA Ordinance. Four items of substance in the proposed revision (as of v3): 1) Remove the mayor from the DDA board as of the end of the current mayor&#39;s term, and replace with the city administrator. 2) Recalculate TIF funding mechanism and the return of surplus funds to taxing entities.  3) &#34;Requires a nexus between development programs and specifically benefited properties within the downtown development district.&#34; 4) Requires TIF report in January, and requires DDA programs to be part of the city&#39;s Capital Improvement Project (CIP) process. Expect this to take a long time to sort out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C-1. &#34;Pizza in the Park&#34;. Changes the Parks ordinance to omit fees for events &#34;where the permitted event&#39;s primary proposed activity is the charitable distribution of goods for basic human needs.&#34; Permits are still required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-1. &#34;Stadium Billboard&#34;. Directs the city administrator to complain to the University of Michigan about the new digital billboard on E Stadium Blvd near Michigan Stadium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC-3. &#34;Ethics&#34;. Directs the city administrator and city attorney to educate city council on professional conduct, and directs the Council Rules Committee to draft standards of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DS-10. Design the Scio Church Road sidewalk, $35,000 from general fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write in candidate: Twenty Pound Carp, Ward 4, Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-29-write-in-candidate-twenty-pound-carp-ward-4-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 06:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-29-write-in-candidate-twenty-pound-carp-ward-4-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/twentypoundcarp&#34;&gt;Twenty Pound Carp&lt;/a&gt; is mounting a quixotic write-in campaign for Ann Arbor City Council in Ward 4, as evidenced by this campaign sign. It faces Democratic candidate &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Jack_Eaton&#34;&gt;Jack Eaton&lt;/a&gt; in the November 5, 2013 general election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even now political operative are fanning out across the 4th Ward and planting signs--signs of political change, yo. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/qaC3Gxlnbw&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/qaC3Gxlnbw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Twenty Pound Carp (@TwentyPoundCarp) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TwentyPoundCarp/statuses/394915371532034048&#34;&gt;October 28, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The back story on this is hard to describe, but suffice it to say that when a bottom feeder takes interest in a political campaign, all bets are off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA: inspection reports for downtown Ann Arbor street lights</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 12:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As sent to the Ann Arbor City Clerk, 23 October 2013:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the clerk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City Council meeting of this week Tuesday (ed.: actually late Monday) had an extended
discussion of street lighting in the downtown area, and council
weighed the problems with rust on street lamps and decided not to
spend money to replace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To follow up on this discussion, and motivated by the uncertainty at
council about the state of the lighting, I&#39;d like to make this
request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please provide the following records:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most recent inspection and safety reports for the eighty one
(81) street lighting poles referenced in City Council item 13-1062
that were proposed to be replaced, referencing the following Whereas
clause:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;Whereas: The Street Lights along Main Street between Huron and
  William are rusting at the base posing a safety issue and are in need
  of replacement; &#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this request is in the public interest, and since the records
have been freshly examined for staff preparation for council, I expect
that the records will be readily available at no charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not know if the records are in electronic form. If they are in
paper form, and if duplication of records would be necessary to
fulfill this request, please inform me before proceeding so that I can
weigh the costs. If possible, if the records are in paper form I would
like to examine them in person to avoid unnecessary costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your prompt response to this request.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council preview for the meeting of Monday, 21 October 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-20-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-the-meeting-of-monday-21-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 23:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-20-ann-arbor-city-council-preview-for-the-meeting-of-monday-21-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some stories that I&#39;m watching about what&#39;s on the Ann Arbor City Council agenda for 21 October 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b002da4b8970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b002da4b8970d&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;A2council-pun-plamondon-1973-a2snooze-cropped&#34; title=&#34;A2council-pun-plamondon-1973-a2snooze-cropped&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b002da4b8970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/10/20/oct-21-2013-ann-arbor-council-preview/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle preview&lt;/a&gt; is a useful guide to the details, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a2gov.legistar.com/MeetingDetail.aspx?ID=222612&amp;amp;GUID=EBFC5C3E-0504-4B72-95C6-12815612D619&amp;amp;Options=info|&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;meeting details from Legistar&lt;/a&gt; give you the play-by-play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consent agenda includes a $26,900.00 project from Keystone Media of Ann Arbor to redesign the city web site. Keystone won the RFP, beating out Flight Plan Creative of Traverse City ($24,650) and B+B Marketing Communications of Midland ($40,000). It is to be noted that the award did not go to the low bidder, as the qualifications for the RFP spelled out that price was not the only consideration for the bid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ypsilanti Township is seeking to join The Ride (The Ann Arbor Area Transportation Authority, or AAATA). Vivienne Armentrout has posted an &lt;a href=&#34;http://localinannarbor.com/2013/10/19/once-again-aaata-exceeds-its-reach/&#34;&gt;article critical of the expansion&lt;/a&gt; which drew a stern rebuke from Larry Krieg of Ypsi Township:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In an era when we can’t afford either to isolate our communities or to link them solely by private automobiles, the clear path to prosperity in Michigan is through regional cooperation and investing together in alternative forms of transportation. We can’t afford &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to make this investment now. Those who think it’s foolish to diversify our transportation options are neglecting the huge expense of our current dependence on automobiles and petroleum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m all for improved service to Ypsilanti Township, but that&#39;s at least a little selfish. If service to that part of the area improves, it will be in part due to improvements in service on AAATA Route 5, which goes right by my house. If I lived on the west side of Ann Arbor, I&#39;d be agitating for Scio Township to buy in to transit improvements, because that would likely add to the quality of service of west-side bus routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s not on the agenda is perhaps as important as what&#39;s on the agenda. This week&#39;s agenda as printed Sunday night does not have any talk of a repeal of the city crosswalk ordinance. That&#39;s been getting a lot of press, including this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2013/10/stay-vigilant-for-coming-attacks-on.html&#34;&gt;piece in Damn Arbor&lt;/a&gt; suggesting additional signage to improve motorist recognition of local ordinances. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2013/10/efforts_underway_to_repeal_ann_arbors_crosswalk_ordinance.html&#34;&gt;dot News story&lt;/a&gt; suggests that a motion to repeal the ordinance might be on the council&#39;s November agenda, perhaps after the elections when there&#39;s new faces on the council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.org/ctn&#34;&gt;CTN&lt;/a&gt; is your source for online city council video, and the #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23a2council&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt; hash tag on Twitter can help you follow along with the play by play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council considers, and declines to study, biweekly trash pickup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-07-ann-arbor-city-council-considers-and-declines-to-study-biweekly-trash-pickup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 23:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-07-ann-arbor-city-council-considers-and-declines-to-study-biweekly-trash-pickup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor City Council decided not to study biweekly trash pickup as a part of its new solid waste plan at its meeting of 7 October 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council discussed the situation in Portland, Oregon. &lt;a href=&#34;http://consumerist.com/2013/05/20/when-you-cut-trash-collection-to-every-two-weeks-parents-will-still-find-a-way-to-get-rid-of-dirty-diapers/&#34;&gt;Consumerist&lt;/a&gt; notes that parents there are recycling their dirty poopy diapers. (ew.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It started when the city went to every other week garbage pickup,” the president of Far West Fibers, which handles much of the curbside recycling for Portland, tells Oregon Public Broadcasting. “Prior to that you’d get a dirty diaper maybe once a month. Now we get 60 pounds per shift. It’s not pretty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ew.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meeting for October 7, 2013: agenda preview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-06-ann-arbor-city-council-meeting-for-october-6-2013-agenda-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 17:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-06-ann-arbor-city-council-meeting-for-october-6-2013-agenda-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s on the agenda for the 7 October 2013 Ann Arbor City Council meeting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Pun Plamondon Addresses Ann Arbor City Council, Ann Arbor News, 1973)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affd06c4a970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affd06c4a970c&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;N011_1336_006-1&#34; title=&#34;N011_1336_006-1&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019affd06c4a970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Sabra Briere, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sabrabriere.org/First%20October%202013.php&#34;&gt;First Ward News&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By my count, this agenda includes 2 action items – 14 administrative acts, 8 infrastructure changes, 1 that address public safety needs, 0 investments in economic development and 0 that relate to affordable housing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Ann Arbor Chronicle, &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/10/04/ann-arbor-council-to-weigh-privilege-waiver/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Council to Weigh Privilege Waiver&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A resolution that’s been added to the Ann Arbor city council’s Monday, Oct. 7, 2013 agenda would, if approved, result in the waiver of attorney-client privilege with respect to a specific advice memo that has already been written by the city attorney’s office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is about Al McWilliams, who was appointed by the Ann Arbor City Council on a 6-5 vote to join the Ann Arbor DDA; there is consideration that the vote requirement might have been 8 votes. There was talk that the minutes for the previous meeting might be contested as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, from the Chronicle: &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/10/03/sidewalks-repair-build-shovel/&#34;&gt;Sidewalks: Repair, Build, Shovel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;City council&#39;s Oct. 7 agenda includes consideration of cross-lot walkways again, with a non-shoveling approach; also: sidewalks connect to projects for stormwater management and public art&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a full preview from the Chronicle: &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/10/06/oct-7-2013-ann-arbor-council-preview/&#34;&gt;October 7 2013 Ann Arbor Council Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Agenda items include attorney-client privilege waiver related to appointment of Al McWilliams, approval of solid waste plan, cross-lot walkways, liquor license fees, Rockefeller Foundation grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, from the Ann Arbor News - well, there&#39;s nothing yet from the Ann Arbor News telling you there would be a meeting on Monday, or what it would be. Look for something coming from the snooze&#39;s government reporter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://connect.mlive.com/staff/ryanstanton/posts.html&#34;&gt;Ryan Stanton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch Ann Arbor City Council in person starting at 7:00 p.m. at City Council chambers at City Hall, or follow along by watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/whats-on/Pages/default.aspx#GovTV&#34;&gt;CTN&lt;/a&gt; on cable TV channel 16 or online. Use twitter hashtag #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23A2Council&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt; to keep score from home, and follow along in the agenda in &lt;a href=&#34;https://a2gov.legistar.com/MeetingDetail.aspx?ID=264635&amp;amp;GUID=B39BA5DC-6483-4153-B4DA-80B517B465A3&amp;amp;Options=info|&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;Legistar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Title updated to reflect correct date, thanks to Vivienne Armentrout for noticing).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>city council report, august 8 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-09-city-council-report-august-8-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-09-city-council-report-august-8-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a relatively early end to city council. No controversial public hearings meant that public comment was small. To make up for it council had an extended discussion of a sidewalk crossing near a school that should have been simple and uncontroversial but ended up being an elaborate parade of city staff talking about a few feet of blacktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part of the night was an account of the party for one of the unsuccessful council candidates. That candidate who will go unnamed was said to have been very upset about losing, and their supporters were said to have been rude to the press and to other politicos present. I wasn&#39;t there to witness it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remind me never to run for public office.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>