<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sisyphus on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/sisyphus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sisyphus on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 16:34:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/sisyphus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the goal of the Internet?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-02-what-is-the-goal-of-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 16:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-02-what-is-the-goal-of-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;#39;s assume for a moment that the Internet is a very large, elaborate, multi-player game. What are its winning conditions?  0. Make money fast. That proves to be difficult, but it&amp;#39;s been pitched so many times that it should go up front first. If you can&amp;#39;t make money quickly, then at least make the promise that you are growing something that will eventually make money even if it&amp;#39;s not making money now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to sending electronic mail; alternatives to receiving electronic mail</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>The weekend is a low email diet, but somehow that&amp;#39;s difficult to do without explaining myself a little bit. Here&amp;#39;s some thoughts as to how I might do things the next time that I work through the world of weekend time, how I can get some more effective communications rather than just more frequent.
Short asynchronous private message. A Twitter direct message works nicely for this, as does an SMS message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from a spell of no email, and starting a new one</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-noemail-recovery/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Sisyphus had it easy.&amp;quot;
I&amp;#39;ll be off email starting Friday night and continuing to Sunday night; the second weekend in a row of a &amp;quot;no email&amp;quot; weekend. It wasn&amp;#39;t quite 100% offline the first weekend, since I&amp;#39;m so addicted, but I made a point of not clicking on any messages in my inbox and not sending any mail.
Part of the plan for not doing email is making sure that at the end of the time you can recover gracefully and not feel overwhelmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaningless indicators of progress</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-meaningless-indicators-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 21:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-meaningless-indicators-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s important to have tasks that provide unambiguous signals that you are making progress, even though individually those tasks do not seem significant.
Think of mindless mindfulness that lets you go diligently through a text and correct each of the small flaws that you notice. None of the flaws are burdensome, but there is need to accumulate evidence of care for a level of detail. Deep thought is not needed to do the work, but when it&amp;#39;s missing the lack is noted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>