<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Republic Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/republic-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Republic Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 12:27:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/republic-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy Yuill (1932-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 12:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/508946.html?nav=5007&#34;&gt;as printed in the Marquette Mining Journal, April 22 2008&lt;/a&gt;.  Joy and Baldy were neighbors of ours in Marquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REPUBLIC — Joy Elizabeth Yuill, 75, of 11676 River Road, Republic, and former Marquette resident, entered eternal life Tuesday afternoon, April 15, 2008, at her home in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula Home Health &amp; Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Born September 11, 1932, in Gaylord, the daughter of Stanley and Dorothy (Siegel) Yuill, Joy was raised in Vanderbilt and graduated from the Gaylord High School in 1949. She attended Hillsdale College for a year before transferring to Grinnell College in Grinnell, Iowa, where she received a bachelor of science degree in education in 1953. Joy taught in Detroit, while also taking classes at Wayne State University, which led to her receiving her master’s degree in special education in 1956, with special emphasis on blind and partially sighted clients. In 1957, Joy moved to Marquette, traveling extensively throughout the Upper Peninsula to serve sight-impaired students. In 1971, Joy received a nursing degree from Northern Michigan University, working at Marquette General Hospital mostly on weekends. She retired from her nursing career in 2000. For over 17 years, Joy worked summers at Bay Cliff Health Camp in Big Bay as a special education teacher and swimming instructor. She retired from this position in 2005 and then assisted with adult campers for one week each year. 1972 was to produce yet another degree for Joy, this time a master’s degree in music from Wayne State. Joy continued teaching full time until 2002 and thereafter taught on a part-time basis for the next two years. When not in the classroom, Joy was the piano accompanist for the Marquette Male Chorus for many years. She also assisted many students with their solo and ensemble pieces at the Negaunee and Westwood high schools for over 20 years. Known locally for her beautiful renditions on the harp, Joy was a participant in many concerts and musical programs over the years. She was a member of the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming. In June 1963, Joy married Vincent “Baldy” Bur, and he preceded her in death in 1999. Joy and Baldy were great animal lovers and took in all sorts of stray and unwanted animals over the years. In her leisure, she enjoyed baking bread, knitting, sewing, gardening, and being involved in anything musical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Joy is survived by her brother, Robert “Beezle” Yuill of Harvey; a brother-in-law, Leonard Bur of Marquette; sister-in-law, Amelia Kent of North Little Rock, Ark.; her niece, Martha Yuill of St. Paul, Minn.; and a nephew, Stephen Yuill of Ishpeming. In addition to her parents and husband, Joy was preceded in death by sisters-in-law, Christine Yuill and Verna Bur; and a nephew, Michael Bur. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The family will receive relatives and friends at the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming on Saturday, May 10, beginning at 1 p.m. A memorial service will follow at 2 p.m. Saturday with the Rev. James Robb officiating. Memorials may be directed to the Marquette County Humane Society, 84 Snowfield Road, Negaunee, MI 49866; or to the United Presbyterian Church, 112 E. Euclid St., Ishpeming, MI 49849.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Fassbender Funeral Home is serving the family, where condolences may be expressed online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&#34;&gt;www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>