<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Events Information Security Infrastructure on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-events-information-security-infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Events Information Security Infrastructure on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:20:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-events-information-security-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup.com DDOS attack continues, March 3, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-03-meetupcom-ddos-attack-continues-march-3-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-03-meetupcom-ddos-attack-continues-march-3-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com&#34;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; has had a series of bad days. Their site has been under a distributed denial of service (DDOS) attack for a number of days. To mitigate the problem, they are using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt; service, but even that has not been working great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net effect is that sometimes the Meetup.com site is unavailable, making it hard to sign up or schedule or reschedule events. The Meetup periodic announcements about the problem emphasize how hard they are working to fix it and how user credit cards are not at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been happily using Meetup to organize the &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/a2b3-lunch&#34;&gt;A2B3 weekly Thursday lunch series&lt;/a&gt; that I run, as well as a monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/a2civictech&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor civic technology meetup&lt;/a&gt; and a monthly Web Analtyics Wednesday meetup. Of the three, only the a2civictech group doesn&#39;t really have any other infrastructure; the other two have existing web sites or mailing lists to carry on even if meetup is down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish Meetup well and look forward to them sorting out the problems they are having. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetupblog.meetup.com/&#34;&gt;Meetup blog&lt;/a&gt; is a source of news, as is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/meetup&#34;&gt;Meetup twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meetup is still under a DDoS attack. All data secure. YOU CAN COUNT ON MEETUP to be stable and reliable soon. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/YyNXdsq9b5&#34;&gt;http://t.co/YyNXdsq9b5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Meetup (@Meetup) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Meetup/statuses/440577840128356353&#34;&gt;March 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>