<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juneberry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/juneberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Juneberry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 11:35:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/juneberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Juneberry season is on its way - trees are in bloom</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 11:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben from Damn Arbor notes that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com/2013/05/in-bloom-juneberries.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;juneberries in town are in bloom&lt;/a&gt;, which means that it shouldn&amp;#39;t be more than about a month before they are ready for street-side snacking.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forager in me always welcomes street trees that provide impromptu nutrition. &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Juneberries&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki has a brief list of some of the places where you can find juneberries downtown&lt;/a&gt;; surprisingly, the municipal parking lots on the west side of downtown are ringed with these trees. Keep your eyes open and get to them before the birds do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-04</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-04-links-for-2009-06-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 04:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-04-links-for-2009-06-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul class=&#34;delicious&#34;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmcvey.net/cable/ex/buell_1860_200-01.htm&#34;&gt;telegraphic codes and message practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;Buell&amp;#039;s Mercantile Cypher (1860) appears on eve of the Civil War and near the end of the canal transport for which it provides language. Code compilation was still tentative at this time; its phraseology is practical but too specific and even politely long-winded, giving it the tone of an exercise book. The nature of the markings throughout the present copy suggest that it was used for preparation for another code, based on and incorporating some, and rejecting much else, of its content.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/telegraph&#34;&gt;telegraph&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/code&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/cipher&#34;&gt;cipher&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmcvey.net/cable/intro.htm&#34;&gt;telegraphic codes and message practice, 1870-1945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;The codes did not appear out of nowhere. Their immediate tributaries were nautical and coastal signal systems (typically involving flaghoist combinations), and visual telegraphs such as the Chappé optical telegraph system that operated across France from the mid-1790s well into the 1840s. With all of these systems, each sign or combination of signs represented a word or phrase in a code dictionary.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/telegraph&#34;&gt;telegraph&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/code&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/signals&#34;&gt;signals&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.thehenryford.org/2009/05/27/of-secret-codes-abbreviations-and-knowledge-lost-and-gained/&#34;&gt;Of Secret Codes, Abbreviations, and Knowledge Lost and Gained « The Henry Ford Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;It turned out that what I had instead was a commercial telegraphic code. From the 19th through the mid-20th centuries, telegrams were integral to business and personal communications. Telegraph codes proliferated as a way to correspond economically and privately. Readily available code books such as the ABC Universal Commercial Electric Telegraph Code, not to mention many others, were published, with many businesses creating in-house codes. According to telegraphy historian-enthusiast John McVey, “Thousands of codes were published or issued privately, but they are largely forgotten now. They present a finely-grained window into their respective domains and their time. And they provide instances of sometimes stunning visual, technical, lexicographic and unwitting poetic achievement.”&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/language&#34;&gt;language&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/telegraph&#34;&gt;telegraph&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/ford&#34;&gt;ford&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/abbreviation&#34;&gt;abbreviation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/party-like-its-1919&#34;&gt;party-like-its-1919&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frontporchrepublic.com/?p=3732&#34;&gt;The New “Freedom” | Front Porch Republic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;You might even call it “utopic” in Thomas More’s wry sense: a seemingly good or perfect place which is really no place at all. Computers displace us. They displace us physically - they enable us to talk to anyone, anywhere, and so forth - but they also displace us emotionally and intellectually. They confuse and distract us.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/osx&#34;&gt;osx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/freedom&#34;&gt;freedom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/internet&#34;&gt;internet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/get-off-the-internet&#34;&gt;get-off-the-internet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/dystopia&#34;&gt;dystopia&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stoweboyd.com/ground/2008/11/acorn-crop-cras.html&#34;&gt;/Ground: Acorn Crop Crashes?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;Logan&amp;#039;s alternative is nimbly and seductively argued. He shows a map in which the distribution of early settled societies throughout the temperate zone appears exactly to coincide with the geographical spread of the 400-odd species of oak. He cites many cultures - in north America, ancient Mesopotamia, the highlands of Mexico - where a style of living midway between nomadic gathering and rooted agriculture was evident long before the advent of cereal farming. You could, I suppose, call it fixed foraging, the communal exploitation of a long-lived local resource. The resource was the oak tree, always there in one form or another - just above the waterline, if you were fisher-people, just below the uplands if you were hunters. And its first and most fundamental gift was the acorn, prolific, nutritious (you just needed to leach out the tannin with water), storable, cookable.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/agriculture&#34;&gt;agriculture&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/foraging&#34;&gt;foraging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/oak&#34;&gt;oak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mykoreankitchen.com/2007/02/08/seasoned-acorn-jelly-dotori-muk-muchim/&#34;&gt;Seasoned Acorn Jelly (Dotori Muk Muchim) at My Korean Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;In my memory, I don’t think I liked the seasoned acorn jelly that much because of its bitter taste, but now I love it, it is like an adult appreciates good food more than a child. It has a slightly bitter taste from the acorn jelly and a slightly sweet and salty taste from the sauce, which I love, and this recipe is like that.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/food&#34;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/vegetarian&#34;&gt;vegetarian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/korea&#34;&gt;korea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/10/seven-random-food-facts.html&#34;&gt;seven random (food) facts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;1.   From an early age I was taught what was good to eat in the north woods and how to find it.  If you&amp;#039;re walking with me and suddenly I dive into the bushes and come up with a handful of berries, you&amp;#039;ll understand.  Locally this means that the first day of blueberry, raspberry, juneberry, and strawberry season are holidays, and I employ a small army of berry-picking advance scouts to keep me informed of when opening day is and how conditions are.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/food&#34;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipe&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/berrypicking&#34;&gt;berrypicking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/berries&#34;&gt;berries&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backwoodshome.com/articles2/clay79.html&#34;&gt;Harvesting the wild: acorns by Jackie Clay Issue #79&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;When all are done, get out your food grinder. Put a fine knife on the grinder and run the shelled acorns through it. This makes a coarse meal. Place this in a large crock or glass bowl. Then add boiling water to cover and let stand an hour. Drain and throw away the brownish, unappetizing water. Repeat. Then taste the meal. It should have a bit of a bitter tang, then taste sweet as you chew a piece. Continue leaching out the tannin as long as necessary.&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/food&#34;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/howto&#34;&gt;howto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/simplicity&#34;&gt;simplicity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/foraging&#34;&gt;foraging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/oaks&#34;&gt;oaks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/survival&#34;&gt;survival&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://everything2.com/title/How%2520to%2520eat%2520acorns&#34;&gt;How to eat acorns@Everything2.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;To get the tannic acid out of acorns, you need to leech them, that is stick them in boiling water for a few minutes, pour the water out, then repeat repeat repeat perhaps 25 times. Leeching is facilitated if you shell (obviously) the acorns and also chop them into fine pieces. Make sure to cut out any discolored or rotten portions of the nuts, and any grubs (unless you want to eat those too- I can vouch that they aren&amp;#039;t poisonous but I don&amp;#039;t know about the little cells that they build around themselves).&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipe&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/howto&#34;&gt;howto&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://plantanswers.tamu.edu/recipes/squirrel.html&#34;&gt;Harvesting the Acorns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;The reason I ask this: When I was a child, my grandfather had me pick up a small bucketful of acorns from under our pin oak tree. A day or two later, he asked me to come over to his house and he fed me acorns. The only problem I have is he never told anyone how in the world he prepared them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some information about eating acorns or rather acorn meal. The tannins have to be removed to avoid the bitterness. I don&amp;#039;t know what your grandfather might have done to remove the tannins in whole acorns unless the type of acorn had less tannins to begin with and could have been removed by soaking the whole acorn.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/food&#34;&gt;food&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipe&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/squirrel&#34;&gt;squirrel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaljournal.com/article/272608&#34;&gt;Climate change driving Michigan mammals north (Includes interview) - Digital Journal: Your News Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;It’s a very complicated system. Oaks have “mast” cycles, which means that some years they produce tons of acorns and some years they produce few or none. Our oaks in Michigan do this as well. Mice eat acorns, and not surprisingly, in the New York study mouse numbers are linked to the mast cycles. More acorns, more white-footed mice.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/oaks&#34;&gt;oaks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/mast&#34;&gt;mast&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/mouse&#34;&gt;mouse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/globalchange&#34;&gt;globalchange&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mypapercrane.com/blog/?p=953&#34;&gt;My Paper Crane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-extended&#34;&gt;My friend Katie told me about a recipe she found for making acorn cookies. I’ve been excited to try them and found a recipe and changed it a little last night. The kids and I shaped the acorns, dipped the tops in chocolate, and then rolled them in ground walnuts. I added some finely ground coffee beans in with the walnuts for a coffee/walnut sort of flavor. The kids preferred their cookies just dipped in chocolate. If you have a nut allergy or just don’t like nuts you could try crushed cookies or something similar.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;delicious-tags&#34;&gt;(tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/recipe&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/cookies&#34;&gt;cookies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/vielmetti/acorn&#34;&gt;acorn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woody plants - identifying the trees of Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year the U of Michigan teaches a Woody Plants class.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t take it when I was in school, but my sister did, and it&amp;#39;s one of these legendary courses that people remember for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the links and notes I could find easily.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s prompted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2009/02/13/where-are-ann-arbors-trees/&#34;&gt;the Ann Arbor Chronicle&amp;#39;s story about the city of Ann Arbor tree inventory going on now,&lt;/a&gt; which I hope will yield a precise map of where all of the public juneberry trees are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Course listing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snre.umich.edu/node/349&#34;&gt;NRE 436: Woody Plants Biology and Identification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0in 0in 0pt 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#34;#000000&#34; face=&#34;Times New Roman&#34; size=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Woody
Plants is an intensive field- and lecture-based learning experience, in
which you will learn to identify 160 trees, shrub and vine species that
are important in Michigan environments. You will learn about their
taxonomy, distribution, habitat associations, and biogeographic history
and how to identify them in their leafless winter condition. The lab
component consists of weekly field trips in the Ann Arbor area, which
include riparian and floodplain habitats, glacial lakes, moraines,
bogs, fens and mesic forests. The lectures cover elementary aspects of
plant identification, taxonomy and ecology; however, the broader themes
include biogeographic history and the assembly of Michigan plant
communities, both before and after major glaciations, ecological
specializiation, and impacts of global warming and other anthropogenic
environmental changes.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://http://sitemaker.umich.edu/woodyplants/home&#34;&gt;Woody Plants - Sitemaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The required textbook for Woody Plants is &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Michigan Trees&lt;/span&gt;
by Burt V. Barnes and Warren H. Wagner. The authors taught the Woody
Plants class from 1965 to 2005 and know their topic well. The books are
available at Shaman Drum bookshop on 311 State Street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snre.umich.edu/profile/bvb&#34;&gt;Burt Barnes home page&lt;/a&gt; at SNRE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Undergraduate and graduate teaching in forest ecology; landscape
ecology; natural history, and identification of Woody Plants. Research
focuses on the theory and application of the landscape ecosystem
approach. Studies emphasize spatial mapping of landscape ecosystems as
the basis for conserving and managing ecosystems at multiple scales.
Research on diversity of ecosystems and biota in upland, riverine, and
wetland ecosystems. Specific areas include genetic and systematic
studies of aspen species (genus &lt;em&gt;Populus&lt;/em&gt;), worldwide and comparative studies of east Asian and North American forests and species of the temperate zone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=Mc0YAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=michigan+trees&amp;amp;ei=rhGbSeCiDZicMq685KEP#PPP3,M1&#34;&gt;An early edition of Michigan Trees, in 1913, as seen on Google Books&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_sectionwrap&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line book_title_line&#34;&gt;Michigan Trees: A Handbook of the Native and Most Important Introduced Species&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;By Charles Herbert Otis&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Edition: 2&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Published by The Regents, 1913&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Original from Harvard University&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Digitized Apr 11, 2008&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;246 pages&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>seven random (food) facts</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-seven-random-food-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 22:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-seven-random-food-facts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4obsessions.blogspot.com/2008/10/7-random-food-facts.html&#34;&gt;Inspired by Kate from Four Obsessions, here are seven food-related things to share.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; From an early age I was taught what was good to eat in the north woods and how to find it.&amp;#0160; If you&amp;#39;re walking with me and suddenly I dive into the bushes and come up with a handful of berries, you&amp;#39;ll understand.&amp;#0160; Locally this means that the first day of &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search?q=ann+arbor+blueberries&#34;&gt;blueberry&lt;/a&gt;, raspberry, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/juneberry/&#34;&gt;juneberry&lt;/a&gt;, and strawberry season are holidays, and I employ a small army of berry-picking advance scouts to keep me informed of when opening day is and how conditions are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.&amp;#0160; When I was a kid we made cookies out of acorns once.&amp;#0160; It took a long time to gather them, and a lot of work to process them, and when they finally got into the oven somehow (mysteriously) they got scorched.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve never had the need to repeat that experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.&amp;#0160; The first complicated recipe I tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://amasci.com/amateur/sciamdx.html&#34;&gt;sauce Bearnaise, using a recipe from Scientific American&amp;#39;s The Amateur Scientist (1979 Dec, pg 178; 1981 Jan, pg 164).&amp;#0160;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160; It turned out pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.&amp;#0160; After having had &lt;a href=&#34;http://williamtozier.com/slurry/2008/09/16/winter-squash-caramel&#34;&gt;sweet dumpling squash&lt;/a&gt;, I can&amp;#39;t go back to ever eating acorn squash again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.&amp;#0160; We are vegetarians at home, but I&amp;#39;m a confirmed omnivore, and so you&amp;#39;ll see restaurant reviews of meat dishes but only vegetarian recipes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m bad at doing recipes because I hardly ever measure anything anymore - mostly I spice things by eye and smell, and as often as not the recipes I end up with are a description of what I did this one time with the food on hand and not instructions for what to go buy.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m sure that there&amp;#39;s some recipe vocabulary in some language that I&amp;#39;m missing which could make them better, other than &amp;quot;cook until it smells good&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve taken to blogging recipes in part because it&amp;#39;s a convenient way to look them up the next time I need to cook them, since I don&amp;#39;t always know which cookbook on our shelf has the recipe on the menu plan for the week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tag: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ourfounder.typepad.com/leblog/2007/10/jimmy-wales-gro.html&#34;&gt;Jim Benson (e.g. &amp;quot;stir-fried wikipedia with pimentoes&amp;quot;)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kitchenchick.com/2008/02/paczki-day-tomo.html&#34;&gt;KitchenChick (my reliable source for Paczki Day information)&lt;/a&gt;, and The Cottage Smallholder (who &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cottagesmallholder.com/?p=855&#34;&gt;got tagged already&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>