<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bitcoin on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/bitcoin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bitcoin on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 14:02:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/bitcoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dogecoin suffers wallet heist. Such currency! Very profit!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-dogecoin-suffers-wallet-heist-such-currency-very-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 14:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-dogecoin-suffers-wallet-heist-such-currency-very-profit/</guid>
      <description>Dogecoin is an alternative to Bitcoin, in the sense that it has the same structure as Bitcoin of being backed by cryptography and by conspicuous consumption of computing power and electricity. It&#39;s distinguished from Bitcoin in that Dogecoin is also backed by a meme of a cute dog. Such currency! Very profit!
Everything is fun and games until the criminal element gets involved, in which case you can be pretty sure that your cryptocurrency has been validated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spy vs spy: Tor (US Naval Intelligence designed anonymous network) attacked by NSA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-04-spy-vs-spy-tor-us-naval-intelligence-designed-anonymous-network-attacked-by-nsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-04-spy-vs-spy-tor-us-naval-intelligence-designed-anonymous-network-attacked-by-nsa/</guid>
      <description>The Tor Project runs Tor (&#34;The Onion Router&#34;), a network designed to provide its users with anonymity when using the Internet. Tor was originally developed by US Naval Intelligence, and a large part of support for the network still comes from government interests.
Tor was in the news recently as the high profile Silk Road anonymous marketplace for drugs was shut down. Silk Road had been hosted as a hidden node reachable only through Tor, and it ran openly on that network for years until a dedicated effort unmasked the organizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin volatility after Silk Road shutdown</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-02-bitcoin-volatility-after-silk-road-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 15:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-02-bitcoin-volatility-after-silk-road-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>The markets have not been kind to Bitcoin over the past few hours. Here&#39;s a 24 hour snapshot from the Bitcoin price tracking site Bitcoinity. What you see is a steady state of $140 per Bitcoin disrupted into a steep decline to $110, and then a ragged recovery up towards the $125 level. Your guess is good as mine what the rate will be in the next 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Bitcoin: notes from the Michigan Bitcoin meetup of 5/22/13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-introduction-to-bitcoin-notes-from-the-michigan-bitcoin-meetup-of-52213/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 23:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-introduction-to-bitcoin-notes-from-the-michigan-bitcoin-meetup-of-52213/</guid>
      <description>Here are some notes from the Michigan Bitcoin meetup of May 22, 2013. They are in no way reflective of everything that was discussed at the meeting; indeed, there&amp;#39;s some things here that we didn&amp;#39;t talk about at the meeting that I discovered later. But here goes anyway.
1. How does Bitcoin work? I&amp;#39;m looking at the Khan Academy series on Bitcoin and listened to one lecture which seems to spell it out quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>