<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>We should do more blogging</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blog every day, whether you want to or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick a topic, learn it well, and write about it as you learn it.
Or pick a topic you know really well already and teach to it.
Sometimes you can do both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time spent blogging can&amp;rsquo;t be any less worthwhile than time
spent on Facebook or Twitter. The exchange is, instead of clicking
the like button and the favorite button, you actually have to think
a little bit and write something down that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>make tidy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been converting over old postings on this blog from Typepad.
The data export and import was imperfect, and this meant that I&amp;rsquo;ve
been poring over the data to figure out what keeps and what goes
and what-not. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to review old words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the artifacts of the old hosting platform was a helpful at
times system called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zemanta.com&#34;&gt;Zemanta&lt;/a&gt;. Zemanta would
figure out what you were writing about and give you helpful suggestions
for related links, both to things that you had written as well as
to things other people had written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided as part of the transformation of the old weblog into
the new one to unlink those &amp;ldquo;related links&amp;rdquo;, in the hope that
eventually Hugo&amp;rsquo;s own system will create some either algorithmically
derived relations or at least an easier way to do that by hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m looking closely at what Zemanta did so I can
undo it. The first set of artifacts is a &amp;ldquo;fieldset&amp;rdquo; with its links,
and that&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to search and destroy. Occasionally but not
always I find my links decorated with a &lt;code&gt;class=&amp;quot;zem_slink&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; marker
that&amp;rsquo;s a little harder to find. Most insidious so far was exactly
one time where Zemanta (or Typepad) rewrote or wrote an Amazon link
to include an affiliate link points to Zemanta, and not to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewriting 1500+ pages is going to take a while. The biggest question
is unpublishing some of them, since time has passed and I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to republish everything. There&amp;rsquo;s conversion from HTML to Markdown
to remove the uglies, spelling errors to catch, next
categories and taxonomies to fill, layout to work on, etc. At
some point I need to sort out image management. But first I&amp;rsquo;m going
to understand the consequences of previous convenience decisions
I made to use Zemanta and to undo that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>diligently editing and converting for production</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to get this blog ready for production.
The tasks remaining include the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a reasonable home page with pagination. Somehow I need
to provide some kind of access to almost 2000 posts, and they
don&amp;rsquo;t all fit on a single page. Sort through the design to make
old things reachable, and then worry next about the formatter.
(This is done at least minimally, though the provided paginator
interface uses a list structure that&amp;rsquo;s not nice. Still, it gets
me to what I need to in a ping.) Open discussion on gohugo is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/pagination-and-group-by-date/1441/3&#34;&gt;Pagination and group by date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish to Github Pages, using vielmetti.github.io. I did this
once (using Octopress) so it should be straightforward to do it again.
I already do have a proper github repo (or nearly proper, it may
be missing some key bits). Done; don&amp;rsquo;t have a perfect build script
yet, but there&amp;rsquo;s at least a start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import all sorts more nonsense here, including a bunch of Superpatron
and Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Secret and FOIA Coordiator weblogs. There&amp;rsquo;s no particular
reason not to make it all one big soup. Import from Typepad is problematic
but not impossible and that would be a good addition to the supported work;
in particular it&amp;rsquo;s not evidently possible to export Markdown from Typepad,
just HTML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sort out theme issues so that I get a reasonable display for category
and subcategory pages. I may have to write some things down by hand
to get an understanding of what I really want. As it is right now
those pages render as blank, in part because I need to convert a bunch
of data imperfectly imported, which was throwing errors in my
templates, which in turn was breaking the build. Dealing with the
errored out builds is a question again for gohugo,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/taxononomy/1445&#34;&gt;taxononomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal with the date problems. Lots of dates got imported without a timezone,
but that was not the real issue; the real issue was also that lots got
imported with &amp;ldquo;layout: post&amp;rdquo;. Take that out and it seems to fix things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Request a dump of the image cache from Typepad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implement, somehow, &amp;ldquo;edit on github&amp;rdquo; so that my workflow is easier.
This might only be on the preview version. Some notes on the Hugo discussion
forums
describing how to do that are on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-to-implement-edit-this-page-on-github/1166&#34;&gt;How to implement “edit this page on github”?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you write something that&#39;s longer than a tweet, but shorter than an essay?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-where-do-you-write-something-thats-longer-than-a-tweet-but-shorter-than-an-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 22:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-where-do-you-write-something-thats-longer-than-a-tweet-but-shorter-than-an-essay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where do you write something that&#39;s longer than a tweet, but shorter than an essay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a space on the net for things that you put together that don&#39;t fit into a tweet, but that also don&#39;t really require a whole long essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been writing these in my blog for years, and so I have a bit of infrastructure put together for organizing, collecting, and finding them again. A lot of people who are on Twitter don&#39;t have a blog, though, and so their fragments stay fragmentary or get lost in the mists of Twitter time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of places to post disconnected paragraphs online - you can stick them on Facebook (where they will be quickly seen and quickly lost), you can dump them into a Github gist (where only techies will be able to find them again), or - best of all - you can use your own web space in some blog-like time-sequenced away to push things into the world for later retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other people talking about this at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gina Trapani: &lt;a href=&#34;http://scribbling.net/2014/10/16/short-form-blogging/&#34;&gt;I find tweets too reductionist and Medium pieces too bloviating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marco Arment: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/2014/11/01/short-form-blogging&#34;&gt;Too much of my writing in the last few years has gone exclusively into Twitter. I need to find a better balance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andy Baio: &lt;a href=&#34;http://waxy.org/2014/10/middling/&#34;&gt;I miss seeing people I admire post stuff longer than a tweet.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was noted by several people that Tumblr fits this pattern well; alas, I don&#39;t Tumbl very well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you still write 750 words a day?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-do-you-still-write-750-words-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-do-you-still-write-750-words-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure that I write way more than that in aggregate, but I&amp;#39;ve not been keeping up with what was once a habit I attempted: to write a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/12/750wordscom-a-writing-environment-for-a-daily-writing-exercise.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;750 word essay&lt;/a&gt; every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that it&amp;#39;s possible to sit down with a single cup of coffee and a single idea and no distractions and crank out 500 words at a sitting. It helps if the coffee doesn&amp;#39;t spill, and if your todo list is in check, and if you have a full sized keyboard and not a tiny phone. The morning ritual of daily coffee and wifi usually produces something publishable, though often it&amp;#39;s much shorter. You might only clip and save and share a single tweet&amp;#39;s worth of someone else&amp;#39;s work and call that a success to capture the idea of the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t sit down and write all the time, though. There&amp;#39;s meetings to go to, code to struggle with, people to see, places to go, dinner to cook, and the endless slog of Internet to wade through. When I do have a chance to write to produce things, it&amp;#39;s often 50 words there, 10 words here, a click of a button there. It&amp;#39;s not always long, extended efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long, extended efforts are fun, don&amp;#39;t get me wrong, and they really focus the mind and help me think about topics for much longer than I would otherwise. The ideal writing environment gets all of the distractions out of the way and shuts out the beep-beep-beep of interrupts that otherwise drive my efforts. Getting away from interrupts turns out to be really hard work, and obtaining an uninterrupted stretch that allows such a focus is a rare treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you focus on if you had 750 words of uninterrupted focus every day? It should be enough to dig deep into a topic, not just to hit the surface but to wallow around in it, trying out lots of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m cutting this self-reflective essay off at about 300 words, because there are 450 words that I&amp;#39;d rather apply to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>write every day</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-write-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 09:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-write-every-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you produce so much writing? It is simple. All you have to do is sit down every single day and write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like a daily deadline to focus the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weblogs do not impose an external deadline. No editor is asking you when your work is going to be ready, and no producer is going to feed you copy. It is just you up against the elements, bravely typing away alone and hoping that your focus is not distracted by systems problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing all the time is a habit. Some parts of the writing week are easy, when it is just you talking to the page and getting fully formed thoughts out as fast as the keyboard or screen will let you. Other days it&#39;s a struggle just to come up with anything that anyone would possibly want to read again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weblog is a mature writing format. The tools are not evolving, and new startups are not appearing with whizzy new high concept takes on the form. The fancy new school tools are for essayists (Medium) or for micro bloggers (Ello). I am happy to see incremental improvements at Typepad to make responsive designs easier to put together, but that is a refinement and not an evolutionary change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to an unfortunate incident with a cup of coffee, my medium of choice at the moment is a mobile phone browser. The small screen gives me about a paragraph of text as context for my writing, and the input box on Typepad&#39;s dashboard is just competent enough to make this no harder than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about other things I wish I did every day, knowing full well that there are only so many daily habits you can sustain. Facebook wants to catch you every day on the birthday treadmill, your dentist wants you to floss your teeth, the pedometer wants to be logged, the dishes washed, the cats fed u.s.w. My morning wants a cup of coffee, and the daily coffee and WiFi lends itself to blogging. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I aspire to being a daily blogger, but I am not one. It is good to have goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the limits of the small screen</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-23-the-limits-of-the-small-screen-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 06:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-23-the-limits-of-the-small-screen-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am operating with the limitation that I do not currently have a full sized keyboard and screen. The laptop accidentally ingested a cup of coffee. It is getting dried out and the bad bits reclaimed now, and in the meantime I am doing all my computing on either library computers or my Nexus 4 phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often awkward to compose messages and to write on such a small screen, but the screen size is not really the problem. What is much harder is the single finger worth of on screen keyboard that I have to get used to. I type really fast with all ten fingers and the small swipe keyboard on the phone is just slower and more error prone and more cumbersome. This affects my thinking too as I do not have a way to write as fast as I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mobile web is surprisingly functional. Responsive design means that many web sites are readable on a small screen, and the plethora of app designs generally work pretty well. The mobile web however is better for very short messages (LOL BRB) and for consuming info and for executing simple commands. It is not designed for the essayist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have looked at a bunch of writing environments, and surprisingly this input window in the Typepad mobile app is one of the better off them. If there is a &#34;word processor&#34; for Android I have not found it yet. Instead I am ending up writing with only Markdown as a formatting language, and I am not using even that. Plain text all the way in a simple browser edit input window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in the small is possible, but it is not fun. I am looking forward to getting a full sized keyboard again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note to self, the cup of coffee should always be to the far right of the keyboard, not on the near left.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long form writing, as first published to Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-long-form-writing-as-first-published-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 01:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-long-form-writing-as-first-published-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to do some long form writing, except that I&#39;d publish it on Twitter. I&#39;ll write essays as I&#39;d normally write them, making sure that sentences are 140 characters or less. The goal would be to encapsulate an entire argument in pithy sentences and make each one stand on its own. I have no doubt that it would be possible to write quite a few words this way, though you might lose some followers in the bargain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change of pace is that you&#39;re not trying to write your whole idea into any given 140 character fragment. You&#39;re looking to spin out a story that holds together over dozens of tweets, without being too distracted by the net you&#39;re writing within. Writing with a net watching can be distracting, but it can also be enlivening; somehow you must make use of the diversions. Some side conversations will give you ideas that you can later reclaim and recast as your own, when the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is a new medium within which to compose original writing, as every sentence you write there has its own URL and feedback loop. By publishing every sentence individually, you can write and then see feedback one line a time - a thought both inspiring and terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oscar Wilde, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/wilde-oscar/soul-man/&#34;&gt;The Soul of Man under Socialism&lt;/a&gt;, 1891. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fact is, that the public have an insatiable curiosity to know everything, except what is worth knowing. Journalism, conscious of this, and having tradesman-like habits, supplies their demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been drafting first versions in vim so that I have a record of the whole context of what I&#39;m writing outside of Twitter. Drafting in vim gives me a chance to write a whole paragraph and then push it to Twitter as separate sentences, once it makes sense. I always edit again within Twitter, where every character is counted for you forcing you to make tough decisions about what not to say. The short format of Twitter leads to better writing, since you must omit needless words to make a complex idea fit into its allotment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My writing is slower when I feel the compulsion to construct an argument that still makes sense when divided into pieces. It&#39;s easier to write quickly when you don&#39;t have to think about the reaction to every word and phrase. The feedback has prompted a handful of offline drafts before committing to publishing - even &#34;just&#34; to publishing to Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The slow drip of progress</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-20-the-slow-drip-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 15:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-20-the-slow-drip-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I come up with a really good idea. More often than not, I don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m content to work on systems that accommodate the work that leads to a steady sense of slow progress. The weblog piles one post upon another; every so often, the middle of the pile is most interesting, and you dust it off and bring it out again as if it were new. The wiki appreciates it when you fix a very small typo, change an &#34;an&#34; to an &#34;a&#34;, tidy up a caption or resize a photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is more often than not measured very slowly, if at all. Just try not to go backwards. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis paralysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Right-now-0-active-visitors-on-site&#34; title=&#34;Right-now-0-active-visitors-on-site&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c-800wi&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a bunch of tools that tell me what people have looked at on the net, including Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools, Clicky, and some Twitter tools. It&#39;s fascinating to see people&#39;s attention move around and occasionally reanimate something that I wrote months or years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these tools don&#39;t easily do is tell me what to write about next. Yes, sometimes they suggest missing things that should be expanded on, and looking at Twitter stats is endlessly fascinating. But that&#39;s a large part of the problem - the endless fascination gets in the way of applying fingers to the keyboard and creating something brand new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s easy to get distracted by the sorts of things that are meant to help you out. It&#39;s hard to be analytical and dispassionate about your past work while at the same time you&#39;re trying to create new work. Not everything worth writing has to rank highly on a search engine or get lots of referral traffic; sometimes, you just need to create something even if it&#39;s only for you to stretch your fingers. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first draft of this essay was 140 characters or less</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-the-first-draft-of-this-essay-was-140-characters-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 14:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-the-first-draft-of-this-essay-was-140-characters-or-less/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time I sit in front of a computer wanting to write, and nothing comes of the urge. Writing in a browser can be very hard work since every other open browser tab wants you to read, not write. You could easily spend hours clicking and not ever utter anything more complex than &#34;like&#34; or &#34;favorite&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one place where writer&#39;s block never seems to be a problem is within Twitter, which for better or worse has been the home of 21,158 of my most pithy observations. Because the Twitter writing environment is so spare, it&#39;s relatively easy to produce something or react to something in a way that doesn&#39;t require a fully formed idea or any of the other agonies that accompany longer format writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a recipe for writing more in this blog. Don&#39;t worry about how much you tweet, because you are treating those tweets as the short form of your work. When the muse is silent, go back to your own tweets and see which ones of them deserve to be longer. Even the stereotypical &#34;eating a sandwich&#34; tweet can be stretched into 200 words if you want, by turning that throwaway observation into a recipe. Almost anything worth visiting in 140 characters is worth revisiting in longer form; take advantage of the short form as a stockpile of ideas to pull from when it&#39;s time to write longer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Amazing Posts EVERY TIME (and why you shouldn&#39;t)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 19:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mackcollier.com/&#34;&gt;Mack Collier&lt;/a&gt; has an amazing post about how to write amazing posts. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mackcollier.com/how-to-write-awesome-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Here, go read it.&lt;/a&gt;) I&#39;m here to tell you why to listen to his advice but not to write like he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collier calls for an amped-up style of blog writing, one that is full of lists and awesome photographs and cheerleading enthusiasm. That&#39;s a good style to recognize, and you&#39;ll see it in some of the most popular parts of the web - the Buzzfeed or Upworthy style, with headlines like &#34;New Dads Learned One Weird Tip To Make Their Blogs POP!&#34;  These are interesting and amazing the way a slow-motion televised car chase is amazing. They are not, however, how I write my weblog - and not a style for you, unless you are in a weird job where counting pageviews drives your wages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net has enough of the hyperkinetic blog fodder to go around. What it doesn&#39;t have, and needs, is bloggers who take an old-school approach to blog writing and who are careful and respectful of their audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is about writing to pick up an audience, one that would read everything you had to say and comment on it. That means not only writing about what people might click on because their eye got caught by a headline, but also writing the day-in, day-out thematic and topical materials that someone who cares more than a little bit will follow along for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is figuring out what sorts of regular obscure parts of the world that you cover and being a go-to resource for that issue when it comes up in the world. To illustrate, I bring you Dave Petley&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.agu.org/landslideblog/&#34;&gt;Landslide Blog&lt;/a&gt;. You won&#39;t find awesome stock photography, but you will find a whole series of carefully selected photos that illustrate the stories he writes about landslides and their origin and effect. Or see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;, which is a lovingly illustrated guide to the bugs of Atlantic Mine, MI with great macrophotography of bugs, beetles, insects, spiders, slugs, and more. There are dozens more like this, people who toil away in relative obscurity writing carefully about their craft, and I love them. It&#39;s a style that lends itself to slowly but surely being a recognized expert in your field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love weblogs that take a narrow view on some interesting part of the world and are thorough in how they document it. They don&#39;t need weird tricks or compelling lists or catchy copy to make their mark on the world. Rather, they illustrate and tell a whole series of stories that might never have been told before, told by someone who is expert in their corner of the world. Even though they might only get a few followers compared to Buzzfeed, they add a lot more to our understanding of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is the topic of the 8 December 2013 #&lt;a href=&#34;http://tchat.io/rooms/blogchat&#34;&gt;blogchat&lt;/a&gt; chat, at 9pm Eastern time).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many publishable words can you write in a day?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-many-publishable-words-can-you-write-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 16:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-many-publishable-words-can-you-write-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a thought experiment. Sit down in the morning with a cup of coffee and a list of topics. Work through them, one at a time, coming up with and writing down 500 words or so on each topic. How many topics do you get to over the course of the day, and how long does it take you to write 500 words that make sense? Assume for the sake of argument that there&#39;s a typical number of distracting email, Twitter, and Facebook posts that you have to deal with. Each of the pieces that you are writing will need to contemplate a part of the net that might lead to its own distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am always impressed by people who have the ability to sit down and crank out clean copy that is ready for publication. It&#39;s not by any means easy to do this, and certainly every written work can be improved by judicious editing. I&#39;m thinking more of the remarkable skill where you can type as fast as you can for a short burst and have the resulting words make sense, flow nicely, and be worth posting to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice I get doing this has a lot to do with blogging, where I want to capture the moment and some momentarily interesting topic and put my mark on it. This is not writing a novel, and not writing a little piece of a 20-page or 400-page non-fiction work; rather, it&#39;s somewhere between journalism and blogging. The work you are composing is temporarily interesting to a number of people in part because it has a good headline for Twitter and a body full of words that search engines like. You&#39;ve written news, but it&#39;s within the context of a blog, and because of that it&#39;s perfectly acceptable to leave questions unanswered and stories unresolved. It&#39;s what musician Michelle Shocked called the &#34;incomplete image&#34;, and perhaps you are waiting for someone with a longer deadline to write up the full story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know from experience that I can put together 500 words in a sitting on one topic without taking a break and without needing to consult an outline. The much more challenging part is making a long, coherent single narrative out of these intermediate pieces parts. The skill of impromptu essay writing is by no means the same as the skill of book writing, and the task of challenging yourself to come up with a story that moves the current understanding a bit forward is a challenge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To some degree, I&#39;m willing to pad out those words with ample quotations from other sources, a sort of journalistic cut-and-paste that sifts through less well known sources to string together a story. (Of course the excerpts are carefully hyperlinked to avoid any suggestion of use without attribution.) Careful reuse of existing copy is one of the qualities that blogging can take advantage of that isn&#39;t generally OK in journalism circles. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all you wrote were impromptu essays for the net, you&#39;d quickly find out what was a keeper by the traffic you were able to draw in. On a good day, I&#39;m happy to write three or four blog posts that either satisfy my own interest in preserving a bit of news or that advance some larger story or that answer a question that&#39;s on more than one person&#39;s mind right now. That would translate into 2000 words on a good day, and that doesn&#39;t sound like a lot. I think you&#39;d have to work hard to keep the hopper full of article ideas and to keep up the research that fed a constant stream of ideas to work from, and to work doubly hard to collect the sort of essay-sized chunks that would eventually tell a story that&#39;s longer and more carefully planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Inspired by #writechat on Sunday, 8 December 2013.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small wins and writing productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 15:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m intrigued of late by the notion of &#34;small wins&#34;. This is prompted by reading Wayne Baker&#39;s book on social networks in which he quotes Karl Weick. Rather than try to solve big problems all at once, you attack them by making progress on a series of smaller more attainable goals. This keeps morale up and shows you that you&#39;re really getting somewhere, even if on the grand scale it doesn&#39;t register yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A small win is a concrete, complete outcome of moderate importance. By itself, one small win may seem unimportant. A series of small wins at small but significant tasks, however, reveals a pattern that may attract allies, deter opponents, and lower resistance to subsequent proposals. A series of small wins is also more structurally sound than a large win because small wins are stable building blocks. Small wins are controllable opportunities that produce visible results. Once a small win has been accomplished, forces are set in motion that favor another small win. When a solution is put into place, the next solvable problem often becomes more visible. Additional resources flow toward winners, which means that slightly larger wins can be attempted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, rather than think about how hard it would be to produce a book of 80,000 words all in one sitting, it gets a lot easier to think how easy it would be to produce 400 words per day (on a topic of your choice naturally) for 200 days over the course of a year. I can bat out 100 words without thinking about it to answer an email message a dozen times a day. So capturing 80,000 words is simply a matter of doing that in some sensible order and not getting sidetracked by the need for everything to make 100% sense at the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(originally published Monday, August 07, 2000)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Former Ann Arbor Public Schools principal accused of plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll start with a confession: I don&#39;t think that plagiarism is as big a deal as some people do, especially when you are recycling your own words. (&#34;Self-plagiarism is style.&#34;) The best writers have a set of phrases that they love to use, and it&#39;s not unusual for them to pull something they&#39;ve done before and rework it a bit to suit the new occasion. This is especially true when you&#39;re writing formulaic work that&#39;s short. How many different very short birthday greetings can you send?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, educators are usually held to higher standards of writing than their students, and writing is expected to be something that they are good enough at that they don&#39;t need to crib from someone else&#39;s words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that as a preface, here&#39;s someone else&#39;s words about someone else using someone else&#39;s words, in this case a former AAPS principal (Sulura Jackson) who is now in Chapel Hill, NC. The reporting is from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indyweek.com/indyweek/chapel-hill-high-school-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/Content?oid=3770001&#34;&gt;Indy Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What they found is startling: Multiple documents obtained by the INDY that show Jackson—before and after her arrival at Chapel Hill High—lifted entire passages and letters from books, online articles and teaching resource guides. She used those passages without citation in staff memos, letters to students and even recommendation letters for colleagues, frequently passing them off as her words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the world of education is full of web sites that are full of reusable forms and letters for communicating with students and teachers, like this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationworld.com/tools_templates/index.shtml&#34;&gt;Education World&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Communicate with parents by snail mail or e-mail with these editable and/or printable forms and letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or the business world in general, with this set of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4hb.com/letters/index.html&#34;&gt;662 business letters&lt;/a&gt; - catchy titles like &#34;Apology to receiver of NSF check&#34; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I received your letter of (date) with my check
  attached marked &#34;insufficient funds&#34;, I called my bank
  immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The gentleman I spoke with, (name) , discovered
  that the bank had failed to credit my account with a
  substantial deposit I had made several days prior.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The bank has assured me that they will be sending you a
  formal letter of apology for their error. Attached is my
  check in the amount of $ to replace the dishonored
  one you have returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communications from authorities are often ritualistic, formulaic, and repetitious. Hopefully, though, they are not careless. Jackson was tripped up by this mistake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Looking back, the alleged plagiarism might have gone unnoticed were it not for one careless sentence the Chapel Hill High School principal wrote in an October condolence letter to a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;Everyone at Skyline is saddened to learn of the death of your mother,&#34; the letter said.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;It seemed Sulura Jackson, who arrived in Chapel Hill this summer with a sparkling, lengthy résumé, had failed to remove the name of her former school, Skyline High, in Ann Arbor, Mich., from the text.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Teachers who spoke to the INDY on the condition that their names not be used for fear of retribution say the incident prompted them to dig deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re going to use a form letter, for goodness sake read the whole form and fill in all the blanks before sending it !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indyweek.com/triangulator/archives/2013/11/21/whats-next-for-chhs-principal-accused-of-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Again from Indy Week&lt;/a&gt;: &#34;More evidence of Chapel Hill High plagiarism?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Members of the Chapel Hill-Carrboro City Schools Board of Education were already scheduled to meet tonight at the Lincoln Center in Chapel Hill. The board&#39;s agenda says members will discuss a personnel matter in closed session starting at 6 p.m. The public portion of the meeting begins at 7 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>