<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We should do more blogging</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Blog every day, whether you want to or not.
Pick a topic, learn it well, and write about it as you learn it. Or pick a topic you know really well already and teach to it. Sometimes you can do both.
The time spent blogging can&amp;rsquo;t be any less worthwhile than time spent on Facebook or Twitter. The exchange is, instead of clicking the like button and the favorite button, you actually have to think a little bit and write something down that makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>make tidy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been converting over old postings on this blog from Typepad. The data export and import was imperfect, and this meant that I&amp;rsquo;ve been poring over the data to figure out what keeps and what goes and what-not. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to review old words.
One of the artifacts of the old hosting platform was a helpful at times system called Zemanta. Zemanta would figure out what you were writing about and give you helpful suggestions for related links, both to things that you had written as well as to things other people had written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you write something that&#39;s longer than a tweet, but shorter than an essay?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-where-do-you-write-something-thats-longer-than-a-tweet-but-shorter-than-an-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 22:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-where-do-you-write-something-thats-longer-than-a-tweet-but-shorter-than-an-essay/</guid>
      <description>Where do you write something that&#39;s longer than a tweet, but shorter than an essay?
There&#39;s a space on the net for things that you put together that don&#39;t fit into a tweet, but that also don&#39;t really require a whole long essay.
I&#39;ve been writing these in my blog for years, and so I have a bit of infrastructure put together for organizing, collecting, and finding them again. A lot of people who are on Twitter don&#39;t have a blog, though, and so their fragments stay fragmentary or get lost in the mists of Twitter time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you still write 750 words a day?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-do-you-still-write-750-words-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-01-do-you-still-write-750-words-a-day/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m sure that I write way more than that in aggregate, but I&amp;#39;ve not been keeping up with what was once a habit I attempted: to write a 750 word essay every day.
I know that it&amp;#39;s possible to sit down with a single cup of coffee and a single idea and no distractions and crank out 500 words at a sitting. It helps if the coffee doesn&amp;#39;t spill, and if your todo list is in check, and if you have a full sized keyboard and not a tiny phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the limits of the small screen</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-23-the-limits-of-the-small-screen-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 06:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-23-the-limits-of-the-small-screen-1/</guid>
      <description>I am operating with the limitation that I do not currently have a full sized keyboard and screen. The laptop accidentally ingested a cup of coffee. It is getting dried out and the bad bits reclaimed now, and in the meantime I am doing all my computing on either library computers or my Nexus 4 phone.
It is often awkward to compose messages and to write on such a small screen, but the screen size is not really the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long form writing, as first published to Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-long-form-writing-as-first-published-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 01:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-06-long-form-writing-as-first-published-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;d like to do some long form writing, except that I&#39;d publish it on Twitter. I&#39;ll write essays as I&#39;d normally write them, making sure that sentences are 140 characters or less. The goal would be to encapsulate an entire argument in pithy sentences and make each one stand on its own. I have no doubt that it would be possible to write quite a few words this way, though you might lose some followers in the bargain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The slow drip of progress</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-20-the-slow-drip-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 15:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-20-the-slow-drip-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while, I come up with a really good idea. More often than not, I don&#39;t.
I&#39;m content to work on systems that accommodate the work that leads to a steady sense of slow progress. The weblog piles one post upon another; every so often, the middle of the pile is most interesting, and you dust it off and bring it out again as if it were new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis paralysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>I have a bunch of tools that tell me what people have looked at on the net, including Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools, Clicky, and some Twitter tools. It&#39;s fascinating to see people&#39;s attention move around and occasionally reanimate something that I wrote months or years ago.
What these tools don&#39;t easily do is tell me what to write about next. Yes, sometimes they suggest missing things that should be expanded on, and looking at Twitter stats is endlessly fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first draft of this essay was 140 characters or less</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-the-first-draft-of-this-essay-was-140-characters-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 14:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-the-first-draft-of-this-essay-was-140-characters-or-less/</guid>
      <description>From time to time I sit in front of a computer wanting to write, and nothing comes of the urge. Writing in a browser can be very hard work since every other open browser tab wants you to read, not write. You could easily spend hours clicking and not ever utter anything more complex than &#34;like&#34; or &#34;favorite&#34;.
The one place where writer&#39;s block never seems to be a problem is within Twitter, which for better or worse has been the home of 21,158 of my most pithy observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Amazing Posts EVERY TIME (and why you shouldn&#39;t)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 19:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>Mack Collier has an amazing post about how to write amazing posts. (Here, go read it.) I&#39;m here to tell you why to listen to his advice but not to write like he does.
Collier calls for an amped-up style of blog writing, one that is full of lists and awesome photographs and cheerleading enthusiasm. That&#39;s a good style to recognize, and you&#39;ll see it in some of the most popular parts of the web - the Buzzfeed or Upworthy style, with headlines like &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many publishable words can you write in a day?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-many-publishable-words-can-you-write-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 16:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-many-publishable-words-can-you-write-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a thought experiment. Sit down in the morning with a cup of coffee and a list of topics. Work through them, one at a time, coming up with and writing down 500 words or so on each topic. How many topics do you get to over the course of the day, and how long does it take you to write 500 words that make sense? Assume for the sake of argument that there&#39;s a typical number of distracting email, Twitter, and Facebook posts that you have to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small wins and writing productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 15:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-small-wins-and-writing-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m intrigued of late by the notion of &#34;small wins&#34;. This is prompted by reading Wayne Baker&#39;s book on social networks in which he quotes Karl Weick. Rather than try to solve big problems all at once, you attack them by making progress on a series of smaller more attainable goals. This keeps morale up and shows you that you&#39;re really getting somewhere, even if on the grand scale it doesn&#39;t register yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Former Ann Arbor Public Schools principal accused of plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-21-former-ann-arbor-public-schools-principal-accused-of-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll start with a confession: I don&#39;t think that plagiarism is as big a deal as some people do, especially when you are recycling your own words. (&#34;Self-plagiarism is style.&#34;) The best writers have a set of phrases that they love to use, and it&#39;s not unusual for them to pull something they&#39;ve done before and rework it a bit to suit the new occasion. This is especially true when you&#39;re writing formulaic work that&#39;s short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writer&#39;s block</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-writers-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 11:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-writers-block/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working on an assignment and I&#39;m stuck. This is an attempt to get unstuck.
The hardest part for me of working on assignments for someone else is the concern (justified or not) that the editor who is getting my work is going to be disappointed by it. I know that from past experience that&#39;s unlikely to happen on this particular gig - not that they won&#39;t see something to fix, but as long as it&#39;s turned in on time and is the right shape and size I&#39;ve had pretty good luck with getting the work approved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Markdown</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-13-learning-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-13-learning-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I have a feeling that I&#39;m going to be doing a lot more writing using the Markdown language rather than using a web based rich text editor or plain HTML. Markdown is supported by Typepad, supported by Octopress (with a bunch of enhancements), supported by Github (with a few changes to be more code-friendly), supported by Vim (with colorizing of text), and supported by Leanpub (which turns them into EPUB and MOBI files).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFC 3 on content standards (or lack of them) as a model for blogging</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-rfc-3-on-content-standards-or-lack-of-them-as-a-model-for-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 15:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-rfc-3-on-content-standards-or-lack-of-them-as-a-model-for-blogging/</guid>
      <description>The original standards for the content of the RFC series, from RFC 3 by Steve Crocker, 1969. Note that these are also good standards for blogging.  CONTENT  The content of a NWG note may be any thought, suggestion, etc. related to the HOST software or other aspect of the network. Notes are encouraged to be timely rather than polished. Philosophical positions without examples or other specifics, specific suggestions or implementation techniques without introductory or background explication, and explicit questions without any attempted answers are all acceptable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing to remember, writing to forget</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 17:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-writing-to-remember-writing-to-forget/</guid>
      <description>This weblog is an unpolished open notebook. It&amp;#39;s primarily full of two things: things I want to remember, and things I want to forget. Let me explain. A weblog is an augmented memory for those fleeting moments of life where you really wish you had some record of, and where you know that if you don&amp;#39;t write it down now it&amp;#39;ll be gone forever. It&amp;#39;s the capture place for that initial review of a piece of software you might or might not grow fond of, the record of what was talked about at a particularly interesting lunch meeting, or the color of a late spring sky (grey, with low clouds; good strawberry picking weather if the rain holds off, but not good for ripening the strawberries).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jay Gatsby - the Wikipedia page from 2009, as edited by Dan Murphy, before the wikivandals took over</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</guid>
      <description>Dan Murphy wrote this biography of the fictional character Jay Gatsby for Wikipedia in 2009. Since then, the anonymous hordes of Wikipedia editors have not improved upon the page. Here is the 23 October 2009 version of &amp;quot;Jay Gatsby&amp;quot;, which is much better written than the current edition.
&amp;#0160;
Jay Gatsby&amp;#0160;is the&amp;#0160;titular character&amp;#0160;of&amp;#0160;F. Scott Fitzgerald&amp;#39;s 1925 novel&amp;#0160;The Great Gatsby. The character has become an archetype of self-made American men seeking to join&amp;#0160;High society&amp;#0160;and the name has become synonymous with successful businessmen with shady pasts in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching your fingers to think</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-01-teaching-your-fingers-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 10:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-01-teaching-your-fingers-to-think/</guid>
      <description>I do a lot of writing in vim these days, in part because my fingers already know how to make words move around on the page. I find it easier to do the work in a place where I can rely on muscle memory for routine changes rather than have to laboriously guide the mouse around to do edits.
Once upon a time there was an outlining tool called MaxThink (it still exists, for Windows only) that applied the same kind of keyboard-heavy work to outline editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the categorical imperative</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-24-losing-the-categorical-imperative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-24-losing-the-categorical-imperative/</guid>
      <description>For a long time - over 2000 posts - I have been putting blog entries into categories. The categories used to live in a long list on the right sidebar. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken them out of the sidebar, and now they&amp;rsquo;re much less visible in the user interface to the point of being invisible unless you happen to search for them.
I have touched enough categories to not be authoritative on any of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing release notes for a new version of my Michigan FOIA book, using Leanpub</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-09-writing-release-notes-for-a-new-version-of-my-michigan-foia-book-using-leanpub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 11:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-09-writing-release-notes-for-a-new-version-of-my-michigan-foia-book-using-leanpub/</guid>
      <description>The book is my&amp;#0160;No-Nonsense Guide to the Michigan Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), which I&amp;#39;m publishing (early) and updating (as its written) using Leanpub. Here&amp;#39;s what I sent out to subscribers - all four of them! - this morning.
I&amp;#39;m happy to have a chance to keep working on this, since even the smallest amount of money from new sales covers the direct costs &amp;#0160;of coffee to do the writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>note to self on the writing for the day</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-22-note-to-self-on-the-writing-for-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 22:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-22-note-to-self-on-the-writing-for-the-day/</guid>
      <description>One cup of coffee generated about 1400 words. Of those, I needed about 1000. It took three hours to write the 1400 words, and two hours more to remove 400 of them. I hope I removed the right ones.
It only took forty five words to summarize the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletionism, or the grim reaper</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-02-deletionism-or-the-grim-reaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 12:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-02-deletionism-or-the-grim-reaper/</guid>
      <description>There is a tremendous appeal to the deletionist point of view.  I spent some time this evening improving Wikipedia by suggesting that some of its less well written articles be removed. The task was relatively simple; hit the &amp;quot;random page&amp;quot; button, read the article, decide if it is so horrible as to be unencyclopedic, and if it is then paste in the &amp;quot;please delete this&amp;quot; template and hope for the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A salute to Oulipo, providing inspiration since my keyboard is missing a key and I wonder if anyone will notice if I don&#39;t use it</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-01-a-salute-to-oulipo-providing-inspiration-since-my-keyboard-is-missing-a-key-and-i-wonder-if-anyone-w/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-01-a-salute-to-oulipo-providing-inspiration-since-my-keyboard-is-missing-a-key-and-i-wonder-if-anyone-w/</guid>
      <description>A France-based school of writing called &amp;quot;Oulipo&amp;quot; embraces a use of constraints in formal writing in order to obtain an interesting result. A most famous case is an entire novel written missing a letter &amp;quot;e&amp;quot;, and a lot of work done on writing long, elaborate palindromes. By work&amp;#39;s end, you are just amazed it&amp;#39;s possible to meet constraints of a stringent writing format.  A constraint I am working under now is an absence of an &amp;quot;h&amp;quot; key on my keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging, memory and forgetting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750-words-on-blogging-memory-and-forgetting-ive-been-blogging-for-a-long-time-and-writing-online-for-longer-than-that-27/</guid>
      <description>750 words on blogging, memory and forgetting
I&amp;#39;ve been blogging for a long time, and writing online for longer than that - 27 years of typing. In the process, a lot of it has been saved, and a lot of it has been discarded. I&amp;#39;m luckier than most to have a complete set of my writing since 2003 all in Typepad. Heaven help anyone who wrote seriously on Prodigy or Compuserve or Facebook and tried to save any of it permanently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In sitting down to write this, my goal is to write exactly one thousand words.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-22-my-goal-sitting-down-to-write-this-is-to-write-a-thousand-words-exhorting-you-to-occasionally-sit-down-and-write-long-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 17:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-22-my-goal-sitting-down-to-write-this-is-to-write-a-thousand-words-exhorting-you-to-occasionally-sit-down-and-write-long-about/</guid>
      <description>In sitting down to write this, my goal is to write exactly one thousand words. I exhort you to sit down and write long about something you are interested in rather than always confining your writing to the 140 character space that dominates contemporary social networks. Keep at it until you have reached some sizable target word count, and then trim it to size. It&amp;#39;s ok to repeat yourself along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write for multiple social media channels at once</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-how-to-write-for-multiple-social-media-channels-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-how-to-write-for-multiple-social-media-channels-at-once/</guid>
      <description>I connected my Twitter feed to my Facebook feed; now I need to learn to write for both at once. Hard to do. Is there a way to be selective?
One suggestion, from long-time blogger Prentiss Riddle, is to write things first in your weblog and then syndicate them out to wherever you want them to go. This is said to behave well with systems like Facebook that reward outbound clicks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six tabs open, and a cup of coffee next to me</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-14-six-tabs-open-and-a-cup-of-coffee-next-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 10:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-14-six-tabs-open-and-a-cup-of-coffee-next-to-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m working on a lot of things, or so it seems, but right now I just want to write.
The working environment at the moment is the Chrome browser, with 6 tabs open. Two are Gmail accounts, one is Twitter, one is the Typepad dashboard from which I&amp;#39;m writing this, and one is a Google Analtyics window set to &amp;quot;real time&amp;quot; view for Arborwiki. A sixth tab is currently on Google search, but it varies from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prompting questions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-21-prompting-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-21-prompting-questions/</guid>
      <description>For reference, here&amp;#39;s some prompting questions that are showing up in my social media streams. These change from time to time as online sites try to cajole, coerce, trigger or prompt people to participate online.
Typepad wants me to share this post, and to &amp;quot;Enter a short message about your blog post to get people excited to come read it.&amp;quot;

Facebook is asking me &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s the best thing that&amp;#39;s happened to you today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing as a way to introduce yourself</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-22-writing-as-a-way-to-introduce-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-22-writing-as-a-way-to-introduce-yourself/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m in the midst of a job hunt, and so I expect that people I talk to who don&amp;#39;t know me very well will take a look at this weblog as part of the things they look for when trying to assess who I am or to help prepare them to make small talk as a part of discussion. This is a good and useful reason to write in a weblog, to make yourself easy to strike up a conversation with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not &#34;producing content&#34;, I&#39;m writing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-01-im-not-producing-content-im-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-01-im-not-producing-content-im-writing/</guid>
      <description>For this blog, at least, I want to make it very clear: I&#39;m not &#34;producing content&#34;, I&#39;m writing. This may be in order to call out attention to the work of a friend or a client, it may be to scratch some particular itch for words that need to be said, and it may be because someone else&#39;s interests dovetail with mine. Generally I try to quote enough of what other people say to be fair to them, and to tell a part of a story that you can find only by chasing through the network looking to connect ideas together at their edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addicted to feedback</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-addicted-to-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-28-addicted-to-feedback/</guid>
      <description>If I read Facebook for too long, I want to post short quips, &amp;quot;like&amp;quot; things, and generally let people know that I exist.
If I read Twitter for too long, I want to post short quips, &amp;quot;favorite&amp;quot; things, and generally let people know that they exist.
When I sit in front of Typepad ready to type, it&amp;#39;s not always for the short post, and often it&amp;#39;s not even for an audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand resolutions vs tiny habits</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-grand-resolutions-vs-tiny-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 21:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-grand-resolutions-vs-tiny-habits/</guid>
      <description>BJ Fogg is hosting an online program in which he encourages people to produce three tiny habits that they can learn to do in the span of a week. One of the ones I&amp;#39;m trying to do, for instance, is to take my medicine after the kitchen is clean. That&amp;#39;s not a huge task - after all, the medicine cabinet is in the kitchen - but it&amp;#39;s one that anchors a little task in a place where I know I can make it happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My draft folder is overflowing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-11-my-draft-folder-is-overflowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 22:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-11-my-draft-folder-is-overflowing/</guid>
      <description>Typepad has a very convenient &amp;quot;drafts&amp;quot; folder into which you can write things that aren&amp;#39;t ready for publication yet. My drafts folder is overflowing. I suppose that means that the editor in me is looking forward to reviewing them and sending them back for revisions.
If you wait long enough between the time you write something and the time you publish it, it&amp;#39;s possible that you can make your writing enough better to be worth the wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the end of the notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 22:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-27-at-the-end-of-the-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Tasks to take on at the end of filling up a paper notebook.
 Read through the whole thing, copying out the good parts. There are bound to be enough good parts that you want to save and remember some of them, and scanning them in is one way to preserve the rough qualities. Retyping a clean copy with additional notes inspired by the original is another way to manage that same task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You own your own words, but so do I</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-you-own-your-own-words-but-so-do-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 10:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-you-own-your-own-words-but-so-do-i/</guid>
      <description>The ability (and the need) to edit other people&amp;#39;s words is a sign of power over them, especially when it can be done without leaving a trace.&amp;#0160;
The WELL, one of the ur-communities online, has this bold fundamental statement of literary authority:
 You own your own words. This means that you are responsible for the words that you post on the WELL and that reproduction of those words without your permission in any medium outside of the WELL&amp;#39;s conferencing system may be challenged by you, the author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My great weird ideas don&#39;t fit in 140 characters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-09-my-great-weird-ideas-dont-fit-in-140-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 09:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-09-my-great-weird-ideas-dont-fit-in-140-characters/</guid>
      <description>I have a brainstorm and want to capture it in a bottle before it dissipates. It&amp;#39;s impossible to fit it into a box that allows too few words. A suitably complex thought asks for at least a couple of paragraphs to stretch out its feelers and see if it grabs ahold of anything.&amp;#0160;
The Twitter input box doesn&amp;#39;t give the thought enough room to spark. It too quickly fizzles out, bumping into traffic and weather reports that ground it or pop culture that doesn&amp;#39;t pop for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-editing old work</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-re-editing-old-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-re-editing-old-work/</guid>
      <description>This weblog has more than 2000 posts in it, and from time to time I sift through it looking at old work looking to make it better.
I can see that my writing improves to the extent that I believe that other people will read it. The best written pieces are publishable, at least in the modern web sense of publishable. The ones that need improvement usually need a new lead paragraph, a bunch of formatting cleanup, and some kind of conclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish quickly, edit at leisure, make the first version coherent.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 22:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</guid>
      <description>Publish quickly. The network rewards the first person to show up on the scene to describe what is going on, and it&amp;#39;s important to get a version of that story underway promptly.&amp;#0160;
Edit at leisure.&amp;#0160;The editing process takes time, and it shouldn&amp;#39;t be unduly rushed. If necessary, work at it one paragraph at a time, and publish each paragraph after it is finished. Every single piece of work can be improved at any time by an edit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This mini essay is exactly 140 words.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-this-mini-essay-is-exactly-140-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 22:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-this-mini-essay-is-exactly-140-words/</guid>
      <description>The world of Twitter has an infinite demand for your 140 character episodes, but it&amp;#39;s not a satisfying place to compose something that has depth or nuance to it. My daily column of 500 words on AnnArbor.com takes an hour or more to write, and I never have the sense that I can dash it off casually.
Perhaps the best approach is to aim for a happy medium. What if the unit of composition is 140 words, not 140 characters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperlinks subvert storytelling</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-26-readwrite-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 23:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-26-readwrite-ratio/</guid>
      <description>You are given a day to produce something of interest. How much of that time should be spend reading, and how much time should be spent writing?
There is a good argument to be made that you want to minimize your research budget and maximize the number of words produced. It&amp;#39;s hard to be a productive writer when the time is spent in the inbox deleting mail or on the net looking aimlessly for something of interest, for neither mode lends itself to long stretches of concentrated thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AOL buys Huffington Post; also, piffle</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-07-aol-buys-huffington-post-also-piffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-07-aol-buys-huffington-post-also-piffle/</guid>
      <description>Paid Content, on the New Yorker&amp;#39;s Auletta&amp;#39;s take on AOL:
 Auletta, who dismisses most of AOL’s content as “piffle,” says “quality is a problem for the entire AOL (NYSE: AOL) empire.”&amp;#0160;
 And some piffle from the Huffington Post, which has elevated the SEO of inane comments to a science:
 Piffle.
What unthinking right wing piffle.
Piffle. Absolute piffle from the pifflinges­t of all British Rightwing, hate-monge­ring tabloids.&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spectral overseers as guides to good online behavior</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</guid>
      <description>James Poulos in a comment on Ricochet on the role of editors:
Writers now have competing pressures -- to be witty, quick, ironic, noticeable, flip, to dispatch every clay pigeon tossed up by a culture pandemic with pigeons; but also to self-edit, to self-moderate, to be reticent at the right time, to pussyfoot expertly, to pick battles, to avoid perils, to besmirch rarely, to duck blame, to satisfy spectral overseers. This is a serious pickle, is it not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the margin is too small to contain this</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-30-the-margin-is-too-small-to-contain-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-30-the-margin-is-too-small-to-contain-this/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to write something short and pithy and insightful for Facebook or Twitter or some other minimalist thing and couldn&amp;#39;t come up with anything. &amp;#0160;The ultrashort format is not suited to ruminations on things you don&amp;#39;t completely understand and are trying to work out in the process of writing about them.
Instead I will go for a walk.
Perhaps this is a rumination on the length of communications, their immediacy and the expected audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finding buckets to refill regularly</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-finding-buckets-to-refill-regularly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-finding-buckets-to-refill-regularly/</guid>
      <description>Much of the writing I do these days has tags but not much in the way of categories. There are a few very broad categories that things can go into, but not much in the way of narrow ones, and the world of tags means that you can always think up one more new tag to apply rather than revisiting an old one.
In some ways I miss the regular reinforcement obtained by the reminders that I&amp;#39;ve written on items in a category previously in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the old name for this blog, &#34;Vacuum&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-05-ive-changed-the-title-of-this-blog-back-to-vacuum-since-all-of-the-extra-gobbledygook-was-making-it-hard-to-bookmark-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 22:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-05-ive-changed-the-title-of-this-blog-back-to-vacuum-since-all-of-the-extra-gobbledygook-was-making-it-hard-to-bookmark-things/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve changed the title of this blog back to Vacuum, since all of the extra gobbledygook was making it hard to bookmark things.
The &#34;quick compose&#34; part of Typepad makes it easier to post things that are short that don&#39;t have titles, so I don&#39;t get stuck figuring out what the title should be and I can just type. Later, when my editor hat goes on, I go back and fix things up and decide what a title might look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing is like talking to the paper.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-25-writing-is-like-talking-to-the-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 15:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-25-writing-is-like-talking-to-the-paper/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on the virtue of cheap paper</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-on-the-virtue-of-cheap-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 16:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-on-the-virtue-of-cheap-paper/</guid>
      <description>At various times I&amp;#39;ve carried beautiful little notebooks in my pocket - fancy little bound volumes of paper designed to capture big thoughts and clever notions.&amp;#0160; So fancy (and expensive), in fact, that I felt bad about writing in them unless there was something so clever that it deserved being saved into perpetuity.
It was thus reassuring and helpful to go into a big box office supply store and get a modest supply of cheap disposable spiral bound pads, with paper so cheap that it is clear that they are designed to be used and then tossed when you are done with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretending to be on an airplane</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-pretending-to-be-on-an-airplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-pretending-to-be-on-an-airplane/</guid>
      <description>I was on a trip to Rhode Island last week for a conference (RILA09). That gave me a chance to enter &amp;ldquo;airplane mode&amp;rdquo;, that rare time in my life when I have lots of time to spend in contemplation but very little network connectivity. And I have to say, I enjoy that time immensely, perhaps more than I enjoy any individual hour trying to be engaged with the net.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog more, twitter less</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-15-blog-more-twitter-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 13:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-15-blog-more-twitter-less/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s an easy recipe for keeping your habits for writing longer format pieces than the 140 character limits of Twitter will allow.
1.&amp;#0160; Write the pithy 140 character Twitter piece, though limit it for a few other technical reasons to 120 or so, better for others to copy.
2.&amp;#0160; Use the headline as a key part of a longer piece that you&amp;#39;ve always wanted to write.&amp;#0160; It might be a punch line inside, it might be a jumping off point for an essay on something completely different, or it might simply be a straightforward summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write for the web -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-21-how-to-write-for-the-web-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-21-how-to-write-for-the-web-/</guid>
      <description>Writing for the Internet is not the same as writing for print.&amp;#0160; Here are ten rules of thumb that will help you shape your writing that&amp;#39;s designed for the screen and to help you adapt and reform words that were first printed out in ways that make them easier to manage.
 The paragraph is the unit of composition.&amp;#0160; Keep your paragraphs together, making it possible to have any one of them pulled out and quoted in some other part of the internet without losing too much in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to future self: on planning ahead and making sense</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-note-to-self-on-organizing-communicating-and-noting-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-05-note-to-self-on-organizing-communicating-and-noting-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>This blog serves a couple of functions, not all of which are sensibly part of the same easy to define train of thought. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;note to self&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;note to future self&amp;rdquo;, for the sorts of things that I want to publicly remember so that I can find them again. It&amp;rsquo;s notes about places I&amp;rsquo;d aspire to be and events I&amp;rsquo;d like to go to. And some of it is research in progress, in which I get interested enough in something to write down what I find out about it and then wait for searchers to come up with good questions that find it (and more) so I can learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogger&#39;s secret: note to future self</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-06-bloggers-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 14:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-06-bloggers-secret/</guid>
      <description>Part of an occasional &amp;quot;blogger&#39;s secret&amp;quot; series.
Write for yourself. Really, you are best off with an audience of one to start, and use your time and effort to write down things that you will want to read in a week or a month or a year. If you are interesting to your audience of one, you have some hope of being interesting to some other person somewhere else on the planet who is interested in you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blogger&#39;s Secret: Repetition is the very soul of the net</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-08-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 23:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-08-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Repetition the very soul of the net.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp; alt.config
&amp;quot;Self-plagiarism is style.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp; Alfred Hitchcock.
thus repeating a blog post from a while ago, which just came to mind as I was looking a postcard that someone sent to me in March after reading this list.
Ten secrets to success (or, ten things that I aspire to doing regularly)  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;  1.&amp;nbsp; Send a postcard.  2.&amp;nbsp; Go for a walk.  3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the blogger&#39;s secret: how to write a great weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Write well, write often, and write with passion.&amp;quot; (Jack Shedd)
Jack has more in a rant that&amp;#39;s making the rounds; the opposite of the great weblog is the &amp;quot;cheese food manufacturing&amp;quot; that Merlin Mann observes as dominating the world of &amp;quot;pro bloggers&amp;quot;.
In some sense, this triple of {well, often, with passion} echoes the computer systems lament of {better, faster, cheaper} - &amp;quot;pick any two&amp;quot; is the easiest answer. It&amp;#39;s possible to write often and well, but what you get is a wire service, with a style guide that homogenizes the passion right out of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>threequel === threequal - of movies, code, and the l33t</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-19-threequel-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 18:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-19-threequel-three/</guid>
      <description>A few definitions for you, with citations from the wild; spelling is as in the original with Google counts of occurences, if possible.
In short: threequel and 3quel are about movies; threequal is the &#34;===&#34; operator; 3qual is hacker speak. More or less.
threequel (33,900): When I was a kid, I assumed all third installments in a horror series had to capitalize on the ability to turn the “3″ in the title into “3-D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: how to be an expert about anything</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>You can be an expert with the blogger&#39;s secret:
1. Pick a topic.
2. Write about it twice a day.
3. At the end of six months, you will be an expert.
Note well: choose carefully what you want to be an expert about! It&#39;s mighty hard to be an expert about more than one thing this way, just because it consumes so much time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of the hand-written note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 09:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</guid>
      <description>I used to send a lot more postcards, back in the day when I was on airplanes all the time.
 Jason Womack sends this out in his newsletter recently, about holiday cards and card writing in general:  Chances are however you celebrate the closing of one year and the opening of another, you will connect with more people in your network during the holiday season. People wonder how I have time for it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>