<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finn Brunton on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/finn-brunton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finn Brunton on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 12:18:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/finn-brunton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Insane coin posse</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-insane-coin-posse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 12:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-insane-coin-posse/</guid>
      <description>The latest in cryptocurrencies is the Juggalocoin, proposed to handle the transactional needs of the fans of the Insane Clown Posse. From Billboard (because after all this is an entertainment story):
 Whoop whoop! A very tech-savvy Juggalo by the name of Papa Nutt has taken it upon himself to create a cryptocurrency specifically for Faygo-chugging devotees of &#34;the Family&#34; to buy goods and services with*, especially at the upcoming Gathering of the Juggalos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 3, 2014: Finn Brunton on Cryptocurrencies, North Quad Space 2435, 4:00 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-april-3-2014-finn-brunton-on-cryptocurrencies-north-quad-space-2435-400-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-april-3-2014-finn-brunton-on-cryptocurrencies-north-quad-space-2435-400-pm/</guid>
      <description>This wide-ranging talk uses the current state of cryptocurrencies (most notably Bitcoin) and their underlying technologies to consider contemporary digital culture and its future. Professor Finn Brunton will discuss peer-to-peer networks, public key cryptography, proof-of-work systems, and the blockchain, illuminating their underlying social, political, and theoretical models and concepts. We will travel from sixth century Chang&#39;an, seventeenth century Switzerland, and the vault of the New York Federal Reserve to IRC channels, software development communities, and closely guarded facilities in Iceland and Hong Kong to understand a system with fascinating implications for identity, ownership, authorship and trust online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African National Congress Secret Communications: &#34;Operation Vula&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-09-african-national-congress-secret-communications-operation-vula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 23:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-09-african-national-congress-secret-communications-operation-vula/</guid>
      <description>Talking to Vula is the story of the secret communications network of Operation Vula, a project of the African National Congress that facilitated clandestine messaging between South African exiles in London and leaders of the resistance in Zambia and in South Africa. The account (which was pointed out to me by Finn Brunton) talks of an inventive use of encrypted text transmitted via analog modem tones recorded to cassette tape and then played back via untraceable pay phones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet - Finn Brunton - MIT Press - 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</guid>
      <description>Finn Brunton has a new book out, called &amp;quot;Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet&amp;quot;, published by the MIT Press. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading it this summer.
Some radio interviews about the book:
An interview with NPR&amp;#39;s Scott Simon on Weekend Edition.
CBC&amp;#39;s Spark, in 2010.
and some print:
Roar so wildly: spam, technology and language. From Radical Philosophy 2010.
This is the raw text output of a chat session with a bot I modified to act as an interlocutor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finn Brunton, The Accidental Archive. Notes on a talk Monday January 28 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-28-finn-brunton-the-accidental-archive-notes-on-a-talk-monday-january-28-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-28-finn-brunton-the-accidental-archive-notes-on-a-talk-monday-january-28-2013/</guid>
      <description>Finn Brunton, U-M Assistant Professor of Information, will present &amp;quot;The Accidental Archive.&amp;quot; Brunton&amp;#39;s talk, with the alternative title &amp;quot;Researching criminals, otherkin, cipher anarchists, spammers and the online history that doesn&amp;#39;t want to be kept,&amp;quot; kicks off a new series of monthly events addressing emergent research. Light refreshments will be served.
Notes to follow. There&amp;#39;s a hashtag, #MLibRes, on which a half dozen people are tracking. This is an impressionistic transcript, not a summary or tidy narrative, more notes drawn from what I remember from the time and some of my own thoughts mixed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finn Brunton on spam; interview with CBC Radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-17-finn-brunton-on-spam-interview-with-cbc-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 23:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-17-finn-brunton-on-spam-interview-with-cbc-radio/</guid>
      <description>Noted: Finn Brunton&amp;#39;s 2009 CBC Radio interview on the unintended consequences of spam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>