<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Meloche on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-meloche/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tom Meloche on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-meloche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for August 6, 2015 at Mi Compadre</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;a2b3&lt;/span&gt; lunch this week was at
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Mi Compadre&lt;/span&gt;, a Mexican place on Packard.
We had a good turnout. I recommend the lengua tacos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was inspired this week for the lunch question by
going to the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Workantile&lt;/span&gt; lunch on Wednesday,
which followed the same general pattern - sit down, introduce
yourself around the table, and answer some simple question.
At Workantile the prompt was simply &amp;ldquo;share something nice that happened to you this week&amp;rdquo;,
and that was enough of a prompt for everyone to be brief and cheery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When lunches are well attended, it seems to be that it happens
because the news gets out in plenty of time and plenty of detail
on Facebook. Not everyone in my world does Facebook, but there&amp;rsquo;s
more people there than on Twitter or Meetup, and it appears that
Facebook might now have the tools for lunch organizing that it didn&amp;rsquo;t
have a year ago when I started using Meetup for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the help of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Tom Meloche&lt;/span&gt; it looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going
to move the primary ritual of notifying people where the next meeting is
through a Facebook event, and move away from Meetup as the primary organizing
tool. That&amp;rsquo;s going to take a few months to pull off but it looks like
the right organizing tool for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss the olden days when &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;eGroups&lt;/span&gt; was so novel that
you could build an instant community around an easy to run mailing
list. Yahoo so completely missed the boat when they turned that
into Yahoo Groups over a decade ago. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 Yahoo group&lt;/a&gt; around indefinitely -
it&amp;rsquo;s free after all, and it&amp;rsquo;s old - but it&amp;rsquo;s not growing and
working on a system that doesn&amp;rsquo;t support growth is a recipe for
stagnatation. Where I used to count on a new person every week from
Yahoo Groups I now only get 10-15 new subscribers a year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>