<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Council on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/ann-arbor-city-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Council on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/ann-arbor-city-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Preview for 17 August 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council meets at 7:00 p.m. on Monday, 17 August 2015. A preview of the agenda is on Arborwiki, complete with a map, on the tag 2015-08-17CCMTG.
Some highlights to note:
The consent agenda includes $36,412 for the purchase of 21 Taser weapons. This is a sole-source purchase, to replace weapons purchased in 2003.
Also on the consent agenda is $83,000 for a sole-source purchase to renew the CityWorks license, which is used for asset tracking and maintenance of city owned resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council highlights for 5 January 2015, a preview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:33:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council is meeting tonight, 5 January 2015, at 7:00 p.m. the Washtenaw County Administration Building. Here are some highlights from the agenda.
Three public hearings are on the docket. The public will get a chance to weigh in on a proposed amendment to the chicken-keeping ordinance and two hearings on downtown zoning.
The chicken-keeping ordinance (Section 107) would be amended to allow people to keep 6 chickens instead of the current 4, and to allow people to keep chickens without getting the mandatory consent of the neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a public meeting with five windows open to the world -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor City Council holds meetings twice each month, which are streamed online through the city&amp;#39;s CTN network. I tuned in last night on my laptop to listen and watch.
While I was listening, I had a few other windows open on my computer. First and foremost, I had a twitter stream that I was watching for the #a2council&amp;#0160;hash tag; that caught commentary from a few other people who were watching at home, plus some reporters in the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meetings now simulcast online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council meetings are now simulcast online, which is handy if you don&amp;#39;t get local CTN cable service. &amp;#0160;This link
http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html
goes to an experimental setup which also tracks the Twitter #aacitycouncil tag.
The CTN Meetingplace page now hosts the current broadcast (both live and delayed) for CTN Channel 16. Meetings are held the first and third Monday nights of the month starting at 7:00 p.m., unless they aren&amp;#39;t for some reason like a holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council, agenda, Feb 2 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</guid>
      <description>This is the January 29, 2009 draft of the Feb 2, 2009 Ann Arbor City Council agenda, as retrieved from the city web site.&amp;#0160; Any errors in transcription from PDF to text are my own; there are some small number of edits throughout, clearly marked, including hyperlinks as appropriate.
My copy of the PDF had various bits redacted, or at least it looked like they were redacted; in fact these are hyperlinks to the underlying documents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>