<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/ann-arbor-city-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Council on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/ann-arbor-city-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Preview for 17 August 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-15-a2council-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Council meets at 7:00 p.m. on Monday, 17 August 2015.
A preview of the agenda is on Arborwiki, complete with a map, on the
tag &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/tags/20150817ccmtg&#34;&gt;2015-08-17CCMTG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some highlights to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consent agenda includes $36,412 for the purchase of 21 Taser weapons.
This is a sole-source purchase, to replace weapons purchased in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also on the consent agenda is $83,000 for a sole-source purchase to
renew the CityWorks license, which is used for asset tracking and
maintenance of city owned resources. Of that amount, $20,000 will be
billed back to the Washtenaw County Water Resources Commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$110,000 would go for the continuation of CLEMIS Public Safety Information
Sharing Services for the Ann Arbor Police Department for FY2016. CLEMIS
runs the dispatch system for police and allows &amp;ldquo;information sharing&amp;rdquo;
with other departments. It&amp;rsquo;s run by Oakland County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HathiTrust has digitized many decades of Ann Arbor City Council minutes,
and it it proposed that the city approve publication of those minutes through
HathiTrust by clearing the copyright on those materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public hearings include one on deer management, and there&amp;rsquo;s a proposal
on the agenda to spend $90,000 on some combination of a deer cull by
sharpshooters and sterlization of deer. Expect this to be a long public
hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In development news, there&amp;rsquo;s a proposed condominium development on N Main St
adjacent to North Main Park, and hearings on proposed annexations on Nixon
Road and on Ann Arbor - Saline Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re following the footing drain disconnect program closely, you&amp;rsquo;ll
note that there&amp;rsquo;s a proposal to lend the builder of 618 South Main
footing drain disconnect credits to allow for full occupancy of that building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More of course at the full agenda. See you on the site plan barricades
(er, see you at council).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a public meeting with five windows open to the world -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor City Council holds meetings twice each month, which are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/meetingplace/Pages/TheMeetingPlace.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;streamed online through the city&amp;#39;s CTN network&lt;/a&gt;. I tuned in last night on my laptop to listen and watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was listening, I had a few other windows open on my computer. First and foremost, I had a twitter stream that I was watching for the #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23a2council&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;hash tag; that caught commentary from a few other people who were watching at home, plus some reporters in the audience. The running cmmentary made it easier to follow what was going on, and it served as a back channel to help make sense of the proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The council was working from an agenda that&amp;#39;s in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Legistar system&lt;/a&gt;, and from time to time I&amp;#39;d go back to that to see what the text of an agenda item was, to look at supporting materials, and see the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor Chronicle does near-real-time news coverage as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/category/civic-news-ticker/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Civic News Ticker&lt;/a&gt;, reporting out results from key votes and decisions during the meeting. This is brief coverage but important, and it sets the stage for their 10,000 word meeting reports that come out a week or so later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I had a window open to &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, which has a local encyclopedia of information about what is going on in the city and the surrounding area. As council considered various options, I looked up what Arborwiki had to say about the current state of affairs, and updated it as best I could to reflect the meeting results and the news that was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure that watching this multi-connected stream was different from the experience of being in the same room as council. You miss the non-verbal communications, the body language, the hallway conversations that take place during breaks, and all sorts of in-person nuance. But for what it was, I&amp;#39;m pretty happy with the experience. It felt like I was engaged with the meeting and could have a sense that I was part of the civic process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meetings now simulcast online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/citycouncil/Pages/Home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor City Council&lt;/a&gt; meetings are now simulcast online, which is handy if you don&amp;#39;t get local CTN cable service. &amp;#0160;This link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;goes to an experimental setup which also tracks the Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23aacitycouncil&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;#aacitycouncil&lt;/a&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/meetingplace/Pages/TheMeetingPlace.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;CTN Meetingplace&lt;/a&gt; page now hosts the current broadcast (both live and delayed) for CTN Channel 16. Meetings are held the first and third Monday nights of the month starting at 7:00 p.m., unless they aren&amp;#39;t for some reason like a holiday. There is a meeting today, May 23, 2011, which is a continuation of budget-related issues that were left unresolved at the May 16, 2011 meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Legistar at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://a2gov.legistar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for the calendar and agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Agendas can and do change up until the last moment, and it&amp;#39;s impossible to know ahead of time whether your topic of burning interest will be addressed at any given meeting. Watching online, and ensuring that you have a person who is tracking your issue close enough to city hall to get to council chambers, can be an alternative to sitting in the pews every other Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council, agenda, Feb 2 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-29-ann-arbor-city-council-draft-agenda-feb-2-2009-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the January 29, 2009 draft of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/meetings/2009/2/3046_A_City_Council_09-02-02_Meeting_Agenda.pdf&#34;&gt;Feb 2, 2009 Ann Arbor City Council agenda, as retrieved from the city web site.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160; Any errors in transcription from PDF to text are my own; there are some small number of edits throughout, clearly marked, including hyperlinks as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My copy of the PDF had various bits redacted, or at least it looked like they were redacted; in fact these are hyperlinks to the underlying documents.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ll try to preserve as much of that as I have patience for but you&amp;#39;d be better off fetching the original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;City Council &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor &lt;br /&gt;Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;100 N. Fifth Avenue &lt;br /&gt;Ann Arbor, MI&amp;#0160; 48104 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org%20&#34;&gt;www.a2gov.org &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;G. C. Larcom, Jr. Municipal Bldg. 2nd Flr. &lt;br /&gt;7:00 PM &lt;br /&gt;Monday, February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;CALL TO ORDER &lt;br /&gt;MOMENT OF SILENCE &lt;br /&gt;PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE &lt;br /&gt;ROLL CALL OF COUNCIL &lt;br /&gt;APPROVAL OF AGENDA &lt;br /&gt;INT INTRODUCTIONS &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3695&#34;&gt;INT-1 09-0006&lt;/a&gt; Environmental Assessment Process for Airport Improvements &lt;br /&gt;(Public Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;PUBLIC COMMENTARY - RESERVED TIME (3 MINUTES PER SPEAKER) &lt;br /&gt;* (SPEAKERS ARE NOT PERMITTED TO GRANT THEIR RESERVED TIME TO AN &lt;br /&gt;ALTERNATE SPEAKER) &lt;br /&gt;* ACCOMMODATIONS HAVE BEEN MADE FOR PERSONS NEEDING ASSISTANCE &lt;br /&gt;WHILE ADDRESSING COUNCIL &lt;br /&gt;PH PUBLIC HEARINGS (3 MINUTES PER SPEAKER) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3706&#34;&gt;PH-1 09-0059 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the Gas Station/Tim Hortons Site Plan, 1.32 &lt;br /&gt;Acres, 3240 Washtenaw Avenue, (CPC Recommendation:&amp;#0160; Approval - 8 &lt;br /&gt;Yeas and 1 Nay) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See DB-1) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3753&#34;&gt;PH-2 09-0060 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the Wintermeyer Office Building Phase 2 &lt;br /&gt;Planned Project Site Plan, 1.87-Acres, 2144 and 2178 South State &lt;br /&gt;Street, (CPC Recommendation: Approval - 9 Yeas and 0 Nays) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See DB-2) &lt;br /&gt;Page 1 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3763&#34;&gt;PH-3 09-0063&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Modify Fees at the City Golf Courses Effective for the &lt;br /&gt;2009 Golf Season and Increase the Senior Citizen Qualification Age &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See DS-9) &lt;br /&gt;COMMUNICATIONS FROM COUNCIL &lt;br /&gt;A APPROVAL OF COUNCIL MINUTES &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3779&#34;&gt;A-1 09-0077&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;City Council Regular Session Minutes of January 20, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk - Jacqueline Beaudry) &lt;br /&gt;CA CONSENT AGENDA &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3751&#34;&gt;CA-1 09-0058 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution Recognizing Vincent York&amp;#39;s Jazzistry as a Civic Nonprofit &lt;br /&gt;Organization Operating in Ann Arbor for the Purpose of Obtaining a &lt;br /&gt;Charitable Gaming License &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk - Jacqueline Beaudry) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3757&#34;&gt;CA-2 09-0062 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution Recognizing The Ann Arbor Art Center as a Civic Nonprofit &lt;br /&gt;Organization Operating in Ann Arbor for the Purpose of Obtaining a &lt;br /&gt;Charitable Gaming License &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk - Jacqueline Beaudry) &lt;br /&gt;B ORDINANCES - SECOND READING &lt;br /&gt;C ORDINANCES - FIRST READING &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3680&#34;&gt;C-1 08-1167 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An Ordinance to Amend Chapter 26, Solid Waste Ordinance, Sections &lt;br /&gt;2:1, 2:2, 2:3, 2:5, 2:7, 2:9, 2:10 and 2:13 to Implement Commercial &lt;br /&gt;Recycling Recommendations &lt;br /&gt;(Systems Planning Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3749&#34;&gt;C-2 09-0055 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An Ordinance to Amend Chapter 55, Section 5:110 to Allow Certain &lt;br /&gt;Zoning Petitions to be Waived from Citizens Participation Requirements &lt;br /&gt;(CPC Recommendation: Approval - 9 Yeas and 0 Nay) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;D MOTIONS AND RESOLUTIONS &lt;br /&gt;DC New Business - Council: &lt;br /&gt;Page 2 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3767&#34;&gt;DC-1 09-0065 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution Establishing the Line of Succession to the Emergency &lt;br /&gt;Management Director for the City of Ann Arbor Office of Emergency &lt;br /&gt;Management &lt;br /&gt;(City Council - Lt. Myron Blackwell, Safety Services) &lt;br /&gt;Sponsors: Hieftje &lt;br /&gt;DB New Business - Boards and Commissions: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3706&#34;&gt;DB-1 09-0059 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the Gas Station/Tim Hortons Site Plan, 1.32 &lt;br /&gt;Acres, 3240 Washtenaw Avenue, (CPC Recommendation:&amp;#0160; Approval - 8 &lt;br /&gt;Yeas and 1 Nay) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See PH-1) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3753&#34;&gt;DB-2 09-0060 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the Wintermeyer Office Building Phase 2 &lt;br /&gt;Planned Project Site Plan, 1.87-Acres, 2144 and 2178 South State &lt;br /&gt;Street, (CPC Recommendation: Approval - 9 Yeas and 0 Nays) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See PH-2) &lt;br /&gt;DS Old Business - Staff: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3655&#34;&gt;DS-1 08-1147&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve a Grant Contract with the Michigan Department &lt;br /&gt;of Transportation for Work Related to the Environmental Assessment &lt;br /&gt;and Preliminary Engineering for the Safety Extension of Runway 6/24 at &lt;br /&gt;the Ann Arbor Municipal Airport ($179,000.00) &lt;br /&gt;(Fleet &amp;amp; Facilities Services - Sue F. McCormck, Public Services Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(Postponed from the 1/20/09 Regular Session) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3657&#34;&gt;DS-2 08-1148&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve a Grant Contract with the Michigan Department &lt;br /&gt;of Transportation for Work Related to the Environmental Assessment &lt;br /&gt;and Integrated Noise Modeling for the Safety Extension of Runway 6/24 &lt;br /&gt;at the Ann Arbor Municipal Airport ($75,000.00) &lt;br /&gt;(Fleet &amp;amp; Facilities Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(Postponed from the 1/20/09 Regular Session) &lt;br /&gt;Page 3 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3653&#34;&gt;DS-3 08-1144 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the October 2008 Professional Services &lt;br /&gt;Agreement between the City and URS Corporation Great Lakes for &lt;br /&gt;Work Related to the Environmental Assessment and Preliminary &lt;br /&gt;Engineering for the Safety Extension of Runway 6/24 at the Ann Arbor &lt;br /&gt;Municipal Airport ($186,000.00)&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;(Public Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(Postponed from the 1/20/09 Regular Session) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3654&#34;&gt;DS-4 08-1145 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the December 16, 2008 Professional Services &lt;br /&gt;Agreement between the City and Smith Group JJR, LLC for Work &lt;br /&gt;Related to the Environmental Assessment for the Safety Extension of &lt;br /&gt;Runway 6/24 at the Ann Arbor Municipal Airport ($112,489.53)&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;(Fleet &amp;amp; Facilities Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(Postponed from the 1/20/09 Regular Session) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3674&#34;&gt;DS-5 08-1162 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve Amendment No. 1 to Existing Professional &lt;br /&gt;Services Contract with Beckett &amp;amp; Raeder, Inc. to Increase the Contract &lt;br /&gt;Budget by $122,862.62 for a Total Contract Amount of $232,246.62,&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;Accept and Appropriate&amp;#0160; $13,538.67 Grant from the DDA, Appropriate &lt;br /&gt;$30,661.97 from the Market Fund Fund Balance, Transfer $48,000.00 &lt;br /&gt;from the Stormwater Fund FY09 Operations and Maintenance Budget, &lt;br /&gt;Appropriate&amp;#0160; $30,661.98 from the Parks Rehabilitation and Development &lt;br /&gt;Millage Fund Balance, and Appropriate $122,862.62 from the Parks &lt;br /&gt;Rehabilitation and Development Millage to the Farmers Market Master &lt;br /&gt;Plan Construction Design Project Budget to Create a Total Project &lt;br /&gt;Budget of $2,056,900.00 (8 Votes Required) &lt;br /&gt;(Parks and Recreation Services - Jayne Miller, Community Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(Postponed from the 1/20/09 Regular Session) &lt;br /&gt;New Business - Staff: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3764&#34;&gt;DS-6 09-0064 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve an Amendment to the Construction Manager &lt;br /&gt;Agreement with Clark Construction Co. for the Courts/Police Building &lt;br /&gt;($35,874,422.00) &lt;br /&gt;(Public Services - Sue F. McCormick, Public Services Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3701&#34;&gt;DS-7 09-0012 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Approve the Management Agreement with Washtenaw &lt;br /&gt;County to Administer the Barrier Busters Program and to Release the &lt;br /&gt;Fund Balance of $10,636.00 in the Ann Arbor Assistance Fund (0038) to &lt;br /&gt;Washtenaw County ($10,636.00 Ann Arbor Assistance Fund) (8 Votes &lt;br /&gt;Required) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;Page 4 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3684&#34;&gt;DS-8 08-1171 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution Accepting the Warranty Deed from Charter Oak Homes, Inc. &lt;br /&gt;(Mallets Creek Park) (8 votes Required) &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3763&#34;&gt;DS-9 09-0063 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Resolution to Modify Fees at the City Golf Courses Effective for the &lt;br /&gt;2009 Golf Season and Increase the Senior Citizen Qualification Age &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;(See PH-3) &lt;br /&gt;E COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE MAYOR &lt;br /&gt;COMMUNICATIONS FROM COUNCIL &lt;br /&gt;F COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE CITY ADMINISTRATOR &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3682&#34;&gt;F-1 08-1169 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;City-County Shared IT Data Center &lt;br /&gt;(Information Technology Services - Dan Rainey, ITSD Director) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3750&#34;&gt;F-2 09-0057 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fourth Quarter 2008 Investment Portfolio Report &lt;br /&gt;(Financial and Administrative Services - Tom Crawford, CFO) &lt;br /&gt;G COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE CITY ATTORNEY &lt;br /&gt;H &amp;amp; I CLERK&amp;#39;S REPORT OF COMMUNICATIONS, PETITIONS AND REFERRALS &lt;br /&gt;H The following communications were referred as indicated: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3777&#34;&gt;H-1 09-0075 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Communication from SEMCOG regarding their Regional Update &lt;br /&gt;Biweekly Publication of SEMCOG, Vol. 14, No. 1, January 12, 2009 - &lt;br /&gt;File &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3778&#34;&gt;H-2 09-0076 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Communication from Washtenaw County Administrator Robert E. &lt;br /&gt;Gunzel, regarding an opportunity to discuss future collaborations &lt;br /&gt;between Washtenaw County and the City - File &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk) &lt;br /&gt;I The following minutes were received for file: &lt;br /&gt;Page 5 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3702&#34;&gt;I-1 09-0013 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Recreation Advisory Commission Minutes - December 2, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(Community Services - Jayne Miller, Area Administrator) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3709&#34;&gt;I-2 09-0016 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Council Liquor License Review Committee - December 12, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk - Jacqueline Beaudry) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3716&#34;&gt;I-3 09-0022 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority Minutes - December 3, &lt;br /&gt;2008 &lt;br /&gt;(Downtown Development Authority - Susan Pollay, Executive Director) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3717&#34;&gt;I-4 09-0023&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Downtown Area Citizens Advisory Council Minutes December 3, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(Downtown Development Authority - Susan Pollay, Executive Director) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3720&#34;&gt;I-5 09-0026 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greenbelt Advisory Minutes of November 5, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(City Clerk) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3747&#34;&gt;I-6 09-0053&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Employees&amp;#39; Retirement System Minutes - December &lt;br /&gt;18, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(Employees&amp;#39; Retirement System Board of Trustees - Willie Powell, Executive Director)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;{{{ &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;editor&amp;#39;s note: an excerpt from this document &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;F-2 Preliminary Investment Reports for the Month Ended November 30, &lt;br /&gt;2008 &lt;br /&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;N. Gail Jarskey, Accountant, submitted the Financial Report for the month ended &lt;br /&gt;November 30, 2008, to the Board of Trustees: &lt;br /&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;11/30/2008 Asset Value (Preliminary) $313,998,772 &lt;br /&gt;10/31/2008 Asset Value (Audited by Northern) $332,722,023 &lt;br /&gt;Calendar YTD Increase/Decrease in Assets&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;(excludes non-investment receipts and disbursements) ($116,890,427) &lt;br /&gt;Percent Gain &amp;lt;Loss&amp;gt; -26.3% &lt;br /&gt;December 17, 2008 Asset Value $ 315,700,984 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;}}}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.a2gov.org/legistar/detailreport/matter.aspx?key=3748&#34;&gt;I-7 09-0054 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Retiree Health Care Benefit Plan &amp;amp; Trust Minutes - &lt;br /&gt;December 18, 2008 &lt;br /&gt;(Employees&amp;#39; Retirement System Board of Trustees - Willie Powell, Executive Director) &lt;br /&gt;PUBLIC COMMENT - GENERAL (3 MINUTES EACH) &lt;br /&gt;CLOSED SESSION TO DISCUSS PENDING LITIGATION AND ATTORNEY / CLIENT &lt;br /&gt;PRIVILEGED COMMUNICATION AND/OR LAND ACQUISITION &lt;br /&gt;ADJOURNMENT &lt;br /&gt;COMMUNITY TELEVISION NETWORK (CTN) CABLE CHANNEL 16: &lt;br /&gt;LIVE:&amp;#0160; MONDAY, FEBRUARY 2, 2009; 7:00 PM &lt;br /&gt;REPLAYS:&amp;#0160; TUESDAY, FEBRUARY 3, 2009 10:00 AM AND FRIDAY FEBRUARY 6, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;7:30 PM &lt;br /&gt;REPLAYS SUBJECT TO CHANGE WITHOUT NOTICE &lt;br /&gt;Page 6 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;br /&gt;February 2, 2009 &lt;br /&gt;City Council Meeting Agenda &lt;br /&gt;Persons with disabilities are encouraged to participate.&amp;#0160; Accommodations, including &lt;br /&gt;sign language interpreters, may be arranged by contacting the City Clerk&amp;#39;s Office by &lt;br /&gt;telephone at 734-794-6140 or by written request addressed to the City Clerk&amp;#39;s Office, &lt;br /&gt;100 N. Fifth Ave., Ann Arbor, MI&amp;#0160; 48104, at least 24 hours in advance. &lt;br /&gt;A hard copy of this Council packet can be viewed at the front counter of the City &lt;br /&gt;Clerk&amp;#39;s office. &lt;br /&gt;Page 7 &lt;br /&gt;City of Ann Arbor Printed on 1/29/2009&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>