<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oklahoma on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/oklahoma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oklahoma on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:23:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/oklahoma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>September 3, 2016 Oklahoma earthquakes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-oklahoma-earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>A magnitude 5.6 earthquake rattled oil country in Oklahoma on September 3, 2016 at 7:02 a.m. The quake&amp;rsquo;s epicenter was eight miles northwest of Pawnee, OK. The USGS maps of the quake are detailed.
The Pawnee Nation declared a state of emergency after ordering evacuations of damaged buildings in the area.
Historically, the incidence of earthquakes in Oklahoma is low, and there is concern in the state that these earthquakes are of man-made origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan softball team in severe weather in Oklahoma City on May 31, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-31-university-of-michigan-softball-team-in-severe-weather-in-oklahoma-city-on-may-31-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 20:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-31-university-of-michigan-softball-team-in-severe-weather-in-oklahoma-city-on-may-31-2013/</guid>
      <description>The University of Michigan softball team is in Oklahoma City for the Women&#39;s College World Series games. They were caught in the May 31, 2013 tornadoes in that area. The team, along with other teams in the games took shelter in an underground parking garage.
News coverage: WXYZ/AP.
We have moves back into the underground garage as a precautionary measure #OKC
&amp;mdash; Michigan Softball (@umichsoftball) June 1, 2013 Michigan players getting comfortable in the underground garage #OKC twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 Moore Oklahoma tornado path map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-21-2013-moore-oklahoma-tornado-path-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 14:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-21-2013-moore-oklahoma-tornado-path-map/</guid>
      <description>This map from the National Weather Service in Norman, Oklahoma (via Atlantic Cities) shows the destructive path of the Moore, Oklahoma tornado of 20 May 2013. This is a preliminary map that also shows the track of a 3 May 1999 tornado that followed a very similar path.
 
There&amp;#39;s too much graphic, devastating imagery from the scene which I won&amp;#39;t include here. Dr Jeff Masters has an excellent overview of the meteorology of the event, including accounts of debris being thrown 100 miles in the air to land on Tulsa, Oklahoma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oklahoma earthquakes, November 5-7 2011 and historical</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-06-oklahoma-earthquakes-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-06-oklahoma-earthquakes-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR USA, November 5-7, 2011 (Vacuum News) - There were a series of earthquakes in Lincoln County, Oklahoma, but we didn&#39;t feel them here in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
Some maps and news from people who did feel the quakes follow. The data here are preliminary, and you&#39;ll want to go to the USGS page for the Oklahoma quake for details, and Oklahoma earthquake history to figure out how normal this is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>