<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet History on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/internet-history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet History on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:51:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/internet-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Engelbart (1925-2013) - inventor of interactive computing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</guid>
      <description>Douglas Engelbart has died at the age of 88.
New York Times obit from John Markoff:
 Douglas C. Engelbart, a visionary scientist whose singular epiphany in 1950 about technology’s potential to expand human intelligence led to a host of inventions — among them the computer mouse — that became the basis for both the Internet and the modern personal computer, died on Tuesday at his home in Atherton, Calif. He was 88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The internet as a moving target (and it&#39;s hard to hit a moving target)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-09-the-internet-as-a-moving-target-and-its-hard-to-hit-a-moving-target/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 22:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-09-the-internet-as-a-moving-target-and-its-hard-to-hit-a-moving-target/</guid>
      <description>From Tracy LaQuey, 1994:
Remember, the Internet is a moving target. Computer names change. Sites disappear. What works today may not work tomorrow.&amp;#0160; Pursuing this phrase where it also shows up: From the introduction to &amp;quot;The Power of the Internet in China&amp;quot;, 2011, emphasis added: “Learning about Internet culture is like learning a new language. Immersion is the most important approach – but immersion in cyberspace has its seductive side. There is always something new: there are new developments related to the Internet, whether technological, social, cultural, or political.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Borrowed nostalgia for the unremembered 90s at Slate</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-25-borrowed-nostalgia-for-the-unremembered-90s-at-slate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 09:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-25-borrowed-nostalgia-for-the-unremembered-90s-at-slate/</guid>
      <description>Slate&amp;#39;s&amp;#0160;Farhad Manjoo&amp;#0160;wonders what the fuss was all about of the Internet of 1996:
I started thinking about the Web of yesteryear after I got an e-mail from an idly curious&amp;#0160;Slatecolleague: What did people do online back whenSlate&amp;#0160;launched, he wondered? After plunging into the&amp;#0160;Internet Archive&amp;#0160;and talking to several people who were watching the Web closely back then, I&amp;#39;ve got an answer: not very much.
Once you get past the &amp;quot;oh ha ha dancing cats&amp;quot; attitude of the article, you discover that the preserved online record of the World Wide Web circa 1996 is incomplete (at least as seen via the Internet Archive) and there&amp;#39;s really not that much to explain why people were interested in it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>