<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 13:09:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;On Wine Bullshit&#34; from the Journal of Wine Economics</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-on-wine-bullshit-from-the-journal-of-wine-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 13:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-on-wine-bullshit-from-the-journal-of-wine-economics/</guid>
      <description>Richard E. Quandt takes on descriptive adjectives for wines in his essay &amp;quot;On Wine Bullshit&amp;quot;.
  We did one other thing. We arranged all the attributes in alphabetical order, and then used a random number generator to select (without replacement) either 10 or 15 attributes from among them and then replicated this experiment a number of times. Here are the results for one particular replication of the experiment for truly hypothetical wines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction markets are too easy to game, so let&#39;s play games instead</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-prediction-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-prediction-markets/</guid>
      <description>Prediction markets provide a nice, idealized way to use market mechanisms to predict the future. They are a slightly idealized version of an office betting pool and allow small scale bets (real or virtual) on future events. Unlike a real futures market, where you can get guarantees of future performance on things like delivery of gasoline or frozen orange juice, there&amp;#39;s no way that betting on some prospective GOP hopeful will lift your candidate to office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 24, 2008: ICOS: Daniel Beunza, Columbia University, &#34;A Model is Not a Market: Promises and Pitfalls of Quantitative Finance&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-october-24-2008-icos-daniel-beunza-columbia-university-a-model-is-not-a-market-promises-and-pitfalls-of-quantitative-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 21:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-october-24-2008-icos-daniel-beunza-columbia-university-a-model-is-not-a-market-promises-and-pitfalls-of-quantitative-f/</guid>
      <description>via the ICOS list; events are at the U of Michigan Business School.
Join ICOS this Friday for a talk by Daniel Beunza of the Columbia Business School. &amp;#0160;Beunza uses ethnographic techniques to explore how traders in financial markets calculate value in the face of fundamental uncertainty -- a timely topic, to say the least! &amp;#0160;Beunza is a leading contributor to
the social studies of finance, and has published papers in Organization Studies, Socio-Economic Review, and Industrial and Corporate Change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>explaining financial leverage in pictures, part one</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-explaining-fina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 14:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-explaining-fina/</guid>
      <description>this photo says most of it:
http://eatock.com/projects/do-not-touch-counter-balance-shelves/
via kottke</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial panic, name the year</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-24-financial-panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 16:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-24-financial-panic/</guid>
      <description>Party like it&#39;s what year?
The characteristics which distinguish a panic of that character from those smaller financial convulsions and industrial set-backs which are of constant occurrence on speculative markets, are five in number: First, a credit crisis so acute as to involve the holding back of payment of cash by banks to depositors, and the momentary suspension of practically all credit facilities. Second, the general hoarding of money by individuals, through withdrawal of great sums of cash from banks, thereby depleting bank reserves, involving runs of depositors on banks, and, in this country, bringing about an actual premium on currency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>