<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Hiner on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hiner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in John Hiner on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hiner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuts coming to MLive, 2016 edition; 29 content positions eliminated</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-cuts-coming-to-mlive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 14:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-cuts-coming-to-mlive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR, MICHIGAN, January 6, 2016. Columbia Journalism Review&amp;rsquo;s
Anna Clark broke the news of cuts at MLive to journalist jobs there,
in this post on Twitter. Details to follow as I have them.
Reports, as of yet unconfirmed, suggest that MLive will shed
jobs statewide including at the Ann Arbor News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLive posted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/index.ssf/2016/01/mlive_media_group_announces_ne.html&#34;&gt;news release&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;MLive Media Group announces news restructuring&amp;rdquo;, which reads in part:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of staff members producing content – reporters, photographers and producers in video and social media – remains intact statewide, although some roles will evolve based on audience demands, Hiner said. Overall, 29 content positions will be eliminated, primarily through reducing management roles and jobs related to newspaper production, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Hiner, a former Bay City Times and Flint Journal editor, is
vice president of content at MLive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Maynard has commentary and some names of locals who are being
reassigned or laid off, in his post
&lt;a href=&#34;http://markmaynard.com/2016/01/a-terrible-blow-to-journalism-mlive-cuts-29-jobs-at-a-time-when-michigan-desperately-needs-quality-reporting/?utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&#34;&gt;A “terrible blow to journalism, ” MLive cuts 29 jobs at a time when Michigan desperately needs quality reporting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s not yet official, as far as I know, word is that several of these 29 jobs eliminated across the company were in the Ann Arbor office. As I understand it, the two managing producers, Cindy Heflin and Julie Taylor, were both laid off, as was entertainment reporter Jenn McKee. And others have been reassigned to statewide positions. Paula Gardener, for instance, will be stepping away from her editorial duties to become a statewide business reporter. Likewise, I’m told that John Counts and Jessica Webster will also be shifting to the statewide team. As for editorial duties, it’s unclear to me what they’ll be doing without Gardener in that role, but I’m told a few new people will be coming into the organization, so perhaps one of them will be charged with such tasks. For instance, I hear that someone named Jen Eyer has been named the new “team leader,” which I’m hoping is something at least approximating an editor. [Without an editor, it might as well be a blog, right?]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A request for comment from MLive Media Group president Dan Gaydou
was not immediately acknowledged. (To be fair, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Twitter
much, and it was my first DM to him.) Ann Arbor News editor
Paula Gardner also did not respond to a Twitter DM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Confirmed: Job cuts have come to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;, incl. on the journalism side. MLive will post a story shortly; I&amp;#39;ll have a CJR story in a bit too.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Anna Clark (@annaleighclark) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annaleighclark/status/684816176791326721&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Since reports are out there now:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I&amp;#39;m absolutely devastated by what&amp;#39;s going on at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;. Some amazing people are losing their jobs today.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kyle Feldscher (@Kyle_Feldscher) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Kyle_Feldscher/status/684824892198547456&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Thoughts are with my friends and former colleagues at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MuskegonChron&#34;&gt;@MuskegonChron&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt;. Too many shorthanded newsrooms stretched even thinner.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dillon Davis (@DillonDavis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DillonDavis/status/684824272381054980&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Sad to hear about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLive&#34;&gt;@MLive&lt;/a&gt; staff cuts. It&amp;#39;s an org full of many talented journalists, &amp;amp; on a personal note, many friends/former Spartans.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Celeste Bott (@celestebott) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/celestebott/status/684823310950117377&#34;&gt;January 6, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>