<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edmund Fitzgerald on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/edmund-fitzgerald/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edmund Fitzgerald on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 01:00:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/edmund-fitzgerald/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>39th anniversary of the wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald on Nov 10, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-10-39th-anniversary-of-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-on-nov-10-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 01:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-10-39th-anniversary-of-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-on-nov-10-2014/</guid>
      <description>More about the song The Wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald on the 70s Pop blog.
 Death and destruction: why were we so obsessed with it in the 70s? So many gruesome, heart wrenching unhappy endings were fodder for pop songs and we gleefully bought the 45s. Well maybe not gleefully, maybe with a maudlin curiosity. This Gordon Lightfoot tune is a great example, a story song about the SS Edmund Fitzgerald sinking in 1975, killing everyone on board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38th anniversary of the wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald on Nov 10, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-09-38th-anniversary-of-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-on-nov-10-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 23:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-09-38th-anniversary-of-the-wreck-of-the-edmund-fitzgerald-on-nov-10-2013/</guid>
      <description>Each year I write a few more words about the wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald, which sank on November 10, 1975. Some notes this year are pulled from my Twitter stream.

Headline: Ludington Daily News, Tuesday, November 11, 1975 via Google News. &#34;Fear all 29 seamen lost / Huge ore carrier is missing on Superior&#34;.
From the Downriver News-Herald, Michigan, news of a memorial service in River Rouge:
 A shipwreck that has held the public’s fascination for nearly 40 years will be remembered once again at a memorial service from 6 to 8 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The searchers all say they&#39;d&#39;ve made Whitefish Bay if they&#39;d put fifteen more miles behind her.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-10-the-searchers-all-say-theydve-made-whitefish-bay-if-theyd-put-fifteen-more-miles-behind-her-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 21:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-10-the-searchers-all-say-theydve-made-whitefish-bay-if-theyd-put-fifteen-more-miles-behind-her-/</guid>
      <description>Whitefish Bay is a bay at the eastern end of Lake Superior.
On Weather Underground, the local weather for Whitefish Bay is LS 321.
Map from NOAA, showing how 15 miles could mean the different between heavy winds and relative calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Ships of the Great Lakes at Lake Erie Metropark, Nov. 22, 2pm, Brownstown MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-09-great-ships-of-the-great-lakes-at-lake-erie-metropark-nov-22-2pm-brownstown-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 14:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-09-great-ships-of-the-great-lakes-at-lake-erie-metropark-nov-22-2pm-brownstown-mi/</guid>
      <description>Cut and paste of a press release, with a few hyperlinks tossed in.

Great Ships of the Great Lakes at Lake Erie Metropark
&amp;#0160;
Join nationally recognized lecturer, model maker and marine historian Keith Steffke for a fascinating look at some of the great ships that have plied and died on the Great Lakes at our special presentation “Great Ships of the Great Lakes,” on Sunday, November 22 at 2 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edmund Fitzgerald - memorial at the Great Lakes Shipwreck Museum, Whitefish Point, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-edmund-fitzgerald---memorial-at-the-great-lakes-shipwreck-museum-whitefish-point-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-edmund-fitzgerald---memorial-at-the-great-lakes-shipwreck-museum-whitefish-point-mi/</guid>
      <description>(write about the display in Paradise)
from the Sault Star:
The Great Lakes Shipwreck Museum is getting to once again ring the bell 29 times, during the 14th annual Edmund Fizgerald Memorial Service. The Edmund Fitzgerald, a 729-foot ore carrier, and her entire crew of 29 men were lost on Lake Superior 34 years ago in one of the worst storms in three decades. The freighter lies north-northwest of Whitefish Point in 160 metres of water.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>