<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and onion curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-02-14-chicken-and-onion-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-02-14-chicken-and-onion-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saveur Magazine has a recipe for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saveur.com/article/Recipes/Chicken-and-Onion-Curry&#34;&gt;chicken and onion curry&lt;/a&gt;
from January 27, 2010. It took a little more than an hour
to cook, but the results were very much worth it - delicious,
and worth repeating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had the meal with rice, kale, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.food.com/recipe/radish-raita-57431&#34;&gt;daikon raita&lt;/a&gt; from
food.com that I kind of liked but which was not a big hit
with the rest of the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current meal planning regime here uses a Google calendar
and a question at the end of every meal: do you want this again,
and how many weeks before we have it again? This curry will
repeat in 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sweet potato cauliflower soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 18:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some sweet potato cauliflower soup recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allyson Kramer likes hers with a bit of garam masala:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Three Peas wants carrots and celery and chicken stock:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food.com and &amp;ldquo;Kelly in TO&amp;rdquo; calls for curry and cinnamon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&#34;&gt;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our meal plan pairs this with biscuits and kale, and it was delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoppin&#39; Giovanni (Rapini with white beans)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 16:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This simple dish of beans and greens comes from Mary Ann Esposito&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ciaoitalia.com/seasons/season-2200/episode-2221/broccoli-rabe-with-white-beans&#34;&gt;Ciao Italia&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s similar in many ways to the traditional &#34;Hoppin&#39; John&#34; served for good luck for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hoppin&#39; Giovanni&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash and chop a bunch of rapini (broccoli rabe). If you can&#39;t find rapini, some other mild green like turnip greens (or even kale) would work nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mince a shallot fine and saute in a large pan in olive oil until fragrant. Add a few generous pinches of red pepper flakes. Put the chopped rapini into the pan and cook until the greens are cooked through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drain and rinse a can of white beans (cannellini). When the greens are cooked through, add the beans and stir. You can add a little more olive oil to the pan at this point if you want to. Stir and then bring back up to heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve hot. This would go good with pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paw Paws at Cobblestone Farm Market on Tuesday, 22 October 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-21-paw-paws-at-cobblestone-farm-market-on-tuesday-22-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 22:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-21-paw-paws-at-cobblestone-farm-market-on-tuesday-22-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following was posted to the Cobblestone Farm mailing list and is repeated here for your edification (and enjoyment of distinctive fruit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobblestone Market has much to offer you and your family&amp;#0160;this Tuesday&amp;#0160;evening (4pm-7pm). Come try some new tastes, then warm your hands and feet by our fire pit!&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be&amp;#0160;paw&amp;#0160;paws&amp;#0160;at the market&amp;#0160;tomorrow, thanks to Marc Boone and his volunteers! Paw&amp;#0160;paws&amp;#0160;are a native fruit which tastes a like a banana and mango combined.&amp;#0160; Come have a taste and take some home. For more information on&amp;#0160;paw&amp;#0160;paws, see&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livescience.com/34669-what-is-a-paw-paw.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.livescience.com/34669-what-is-a-paw-paw.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also for sampling, will be&amp;#0160;Locavorious&amp;#0160;with&amp;#0160;frozen local fruits &amp;amp; veggies. Welcome back,Locavorious!&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.locavorious.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.locavorious.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lydia and Mum&amp;#0160;are excited to share their new&amp;#0160;baking adventures&amp;#0160;which will include Winter Squash and Pumpkin pies (even a gluten free pie), breads, whole wheat pumpkin muffins along with expanding choices of whole grain, gluten free, and vegan breads.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides all this will be the usual at market: apples, winter squash, freshly dug potatoes, broccoli, giant kohlrabi suitable for winter storage ,eggplant, beets, carrots, salad greens, collards, kale, onions, tomatoes, garlic, peppers, cabbage, chard, celery, herbs, turnips, Brussels sprouts.&amp;#0160; Also at the market: goat milk soap, jams &amp;amp; jellies, grass-fed beef and pork, honey, eggs, artisan bread, baked goods, artisan bars, flowers dinner food, plants, tool sharpening, chair messages and more!&amp;#0160;Herbology&amp;#0160;Organics, which had to cancel at the last minute last week, plans to be there with candles, lotion and other skin care products including soaps, balms and oils. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/22/13&amp;#0160;Events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-4:30 pm&amp;#0160;Kids Crafts with Stacey and Starr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4:30-5 pm&amp;#0160;Weekly Kids Rhythm Circle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 pm&amp;#0160;Giant Bubbles with Jeanne and Pattie &amp;amp; Music by Lawrence Miller the Accordion Piper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6-7 pm&amp;#0160;Music by Samantha Steinbacher, Indie Singer/Songwriter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have food or toiletries that you would like to donate to Back&amp;#0160;Door&amp;#0160;Food&amp;#0160;Pantry&amp;#0160;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backdoorfoodpantry.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.backdoorfoodpantry.org/&lt;/a&gt;), Cobblestone Farm Market is setting aside a donation box at the information table each week. &amp;#0160;Please take a look at their website for items needed.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you at the market,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackie and Cobblestone Farm Market Team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>