<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 21:18:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports (as of yet unconfirmed) of enforcement of laws against Uber drivers in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-25-reports-as-of-yet-unconfirmed-of-enforcement-of-laws-against-uber-drivers-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 21:18:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-25-reports-as-of-yet-unconfirmed-of-enforcement-of-laws-against-uber-drivers-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Noted on Twitter; I&#39;ve asked some folks for more clarification and confirmation about what precisely is going on.
@Uber Ann Arbor charging drivers with misdemeanor. What&amp;#39;s up with that? #canigetalawyer
&amp;mdash; Richard Roe (@MrRoeAA) June 25, 2015 
@vielmetti @Uber state law driving without a limo license, $500 misdemeanor.
&amp;mdash; Richard Roe (@MrRoeAA) June 26, 2015 
reliable source confirms some Uber drivers in Ann Arbor are being issued citations under Michigan&amp;#39;s limo law;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just fix the fire hydrant, OK?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-04-just-fix-the-fire-hydrant-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 16:02:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-04-just-fix-the-fire-hydrant-ok/</guid>
      <description>@A2GOV just fix the fire hydrant ok?
&amp;mdash; Edward Vielmetti (@vielmetti) June 4, 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pothole or sidewalk? Substandard repairs to sidewalks using cold patch at State and Packard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-29-pothole-or-sidewalk-substandard-repairs-to-sidewalks-using-cold-patch-at-state-and-packard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 01:08:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-29-pothole-or-sidewalk-substandard-repairs-to-sidewalks-using-cold-patch-at-state-and-packard/</guid>
      <description>Sloppy sidewalk repair state and Packard @a2gov cc @A2CivCity pic.twitter.com/GjDdOAL8rW
&amp;mdash; Edward Vielmetti (@vielmetti) April 27, 2015 
Finding out more via this FOIA request
 Please send the following records: 1) All records pertaining to the repair of the sidewalk on Packard St at the intersection of S State St on the N side of the street, both east and west of S State St between Hill St and Arch St, with cold patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times notices when the Michigan Daily scoops the Ann Arbor News</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-new-york-times-notices-when-the-michigan-daily-scoops-the-ann-arbor-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 21:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-new-york-times-notices-when-the-michigan-daily-scoops-the-ann-arbor-news/</guid>
      <description>The story is Local News, Off College Presses, from April 13, 2014.
 The constant changes have muddled The Ann Arbor News’s identity and, according to some residents, eroded its standing as the go-to source of news in the community. That sense was reinforced by the football article, on which The Ann Arbor News played catch-up after student reporters broke the story.
 Poynter noted in 2011 that the University of Michigan had placed a member of its PR staff on the AnnArbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 22, 2014: Washtenaw County Clerk to issue licenses for same-sex marriages</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-march-22-2014-washtenaw-county-clerk-to-issue-licenses-for-same-sex-marriages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-march-22-2014-washtenaw-county-clerk-to-issue-licenses-for-same-sex-marriages/</guid>
      <description>From Facebook and from Washtenaw County Clerk Larry Kestenbaum:
Same sex marriage is now the law in Michigan.
This afternoon, Judge Friedman of the Eastern District federal court struck down the ban on same-sex marriage in Michigan. Unexpectedly, there was no &#34;stay&#34; pending appeal, and thus the ruling went into effect immediately.
Michigan Attorney General Bill Schuette is seeking an injunction or stay from the U.S. Court of Appeals. The court may or may not do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headline goes here</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-headline-goes-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-19-headline-goes-here/</guid>
      <description>A characteristically informative caption in today&#39;s Sunday, January 19 2014 Ann Arbor News.

As spotted by Kirk Westphal; too good not to share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan 6, 2014: Washtenaw County Snow Emergency Council response to warmth for the homeless</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-06-jan-6-2014-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council-response-to-warmth-for-the-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 12:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-06-jan-6-2014-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council-response-to-warmth-for-the-homeless/</guid>
      <description>A letter from Yousef Rabhi regarding the homeless, and the response to the storm by Washtenaw County; reproduced with permission. All hyperlinks go to Arborwiki pages, which should have more detail and explanations.
 FYI: I discussed this issue with the Washtenaw County Snow Emergency Council and options were discussed. County government has been mobilized to do our part to ensure that members of our community that are homeless are able to keep warm over the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the a2gov.org website down?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-07-is-the-a2govorg-website-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 14:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-07-is-the-a2govorg-website-down/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, 7 December 2013 - ANN ARBOR - It looks like the a2gov.org web site is not functioning correctly.
The error behavior is strange, in that every valid page fetched yields a blank page, but if you go to a page that&#39;s not valid on the site you get a 404 error (and another blank page).
I don&#39;t know if a2gov.org email is also affected. UPDATE: All systems appear to be functioning correctly again at 3:10p Saturday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AnnArbor.com down?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-06-is-annarborcom-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 01:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-06-is-annarborcom-down/</guid>
      <description>Yes.
UPDATE 12/7/13: Mostly. All articles on the old site now redirect to mlive.com. I am told this will be back working by Monday 12/9/13.

No idea if it will come back.
At the moment, all www.annarbor.com URLs redirect to the MLive Ann Arbor home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3d Ann Arbor Civic Tech meetup - a writeup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-the-3d-ann-arbor-civic-tech-meetup-a-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 08:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-the-3d-ann-arbor-civic-tech-meetup-a-writeup/</guid>
      <description>We had a good time and a lively discussion at the 3d Ann Arbor Civic Technology meetup. There were about 18 people in attendance, including the City of Ann Arbor CFO/CIO, the webmaster from Washtenaw County, several U of Michigan SI students, some townies, a fellow who drove down from Lansing who had organized Code Michigan hackathon, and a number of folks who were drawn in from Meetup. (who did I miss)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedestrian safety in Ann Arbor is a downtown issue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-pedestrian-safety-in-ann-arbor-is-a-downtown-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 07:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-pedestrian-safety-in-ann-arbor-is-a-downtown-issue/</guid>
      <description>Pedestrian safety in Ann Arbor is a downtown issue, as illustrated by this map of 2012 car-pedestrian crashes.
What, if anything, is the Ann Arbor DDA and the City of Ann Arbor doing to make the downtown streetscape safer for pedestrians? Most of the rhetoric in recent City Council meetings has been about pedestrian safety in neighborhoods, but that&#39;s visibly not the only issue at hand.

Data from Michigan Traffic Crash Facts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) Fifth Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 20:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>I went with S and J to the University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) on the UM North Campus in the basement of the Duderstadt Center. They were celebrating their fifth anniversary with cupcakes and a Mario tournament. The boys had a chance to play games, and I had a chance to talk to David S. Carter (aka superman@umich.edu) about the collection. Here are some notes.
There are about 5000 games in the collection, and about half of them are donated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Web Analytics Wednesday planning</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-ann-arbor-web-analytics-wednesday-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-ann-arbor-web-analytics-wednesday-planning/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working with a few other folks on setting up a relatively regular local group that has discussions of tools like Google Analytics and other systems used to instrument web sites and web applications. We&#39;re looking at a date in January 2014 to start, and a Wednesday as the day of the week we think might work best. Let me know if you&#39;re interested, or join the Ann Arbor Web Analytics Wednesday meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasty Green Cafe at Ann Arbor City Hall</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-tasty-green-cafe-at-ann-arbor-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-15-tasty-green-cafe-at-ann-arbor-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re looking to bump into city employees and talk shop, there&#39;s no better place to stop in than at the Tasty Green Cafe inside Ann Arbor City Hall. The menu includes the usual coffee drinks plus lunchtime choices like meat and spinach pies. There are three tables inside and a few more outside on the patio, and you get a nice view of the city hall fountain (which isn&#39;t running at the moment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor SPARK audited financial statements are on a2docs.org</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-08-ann-arbor-spark-audited-financial-statements-are-on-a2docsorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 18:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-08-ann-arbor-spark-audited-financial-statements-are-on-a2docsorg/</guid>
      <description>Audited financial statements for Ann Arbor SPARK are available on a2docs, courtesy of Kai Petainen who obtained them from the State of Michigan Attorney General.
See Ann Arbor SPARK 2012 Audited Financial Statement and SPARK Audited Financial Statements 2006 to 2011.
a2docs is the Ann Arbor Area Government Document Repository, &#34;A place to upload documents relevant to local governance.&#34;
Media commentary:
Forbes, a story by Kai Petainen:  According to Tom Crawford at city hall, 100% of the LDFA money to SPARK (about $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 26, 2013: Saturday night shooting at Rush Street, Ann Arbor - eyewitness accounts from Facebook, Instagram</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-shooting-down-on-main-street-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 17:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-shooting-down-on-main-street-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>A 25 year old man from Illinois was shot by a 25 year old man from Westland on Saturday night, October 26, 2013, at Rush Street, a bar on Main Street in Ann Arbor. The most detailed eyewitness report of this weekend&#39;s shooting comes from Hatim Elhady&#39;s Facebook page.
 How did my WILD Saturday night OFF WORK go? Celebrated my friend&#39;s, Sarita LH,birthday who is a medic as well with my other awesome medic buddy Tim Skeeters at Rush Street in Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 23, 2013: State St closed at Granger because of one-car accident, power out in Lower Burns Park</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-october-23-2013-state-st-closed-at-granger-because-of-one-car-accident-power-out-in-lower-burns-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 17:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-october-23-2013-state-st-closed-at-granger-because-of-one-car-accident-power-out-in-lower-burns-park/</guid>
      <description>The news, as ever, comes via twitter and via my neighborhood email list: a single-car accident on S State St has closed the street at Granger. Details follow via Twitter reports.
Some car crashed into a house on south state street right by the field hockey stadium. Knocked out power all up in my neighborhood
&amp;mdash; Dan Jahanian (@danjahan) October 23, 2013 This is the scene on State St. Man went into diabetic shock and knocked out power lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA: inspection reports for downtown Ann Arbor street lights</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 12:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</guid>
      <description>As sent to the Ann Arbor City Clerk, 23 October 2013:
To the clerk:
The City Council meeting of this week Tuesday (ed.: actually late Monday) had an extended discussion of street lighting in the downtown area, and council weighed the problems with rust on street lamps and decided not to spend money to replace them.
To follow up on this discussion, and motivated by the uncertainty at council about the state of the lighting, I&#39;d like to make this request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affinia Group to move headquarters from Ann Arbor, MI to Gastonia, NC; 50 jobs at stake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</guid>
      <description>From the Charlotte Observer:
 Affinia Group Inc., a firm that designs, manufactures, distributes and markets industrial grade products and services, will relocate its Ann Arbor, Mich., headquarters to Gastonia, home of its Global Filtration group. The transition to the new corporate headquarters will occur in phases during 2014.
 Wikipedia gives a little background
 The Affinia Group, a motor industry company, was formed in 2004 and specializes in the design, manufacture and replacement of parts for and on and off-road vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Caribou Coffee, hello Peet&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-14-goodbye-caribou-coffee-hello-peets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-14-goodbye-caribou-coffee-hello-peets/</guid>
      <description>Our local Caribou Coffee closed its doors for the last time on Sunday. A trailer appeared in the front of it Monday sporting a Peet&#39;s logo. The effort to rebuild the corner coffee shop under a new name is expected to take a couple of weeks, with a planned opening date in mid-November.
Change is hard, and change in a coffee routine is doubly hard. The corner Caribou had been a study spot, a meeting place, a second office and a place to see Mike the Mailman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under new management: Frank&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-under-new-management-franks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 11:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-under-new-management-franks/</guid>
      <description>Frank’s Restaurant is under new management – as of October 1, says the sign. They are advertising extended late night hours.
Frank&#39;s is well known as &#34;the fortified high point of Ann Arbor&#34;, according to its menus.
I wrote about Frank&#39;s 6 years ago as part of a review of Placeshout, which was a simple application for taking short (100 character) notes on locations. That was from the era of the Ann Arbor &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Wikipedians - U of Michigan student Wikipedia association</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-01-michigan-wikipedians-u-of-michigan-student-wikipedia-association-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 09:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-01-michigan-wikipedians-u-of-michigan-student-wikipedia-association-/</guid>
      <description>Michigan Wikipedians is a University of Michigan student association.  Michigan Wikipedians (or MWiki) is a Wikipedia student organization at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor. The group was the first student Wikipedia club in the United States. The club is open to all students and faculty of the University of Michigan, as well as community members who are interested in Wikipedia. It meets every Monday at 8:00PM at the Language Resource Center in the basement of North Quadrangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just say no: Just Energy complaints are legion</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-25-just-say-no-just-energy-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 16:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-25-just-say-no-just-energy-complaints/</guid>
      <description>From my Ann Arbor neighborhood email list, September 2013:
 Some weaselly-looking character from an outfit called &#34;Just Energy&#34; knocked on our door today. They are of course scam artists and we just tell them we are not interested. They are very pushy and actually try to mislead people into thinking they have something to do with the utility companies. The especially like to prey on the elderly.  Complaints about this company are legion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce your water bill in four (well, five) easy steps</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-19-reduce-your-water-bill-in-four-well-five-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 14:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-19-reduce-your-water-bill-in-four-well-five-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Identify the toilet tank in the basement that no one uses that&#39;s leaking.
 Squirt WD-40 on the stuck valve on the supply line to the tank.
 Use elbow grease and a vise-grip to turn the supply line valve to &#34;off&#34;.
 Remind people not to use the toilet.
 Check your daily usage to see that instead of using 200 units of water on a slow day, you&#39;re using 50 (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An active if diffuse media ecosystem</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-an-active-if-diffuse-media-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 14:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-an-active-if-diffuse-media-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Anna Clark, writing in the Columbia Journalism Review, has a story about the end of AnnArbor.com and what sorts of alternatives people have when they are looking for news. I get a brief mention.
The question I want to explore is what does it mean to no longer have a single daily newspaper, or even a special daily comprehensive news web site, but instead to have a world where news about your home town is coming from lots of places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes at AnnArbor.com; newspaper rebrands as Ann Arbor News, shuts down website</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-changes-at-annarborcom-newspaper-rebrands-as-ann-arbor-news-shuts-down-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 11:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-13-changes-at-annarborcom-newspaper-rebrands-as-ann-arbor-news-shuts-down-website/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I wrote for AnnArbor.com for about a year and a half, and I miss the daily morning deadlines that used to define my day. So when I heard that AnnArbor.com was shutting down its web site, moving new content to MLive, and rebranding as the Ann Arbor News, a little bit of worry was there. Would the owners scrub the site of that newspaper entirely in their quest to build something new?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calligraphy, a new album and Indiegogo campaign from Papillon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-calligraphy-a-new-album-and-indiegogo-campaign-from-papillon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 13:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-calligraphy-a-new-album-and-indiegogo-campaign-from-papillon/</guid>
      <description>My friend Papillon is working on a double album &#34;Calligraphy&#34; which he&#39;s producing with the help of an Indiegogo campaign. Of this he says
 Over the past few years I have traveled to many places, through many cultures and created music with many people on our planet. This resulted in the Calligraphy collection to be released on a double album later this year.
The next few steps of the way will require a small push from my community of dreamers, makers and supporters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A2Digital Media, a new archival-quality service</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-10-a2digital-media-a-new-archival-quality-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 11:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-10-a2digital-media-a-new-archival-quality-service/</guid>
      <description>My friend David Erdody has started A2Digital Media, a service for people who have analog media that needs to be converted to digital formats. David&#39;s background includes time spent at the Bentley Historical Library, and he brings this careful archival quality to his work.
A2Digital handles photographs, audio cassettes, VHS, reel to reel tapes, and scanning of paper. He&#39;ll correct damaged photos and improve audio and video quality. Rates are reasonable - contact him today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Largebeat Art and Music Benefit fundraiser for James &#34;Largebeat&#34; Gertz who is fighting lymphoma. Weds. September 4, 2013, Arbor Brewing Company, 8:00 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-29-largebeat-art-and-music-benefit-fundraiser-for-james-largebeat-gertz-who-is-fighting-lymphoma-weds-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 23:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-29-largebeat-art-and-music-benefit-fundraiser-for-james-largebeat-gertz-who-is-fighting-lymphoma-weds-s/</guid>
      <description>The Largebeat Art and Music Benefit is a fundraiser to cover the medical expenses of James Largebeat Gertz who is fighting lymphoma. Wednesday September 4, 2013 at Arbor Brewing Company, doors open at 8:00 p.m. The poster is below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11th Kerrytown Bookfest, September 8, 2013, Ann Arbor Farmers Market</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-11th-kerrytown-bookfest-september-8-2013-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-11th-kerrytown-bookfest-september-8-2013-ann-arbor-farmers-market/</guid>
      <description>From the official Kerrytown Bookfest web site:
 The 11th Kerrytown BookFest will celebrate Detroit and its writers with three panel discussions featuring celebrated auto executive Bob Lutz (“Icons and Idiots”), rock ‘n’ roll writers Steve Miller (“Detroit Rock City”) and Peter Benjaminson (“Mary Wells”) and urban observers Edward McClelland (“Nothin’ But Blue Skies: The Heydey”), Gordon Young (“Teardown”), June Thomas (“Redevelopment and Race”) and John Gallagher (“Revolution Detroit”) of the Detroit Free Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arson on Mary Street? The Michigan Daily is on it, the AnnArbor.com not so much</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-arson-on-mary-street-the-michigan-daily-is-on-it-the-annarborcom-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 17:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-25-arson-on-mary-street-the-michigan-daily-is-on-it-the-annarborcom-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>Two reports of a fire on the 900 block of Mary Street on Saturday at around 3:00 a.m. The sirens woke me up.
The AnnArbor.com story notes that a 3 car garage was destroyed and gives the &#34;we don&#39;t know very much&#34; report:
 The cause of the fire was not immediately known. The cost of the damage is unknown.
 The Michigan Daily story gives more details, including a photo from neighbor Raymond Brokowski, and has this disturbing detail: it&#39;s being investigated as arson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prime Red apples are in at Farmers Market (August 24, 2013)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</guid>
      <description>We got some Prime Red apples at Farmer&#39;s Market from Wasem&#39;s Fruit Farm.
Prime Red is also known as Akane or Tokyo Rose. From Orange Pippin, an encyclopedia of apples:
 Akane was developed in Japan in the 1930s, and represents an unusual marriage of the classic English early variety, Worcester Pearmain, and the high quality American heritage apple variety, Jonathan - and it is a marriage that works very successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The local news, omnibus edition, for August 21 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-21-the-local-news-omnibus-edition-for-august-21-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 23:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-21-the-local-news-omnibus-edition-for-august-21-2013/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m on vacation for a week up north, but news still hits my inbox. Here&#39;s a very brief take on some things that I have learned while I&#39;ve been gone that deserve to be dumped out into the internet so that our fine intelligence agencies have something more to chew on.
 Bob Needham, long time Ann Arbor News and AnnArbor.com entertainment editor, has left the friendly confines of the newspaper industry to join the University of Michigan&#39;s Ross School of Business as a &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blimpy Burger is closing, it&#39;s closing, it&#39;s closing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-blimpy-burger-is-closing-its-closing-its-closing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 17:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-blimpy-burger-is-closing-its-closing-its-closing/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed it, Blimpy Burger is closing; three stories in the dotcom should convince you of that. Read about how it was - and how it might be in the future - on Arborwiki&amp;#39;s Blimpy Burger page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Ann Arbor City Planning Commission of August 7, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-08-notes-from-the-ann-arbor-city-planning-commission-of-august-7-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-08-notes-from-the-ann-arbor-city-planning-commission-of-august-7-2013/</guid>
      <description>I went to the City Planning Commission meeting on Wednesday, August 7, 2013. Here&amp;#39;s a few notes. The AnnArbor.com story about the meeting and a Civic News Ticker from the Ann Arbor Chronicle focus on a vacant parcel on Packard near Platt that&amp;#39;s currently zoned for single-family residential. The owner of the property wants to put a duplex on the site, and asked to have the the parcel rezoned to a new zoning that would also allow duplexes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wondering if other cities have dog park subcommittees that issue press releases</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-07-wondering-if-other-cities-have-dog-park-subcommittees-that-issue-press-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 11:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-07-wondering-if-other-cities-have-dog-park-subcommittees-that-issue-press-releases/</guid>
      <description>PRESS RELEASE
For Immediate Release&amp;#0160;
CONTACT: Karen Levin, Chair, Dog Park Subcommittee of the Park Advisory Commission,&amp;#0160;734.645.8904
PARK ADVISORY COMMISSION SEEKS PUBLIC INPUT ON POTENTIAL DOG PARK LOCATIONS
ANN ARBOR, Mich., July 29, 2013 — The City’s Dog Park Subcommittee of the Park Advisory Commission (PAC) is inviting the public to participate in an online survey to gather feedback and opinions on potential dog park locations and features. The survey,&amp;#0160;www.surveymonkey.com/s/7YXPKXG, is brief and should take about 10 minutes to fill out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Violin Monster has been kicked off the streets for Ann Arbor&#39;s Art Fair (UPDATE: He&#39;s Back)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-the-violin-monster-has-been-kicked-off-the-streets-for-ann-arbors-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 17:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-the-violin-monster-has-been-kicked-off-the-streets-for-ann-arbors-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, JULY 18, 2013 - Find the Violin Monster at the corner of Liberty and Main at the Art Fair on Main Street, he&#39;s a guest there of the Main Street Area Association.
@jhritz I&amp;#39;m heading out to Liberty and Main right now. The Main Street area saw my Facebook post, and welcomed me to their turf!
&amp;mdash; Violin Monster (@ViolinMonster) July 18, 2013  ANN ARBOR, JULY 17, 2013 - The &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art Fair Bingo, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-art-fair-bingo-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 14:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-art-fair-bingo-2013/</guid>
      <description>This graphic is making the rounds; original artist Katy McGrady (happy to give credit where credit is due). And of course it&amp;#39;s hot for the Ann Arbor Art Fair, and there&amp;#39;s a bit of rain.
More Art Fair bingos, courtesy of Damn Arbor, from Osric; some more commentary from Reddit /r/annarbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Meeting to Discuss the closure of Main Street for Football Games, July 24, 2013, 6:00 p.m., Ann Arbor District Library</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-public-meeting-to-discuss-the-closure-of-main-street-for-football-games-july-24-2013-600-pm-ann-arbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 14:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-public-meeting-to-discuss-the-closure-of-main-street-for-football-games-july-24-2013-600-pm-ann-arbo/</guid>
      <description>This message was forwarded from an initial message sent by Marcia Higgins, who is on Ann Arbor City Council. I am not certain how else this meeting was promoted; there&amp;#39;s no sign of this on the city&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;News&amp;quot; page, nor does a full text search of the City web site turn up a copy of it elsewhere. It affects everyone who goes to U of Michigan football games.
The Ann Arbor dotcom had previously reported on the same plans when they surfaced in 2010, and provides a few more details in their 2013 story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10,000 gallons of raw sewage dumped into the Huron River on June 27, 2013 after torrential rainstorms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</guid>
      <description>This press release from the City of Ann Arbor was sent to news media on June 28, 2013. As far as I can tell, AnnArbor.com did not run a story. The Ann Arbor Chronicle did publish information about this discharge as part of its meeting reporting for the July 15, 2013 city council meeting.
UPDATE: AnnArbor.com story of July 19, 2013 is up now.
A copy of this news release is available on the Ann Arbor Area Government Document Repository (a2docs), but there&amp;#39;s no copy to be found on the City of Ann Arbor web site as of this writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I hear #a2council talking about the city and the university, I think about China Mieville&#39;s &#34;The City and the City&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-when-i-hear-a2council-talking-about-the-city-and-the-university-i-think-about-china-mievilles-the-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 20:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-when-i-hear-a2council-talking-about-the-city-and-the-university-i-think-about-china-mievilles-the-ci/</guid>
      <description>As reviewed on Wikipedia -
 These two cities actually occupy much of the same geographical space, but via the volition of their citizens (and the threat of the secret power known as Breach), they are&amp;#0160;perceived&amp;#0160;as two different cities.
 The two cities are the University of Michigan and Ann Arbor; both treat themselves as sovereign nations as best they can, and though the freeway ring mostly encircles both they are distinguished by having separate police forces, separate budgets, separate public green space and separate social circles and hierarchies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Karl Pohrt, 65, owner of Ann Arbor&#39;s Shaman Drum Bookshop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-12-obituary-karl-pohrt-65-owner-of-ann-arbors-shaman-drum-bookshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 13:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-12-obituary-karl-pohrt-65-owner-of-ann-arbors-shaman-drum-bookshop/</guid>
      <description>Karl Pohrt died Wednesday, July 10, 2013, after a battle with anaplastic thyroid cancer. He wrote about books and life on his weblog &amp;quot;there is no gap&amp;quot;. Karl was the owner of the Shaman Drum Bookshop, an independent bookstore on Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s State Street which closed in 2009 after a 29 year run.
Some obituaries from the net:
Publisher&amp;#39;s Weekly:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;quot;Karl Pohrt was a true bookman: a bookseller, compulsive reader, and a publisher as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Fourth of July parade, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-04-ann-arbor-fourth-of-july-parade-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 13:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-04-ann-arbor-fourth-of-july-parade-2013/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Fourth of July 2013 parade was this morning. Some brief highlights, so I don&#39;t forget them; I&#39;ll include pictures if I have them. In approximate order of the parade route.
Lots of candy, lots of politicians, lots of kids on bikes.
The Star Wars marching band playing the Imperial March, and a bun-headed Leia. Darth Vader was driving the car that towed an R2D2 float.
A Star Wars band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Power Of The Blog&#34;, Ann Arbor Observer, June 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-30-the-power-of-the-blog-ann-arbor-observer-june-2013-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-30-the-power-of-the-blog-ann-arbor-observer-june-2013-2/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The Power Of The Blog&#34;, Ann Arbor Observer, June 2013
 Vacuum&#39;s subject material is a hodgepodge, but that&#39;s because Vielmetti sees the blog very much in the classical context: as a personal, yet very public, journal. A longtime notebook keeper, Vielmetti sees Vacuum mostly as just another way to record and archive his own thoughts--although it recently hit a traffic milestone, with one million total page views.
 Patrick Dunn&#39;s story also has accounts from A2Gastroboy, Ben Connor Barrie of Damn Arbor, and Mark Maynard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 27, 2013 flooding in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-27-june-27-2013-flooding-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 16:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-27-june-27-2013-flooding-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Several streets in Ann Arbor have flooded as a result of slow-moving storm cells that passed through the city on the afternoon of Thursday, June 27, 2013. Reports are still filtering in, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I know about right now.
The City of Ann Arbor is building a “Citizen Storm Corps” volunteer group to assist in stormwater/flooding data collection. Volunteers will visit Large Event Data Gathering locations after significant rain events, record visual observations about the stormwater&amp;rsquo;s behavior at that location using a LEDG Stormwater/Flooding Reporting Form, and submit the data to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Ann Arbor edition of the National Day of Civic Hacking 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-24-photos-from-the-ann-arbor-edition-of-the-national-day-of-civic-hacking-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 12:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-24-photos-from-the-ann-arbor-edition-of-the-national-day-of-civic-hacking-2013/</guid>
      <description>Photos from Hans Kokx of the National Day of Civic Hacking event in Ann Arbor for 2013. See the full set on Flickr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stadium Bridges art survey</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-19-stadium-bridges-art-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 12:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-19-stadium-bridges-art-survey/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor is conducting a survey to get public input on several proposals for monumental public art to accompany the newly build Stadium Bridges. There are four proposals in all. The Ann Arbor dotcom has a review of the works.&amp;#0160;The City of Ann Arbor project page includes links to full proposals from artists.
Fill out the survey!
The artists, and their works, are
Sheila Klein, &amp;quot;Untitled&amp;quot;. Maize and blue striped poles, trees in planters on the bridge, a sculpture of cheerleaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council to consider restricting public comment time</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-ann-arbor-city-council-to-consider-restricting-public-comment-time/</guid>
      <description>As reported in the Ann Arbor Chronicle:
 A June 13, 2013 meeting of the Ann Arbor city council’s rules committee has resulted in proposed revisions to the council’s rules, many of which affect speaking turns and time – for members of the public and for councilmembers.
  An across-the-board proposed change for city council meeting public speaking times is a reduction from three minutes to two minutes for each turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One reason why you, as a politician, should keep your domain registration current even if you are not running</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 16:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-14-one-reason-why-you-as-a-politician-should-keep-your-domain-registration-current-even-if-you-are-not-/</guid>
      <description>The web site is http://higginsforcouncil.com . It was once a campaign website; it&amp;#39;s now an anti-campaign site, with the (anonymous) person hosting it heaping invective and scorn upon a local politician.
If you&amp;#39;re running for office and have a web site set up to support your campaign, use some of your campaign money to buy a domain registration that lasts a long time. You&amp;#39;ll avoid problems like this in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Hands On Museum &#34;Tech Twilight&#34; 2013 video</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum-tech-twilight-2013-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-ann-arbor-hands-on-museum-tech-twilight-2013-video/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of Bill Bennett, here&amp;#39;s a video with some highlights of the 2013 &amp;quot;Tech Twilight&amp;quot; event at the Ann Arbor Hands On Museum.
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweetwaters Ginger-Lemon Tea recipe (or at least something close)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-sweetwaters-ginger-lemon-tea-recipe-or-at-least-something-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 17:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-22-sweetwaters-ginger-lemon-tea-recipe-or-at-least-something-close/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s a few sources for recipes that are similar to what you get at Sweetwaters when you order a Ginger-Lemon Tea (one of my favorites).
From Coppertop Kitchen (a blog by someone who was a Sweetwaters barista): Ginger Lemon Tea
2 cups fresh lemon juice
1 3- by 1-inch piece of fresh ginger, peeled and sliced thinly
10 cups water
1 cup honey
Place lemon juice, ginger, and water in a large saucepan over medium heat, and bring to a boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for city council deliberation of 413 E Huron St development: Yuppies in the Sky</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-13-music-for-city-council-deliberation-of-413-e-huron-st-development-yuppies-in-the-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-13-music-for-city-council-deliberation-of-413-e-huron-st-development-yuppies-in-the-sky/</guid>
      <description>Tom Paxton singing &#34;Yuppies in the Sky&#34;.
 Condos for sale / condos to buy / Yuppies in the sky</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Mall nearing demolition? Heavy equipment from 21st Century Salvage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-12-georgetown-mall-nearing-demolition-heavy-equipment-from-21st-century-salvage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 13:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-12-georgetown-mall-nearing-demolition-heavy-equipment-from-21st-century-salvage/</guid>
      <description>John Hritz spotted this heavy equipment in front of the decrepit Georgetown Mall; the markings on the side of the middle bulldozer say &amp;quot;21st Century Salvage&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juneberry season is on its way - trees are in bloom</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 11:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-juneberry-season-is-on-its-way-trees-are-in-bloom-/</guid>
      <description>Ben from Damn Arbor notes that the juneberries in town are in bloom, which means that it shouldn&amp;#39;t be more than about a month before they are ready for street-side snacking.&amp;#0160;
The forager in me always welcomes street trees that provide impromptu nutrition. Arborwiki has a brief list of some of the places where you can find juneberries downtown; surprisingly, the municipal parking lots on the west side of downtown are ringed with these trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2geeks 2013 annual meeting, Thursday May 16 2013, 5:30 p.m. at Ann Arbor SPARK</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-07-a2geeks-2013-annual-meeting-thursday-may-16-2013-530-pm-at-ann-arbor-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-07-a2geeks-2013-annual-meeting-thursday-may-16-2013-530-pm-at-ann-arbor-spark/</guid>
      <description>From the Facebook event announcement:
 a2geeks&amp;#39; third annual meeting is a gathering-of-the-geeks - inventors and innovators, makers and hackers, students and grandparents, town and gown. This event will also kick-off the A2Geeks Civic Apps Contest. Food and fun galore.
 The event starts at 5:30 p.m. I&amp;#39;ll be there pitching the Civic Apps contest, which I&amp;#39;ve been working on for a while now to organize. See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Stadium Bridges Dedication Ceremony is Tuesday, May 14, 2013 at 10 a.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-04-e-stadium-bridges-dedication-ceremony-is-tuesday-may-14-2013-at-10-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 19:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-04-e-stadium-bridges-dedication-ceremony-is-tuesday-may-14-2013-at-10-am/</guid>
      <description>Press release from the City of Ann Arbor
-----
E. Stadium Bridges Dedication Ceremony is Tuesday, May 14, 10 a.m.
ANN ARBOR, Mich., April 11, 2013 — A brief dedication ceremony for the City of Ann Arbor’s E. Stadium Bridges Replacement Project will be held at 10 a.m., Tuesday, May 14, 2013 near 1501 S. State Street, next to the E. Stadium Boulevard Bridge over S. State Street. Congressman John Dingell will be joined with representatives from the national Department of Transportation, as well as officials from MDOT, Washtenaw County, City of Ann Arbor, project contractors, neighbors, and the general public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on water</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-walking-on-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 14:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-walking-on-water/</guid>
      <description>I was out for a walk along the Huron River, and Runtastic mapped it as though I was actually in the middle of the river.
 
There&amp;#39;s actually a path in the &amp;quot;middle&amp;quot; of the river, a berm that separates the Argo Cascades city park from the Huron River per se. Microsoft and Nokia don&amp;#39;t appear to know about that path, just illustrating some of the perils of computing walking directions in an urban environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Nerd Nite, Wednesday April 17, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-15-ann-arbor-nerd-nite-wednesday-april-17-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-15-ann-arbor-nerd-nite-wednesday-april-17-2013/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s monthly Nerd Nite is coming Wednesday, April 17; doors open at 6:30pm for a 7:00pm event. Here&amp;#39;s a bit from the Ann Arbor Nerd Nite web site&amp;#0160;which also has more in the way of details about the speakers and the format.
Wham! W00t! Wednesday!  What up, A2nerds? We’re mixing things up a bit this month by bringing the nerdery to Wednesday. For those of you that are new to the fold,&amp;#0160;Nerd Nite&amp;#0160;is a monthly social event where nerds of all disciplines give 18-21 minute funny and informative talks while the audience drinks along and asks questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Healthcare Decisions Day is April 16, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-13-national-healthcare-decisions-day-is-april-16-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-13-national-healthcare-decisions-day-is-april-16-2013/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Merilynne Rush for notice of this event.
National Healthcare Decisions Day is April 16.
Join with other Americans across the country completing Advance Directives documents at an Advanced Directives Party at the Center for the Childbearing Year, 722 Brooks St., Ann Arbor  6:30 Drinks and hors d’oeuvres
7:00 Presentation and Q &amp;amp; A
8:00 Small Group discussion and filling out documents
 Cost: $15 per person or $20 per family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Football spring game 2013: parking restrictions in effect</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-12-michigan-football-spring-game-2013-parking-restrictions-in-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 19:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-12-michigan-football-spring-game-2013-parking-restrictions-in-effect/</guid>
      <description>Michigan Football has its spring football game on Saturday, April 13, 2013. The following map shows restricted parking areas near the stadium for the event. Move your car - or the city will move it for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools superintendent Patricia Green resigns</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</guid>
      <description>Patricia Green, superintendent of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, has resigned effective 90 days from April 10, 2013. Her letter of resignation, which was distributed by electronic mail to AAPS parents, follows.
Ruth from A2 Schools Muse has insightful commentary.
April 11, 2013
Dear Colleagues and AAPS Families: Last evening, I gave President Deb Mexicotte a letter in which I asked her to accept my resignation as Superintendent of Schools of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, effective 90 days from yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuri&#39;s Night in Ann Arbor, Friday April 12, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-yuris-night-in-ann-arbor-friday-april-12-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 14:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-yuris-night-in-ann-arbor-friday-april-12-2013/</guid>
      <description>From the a2geeks mailing list - added links are mine.
Friday April 12th is&amp;#0160;Yuri&amp;#39;s Night&amp;#0160;- celebrating spaceflight on the anniversary of&amp;#0160;Yuri Gagarin&amp;#39;s&amp;#0160;flight in 1961, and the first space shuttle flight in 1981. The&amp;#0160;Ann Arbor District Library&amp;#0160;is bringing laptops running&amp;#0160;Kerbal Space Program&amp;#0160;(an awesomely fun space exploration sandbox game) to&amp;#0160;The Bar at 327 Braun Court. Come celebrate space exploration!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penny Stamps: Arduino creator Massimo Banzi, “Opensourcing Imagination,” Thursday, April 11, 2013 at Michigan Theater</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-10-penny-stamps-arduino-creator-massimo-banzi-opensourcing-imagination-thursday-april-11-2013-at-michig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 11:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-10-penny-stamps-arduino-creator-massimo-banzi-opensourcing-imagination-thursday-april-11-2013-at-michig/</guid>
      <description>From a press release from ORCI; added hyperlinks are mine.
Posted on&amp;#0160;April 9, 2013&amp;#0160;by&amp;#0160;Dan Meisler  What:&amp;#0160;Penny Stamps College of Art and Design Distinguished Speaker Series featuring Massimo Banzi
When:&amp;#0160;Thursday, April 11, 5:10 p.m.
Where:&amp;#0160;Michigan Theater, 603 E. Liberty, Ann Arbor
Cost: Free
Interaction designer Massimo Banzi&amp;#0160;(@mbanzi) helped invent the Arduino, a tiny, easy-to-use open-source microcontroller that has inspired people around the world to make the coolest things they can imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festifools photos from 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-07-festifools-photos-from-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 22:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-07-festifools-photos-from-2013/</guid>
      <description>A lovely day for a foolish parade. We were out and got some choice standing places in the springtime sunshine, and when the parade got to be too much for the youngest of the party, we went out for hot chocolate and a muffin.
This photo gives some idea of the fun. I didn&amp;#39;t get a picture of my favorite puppet, which was a camera complete with &amp;quot;flash&amp;quot;. This was definitely a time to get photos with as much resolution as you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fool Moon photos from 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-06-fool-moon-photos-from-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 14:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-06-fool-moon-photos-from-2013/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of Fool Moon photos from 2013 online; I&amp;#39;ll note them here as I find collections. But I thought I&amp;#39;d add my own in to start of this cat/bunny/Peep.
 
Some collections:
Moon Unit Face Pong.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;quot;A video booth projected faces into a moon from green screen onto a building in real-time, while Fool Mooners play pong with the faces using wii-motes.&amp;quot;
Myra Klarman: FoolMoon 2013. &amp;quot;It was great to see so many veteran and first-time Fools participating in FoolMoon 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 4-5, 2013: Visual Culture and Archives symposium hosted by the Bentley Historical Library at Rackham Amphitheature</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-03-april-4-5-2013-visual-culture-and-archives-symposium-hosted-by-the-bentley-historical-library-at-rac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 08:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-03-april-4-5-2013-visual-culture-and-archives-symposium-hosted-by-the-bentley-historical-library-at-rac/</guid>
      <description>The Bentley Historical Library is hosting a symposium on Visual Culture and Archives at Rackham Amphitheatre &amp;#0160;on the University of Michigan Central Campus on April 4-5. The event will be live tweeted with the hash tag #bhlvisual, and there&amp;#39;s live streaming of the talks. See the event home page for details.
 
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Frauenfelder, &#34;Making Makers&#34;, April 5, 2013 at Chesebrough Auditorium, U of Michigan North Campus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-02-mark-frauenfelder-making-makers-april-5-2013-at-chesebrough-auditorium-u-of-michigan-north-campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 16:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-02-mark-frauenfelder-making-makers-april-5-2013-at-chesebrough-auditorium-u-of-michigan-north-campus/</guid>
      <description>As originally noted by Dale Grover to the GO-Tech mailing list:
Mark Frauenfelder, editor-in-chief of Make Magazine and co-editor of the blog Boing Boing, will be giving a lecture &amp;quot;Making Makers&amp;quot; this Friday, April 5, 6-7:30 pm at the Chesebrough Auditorium, 220 Chrysler Center, 2121 Bonisteel Blvd, Ann Arbor MI 48109
 (Map:&amp;#0160;http://www.engin.umich.edu/facilities/maps/chrysler.html)
Free, open to public. Plan ahead for where you want to park; a number of lots are free parking after 5:00 pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 28, 2013 North Quad flood</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-march-28-2013-north-quad-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-march-28-2013-north-quad-flood/</guid>
      <description>North Quad at the U of Michigan had a flood today, causing classes to be cancelled and students to be evacuated from their rooms. There is no estimate of the damage at this time, but it&#39;s extensive.
The University of Michigan School of Information has a flood information page with reschedule and relocate information for classes and talks.
 All media inquires about the flooding should be directed to Kelly Cunningham in the UM Public Affairs Office: kecunham@umich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Spring CSA (Community Supported Agriculture) Fair, Sunday, March 24, 2013 at Pittsfield Grange</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-18-ann-arbor-spring-csa-community-supported-agriculture-fair-sunday-march-24-2013-at-pittsfield-grange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 10:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-18-ann-arbor-spring-csa-community-supported-agriculture-fair-sunday-march-24-2013-at-pittsfield-grange/</guid>
      <description>Kim Bayer asked me to pass this event along, which sounds like a great time if you are considering getting a CSA farm share for 2013 in the Ann Arbor area.
---------------------------------
Greetings
Slow Food Huron Valley invites you to the first annual CSA Fair on Sunday, March 24, 2013 from 2-4pm at the Pittsfield Grange. It is free to attend, and more than 20 CSAs will be represented. Meet CSA farmers, find out which option works for you and sign up for the perfect CSA match - whether it&amp;#39;s vegetables, humanely raised meat, whole grains, prepared meals, frozen fruits and vegetables, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids Read Comics 2013, June 22 &amp; 23, 2013 at the Ann Arbor District Library</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-17-kids-read-comics-2013-june-22-23-2013-at-the-ann-arbor-district-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-17-kids-read-comics-2013-june-22-23-2013-at-the-ann-arbor-district-library/</guid>
      <description>Mark your calendars.&amp;#0160;More details at the Kids Read Comics web site, or on Facebook.
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boil water advisory lifted March 8, 2013 / was City of Ann Arbor boil water advisory issued on March 7, 2013 (with map of northeast side affected)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-07-city-of-ann-arbor-boil-water-advisory-issued-on-march-7-2013-with-map-of-northeast-side-affected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 11:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-07-city-of-ann-arbor-boil-water-advisory-issued-on-march-7-2013-with-map-of-northeast-side-affected/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: &amp;ldquo;The City of Ann Arbor’s boil water advisory for the northeast side has been lifted. Tests results have confirmed there is no contamination and the water is safe to drink.&amp;rdquo; via Facebook
  The following is from a City of Ann Arbor press release sent through the city&amp;rsquo;s Code Red system.
&amp;mdash;-
 The City of Ann Arbor has issued a boil water advisory for the northeast side. This is the result of the water system being depressurized due to a city contractor conducting scheduled valve maintenance on the northeast side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Former Michigan Supreme Court Justice Diane Hathaway pleads guilty to bank fraud charges in an Ann Arbor federal courtroom</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-29-former-michigan-supreme-court-justice-diane-hathaway-pleads-guilty-to-bank-fraud-charges-in-an-ann-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 13:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-29-former-michigan-supreme-court-justice-diane-hathaway-pleads-guilty-to-bank-fraud-charges-in-an-ann-a/</guid>
      <description>The story from the Detroit News&amp;rsquo;s Chad Livengood (@chadlivengood):
 Ann Arbor&amp;nbsp;— Former Michigan Supreme Court Justice Diane Hathaway pleaded guilty Tuesday to bank fraud and could face up to 18 months in prison.
Hathaway negotiated a guilty plea with federal prosecutors and waived her right to indictment or trial. She appeared before U.S. District Court John Corbett O&amp;rsquo;Meara in his Ann Arbor courthouse just eight days after stepping down from the high court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downtown Ann Arbor fire at 401 S Division St</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-downtown-ann-arbor-fire-at-401-s-division-st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 20:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-downtown-ann-arbor-fire-at-401-s-division-st/</guid>
      <description>A downtown rental house caught fire on the evening of Friday, January 25, 2013. Initial reports did not include any mention of injuries, and two dogs were reported rescued.
Coverage:
Damn Arbor: &amp;nbsp;Huge fire!
AnnArbor.com:&amp;nbsp;Fire breaks out at apartment house in downtown Ann Arbor; pets saved; Saturday 1/26/2013 update Ann Arbor fire aftermath: &#39;I&#39;m so grateful&#39; about dog rescue and resident safety
Michigan Daily: Fire breaks out at house near ISR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor is &#34;very bikeable&#34;, according to Bike Score (with map)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-26-ann-arbor-is-very-bikeable-according-to-bike-score-with-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 17:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-26-ann-arbor-is-very-bikeable-according-to-bike-score-with-map/</guid>
      <description>I watched a cyclist go down Packard today in the middle of a snowstorm, so you get an idea of how intrepid you need to be to enjoy Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s bicycle routes around town. Here&amp;#39;s a map of where Bike Score thinks the city is most bikeable.&amp;#0160;It looks like they are missing the bicycle path along the river through Gallup Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Distinguished Lecture Series, Dr. Richard Stallman, Jan 17, 4:15 pm, Stamps Auditorium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-19-cse-distinguished-lecture-series-dr-richard-stallman-jan-17-415-pm-stamps-auditorium-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 16:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-19-cse-distinguished-lecture-series-dr-richard-stallman-jan-17-415-pm-stamps-auditorium-/</guid>
      <description>Richard Stallman will be on the University of Michigan campus on January 17, 2013. Here&amp;#39;s the event poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faces of Faith 2013, Sunday January 13, 2013, 2-4pm at Zion Lutheran Church</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-15-faces-of-faith-2013-sunday-january-13-2013-2-4pm-at-zion-lutheran-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 15:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-15-faces-of-faith-2013-sunday-january-13-2013-2-4pm-at-zion-lutheran-church/</guid>
      <description>FACES OF FAITH 2013 Sunday, January 13th 2 - 4 pm Zion Lutheran Church 1501 W. Liberty, Ann Arbor 48103 Sponsored by &amp;#0160;The Interfaith Round Table of Washtenaw County  Have you ever wondered what inspires people to practice different faiths or follow different spiritual teachings? &amp;#0160;  FACES OF FAITH lets you meet with people from a variety of faith backgrounds and spiritual paths including atheists and religiously unaffiliated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to (and participating in!) the W8UM net for Sunday, November 18, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-18-listening-to-and-participating-in-the-w8um-net-for-sunday-november-18-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 21:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-18-listening-to-and-participating-in-the-w8um-net-for-sunday-november-18-2012/</guid>
      <description>My friend Dan KB6NU&amp;#0160;was network control for the W8UM net tonight at 8:00 p.m. Eastern&amp;#0160;(145.230 MHz, -600 kHz shift, 100 Hz PL). This was my first try at being on for the net, and so I waited patiently until my radio started making noises other than static.
After most everyone else checked in, I hit the transmit button and gave my call sign (KD8OQG) and was acknowledged by Dan.&amp;#0160;
Among other things discussed tonight:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many signs did the City of Ann Arbor remove from the right of way in 2012?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-15-how-many-signs-did-the-city-of-ann-arbor-remove-from-the-right-of-way-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 22:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-15-how-many-signs-did-the-city-of-ann-arbor-remove-from-the-right-of-way-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Community Standards Department routinely removes signs from the right of way when someone puts something there that doesn&amp;#39;t belong. This might be an advertising sign, a political yard sign, or something else that fits the bill. The city&amp;#39;s sign ordinance sets the standards.
I asked the city in a FOIA request to give me more information about sign removals, and after we went back and forth a while to get a request that was easy to fill, here&amp;#39;s what I got: a count of the number of signs removed each month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geek tour: WCBN-FM control room, Wednesday, November 14, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</guid>
      <description>a2geeks is hosting a tour of the WCBN-FM control room on Wednesday, November 14, 2012. Tours start at 5:30p, 6:30p, and 7:30p, and you should RSVP for your space. (I&amp;#39;ll be at the 5:30pm tour.)
WCBN is an amazing student-run radio station at the University of Michigan, founded in 1972 and broadcasting from the basement of the Student Activities Building. Listen live to WCBN at 88.3 FM (all the way to the left on your dial) or online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stadium Bridges to reopen!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-stadium-bridges-to-reopen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 14:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-13-stadium-bridges-to-reopen/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Stadium Bridges are reopening on Wednesday, November 14, 2012 after about a year of being closed for reconstruction, according to messages from the city. The latest information that I have is that the bridge will open at 5:00 p.m. Wednesday, but that there will be intermittent lane closures for the rest of the week to finish up the job. City engineer Mike Nearing emailed me to say that &amp;quot;at least one sidewalk will be open while our contractor works to clean and finish the work on the roadway and bridges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He is a carp of constant sorrow.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-he-is-a-carp-of-constant-sorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-he-is-a-carp-of-constant-sorrow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m being followed (on Twitter) by a twenty pound carp - and not just any old carp, but a&amp;#0160;cyprinid philosopher-fish.
This particular carp - and it&amp;#39;s a distinctive carp, having been transported from its west side retention pond hood into the Waters of the State, namely the mighty Huron River - is a keen observer of riparian life, a stalwart proponent of local governance, and an aspiring banjo player. A carp of constant sorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor precinct polling places for November 2012 election</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-05-ann-arbor-precinct-polling-places-for-november-2012-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 18:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-05-ann-arbor-precinct-polling-places-for-november-2012-election/</guid>
      <description>The original of this list is on the Ann Arbor City Clerk&amp;#39;s web site, but for some reason it&amp;#39;s a PDF. I&amp;#39;ve linked these to Arborwiki pages where they exist as I can.
If you&amp;#39;re looking for a Michigan sample ballot, see the Michigan Voter Information Center, at&amp;#0160;https://webapps.sos.state.mi.us/mivote/.&amp;#0160;
Precinct Polling Places – November 6, 2012 1-1 Michigan Union 530 S. State St. 1-2 Michigan Union 530 S. State St. 1-3 Community High School 401 N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir Vitae Coffee and Tea, E Liberty St, Ann Arbor next to Liberty St Robot Supply</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-18-elixir-vitae-coffee-and-tea-e-liberty-st-ann-arbor-next-to-liberty-st-robot-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 15:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-18-elixir-vitae-coffee-and-tea-e-liberty-st-ann-arbor-next-to-liberty-st-robot-supply/</guid>
      <description>I had my first chance to sit at the new Elixir Vitae cafe on East Liberty today. The store is one of two with that name, after the Cafe Ambrosia store on Maynard Street changed its name. (Same ownership, just a new name, because of conflicts with too many other coffee businesses called Ambrosia).
Some impressions:
There&amp;#39;s a lot more sunshine in the new cafe than there ever was in the old one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-afternoon notes on an ordinary 9/11</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-11-mid-afternoon-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-11-mid-afternoon-notes/</guid>
      <description>Some news notes from 9/11/12; I&amp;#39;m not including any memorials of 9/11/01 in this listing.
Newfoundland lashed by&amp;#0160;Hurricane Leslie.&amp;#0160;Power was out to over 20,000 subscribers, and the strong winds (up to 137 km/hr, or 85 mph) toppled trees and ripped roofs off buildings. &amp;#0160;[CBC]&amp;#0160;[wikipedia] The track of Leslie is next expected to hit Iceland. [Weather Underground].
Chicago teachers strike in second day. [Chicago Tribune] City parks have opened up activity centers to help take care of the some 350,000 students affected by the labor action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the importance of a morning deadline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-10-morning-deadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 10:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-10-morning-deadline/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve always written better when there has been a deadline. Here&amp;#39;s what I have on top of my mind on a chilly September morning, written over the span of about an hour.
Chicago teachers are on strike. The Chicago Tribune&amp;#39;s live blog of the strike&amp;#0160;notes that 144 locations are open to handle kids that get free lunches and breakfasts, and that the CTA is offering free fares to students to get to those schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erratic water levels on the mighty Huron River, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>This graph measures water levels downstream from Argo Dam. Water levels are not supposed to fluctuate this much - it&amp;#39;s not good for the river.
More data at the USGS.
Update: I checked with USGS to make sure that the gauges were working fine, and got back this result:
We&amp;#39;re pretty certain everything is working just fine there. I believe we have a hydrologic technician there today making a streamflow measurement and he&amp;#39;ll verify the operation of the equipment at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantified Self show at the Gallery Project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-quantified-self-show-at-the-gallery-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-quantified-self-show-at-the-gallery-project/</guid>
      <description>From the news release:
The&amp;#0160;Gallery Project presents&amp;#0160;Quantified Self, a multimedia exhibit in which 34 local, regional, and national artists examine how individuals collect and often project information about themselves and others in the digital world. Artists examine the quantified self from two unique perspectives: one, how information about individuals is collected, stored, processed, and used by these individuals and communicated to others; and two how entities collect information about individuals and groups for commercial and other purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Newshawks Summer 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-24-ann-arbor-newshawks-summer-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 23:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-24-ann-arbor-newshawks-summer-2012/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s #1 investigative news team!
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor District Library to circulate electronic music tools; Moog Foundation event August 1, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-30-ann-arbor-district-library-to-circulate-electronic-music-tools-moog-foundation-event-august-1-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-30-ann-arbor-district-library-to-circulate-electronic-music-tools-moog-foundation-event-august-1-2012/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Eli Neiburger for the heads up for this event -&amp;#0160;
The Ann Arbor District Library is launching a new circulating collection of&amp;#0160;electronic music tools, and they are brining &amp;quot;Dr. Bob&amp;#39;s Sound School&amp;quot;, a&amp;#0160;program of the Robert Moog Foundation, to AADL this Wednesday August 1, 2012.&amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s an introduction to the principles of electronic sound synthesis,&amp;#0160;a little history of Moog, and a chance to get your hands on some&amp;#0160;seriously cool and unusual music tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE substation fire and Ann Arbor power outage, June 28, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-28-dte-substation-fire-and-ann-arbor-power-outage-june-28-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 17:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-28-dte-substation-fire-and-ann-arbor-power-outage-june-28-2012/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (June 28, 2012): A fire at a DTE substation on South State Street caused over 6,000 people to lose power on the hottest day of the year so far. The fire was located at the State Substation, located between South State Street and Boardwalk near the Ann Arbor Public Schools&amp;#0160;Balas Administration Building.
A number of organizations have been reported to be affected by the outage. News coverage includes reporting from Detroit WXYZ Channel 7,&amp;#0160;AnnArbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs in Ann Arbor, a list of links to employer web sites on Arborwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-26-jobs-in-ann-arbor-a-list-of-links-to-employer-web-sites-on-arborwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 11:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-26-jobs-in-ann-arbor-a-list-of-links-to-employer-web-sites-on-arborwiki/</guid>
      <description>As part of my search for work in Ann Arbor, I&amp;#39;ve been compiling a list of employers who maintain lists of open opportunities on their web sites. You can see the list here
http://arborwiki.org/city/Jobs
As of this writing there are about 60 employers listed, though not all of them have open positions at this time.
There&amp;#39;s a wide variety of online job postings systems being used by employers, ranging from the simple web page listing one or two positions to the unimaginably complex setup when an HR organization has hundreds of positions to fill worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Book Festival June 22-23 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-19-ann-arbor-book-festival-june-22-23-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-19-ann-arbor-book-festival-june-22-23-2012/</guid>
      <description>The University Library is pleased to be a partner of the Ann Arbor Book Festival this year, and cordially&amp;#0160;invites&amp;#0160;you to the&amp;#0160;following&amp;#0160;free events:&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;
 Friday, June 22, 4:30 pm&amp;#0160;-- reception to celebrate the Ann Arbor Book Festival Exhibit in the Hatcher Graduate Library north lobby, meet the authors and illustrators featured in the exhibit, and enjoy delicious refreshments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobblestone Farm Market, Ann Arbor - opening day June 19, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-18-cobblestone-farm-market-ann-arbor-opening-day-june-19-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 13:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-18-cobblestone-farm-market-ann-arbor-opening-day-june-19-2012/</guid>
      <description>Cobblestone Farm Market is opening June 19, 2012 from 4:00 p.m. to 7:00 p.m. at historic Cobblestone Farm in Ann Arbor. Details: http://cobblestonefarmmarket.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Chronicle vs Com dustup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-04-on-the-chronicle-vs-com-dustup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 16:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-04-on-the-chronicle-vs-com-dustup/</guid>
      <description>Why oh why can&amp;#39;t we have a&amp;#0160;better press corps?
I am sure that all this “you’re doing it wrong” media criticism hearkens back to a golden era of competition in journalism, so bully for you all&amp;#0160;in stirring up a Newhouse/funhouse fight.
Perhaps instead of throwing up wadded old balls of newsprint at each other you could both get back to focus on accurate attention to details, expressed concisely enough to be grasped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My little pixelated town</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-01-my-little-pixelated-town/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 11:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-01-my-little-pixelated-town/</guid>
      <description>Herb David, Jerusalem Garden, and Earthen Jar as depicted in the Ann Arbor District Library&amp;#39;s Minecraft server and spotted by Eric Klooster.
More details at http://minecraft.aadl.org .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I voted; this year&#39;s Automark trial and error</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-09-i-voted-this-years-automark-trial-and-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-09-i-voted-this-years-automark-trial-and-error/</guid>
      <description>I used the Automark machine to vote today, as I did in 2010 (AnnArbor.com story) and in 2008 (Vacuum post).

This year&amp;#39;s voting excursion was harder, because the poll worker initially told me that I could not use the machine and that it was reserved for the handicapped. That was wrong; any voter in my precinct could use that system. The issue was resolved quickly.
For the first time, I used the audio interface and had the (one) issue on the ballot read out to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Water Hill Music Fest: Sunday, May 6th, from 2 to 6 p.m. (rain date May 13th).</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-23-2012-water-hill-music-fest-sunday-may-6th-from-2-to-6-pm-rain-date-may-13th-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-23-2012-water-hill-music-fest-sunday-may-6th-from-2-to-6-pm-rain-date-may-13th-/</guid>
      <description>From Paul Tinkerhess, organizer:
 The 2012 Water Hill Music Fest is set to happen Sunday, May 6th, from 2 to 6 p.m. (rain date May 13th). &amp;#0160;All residents of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Water Hill neighborhood are invited to play music on their front porches during this unique celebration. &amp;#0160;Expectations are high this year after thousands of visitors attended last year&amp;#39;s inaugural event.  More information:&amp;#0160;www.waterhill.org&amp;#0160;and&amp;#0160;www.facebook.com/waterhillmusicfest&amp;#0160;.
From last year&amp;#39;s event, as documented by Michigan Radio:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoBuPa neighborhood meeting, April 11, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-03-lobupa-neighborhood-meeting-april-11-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 06:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-04-03-lobupa-neighborhood-meeting-april-11-2012/</guid>
      <description>The Lower Burns Park Neighborhood Association announces its spring meeting for neighbors in LoBuPa. Please join us, details follow. Thanks go to Nancy Leff for organizing this meeting.
WEDNESDAY, APRIL 11, 2012
7 pm - 8:30 pm
Buddhist Temple on Packard
1.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Jim Kosteva, UM Director of Community relations, A2 city representative(s), and our local city council representatives, Margie Teall &amp;amp; Marcia Higgins&amp;#0160;will all be in attendance.&amp;#0160;There are&amp;#0160;many&amp;#0160;issues to discuss&amp;#0160;related to the Athletic department’s current&amp;#0160;Big House rental agreement&amp;#0160;with pro hockey and potential rentals for other events and how these events will&amp;#0160;affect our neighborhood: will parking on lawns be permitted during these events, how will traffic be managed, how will events with liquor licenses mange potentially unruly, intoxicated&amp;#0160;attendees, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insomnia cookies stop work order [with photo]</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-29-insomnia-cookies-stop-work-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 23:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-29-insomnia-cookies-stop-work-order/</guid>
      <description>This stop work order on a new Insomnia Cookies store caught my eye tonight as I was walking down South University.

The relevant permits - or the absense of same - can be found in the City of Ann Arbor eTrakit system. As of 3/23/2012, the ones that have been pulled are
COFO12-0037, which I presume is a certificate of occupancy and is &amp;quot;under review&amp;quot;.
&amp;#0160;
REOC12-0036, reoccupation, change of use &amp;quot;YOGURT SHOP TO INSOMNIA COOKIES&amp;quot;, under review SIGN12-0032, awning &amp;quot;Insomnia Cookies&amp;quot; approved 3/29/2012 &amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festifools and Fool Moon 2012 Calendar</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-20-festifools-and-fool-moon-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-20-festifools-and-fool-moon-2012/</guid>
      <description>Foolish plans!
FRIDAY (3/30/2012): FoolMoon, Dusk-Midnight, @ Washington &amp;amp; Ashley. FREE! **Luminary constellation stations include: Slauson Middle School, Kerrytown Farmers Market, and University of Michigan Museum of Art. Join us with a luminary and maybe a kazoo at 7:30 p.m. and we&amp;#39;ll process and parade our way to FoolMoon!
SATURDAY (3/31/2012): Foolish Acts, 9 p.m. @ the Blind Pig. 18+ show. $10. **Music by Appleseed Collective, Third Coast Kings, and LMFA2O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor turns down request for meeting minutes, again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 19:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-02-18-ann-arbor-municipal-irritant/</guid>
      <description>The City of Ann Arbor has dozens of citizen boards and commissions, with members appointed by the mayor, that conduct some of the decision making parts of city government. Most of these boards toil in utter obscurity, with no one in attendance at meetings other than the minimum required board members and staff.
Despite (or perhaps because of) this obscurity, there are some interesting things to be discovered by reading board minutes and board packets from these groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor plow trucks: public tracking</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-02-ann-arbor-plow-trucks-public-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 23:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-02-ann-arbor-plow-trucks-public-tracking/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor plow truck public tracking page shows where the snow plows are out and about in Ann Arbor.

This view shows 4 of the 5 trucks that were out on Monday evening, January 2, 2012.
Plow routes are color coded, and plow trucks are numbered. One tip: if you are using Chrome, turn on and off the &amp;quot;label&amp;quot; field to get the trucks to show.
The system is build by Radio Satellite Integrators, and uses ESRI map technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lumineria of upper Brooklyn Avenue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-the-lumineria-of-upper-brooklyn-avenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 21:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-the-lumineria-of-upper-brooklyn-avenue/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: next year, on the solstice, arrange that lower Brooklyn Avenue joins in the collection of lumineria that grace upper Brooklyn Avneue (between Packard and Lincoln) tonight.
(photo to follow)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free things on your (happy) birthday in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</guid>
      <description>One of the most popular pages on Arborwiki is the Birthday deals page, which tracks the ever-changing Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti area retail landscape by looking at places which give you some kind of special deal on your birthday. If your birthday is coming up soon, give it a look, and if you need to poke someone on your favorite social network site to wish them a happy birthday, a link to this page is always appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Elementary school closed December 7, 2011 due to power outage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-burns-park-elementary-school-closed-december-7-2011-due-to-power-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 07:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-burns-park-elementary-school-closed-december-7-2011-due-to-power-outage/</guid>
      <description>We got word via telephone this morning before school started that a power outage at Burns Park Elementary School (see map below, from the DTE outage map) has cancelled school for the day. The outage affects over 1400 customers in Burns Park, Lower Burns Park, and along South State Street. I can&#39;t tell from the map whether University of Michigan facilities are also affected, but the report from the dotcom is that traffic signals are also affected along Packard and on East Stadium near the Stadium Bridges project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 13:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>And, if I am able to rectify the situation, I will share my profits with Jordan Miller.
 I agree! There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this website. I, for one, love sandwiches. What if all the pet stories were sandwich stories instead? Everyone isn&#39;t into pets, but who doesn&#39;t like sandwiches? Not anyone I want living in my town. PS if [redacted] puts this advice into action, I expect a share of what is sure to be a tremendous surge in profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiku for a construction project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-haiku-for-a-construction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 11:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-haiku-for-a-construction-project/</guid>
      <description>The bridges are out
So I will go two new ways
Down your one way street
 A bridge to nowhere
Barriers upend us all
Together we cope
 Confusion arrives
Cars become pedestrians
Can&#39;t wait for State Street!
 Stadium is closed?
The bridge is being torn down?
How do I get home?
Credits: Edward Vielmetti, Pam Hoffer (twice), Bill Ingram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Onion leaves Ann Arbor, three months after it arrived</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-30-the-onion-leaves-ann-arbor-three-months-after-it-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 21:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-30-the-onion-leaves-ann-arbor-three-months-after-it-arrived/</guid>
      <description>The Onion&#39;s local arts and entertainment section AV Club Ann Arbor is leaving town, only three months after it set up shop. Michigan Radio had the news, though they were too polite to run their recording of a conversation with the franchisee, Bobby Mitchell of Bopper Media. I spoke with the director of sales who referred questions to Mitchell who wasn&#39;t available for comment (i.e. I didn&#39;t have his phone number).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council proposes, but does not vote on, anti free newspaper distribution law</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-21-ann-arbor-city-council-anti-free-newspaper-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 23:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-21-ann-arbor-city-council-anti-free-newspaper-law/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (December 5, 2011): There are a number of neighborhoods in Ann Arbor where there are citizens who receive newspapers, and &#34;newspaper-like items&#34;, where the citizen does not pay for the newspaper. We receive a free copy of the Ann Arbor Journal, and there are some neighborhoods where a number of students receive the Wall Street Journal gratis.
Alas, not everyone who gets a free paper opens it up in time for it to be useful, and some of it turns into litter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusing pedestrian detour signs are up in Lower Burns Park neighborhood for @annarborbridges project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-pedestrian-detour-lower-burns-park-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 23:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-17-pedestrian-detour-lower-burns-park-signs/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, LOWER BURNS PARK (November 17-19, 2011): There is concern among neighbors in the Lower Burns Park Neighborhood Association that the pedestrian detour signs that have been posted in the neighborhood for the Stadium Bridges project are non-standard and will be interpreted as traffic control signs for cars, not for people. Two vehicles were observed going the wrong way on Golden Avenue on Friday night, November 18.
The signs in question is similar to, but not the same as, standard MUTCD sign M4-9b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower Burns Park, Golden Avenue: plans from the City of Ann Arbor for two way traffic during State St closing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-16-golden-avenue-two-way-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-16-golden-avenue-two-way-plans/</guid>
      <description>Attached, please find the signing and pavement marking plan that we prepared to support the two week period when E. Stadium and S. State Street will both be closed to through traffic.
 
A more detailed copy of this is available at the Ann Arbor Government Document Repository, as document 300. You will note that the city&#39;s signage plan, at the date of publishing this article, is to run two way bus traffic on Golden for two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riverwood house fire, Ann Arbor MI 48103 (with video)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-11-riverwood-fire-ann-arbor-mi-48103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-11-riverwood-fire-ann-arbor-mi-48103/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (Friday, November 11, 2011) - A house on Riverwood (at Timber Trail, off Newport north of M-14) caught fire at about 10:00 a.m. this morning. No estimate on damages yet, no report of injuries to people. Details follow.
(ANN ARBOR CITY - INTEROP 4) FULLY INVOLVED 2 STORY HOUSE FIRE. FULL AAFD RESPONSE. MA YPSI CITY, YPSI TWN, AND PITTSFIELD FIRE DEPARTMENT. (as seen on Radio Reference)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County election results, November 8, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-08-ann-arbor-and-washtenaw-county-election-results-november-8-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 20:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-08-ann-arbor-and-washtenaw-county-election-results-november-8-2011/</guid>
      <description>A live blog of election results. Unofficial county results from Washtenaw County elections; most links that don&#39;t go to news stories for individual information are going to Arborwiki.
For news coverage, see AnnArbor.com, the Ann Arbor Chronicle, and News of Ann Arbor (this is satire), not necessarily in that order. Additional reporting from the Heritage News&#39;s ChelseaDexter twitter feed, the Manchester Enterprise, and the Michigan Daily. Blogs include Damn Arbor: Happy election day citizens!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moonset over University Hospital, Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-06-moonset-over-university-hospital-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 23:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-06-moonset-over-university-hospital-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Time lapse photography from Kai Petainen, looking west towards U Hospital in Ann Arbor. Used with permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 6 Ann Arbor is Sunday, November 6, 2011!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-03-ignite-6-ann-arbor-is-sunday-november-6-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 23:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-03-ignite-6-ann-arbor-is-sunday-november-6-2011/</guid>
      <description>Flier below. Details at the Ignite Ann Arbor site, RSVP at Eventbrite. Ignite Ann Arbor 6 will be held at Blau Auditorium, 701 Tappan Street, at 7pm on Sunday November 6th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conquer the cold! Preparing for the winter commute</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-02-conquer-the-cold-preparing-for-the-winter-commute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 20:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-02-conquer-the-cold-preparing-for-the-winter-commute/</guid>
      <description>Conquer the Cold is a program for submissions and suggestions on how to best make your winter commute a good one. It&#39;s run by get!Downtown, the Ann Arbor downtown commuter program, and there are fabulous prizes. Send in a 150 word essay and you could win a $500 shopping spree or one of many $5 gift certificates. To be eligible to participate in the Conquer the Cold essay contest, you must have a current go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding the overnight storm of October 24 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-24-regarding-the-overnight-storm-of-october-24-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 05:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-24-regarding-the-overnight-storm-of-october-24-2011/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, October 24, 2011, 5:00 a.m. - I wasn&#39;t expecting to be woken up by lightning, but there you are. The map is from StrikeStar, and a zoomed in power outage showing the north shore of Base Line Lake.


500a woken up by thunder and lightning
522a localized power outage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Burns Park Association fall 2011 meeting at Ann Arbor Friends Meeting House</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-11-north-burns-park-association/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 22:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-11-north-burns-park-association/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, October 11, 2011. Residents of North Burns Park gathered at the Friends Meeting House on Hill Street for the annual North Burns Park Association meeting this evening.
The organization announced its new web site, northburnspark.org , which includes a neighborhood calendar, history, photographs of notable homes and a directory of city and civic resources. The webmaster, (who?), was generous in recognizing volunteers who had helped compile and edit text and photography for the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoky house fire on Harpst Street in Ann Arbor on the evening of October 7, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-07-fire-harpst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 22:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-07-fire-harpst/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, October 7, 11:30 p.m. - A house near the corner of Harpst Street and Tremmell Avenue was on fire on the evening of October 7, 2011. This photo is provided courtesy of Mike Nowak (@snackdog) and is used with permission. The Ann Arbor Fire Department cleared the scene just after 11:00 p.m, according to radio monitoring reports.
 Enough smoke was generated by the fire that residents of the nearby Woodbury Gardens complex called for help, and trucks from Pittsfield Township and Ypsilanti Township were seen departing the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Borders Books (1971-2011)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-19-borders-books-1971-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-19-borders-books-1971-2011/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, Mich., July 18, 2011 /PRNewswire via COMTEX/ --
Borders Group reported today that, in accordance with the terms of its financing agreement, the Company will submit to the Court for approval the previously-announced proposal from&amp;#0160;Hilco and Gordon Brothers&amp;#0160;to purchase the store assets of the business and administer the liquidation process. Borders said that, in the absence of a formal proposal from a going concern bidder, it did not require an auction prior to presenting the proposal to the Court at a scheduled hearing on&amp;#0160;Thursday, July 21, 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recyclebank Ann Arbor reports released; coupon redemption rates are low, but people recycle anyway</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-08-recyclebank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 11:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-08-recyclebank/</guid>
      <description>In response to a Freedom of Information Act request, the City of Ann Arbor has released reports showing the participation rate of Ann Arbor households in the Recyclebank program, which rewards citizens for putting out their recycling. The reports were provided in graphical format, so all numbers here are approximated.
The summary report of program performance provided in response to the request shows that about 40% of eligible citizens (about 9500 of 24000) have signed up for the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Around: bonus points</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-29-walking-around-bonus-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 10:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-29-walking-around-bonus-points/</guid>
      <description>I walked a lot more today than I normally would have walked, thanks to my new game Walking Around. Here&amp;#39;s some of the bonus points I scored that I wouldn&amp;#39;t have scored in my previous quest, Sitting Around Typing.
Pedestrian Path (+1). It&amp;#39;s always good to find a way to get from here to there that&amp;#39;s not on any map. The pedestrian path I found connects Needham Road to Amelia Place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Aid Benefit Concert with Joe Reilly, Ann Arbor, Sunday, June 5, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-25-japan-aid-benefit-concert-with-joe-reilly-ann-arbor-sunday-june-5-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-25-japan-aid-benefit-concert-with-joe-reilly-ann-arbor-sunday-june-5-2011/</guid>
      <description>A fundraiser with Joe Reilly for&amp;#0160;the Japan Earthquake and Tsunami victims. Join on&amp;#0160;Sunday, June 5, 2011 from 3:30-5:00pm at the Ann Arbor Senior Center in&amp;#0160;Burns Park (1320 Baldwin Ave.). $7 (or more) per person or $20 (or&amp;#0160;more) per family at the door. There will be a craft sale on site and&amp;#0160;all the proceeds go to the Japan Red Cross.&amp;#0160;
Details: MichiganJapan.com&amp;#0160;or contact Junko Meschievitz at&amp;#0160;me.junko@gmail.com .
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FoolMoon 2011 luminary parade map, April 1, 2011; gather at 7:45 p.m., procession starts at 8:15 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-foolmoon-2011-luminary-parade-map-april-1-2011-gather-at-745-pm-procession-starts-at-815-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-foolmoon-2011-luminary-parade-map-april-1-2011-gather-at-745-pm-procession-starts-at-815-pm/</guid>
      <description>From the Facebook event page for FoolMoon 2011:
 Bring your luminary (or kazoo / chicken suit / saxophone / what have you) to one of our three “Constellation Stations” (aka starting points), and join fellow frolickers for the Foolish stroll to W. Washington Street. We will begin gathering around 7:45pm, and the processionals will set off at 8:15pm.&amp;#0160;
 The starting points on the map below: U of Michigan Museum of Art on State Street, Farmers Market in Kerrytown, and Slauson Middle School on West Washington St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Justice Center grand opening, Saturday April 16, 2011, 10a-noon</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-31-ann-arbor-justice-center-grand-opening-saturday-april-16-2011-10a-noon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 23:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-31-ann-arbor-justice-center-grand-opening-saturday-april-16-2011-10a-noon/</guid>
      <description>The building is at the corner of Huron and Fifth Avenue in Ann Arbor, across the street from the downtown fire department and also across the street from the striking brutalist wonder of the Michigan Bell telecom bunker.
With every downtown event comes the &amp;quot;where do we park&amp;quot; question, to which I am certain that there must be an answer.
Light refreshments will be served!
Edward Vielmetti collects municipal ephemera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are we going to do about South U? Vote early, vote often!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-31-poll-ann-arbor-south-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 22:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-31-poll-ann-arbor-south-university/</guid>
      <description>For reference, see the Arborwiki South University page, which has some fragments of history that might be referenced in one or more poll items.
  Edward Vielmetti misses Steve&#39;s Lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partial failure of retaining wall near Earthen Jar, Jerusalem Garden at Library Lot</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-24-library-lot-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-24-library-lot-construction/</guid>
      <description>A portion of a retaining wall failed on March 24, 2011 before 5:00 p.m. at the Ann Arbor &amp;quot;Library Lot&amp;quot; construction project, and Earthen Jar and Jerusalem Garden have been evacuated as a result.
 Contractors from Christman, Soil and Materials Engineers, DTE Energy, and Doan Companies&amp;#0160;were on site at 9:00 p.m. to stabilize the sinkhole that formed when a portion of the retaining wall gave way.&amp;#0160;
 I spoke with senior project manager&amp;#0160;Adrian Iraola&amp;#0160;of&amp;#0160;Park Avenue Consultants, who got on site about when I did shortly after 5:00 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-11-07-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 20:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-11-07-predictions/</guid>
      <description>A much-beloved but seedy local landmark will close, with developers planning to build a shiny hi-rise on the location. The developers will raise enough money to partially demolish the landmark, but will run out of money before they start building the hi-rise. A decade and several bankruptcies later, a new building will be built on top of the rubble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Gears, NPR project adding staff for Rustbelt local coverage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 00:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Award-winning journalists from public media, the Web and newspapers are now part of the Changing Gears team. via www.changinggears.info
National Public Radio launching local coverage out of Cleveland, Ann Arbor, and Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Hands Active, downtown Ann Arbor hacker space</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-27-all-hands-active-downtown-ann-arbor-hacker-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-27-all-hands-active-downtown-ann-arbor-hacker-space/</guid>
      <description>All Hands Active is a downtown Ann Arbor hacker space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>muskrat love</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-17-muskrat-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 23:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-17-muskrat-love/</guid>
      <description>As part of a &amp;quot;town fauna&amp;quot; series on AnnArbor.com, I wrote this piece on a muskrat rescue by a 4th grade group on a field trip to a water treatment plant.
I take no small measure of pride in the first comment: &amp;quot;thank god for the ann arbor news and their hard-hitting muskrat coverage. unbelievable.&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. David Aberdeen, former Burns Park Elementary principal, obituary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 02:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</guid>
      <description>original from annarbor.com, hyperlinks mine
 F. David Aberdeen
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;addThis&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_AddThis&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt; var addthis_pub = &amp;amp;quot;legacycomobituaries&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_brand = &amp;amp;quot;Legacy.com&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_options = &amp;amp;quot;favorites, delicious, reddit, google, facebook, digg, twitter, yahoobkm, myspace, bebo&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_header_color = &amp;amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_header_background = &amp;amp;quot;#546F82&amp;amp;quot;;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;javascript:void(0);&amp;quot; onmouseout=&amp;quot;addthis_close();&amp;quot; onmouseover=&amp;quot;return addthis_open(this, &amp;amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;, &amp;amp;quot;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;amp;pid=133524746&amp;amp;quot;, &amp;amp;quot;F. Aberdeen Death Notice: F. Aberdeen’s Obituary by the AnnArbor.com.&amp;amp;quot;);&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Share&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;obitEmail&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary-email.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;amp;pid=133524746&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_EmailObituaryLink&amp;quot;&amp;gt;E-mail&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;viewSignGuestBook&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://www.legacy.com/gb2/default.aspx?bookid=3762524876042&amp;amp;amp;cid=full&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_VisitGuestBookLink&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Visit Guest Book&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;obitText&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; hspace=&amp;quot;10&amp;quot; lgyorigname=&amp;quot;0003443845-01-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s just dirt</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-25-its-just-dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 02:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-25-its-just-dirt/</guid>
      <description>From Concentrate: &amp;quot;The politics of dirt in downtown Ann Arbor&amp;quot;
The hole is for the Library Lot underground parking deck next to the Ann Arbor District Library. The city has started on some of the work to build a 677-car parking garage underneath a surface parking lot on Fourth Street and to replace some of the surrounding infrastructure, such as sewer and water lines. 
But the big hole for all of those cars is coming later this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Morning Physics 2009-2010 letter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-23-saturday-morning-physics-20092010-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 09:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-23-saturday-morning-physics-20092010-letter/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s the annual letter for Saturday Morning Physics at Michigan, published in its entirety because I am lazy.
----
Greetings Saturday Morning Physics Community Members,
&amp;#0160;
September marks the start of a new academic year, the return of Michigan Football, and the beginning of a new and exciting year of Saturday Morning Physics (SMP)! We are proud to be starting our 14th year of SMP on October 3rd and are very grateful to our speakers and our audience for their time and enthusiasm, which has made SMP so successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>will the construction on Packard be done for student move in?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-21-will-the-construction-on-packard-be-done-for-student-move-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 09:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-21-will-the-construction-on-packard-be-done-for-student-move-in/</guid>
      <description>What just happened: I rode into town on the #5, including the portion of it which is under construction on Packard near campus. &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;
The back story: City streets are always under construction in the summer time. &amp;#0160;Some times construction projects unexpectedly run late. &amp;#0160;When students move in, every single street near campus - including that stretch of campus near Packard - is jammed full of returning students. &amp;#0160;The students are coming (EEEK).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2geeks: weekly events for week of 8/3/09 via @dugsong</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-03-a2geeks-weekly-events-for-week-of-8309-via-dugsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-08-03-a2geeks-weekly-events-for-week-of-8309-via-dugsong/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Dug Song for this events listing - posted as he emailed it out to the a2geeks list.Monthly events piled up again on Wednesday. Have a great week!
Wednesday:
- Weekly CITI donuts, 10 AM at CITI:&amp;#0160;http://www.citi.umich.edu
- Weekly LA2M meeting, noon at Conor O&amp;#39;Neill&amp;#39;s.
http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=10523192702
- Weekly CoffeeHouseCoders hackathon, 9 PM at Espresso Royale on State
St. (through the summer).&amp;#0160;http://coffeehousecoders.org
- Monthly SPARK Mingle &amp;amp; Match networking session, 5 PM at SPARK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still a few bugs to work out</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-26-still-a-few-bugs-to-work-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 14:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-26-still-a-few-bugs-to-work-out/</guid>
      <description>notes on the AnnArbor.com launch; first Sunday edition on the streets.
We were at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market a week ago, and market manager Molly Notarianni had a sample left of an item that a vendor was gearing up to sell for next year: a tub with a praying mantis ootheca which, when left inside, would hatch little bitty mantids for your garden. Well, today was the day that they hatched - this video is someone else&amp;rsquo;s kids enjoying their mantid hatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh: site launch for AnnArbor.com</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-25-whoosh-site-launch-for-annarborcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 01:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-25-whoosh-site-launch-for-annarborcom/</guid>
      <description>Some notes, before I quit for the night, from the launch of AnnArbor.com .
We went live at 8pm Thursday.&amp;#0160; I took a nap after coming home from work, got up at about 830pm, and went online looking at the comments; most of that evening was spent answering comments, dealing with details, being helpful and present and attentive.&amp;#0160; As much as possible, I tried to be like Caterina and George were like at the launch of Flickr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jolly Pumpkin on its way to Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-22-jolly-pumpkin-on-its-way-to-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 12:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-22-jolly-pumpkin-on-its-way-to-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>The Jolly Pumpkin has a sign up at 311 S Main St, where Pepperz used to be, in downtown Ann Arbor. Barbara Tozier snapped a photo of the sign, a photo which has been making its rounds of the beer-loving community around town. Permits were approved for the space on July 21, 2009 for electrical work; ELEC09-0838 goes to contractor Top Line Electric LLC. Mechanical work on MECH09-1259 goes to Koch &amp; White Heating &amp; Cooling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Plate 765 steaming through Ann Arbor on its way to Owosso for Trainfestival 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-21-nickel-plate-765-steaming-through-ann-arbor-on-its-way-to-owosso/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-21-nickel-plate-765-steaming-through-ann-arbor-on-its-way-to-owosso/</guid>
      <description>The Fort Wayne Railroad Historical Society brought Nickel Plate 765, a steam engine, through Ann Arbor on its way to Owosso for Trainfestival 2009.  Of the engine they write:  This is the historic steam locomotive no. 765: a high-stepping, fourteen wheeled magnificent machine that stands 15 feet tall, weighs 404 tons, and goes over 60 miles an hour; restored to the way it looked and sounded when it was built by the Lima Locomotive Works in 1944.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a blogger reads the newspaper: day 13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-17-a-blogger-reads-the-newspaper-day-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-17-a-blogger-reads-the-newspaper-day-13/</guid>
      <description>Another copy of the Ann Arbor Gerbil showed up on my sidewalk this morning. &amp;#0160;It&amp;#39;s nice to have a morning paper, much nicer than the mid-afternoon Ann Arbor Snooze that used to never arrive quite early enough to read over lunch, and by the time it got to be after dinner to read it it was most of a day old.

Some of last week&amp;#39;s Gerbils that were left on lawns unread decayed enough to leave crumbs of newspaper on the lawns of apartment buildings on Packard, no worse so far than the occasional decaying NY Times or Wall St Journals that sometimes pile up in front of student rentals unread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Angels fly over Ann Arbor in preparation for &#34;Thunder Over Michigan&#34; air show at the Yankee Air Museum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-17-blue-angels-fly-over-ann-arbor-in-preparation-for-thunder-over-michigan-air-show-at-the-yankee-air-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-17-blue-angels-fly-over-ann-arbor-in-preparation-for-thunder-over-michigan-air-show-at-the-yankee-air-m/</guid>
      <description>The Blue Angels flew loud and low over the Ann Arbor Art Fairs on Thursday in preparation for their show at the Yankee Air Museum this weekend, July 18-19 2009. Whoosh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a blogger reads the newspaper; day 9</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-11-a-blogger-reads-the-newspaper-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-11-a-blogger-reads-the-newspaper-day-9/</guid>
      <description>day 9 of notes on my new job at annarbor.com
A new newspaper showed up on my sidewalk yesterday afternoon; I&amp;#39;m not going to name it by name, but let&amp;#39;s just call it the A2 Gerbil.&amp;#0160; It was a happy little paper, full of happy little stories about quaint things happening in some leafy town somewhere near here.&amp;#0160; It took me a couple of minutes to leaf through it and a few more minutes to hunt down the web site for it and appreciate some of its finer points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what I saw on my walk home, day 6</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-what-i-saw-on-my-walk-home-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 09:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-what-i-saw-on-my-walk-home-day-6/</guid>
      <description>day six of notes about my new position at annarbor.com
It&amp;#39;s about a mile and a half as the crow flies from my office at annarbor.com to my home.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; If I&amp;#39;m willing to detour a bit out of the way along the way, I can make a reasonable direct path by bus, bicycle, or walking that takes me through a big part of central campus, the athletic campus, a few neighborhoods, about 20 coffee and ice cream shops, and dozens of bulletin boards where events and notices are posted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what can you grow in your Ann Arbor street easement? 36 inch height limit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-what-can-you-grow-in-your-ann-arbor-street-easement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 06:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-08-what-can-you-grow-in-your-ann-arbor-street-easement/</guid>
      <description>A neighbor got a citation for his day lilies, which were in violation of something; I haven&amp;#39;t seen the actual paper he got to know which chapter and verse of city code they violated.
Looking through it I see Chapter 47 STREETS and section 4:2
(4)&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;It is the duty of each owner of property adjacent to a street to maintain that property so that trees, shrubs and other vegetation do not obstruct the passage of vehicles, bicycles or pedestrians on streets or sidewalks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite Ann Arbor 1 a rousing success</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-ignite-ann-arbor-1-a-rousing-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 23:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-30-ignite-ann-arbor-1-a-rousing-success/</guid>
      <description>There were a ton of people twittering from the event, held tonight at the Neutral Zone.&amp;#0160; It started promptly at 7pm, ended promptly at 9pm, featured a single-elimination rock scissors paper tournament (A2RSP, of course), and was generally and genuinely awesome.&amp;#0160; Attendance was about 200.
Trek Glowacki:
Best event I&amp;#39;ve attended all year. Nearly perfect execution from both speakers and organizers. Congrats to all involved.
A few high points: Eli Neiburger from the AADL on hacking your library; Eric from the Ann Arbor Go Club on the game of Go; the friggin lasers at the A2 Mechshop; high flying balloons; backyard satellite weather, and two versions of News 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photowalk at AADL June 27, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-photowalk-at-aadl-june-27-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-photowalk-at-aadl-june-27-2009/</guid>
      <description>pictureAnnArbor is a photography collection of Ann Arbor maintained and managed by the Ann Arbor District Library.&amp;#0160; It has a mix of personal and historical collections, including a wonderful Ann Arbor signs collection with photos from the city sign inspector from the 1970s.&amp;#0160; The AADL is hosting a photo walk this coming weekend to add more local and neighborhood photography to the collection.

Photowalk - Capture The Beauty of Ann Arbor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Gold gift certificates being redeemed by the Ann Arbor Area chamber; Certifichecks Chapter 7 bankruptcy in progress</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-01-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificates-being-redeemed-by-the-ann-arbor-area-chamber-certifichecks-chapter-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-01-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificates-being-redeemed-by-the-ann-arbor-area-chamber-certifichecks-chapter-/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Chronicle reported that the Ann Arbor Gold gift certificates will be redeemed by the Chamber of Commerce:
The Ann Arbor Area Chamber of Commerce now plans to use its own funds to reimburse people who purchased Ann Arbor Gold certificates. Earlier this year, the company that administers the program, CertifiChecks, filed for bankruptcy.

An April 15 story from the AP notes that the bankruptcy filing has gone through in Dayton, OH (via the Newark Advocate):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickens!  How to raise your own yard hens (and deal with The Man along the way)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-28-chickens-how-to-raise-your-own-yard-hens-and-deal-with-the-man-along-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-28-chickens-how-to-raise-your-own-yard-hens-and-deal-with-the-man-along-the-way/</guid>
      <description>from Matthaei Botanical Gardens Adult Education:
4/29/2009 - Yard Hens II; Raising and keeping happy, healthy hens at home
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;table style=&amp;quot;margin: 0pt 0pt 0pt 45px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Dates:&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; Wednesday April 29, 7-9pm&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Fee:&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; $20.00&amp;amp;#0160;(  $16.00 for members)   Class Number: 09-AE-19s   Description: Ready for spring chickens? Welcome hens into your yard with Part II of our wildly successful class, Yard Hens. In this second installment we expand on Part I and take an in-depth look at how to raise and care for happy, healthy birds at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Gold gift certificate vendor Certifichecks sued by Ohio Attorney General Richard Cordray, MSU &#39;81</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-10-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificate-vendor-certifichecks-sued-by-ohio-attorney-general-richard-cordray-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 14:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-10-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificate-vendor-certifichecks-sued-by-ohio-attorney-general-richard-cordray-m/</guid>
      <description>Previously: &amp;quot;Ann Arbor Gold Turns To Lead&amp;quot;
The Chamber was recently informed that CertifiChecks, the company that administered the Ann Arbor Gold program, has gone out of business.


The Ohio Attorney General, Richard Cordray, has sued Ann Arbor Gold vendor Certifichecks in Dayton, OH for violation of Ohio’s Consumer Sales Practices Act in conjunction with them shutting down redemptions of gift certificates from the Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce and 100s of other Chambers and civic organizations around the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Gold gift certificates turn to lead; CertifiChecks of Dayton, OH in Chapter 7 bankruptcy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-27-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificates-turn-to-lead-certifichecks-of-dayton-oh-in-chapter-7-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 21:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-27-ann-arbor-gold-gift-certificates-turn-to-lead-certifichecks-of-dayton-oh-in-chapter-7-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>First noted on Twitter:
&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;CertifiChecks, administer of the Ann Arbor Gold program, has gone out of business

which leads to this Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce news:
The Chamber was recently informed that CertifiChecks, the company that administered the Ann Arbor Gold program, has gone out of business. The statement below was available on their website. Calls to the CertifiChecks management team have not been returned.&amp;#0160;
CertifiChecks will no longer administer Ann Arbor Gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge Inspection Program Reduced Weight Postings for E. Stadium Boulevard over S. State Street File No. 2006-014.17</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-20-bridge-inspection-program-reduced-weight-postings-for-e-stadium-boulevard-over-s-state-street-file-n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-20-bridge-inspection-program-reduced-weight-postings-for-e-stadium-boulevard-over-s-state-street-file-n/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Alan Pagliere for unearthing this memo, entitled &amp;quot;The Bridge Is Falling&amp;quot;.&amp;#0160; Note the date.&amp;#0160; Alan says &amp;quot;read it, appreciate the dates and the content, and when you pick your jaw up off the floor, contact the City of Ann Arbor before driving confidently under or over that bridge.&amp;quot;
MEMORANDUM DATE:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; February 26, 2008
TO:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Homayoon Pirooz, P.E.
Manager, Project Management Unit
FROM:&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Michael G. Nearing, P.E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public meeting: Feb 13, 2009: Ann Arbor applying for League of American Bicyclists “Bicycle Friendly Community Award” in 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-14-public-meeting-feb-13-2009-ann-arbor-applying-for-league-of-american-bicyclists-bicycle-friendly-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 11:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-14-public-meeting-feb-13-2009-ann-arbor-applying-for-league-of-american-bicyclists-bicycle-friendly-com/</guid>
      <description>from a City of Ann Arbor press release, rescued from a PDF
CONTACT:&amp;#0160; Eli Cooper, Transportation Program Manager,&amp;#0160; (734) 794-6430 x 43710 e-mail ecooper@a2gov.org &amp;#0160;
FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE &amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;
BICYCLISTS FEEDBACK WANTED Bicycle Friendly Community Award Meeting on February 18 from 6-8 p.m.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;
ANN ARBOR, Mich., Feb. 13, 2009 — The City of Ann Arbor is reapplying for the League of American Bicyclists “Bicycle Friendly Community Award” in 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ann arbor skatepark fund!  w00t</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-ann-arbor-skatepark-fund-w00t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 13:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-ann-arbor-skatepark-fund-w00t/</guid>
      <description>Subject: ann arbor skatepark fund!
 PRESS RELEASE
 Ann Arbor Skatepark Action Committee Announces The Ann Arbor Skatepark Fund and The Ann Arbor Skatepark Endowment Fund
 Ann Arbor, January 19 – The Ann Arbor Skatepark Action Committee is starting its big-time fundraising with the formation of two funds at The Ann Arbor Area Community Foundation. One of the funds will support the design and construction of the skatepark, the other is an endowment to help the City pay for maintenance, improvements and upgrades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casa Dominick&#39;s: public meeting on proposed zoning changes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-08-casa-dominicks-public-meeting-on-proposed-zoning-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-08-casa-dominicks-public-meeting-on-proposed-zoning-changes/</guid>
      <description>From the city&amp;#39;s web site:
THE PROPOSED ZONING CHANGES.&amp;#0160; Casa Dominick’s, the restaurant at 812-814 Monroe Street, will be submitting a petition to the City of Ann Arbor Planning Commission and City Council to have six parcels of property rezoned as a planned unit development (“PUD”) to provide greater flexibility for the restaurant and to allow some additional uses in the area.&amp;#0160; The real estate parcels to be included in the proposed PUD are: &amp;#0160;812-814 Monroe, 808 Monroe, 700 Tappan, 706 Tappan, and 705 Oakland The proposed PUD will attempt to outline the possible uses for these properties over the next 50 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDA meeting, downtown, today; I have 4 minutes on the agenda; here&#39;s what I said</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-dda-meeting-downtown-today-i-have-4-minutes-on-the-agenda-heres-what-i-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 12:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-dda-meeting-downtown-today-i-have-4-minutes-on-the-agenda-heres-what-i-said/</guid>
      <description>Thanks all for your suggestions; I gave them my 4 minutes. Here&amp;#39;s what I said.
 1. &amp;#0160;Not going to talk about the Link Bus and how bad the signage is; I did my own pocket schedule and now I&amp;#39;m OK.&amp;#0160; This is not the right board to give that feedback to.
 2. &amp;#0160;Not going to talk about how the AATA Ridetrak is down and how it&amp;#39;s been down for a month; that&amp;#39;s a message to the AATA board, not this board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get a copy of the Google Transit data set for your bus system; part 1, AATA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-how-to-get-a-copy-of-the-google-transit-data-set-for-your-bus-system-part-1-aata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 16:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-how-to-get-a-copy-of-the-google-transit-data-set-for-your-bus-system-part-1-aata/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: ask.
From: &amp;quot;Edward Vielmetti&amp;quot; &amp;lt;edward.vielmetti@gmail.com&amp;gt;
To: aatainfo@theride.org
Date: Tue, 30 Dec 2008 16:20:46 -0500
Subject: data request: schedule data
Cc: editor@annarborchronicle.com
Please provide a copy of the AATA schedule data provided to Google for their Google Transit application in a digital format as described by
http://code.google.com/transit/spec/transit_feed_specification.html
A favor of a prompt reply is welcomed.
Step 2: wait.
Step 3. Wish you didn&amp;#39;t have to ask.
Some other systems that are proactive:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The First Amendment, Freedom of the Press and the Future of Journalism&#34; - Dec 3 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-the-first-amendment-freedom-of-the-press-and-the-future-of-journalism-dec-3-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 21:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-the-first-amendment-freedom-of-the-press-and-the-future-of-journalism-dec-3-2008/</guid>
      <description>via the SI weekly list:
National Press Club Forum:
&amp;quot;The First Amendment, Freedom of the Press and the Future of Journalism&amp;quot;
7:30 PM
Wednesday, December 3, 2008
1000 Beal Ave.  The National Press Club, the world&amp;#39;s leading professional organization for journalists, is teaming up with the Gerald R. Ford Presidential Library to look at where the news business is going and how to protect its core values. Panelists will be Jonathan Wolman, editor and publisher of the &amp;quot;Detroit News&amp;quot;; Omari Gardner, news editor/digital media at the &amp;quot;Detroit Free Press&amp;quot;; Marla Drutz, vice president and general manager, WDIV-TV, Detroit; and Vincent Duffy, news director, Michigan Public Radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2, 2008: Ann Arbor Active Against ALS Family Field Day</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-november-2-2008-ann-arbor-active-against-als-family-field-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 11:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-27-november-2-2008-ann-arbor-active-against-als-family-field-day/</guid>
      <description>Family Field Day, to benefit Ann Arbor Active Against ALS*,is THIS COMING SUNDAY,&amp;#0160;November 2nd, at Burns Park, from 1-4pm. Registration forms and a drop box are in the office, or you can email a2a3als@gmail.com, to let us know you&amp;#39;re coming.Early in the afternoon we will have relay races, a scavenger hunt and kickball game for adults and kids of all ages. From 3-4, some of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s best coaches are running clinics - field hockey, football, lacrosse and soccer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor real estate marketing seminar with Missy Caulk, Bob Stewart (Active Rain)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-ann-arbor-real-estate-marketing-seminar-with-missy-caulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 10:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-ann-arbor-real-estate-marketing-seminar-with-missy-caulk/</guid>
      <description>Missy Caulk is doing a seminar at Keller Williams about blogging in real estate in the Ann Arbor market.&amp;#0160; Some impressionistic notes.
&amp;quot;Google likes fresh content&amp;quot; - static content with 10 years worth of stuff that is mostly the same.
Examples of real estate content - information about schools, neighborhoods, real estate issues.
Blog to learn, blog to grow, blog to share, blog for relationships.
&amp;quot;MIssy, you need to do more hyperlocal&amp;quot; = become an expert on that subdivision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Cable Commission meetings online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-ann-arbor-cable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-11-ann-arbor-cable/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Kill your television.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp; Quoting Robert Efroymson&#39;s long since abandoned home page at U Minnesota:
My favorite reason for not watching TV is that it has a fixed, low bandwidth.&amp;nbsp; You can&#39;t watch tv fast or slow, you have to watch it at the rate the show goes, which could very well be much slower than you can accept the information (or much faster).&amp;nbsp; A book you can read at your own pace, a tv show sets the pace for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Fire Department Open House 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-ann-arbor-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-ann-arbor-fire/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor Fire Department Open House 2008
Sunday, October 5th - 1-3pm - Station #1- 111 N. 5th Ave
Fire Safety Presentations Smoke House Cogs the Fire Safety Robot Hazmat &amp;amp; Technical Rescue Team Face Painting Snacks &amp;amp; Goodie Bags I found out about this via the new City of Ann Arbor news notification service, which emails out updates from the city&#39;s web site.&amp;nbsp; That site in turn is run by GovDelivery, which says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Chronicle, some early reviews</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-ann-arbor-chron/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-ann-arbor-chron/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Chronicle has appeared on the scene.&amp;nbsp; Here are some early reviews.
The Vassar Miscelleny of 1872 writes:
 The Yale Literary Magazine opines:

The Yale Literary Magazine&amp;nbsp; By Yale University
Finally, the Hamilton Literary Magazine has its say in 1885:

Hamilton Literary Magazine&amp;nbsp; By Hamilton College (Clinton,&amp;nbsp; N.Y.)
Early reviews are priceless.&amp;nbsp; Best of luck to the new editorial team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmer&#39;s Market report for late August 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-23-farmers-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 17:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-23-farmers-market/</guid>
      <description>Every single thing you might possibly want to eat is ripe.&amp;nbsp; Enjoy.
(Stock up for February.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homeless Dave interview on MLive.com</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-homeless-dave-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 14:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-homeless-dave-i/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a very fun interview of Dave Askins online - his blog Teeter Talk is must reading.
WHOis: David Askins </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paper, plastic, or burlap?  on plastic bag bans</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-31-paper-plastic-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 09:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-31-paper-plastic-o/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been collecting information about bans on plastic bags, with an eye towards the Ann Arbor City Council&#39;s discussion of banning disposable plastic bags here in town.
Bob Lilienfeld from Use Less Stuff has a good and thorough paper vs. plastic lifecycle research analysis to understand some perspective on the levels of tradeoffs involved in the decision.
municipalities with bag ban laws, passed or not Cities with bag bans:
San Francisco, CA - Plastics News coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Startup Weekend, June 20-22 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-ann-arbor-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 09:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-ann-arbor-start/</guid>
      <description>Laura Fisher (and a cast of thousands) is organizing Ann Arbor Startup Weekend, June 20-22 2008 in downtown Ann Arbor.

There&#39;s a nice story in the Ann Arbor News about the event; I&#39;ll excerpt:

The intent of the event, which has been held in several cities throughout the country, is to start the weekend with no formal business plans and emerge a few days later with a couple of real companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scio Residents for Safe Water and the Pall/Gelman dioxane plume</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-scio-residents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 13:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-scio-residents/</guid>
      <description>Scio Residents for Safe Water will be at the Ann Arbor Green Fair on Friday, June 13, 2008. They have been tracking the dioxane contamination associated with the Pall/Gelman site - see map above, which links to the Washtenaw County government PDF.

Previous discussion on this on Vacuum from 2004, and it&#39;s not getting any better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor May 6 2008 election results and AutoMARK voting issues</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-ann-arbor-may-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 21:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-ann-arbor-may-6/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ll link to election results when they go online here. The Washtenaw County site has the official results. The Ann Arbor News has coverage on the blog, but, true to form, they don&#39;t link to the official results site in their coverage.
Early returns (63% counted at 9:30pm) have both Ann Arbor millage proposals passing 3-1, and incumbent school board member Helen Gates-Bryant leading 2-1. Voter turnout looks like it&#39;s going to be less than 10% county wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Run 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-04-burns-park-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 12:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-04-burns-park-run/</guid>
      <description>I walked the 5k - official time 39:47 (a 12:49 pace). Lots of fun! More details and link to race results when it&#39;s online.
UPDATE: Burns Park Run 2008 results are up! Searchable complete results (789 finishers), 10K run, 5K run, 5K walk.
The official race site for the Burns Park Run is where the race results will be.
Some race photos from Mae&#39;s Real Stories and The Corkys.
This movie has the course sped up to 5 minutes - it&#39;s a terrific route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Code: littering</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-09-ann-arbor-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 22:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-09-ann-arbor-city/</guid>
      <description>in our series on relevant parts of the city code, here&amp;rsquo;s the piece that lets you quote chapter and verse when some part of your walk to town goes past a building littered with soggy 3+ day old newspapers.  Chapter 82 LITTERING AND DISTRIBUTION OF HANDBILLS  7:103. Owner to maintain premises free of litter, handbills and newspapers. The owner or person in control of private property shall at all times maintain the premises free of litter, handbills or more than three days accumulation of newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA2M - Lunch Ann Arbor Marketing - Wednesday at Eastern Flame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-la2m---lunch-an/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 00:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-17-la2m---lunch-an/</guid>
      <description>Derek Mehraban organized the first weekly Wednesday downtown Ann Arbor lunch for people in the marketing world at Eastern Flame on Ashley next to the Fleetwood Diner. He&amp;rsquo;s calling it LA2M.  You can see what a QSL card for LA2M looks like from the 1920s. Derek, if you want to print a sticker, you have a design ready-made.
 There were 12 for lunch for the first event, and the restaurant obliged with a soup and sandwich for $5 special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galbi tang at Maru - new Korean restaurant where Seoul Korner used to be</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-07-galbi-tang-at-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 23:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-07-galbi-tang-at-m/</guid>
      <description>Bob, Kim, Margaret and I went out for lunch at Maru today. Bob and Margaret had the bi bim bop, and Kim had a bento with spicy chicken (and a side of macaroni). I had the galbi tang, a big bowl of steaming delicious beef short rib soup for $9.  We talked about a bunch of things, and it was pleasant.  Maru is about $1 or $2 per dish more than Seoul Korner was, and for that extra you get table service, somewhat bigger portions, more banchan (we had 4 for 4 people), and a broader menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Marketing Trends 2007</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-07-internet-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-07-internet-market/</guid>
      <description>Slides from the Marketing Roundtable presentation - this has had 2000+ views on Slideshare already!
 | View | Upload your own Technorati Tags: marketing, trends, roundtable</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>