<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/yarn/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/yarn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>yarns made in Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-03-yarns-made-in-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 00:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-03-yarns-made-in-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
An unnamed reader of this blog searched for the phrase &#34;yarns made in Michigan&#34; and found some page here that wasn&#39;t the best answer for that query; let&#39;s fix that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Spun and dyed in Michigan:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stonehedgefibermill.com/yarn.html&#34;&gt;Stonehedge Farm and Fiber Mill&lt;/a&gt; in East Jordan, MI makes and sells the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stonehedgefibermill.com/yarn.html#shepherd&#34;&gt;Shepherd&#39;s Wool&lt;/a&gt; line of yarns, 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
The three-ply yarn is spun to 1000 yards per pound, which in 4-ounce skeins is 250 yards per skein. It knits like any commercial worsted weight yarn, about 5 stitches to the inch on size 6-8 needles. This yarn is worsted spun, meaning it&#39;s very very smooth and almost shiny in appearance. It will give great stitch definition for intricate patterns such as lace, cables, and knit/purl patterns.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://happyfuzzyyarn.com/&#34;&gt;Happy Fuzzy Yarn&lt;/a&gt; - Riin Gill, Ann Arbor. Rovings, too.  And she rides the bus too!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you&#39;re a knitter, the bus totally rocks!  Someone to drive you everywhere you go and give you the gift of time to knit?  Golden.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dyed in Michigan
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.briarrosefibers.net/&#34;&gt;Briar Rose Fibers &lt;/a&gt;- hand painted yarns
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://colorjoy.com/shop/&#34;&gt;Color Joy&lt;/a&gt; “Lynn from Lansing” - yarns, patterns, especially sock yarns and patterns
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Joan Sheridan Hoover of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heritagespinning.com/main.htm&#34;&gt;Heritage Spinning and Weaving&lt;/a&gt; in Lake Orion also dyes some beautiful yarn, including luxury fibers like silk.  Here’s her website but I cannot find a link to her hand-dyed yarns. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://spinnersflock.org/&#34;&gt;Spinner&#39;s Flock&lt;/a&gt; is a group for hand-spinning enthusiasts, and the people who raise the sheep (and goats and rabbits) that provide the fibers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://freddyknits.blogspot.com/2005/03/beginners-fair-isle-baby-hat-free.html&#34;&gt;freddyknits&lt;/a&gt; for the details - esp. the East Jordan store (hm that&#39;s on our way up north...) 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>