<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strawberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/strawberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strawberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/strawberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2009 strawberry season delayed by cold weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s some reports from around the state of the strawberry crop.&amp;#0160; (We&amp;#39;re planning a trip to Rowe&amp;#39;s in Rawsonville for Father&amp;#39;s Day).
From the Detroit Free Press via FreshPlaza:
At DeGroot&amp;#39;s Strawberries in Gregory, 16 acres of lush plants are close to ripening.
&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s not too hot and could be a little warmer,&amp;quot; says Marsha DeGroot, who with her family has owned the Livingston County farm since 1978. &amp;quot;But the lovely winter with lots of snow made for a nice insulating blanket for the plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan u-pick strawberry season opens June 3, 2009 in Rawsonville, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 22:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</guid>
      <description>We haven&amp;#39;t scheduled our visit yet to Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm in Rawsonville, MI, but as a public service you should know that they are open.&amp;#0160; From the mailing they sent out:
STRAWBERRY SEASON TO BEGIN SOON !!!!!! 
The first day of the 2009 strawberry season will be Wednesday June 3rd. As usual, when we first open not all of our varieties of berries are&amp;#0160; ready to pick. If you are looking to pick massive amounts to freeze or make jam it would be better to wait until they are more plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Strawberry season field report, SE Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-16-2008-strawberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 09:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-16-2008-strawberry/</guid>
      <description>I went strawberry picking with the boys on Father&#39;s Day at Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm in Rawsonville, about a mile s. of the Rawsonville Road exit between Ypsilanti and Belleville. It was a hot day with a bright sun, the berries were ripe but not overripe, and we picked an 8 qt tray in no time at all.
Afterwards I washed and picked over the berries (a 3 y/o, no matter how enthusiastic, is not a perfect judge of ripeness or berry quality).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberries are in for the 2008 season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-05-strawberries-ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-05-strawberries-ar/</guid>
      <description>via arborparents, a report that strawberries are in at Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm - head there from the Rawsonville Road exit, south to Martz Rd between Ypsi and Belleville. Price of strawberries is $1.43/lb.
www.rowesproducefarm.com
UPDATE: Peas too!
Hello Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm customers,
SUGAR SNAP PEAS ARE NOW READY TO BE PICKED!!!!!
We opened our first field of sugar snap peas for picking today and they are LOADED. Now is the time to pick!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>