<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strawberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/strawberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strawberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/strawberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Strawberry season field report, SE Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-16-2008-strawberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 09:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-16-2008-strawberry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went strawberry picking with the boys on Father&#39;s Day at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Rowes&#34;&gt;Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Rawsonville&#34;&gt;Rawsonville&lt;/a&gt;, about a mile s. of the Rawsonville Road exit between &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Ypsilanti&#34;&gt;Ypsilanti&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Belleville&lt;/a&gt;Belleville&lt;/a&gt;.  It was a hot day with a bright sun, the berries were ripe but not overripe, and we picked an 8 qt tray in no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I washed and picked over the berries (a 3 y/o, no matter how enthusiastic, is not a perfect judge of ripeness or berry quality).  We froze 3 qts whole on a cookie sheet, and the rest were used for strawberry shortcake w/fresh whipping cream delivered from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Calder_Dairy&#34;&gt;Calder Dairy&lt;/a&gt;.  Mmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes to self for next year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring more water!  Picking in the hot sun is hot, and you get dried out fast.  I should have had a gallon with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have sunglasses and a good hat!  I felt pretty sun-bleached afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go out as early as you can, so it&#39;s not so hot and the sun is not so bright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a field trip to the &lt;A href=&#34;http://www.geocities.com/histmich/otisvillecem.html&#34;&gt;Otisville Cemetery&lt;/a&gt; south of Belleville, where I have some ancestors buried - there&#39;s a story to that settlement that I haven&#39;t figured out yet, it&#39;s a pleasant but nondescript spot in a rural area with graves from the 1840s-1900s.  Some bits of family history are in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocities.com/histmich/belleville.html&#34;&gt;Carpenter-Hope&lt;/a&gt; section of a Belleville city history.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
CARPENTER-HOPE &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;John and Lucy Carpenter&lt;/b&gt;, one of Van Buren&#39;s pioneering family raised a family of four girls one their farm land on Martinsville Road. Their daughter, Angeline M. married to Richard Hope and moved into a home located at 187 Main Street in Belleville. Daughter, Matilda, married Jenx Pullen and moved into a home located on Martinsville Road. &lt;b&gt;Mary Jane&lt;/b&gt; married &lt;b&gt;Woodbury Clark&lt;/b&gt;, and lived in one of the Clark residences. Lucy married George Quirk. A descendant of the Hope family , named Margaret later wrote that the property located at 187 Main Street, was the site of the 1886 Soldiers and Sailors Encampment. &lt;br /&gt;
Margaret Hope was born April 9, 1876, the daughter of Richard and Angeline (Carpenter) Hope. Her father, Richard was born in Detroit in 1844 and came to Belleville with his parents, John and Joanne (Winkleman) Hope, sometime in the 1850&#39;s. John Hope served as Treasurer in 1859 and Justice of the Peace in 1868. By 1875 he had changed his occupation from blacksmith to cobbling boots and shoes. &lt;br /&gt;
Richard Hope built his home at 187 Main Street about 1880. He and his wife, Angeline had previously resided in a backhouse behind the home of William Warren. Richard worked as a drover, a livestock buyer, and was the proprietor of a meat market. He later owned a second farm on Sumpter Road and served as Belleville&#39;s Drain Commissioner in 1894/95. &lt;br /&gt;
Richard Hope died on November 19, 1901 at that age of 57, killed at the Wabash RailRoad crossing on Sumpter Road, as he traveled to his farm. He and his wife had, had 2 children, Louis, who later moved to Texas and married, where he had a son named, Stewart. When Louis passed away, his son, Stewart came back to Belleville and was raised by Margaret Hope. &lt;br /&gt;
Margaret, moved with her parents to their home at 374 Main Street when she was 4 years old. She worked in many local community occupations such as teacher and secretary for Henry Van Schoick Harness, Carriage, and Hardware business. She also worked at the Peoples Bank of Belleville. She also had a lifelong committment to the Belleville Grange, a local farmers group, where she worked as its secretary from 1906 to 1955. Margaret passed away in September of 1955.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2009 strawberry season delayed by cold weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s some reports from around the state of the strawberry crop.&amp;#0160; (We&amp;#39;re planning a trip to Rowe&amp;#39;s in Rawsonville for Father&amp;#39;s Day).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshplaza.com/news_detail.asp?id=45468&#34;&gt;From the Detroit Free Press via FreshPlaza:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;At DeGroot&amp;#39;s Strawberries in Gregory, 16 acres of lush plants are close to ripening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s
not too hot and could be a little warmer,&amp;quot; says Marsha DeGroot, who
with her family has owned the Livingston County farm since 1978. &amp;quot;But
the lovely winter with lots of snow made for a nice insulating blanket
for the plants.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pick-your-own strawberries will be $1.20 a
pound at DeGroot&amp;#39;s this year. Whittaker&amp;#39;s strawberries sell for $1.25 a
pound. And at Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm in Ypsilanti, the cost is $1.46 per
pound, up 3 cents from last year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshplaza.com/news_detail.asp?id=45470&#34;&gt;From mlive.com again via FreshPlaza&lt;/a&gt; on the season in mid-Michigan:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Geri R. Hingston and her husband, James H. Hingston, own Hingstons
Country, 18670 Dice in Merrill, a 4-acre you-pick farm with
strawberries and other produce.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Customers usually begin
harvesting the fruit about June 14, but she said she probably will
delay by five or more days because of cooler weather, frost warnings
and bees not coming out to pollinate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/528487.html&#34;&gt;A June 8 story in the Marquette Mining Journal (via the Escanaba Press) about UP strawberries:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;There were also a few days where overnight lows dropped close to
the freezing mark at the Delta County Airport, however, it is possible
inland areas did drop to or below freezing,&amp;quot; said Fleegel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;A call by the Daily Press to Victor Ledvina, owner of Ledvina&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm in Flat Rock was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;There was also no indication of when picking would begin at Ledvina&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Dave
Pellegrini, operator of Pellegrini&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm said they had been
irrigating five out of the past eight nights to prevent the fragile
blossoms from frosting over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;The full moon in June is called the strawberry moon; it was on June 7.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan u-pick strawberry season opens June 3, 2009 in Rawsonville, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 22:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We haven&amp;#39;t scheduled our visit yet to &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowesproducefarm.com/&#34;&gt;Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm in Rawsonville, MI&lt;/a&gt;, but as a public service you should know that they are open.&amp;#0160; From the mailing they sent out:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;il&#34;&gt;STRAWBERRY&lt;/span&gt; SEASON TO BEGIN SOON !!!!!!
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first day of the 2009 &lt;span class=&#34;il&#34;&gt;strawberry&lt;/span&gt; season will be Wednesday June 3rd.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As usual, when we first open not all of our varieties of berries are&amp;#0160;
ready to pick. If you are looking to pick massive amounts to freeze or
make jam it would be better to wait until they are more plentiful. With
the cool temperatures predicted the berries may not ripen that quickly.
It is advisable to call the farm before you come out to make sure we
are not closed to let them ripen up.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The price of the berries is $1.46 per pound and we furnish the
containers for free.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We are open 7 am to 8 pm daily (weather permitting).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did I find out about this, you ask?&amp;#0160; &amp;quot;The List&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;UpickText blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We at Rowes have been compiling lists of customer
addresses over the years and been sending postcards to our customers
when the strawberry and raspberry seasons are at their peak. Our
strawberry list has over 12,000 addresses and the raspberry list has
over 4,500. Due to rising costs of printing and postage we are no
longer taking addresses for our lists. Instead we have started an email
list. You can sign up for &amp;quot;The List&amp;quot; by sending us an email via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowesproducefarm.com/contact.html&#34;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/a&gt;
page. Once you send us an email the email address you send from will be
added to our new list. This way instead of getting one notice we are
able to send updated information on picking conditions more often,
better serving our customers. If you are on the &amp;quot;old&amp;quot; postcard list it
would be appreciated if you would sign up for the email list and tell
us your street address so we can remove it from the old list. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12000 strawberry pickers!&amp;#0160; wow.&amp;#0160; you should get on The List if you want more updates.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t see any current info on their web site (other than &amp;quot;get on The List&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberries are in for the 2008 season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-05-strawberries-ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-05-strawberries-ar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;via arborparents, a report that strawberries are in at Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm - head there from the Rawsonville Road exit, south to Martz Rd between Ypsi and Belleville.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price of strawberries is $1.43/lb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rowesproducefarm.com&#34;&gt;www.rowesproducefarm.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Peas too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Rowe&#39;s Produce Farm customers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SUGAR SNAP PEAS ARE NOW READY TO BE PICKED!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We opened our first field of sugar snap peas for picking today and they are LOADED. Now is the time to pick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price of the peas is the same as last season, $16.00 per bushel, $9.00 per half bushel, $5.00 per peck basket or if you just want a few they are $1.25 per pound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strawberries picking is fantastic now also so don&#39;t wait too long to get in on this years fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are hoping the English peas and Chinese pea pods will be ready this weekend. We will keep you informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you and have a very berry day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowe&#39;s&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>