<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greg Peters on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/greg-peters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greg Peters on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/greg-peters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/blogofneworleans/archives/2013/08/02/suspect-device-cartoonist-greg-peters-dies&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;obituary for Greg Peters&lt;/a&gt; is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-600wi&#34; alt=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obit as published in NOLA.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cartoonist and writer Greg Peters died Friday morning, Aug. 2, after emergency surgery at Ochsner Medical Center. Mr. Peters, who had suffered from a congenital heart condition throughout his life, was 50 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in Marquette, Mich., Peters arrived in Louisiana in 1990 to pursue a doctorate in English literature at the University of Louisiana at Lafayette. He became best known as the creator of “Suspect Device,” a starkly crafted, blackly funny Louisiana-themed political comic strip that made its debut in 1996, in the Times of Acadiana, and ran in New Orleans’&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/&#34;&gt;Gambit Weekly&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from 1999 to 2010. “Suspect Device” famously pulled no punches: In 1998, editor Harris Meyer resigned from the Times of Acadiana, when the paper’s publisher refused to run one of Mr. Peters’ strips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suspect Device” was recognized with awards from the Press Club of New Orleans and the Association of Alternative Newsweeklies, and in 2004 was anthologized in “&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=r18Or31mODcC&amp;amp;pg=PT95&amp;amp;dq=greg+peters+attitude+2&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=ih78UY3HG8iWqQHx7YFw&amp;amp;ved=0CC8Q6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=greg%20peters%20attitude%202&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Attitude 2: The New Subversive Alternative Cartoonists&lt;/a&gt;.” Mr. Peters’ work was displayed in exhibitions in conjunction with the book at New York City’s Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters was “one of the few alternative weekly political cartoonists whose mission is to skewer local and state politicians,&#34; anthology editor Ted Rall told Gambit’s Scott Jordan in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/gambit/unusual-suspect/Content?oid=1243221&#34;&gt;a 2004 profile of Mr. Peters&lt;/a&gt;. &#34;One would think that there would be such a cartoonist, or several, in every major city, but there just aren&#39;t,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Coupled with an over-the-top clip-art style and incredibly distinct cartooning personality, Greg&#39;s strip is everything that his readers and editors can hope for.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peters’ distinctive style involved the use of stock clip art images, arranged and annotated with wry, extensive text to skewer public figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The clip art thing was always a punk staple,&#34; Mr. Peters told Jordan. &#34;Like the cut-out letters and clip art that Jamie Reid, the Sex Pistols designer, did using Queen Elizabeth with the safety clip through her cheek picture. They&#39;re very much out of the DIY ethos. And the attitude simply of baseline mistrust for authority, and the demand that you be shown, not told.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters is survived by his parents, Reg and Kay Peters of Lafayette; his partner, Eileen Loh; his former wife, Saundra Scarce; and his two sons, Wilder, 12, and Magnus, 10. Plans for a memorial service in the New Orleans area are pending.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leveesnotwar.org/in-memoriam-greg-peters-suspect-device-artist-and-blogger-father-friend/&#34;&gt;Levees Not War&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>