<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: notes | Edward Vielmetti on Github]]></title>
  <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-12T00:02:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://vielmetti.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Edward Vielmetti]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That new blog smell]]></title>
    <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/that-new-blog-smell/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T23:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/that-new-blog-smell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With any new system there&rsquo;s a tendency to give a lot of things a try.
Here&rsquo;s some more observations from the new part of things.</p>

<p>Comments are now enabled here through <a href="http://disqus.com">Disqus</a>. I don&rsquo;t expect that
there will be a lot of comments, but at least there is an easy way
to integrate them. The default configuration included a lot of &ldquo;promoted
posts&rdquo; at the bottom of the screen; I guess that if you click on those,
there&rsquo;s some small chance that I might get some small amount of money.
They are also somewhat distracting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/notes-on-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T22:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/notes-on-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some notes while I am still new to the system.</p>

<ol>
<li>It doesn&rsquo;t have comments; presumably there&rsquo;s some way to wire up
an external comment system of some type to handle that, like Disqus.</li>
<li>I really wanted to start doing this by having a flexible sidebar.
There is a sidebar with some default information in it (github repos,
recent pinboard bookmarks) but not a flexible editable sidebar. I suppose
that&rsquo;s why there&rsquo;s source code.</li>
<li>I miss &ldquo;edit this page&rdquo; as a button; that&rsquo;s the downside of not having
a web-based content management system.</li>
<li>Out of the box it looks nicer than Jekyll&rsquo;s default config, and I
heartily approve of that. I am sure there are other styles I can try too.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m going to have to step up my reading skills if I&rsquo;m going to understand
everything behind this system, especially my Ruby reading skills.</li>
<li>The default config&rsquo;s mobile design is pretty good on my phone, better
than the best I&rsquo;ve been able to do so far with Typepad.</li>
<li>I like it that github is doing the hosting because there&rsquo;s not much to
worry about that &ndash; I don&rsquo;t have to do any more in the way of babysitting
a machine just to have a blog.</li>
</ol>


<p>So far so good, nothing too weird, everything pretty straightforward.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Octopress on MacOS X 10.6.8]]></title>
    <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/installing-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T17:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/installing-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Started to install <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> on my Mac, but got into a problem
where one of the dependencies wanted a later version of ruby
(or at least a later patchlevel) than the one I had just built.
That&rsquo;s enough to stop me for now.</p>

<p>But not for very long!</p>

<p>This <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10553887/having-trouble-installing-any-ruby-1-9-x-with-rbenv-on-mac-osx-due-to-psych-ya">Stack Overflow</a> post gives the syntax for installing a particular
patchlevel of ruby, and so I did it.</p>

<p>Then it came to creating a repo on github, and I got confused; should
the URL be vielmetti.github.com or vielmetti.github.io ? Because one part
of the doc used one name and the in-line code example used another. I
had a skew between the two, and now it looks like things are hopelessly
confused (or at least confused enough that I should delete a repo and
start over).</p>

<p>Finally, I found this <a href="http://www.nicecabbage.com/blog/2012/03/04/blogging-for-rubyists/">Nice Cabbage</a> post which strips the install
down to its very barest minimum; that brought me past a hurdle with
the above mentioned github repo.</p>

<p>One last issue: the system was complaining with an OS X credentials error,
&ldquo;error: git-credential-osxkeychain died of signal 11&rdquo;. To fix that, I went
to a <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/set-up-git">page where I could get the latest version</a> and updated my copy.</p>

<p>Since you&rsquo;re reading this, it must work! Yay!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[11 August 2013 notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/notes/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T15:06:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vielmetti.github.io/blog/2013/08/11/notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Installed Jekyll on my Mac, just so that I have something I can
start from. A next step will be to push to Github Pages, but I&rsquo;m
not ready for that just as of yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
