<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Coffee Travel on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-coffee-travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Coffee Travel on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 20:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-coffee-travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I wish I had written, September 2010 edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/2010-09-30-things-i-wish-i-had-written/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/2010-09-30-things-i-wish-i-had-written/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A travel guide from here to South Bend via US-12, with roadside geology and history; ditto, the road south on US-23 and its cross-section through the surface of the earth towards Bowling Green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A look out the window of the Oxford Shuttle, a bus that goes around the University of Michigan central campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reprise of the &amp;quot;top 10 internet cafes&amp;quot; post from 2006, updated with a lot of 2010 details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 bed and breakfasts in the area, plus a long list more, all based on first hand research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to watch the Michigan-Notre Dame Game anywhere in the country, with notes on which of the places serve Michigan beers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which little place between here and Amherst, Mass. serves a mean Michigan dog, and what exactly do they mean by Michigan dogs there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to ship a shipping container on the Great Lakes, and how to float one downstream from Ann Arbor to the sea or up the lakes to the UP. &amp;#0160;Portaging might be hard, especially with low water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a chance to write all these again, but sometimes the idea is overtaken by events, and then you have to have a new idea.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>