<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tomato on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/tomato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tomato on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/tomato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew: six recipes to mix and match from</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</guid>
      <description>Haven&#39;t cooked any of these yet, but there&#39;s some recipes to work through:
Ricki Heller: Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew. Uses tahini to enrich the sauce.
Fit Pregnancy: Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew with Chard . With chard, paprika, parsley.
The First Mess: moroccan-style vegetable + chickpea stew . Sweet potatoes instead of potatoes, and a cinnamon+coriander+cumin spice.
The Picky Eater: Indian Chickpea and Potato Stew. Curry is the flavor here, and cilantro replaces parsley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrambled eggs with slow roasted tomatoes (炒鸡蛋西红柿)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-scrambled-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-scrambled-eggs/</guid>
      <description>I did the slow roasting during high tomato season, and there are a few quarts of them in the freezer.
Wondering which recipes would show up for a search for &amp;quot;recipe egg tomato&amp;quot; on Twitter, I ended up much to my surprise on a Beijing travel web site, which had a recipe for Fried Egg and Tomato – Chǎo Jīdàn Xīhóngshì – 炒鸡蛋西红柿.
Egg and tomato might sound like an odd combination, but this is a really common Chinese dish which can be found on the menu at every cheap and cheerful Chinese eatery in Beijing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>