<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marquette-michigan/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/marquette-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A localwiki for the Marquette, Michigan area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-03-a-localwiki-for-the-marquette-michigan-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 13:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-03-a-localwiki-for-the-marquette-michigan-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no better way to learn about your home town than by trying to start a wiki for it. In that regard, I&#39;m happy to announce a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/&#34;&gt;Localwiki installation for Marquette County, Michigan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.org&#34;&gt;Localwiki&lt;/a&gt; crew has developed a new hosting platform for people who want to start a wiki for their area, but who don&#39;t have the resources or the time or the skills to launch their own server. It runs on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net&#34;&gt;Localwiki.net&lt;/a&gt;, and currently has about two dozen sites up and running. Your town or region could be next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I originally envisioned doing a wiki for Marquette, I was thinking ambitiously and thought &#34;hey, I&#39;ll do the whole U.P.&#34; I&#39;m glad I didn&#39;t, not at least yet. There&#39;s enough small amounts of nitty-gritty detail about local history, ghost towns, old mines, and bits of industrial archaeology that I have just enough knowledge to tackle for the Marquette area, but don&#39;t have any clue where I&#39;d start for Houghton or Escanaba or the Soo. Someone else can tackle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marquette County is the biggest county (by area) in Michigan, so there&#39;s plenty of geography to cover. It&#39;s also home to some political subdivisions like &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Humboldt_Township&#34;&gt;Humboldt Township&lt;/a&gt; that have less than 500 inhabitants, no post office of their own, and no chance ever that anyone there would start a wiki just for that place alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, which covers Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County, I see this as the very first step towards a project that could last a long time. At a few pages a day for a few years you could start to get to the point where you had enough material to be useful for a visitor, a local, or a historian, and where people who would never be notable enough for a first draft biography on Wikipedia might get properly noted or memorialized. I&#39;m looking forward to learning more so that the next time I visit I&#39;ll be that much better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>