<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/upper-peninsula/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/upper-peninsula/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A localwiki for the Marquette, Michigan area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-03-a-localwiki-for-the-marquette-michigan-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 13:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-03-a-localwiki-for-the-marquette-michigan-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no better way to learn about your home town than by trying to start a wiki for it. In that regard, I&#39;m happy to announce a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/&#34;&gt;Localwiki installation for Marquette County, Michigan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.org&#34;&gt;Localwiki&lt;/a&gt; crew has developed a new hosting platform for people who want to start a wiki for their area, but who don&#39;t have the resources or the time or the skills to launch their own server. It runs on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net&#34;&gt;Localwiki.net&lt;/a&gt;, and currently has about two dozen sites up and running. Your town or region could be next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I originally envisioned doing a wiki for Marquette, I was thinking ambitiously and thought &#34;hey, I&#39;ll do the whole U.P.&#34; I&#39;m glad I didn&#39;t, not at least yet. There&#39;s enough small amounts of nitty-gritty detail about local history, ghost towns, old mines, and bits of industrial archaeology that I have just enough knowledge to tackle for the Marquette area, but don&#39;t have any clue where I&#39;d start for Houghton or Escanaba or the Soo. Someone else can tackle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marquette County is the biggest county (by area) in Michigan, so there&#39;s plenty of geography to cover. It&#39;s also home to some political subdivisions like &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.net/marquettemi/Humboldt_Township&#34;&gt;Humboldt Township&lt;/a&gt; that have less than 500 inhabitants, no post office of their own, and no chance ever that anyone there would start a wiki just for that place alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, which covers Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County, I see this as the very first step towards a project that could last a long time. At a few pages a day for a few years you could start to get to the point where you had enough material to be useful for a visitor, a local, or a historian, and where people who would never be notable enough for a first draft biography on Wikipedia might get properly noted or memorialized. I&#39;m looking forward to learning more so that the next time I visit I&#39;ll be that much better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marquette Mining Journal removes reader comments from newspaper web site</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 20:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-23-marquette-minin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/506528.html?nav=5003&#34;&gt;The Marquette Mining Journal recently ran this editorial regarding taking interactive comments off of the internet version of their newspaper, reading in part:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
The comments were posted, without prior screening, in order to make it as easy as possible for Journal readers to submit their input directly. Unfortunately, a handful of participants abused the system. While most comments were astute and relevant, some relentless individuals decided to turn the comments section into a chat room that ventured, frankly, into the realm of inappropriate, sophomoric  idiocy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The roots of The Mining Journal’s editorial ethical standards go back some 163 years. In order for a letter to the editor to be considered for publication in our print edition, a name and other verifiable information must be included. Not so, however, with the Internet comments. Subsequently, on our Web site a small but persistent group of people threatened to tarnish The Mining Journal’s reputation for responsible journalism. A few Web comment submissions even consisted of cowardly anonymous personal attacks on local citizens. That could not be allowed to continue.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The New Orleans online newspaper, nola.com, also has unmoderated comments.  Alan Gutierrez notes what this does to the discussion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thinknola.com/post/coldcock/&#34;&gt;quoting Mayor Ray Nagin:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Your news cast and the local newspapers are feeding these awful, ugly talk shows, that are feeding these blogs. You go look at these some of these blogs out there and some of the stories that come from the paper and you read the comments, it’s the most vile angry people that I’ve ever seen in this community.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Alan notes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is a common misconception in New Orleans, that the bloggers are the rabble. The city newspaper’s website, NOLA.com, is entirely unmoderated. NOLA.com calls these free-for-alls blogs.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Newspapers always run letters to the editor after verifying the identity of the writer.  Should online newspapers be any different?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>