<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Needs Photo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/needs-photo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Needs Photo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/needs-photo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy: Greystone Jazz rescue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</guid>
      <description>The Detroit Sound Conservancy went to the vacant Book Building in Detroit on July 7, 2015 to salvage the collection of the defunct Graystone International Jazz Museum. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice writeup in MLive, Graystone jazz artifacts, forgotten in Detroit skyscraper, now being preserved. Photographer Doug Coombe went along to document the effort with a photo set on Facebook.
 &amp;ldquo;We knew that things were bad,&amp;rdquo; said DSC&amp;rsquo;s Founder and President Carleton Gholz about the neglected collection, but Gholz didn&amp;rsquo;t know how bad until he discovered many of the former museum&amp;rsquo;s records were broken and strewn across the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Lucky&#39;s Farmers Market replace the South Industrial Kroger?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-06-will-luckys-farmers-market-replace-the-south-industrial-kroger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 16:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-06-will-luckys-farmers-market-replace-the-south-industrial-kroger/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: MLive says yes and has an interview with the CEO.
It&#39;s a distinct possibility, if this corporate registration from the Michigan LARA is any guide.
 Searched for: LUCKY&#39;S FARMERS MARKET OF ANN ARBOR, LLC ID Num: D9250J Assumed Names Name:LUCKY&#39;S FARMERS MARKET OF ANN ARBOR, LLC Type: Foreign Limited Liability Company Resident Agent: PARACORP INCORPORATED Registered Office Address: 42180 FORD ROAD STE 101 CANTON MI 48187 Mailing/Office Address:  Formation/Qualification Date:7-15-2013 Jurisdiction of Origin:COLORADO Managed by: Status: ACTIVE Date: Present   More from the Ann Arbor News which is following the story of the store closing, and the Boulder Daily Camera which has news of Lucky&#39;s expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>