<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of BBQ at Ricewood.
 One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and manual file transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink. Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong iced latte, just add a little half and half.
The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence of mind seven years ago to write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick for image manipulation and that helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-07-13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-13-links-for-2009-07-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 04:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-13-links-for-2009-07-13/</guid>
      <description>Comments Dead, Twitter Holds Smoking Gun At the recent Real-Time CrunchUp 2009, Khris Loux, CEO of one of the web&amp;#039;s largest commenting services, announced the &amp;quot;death of the comment&amp;quot;. This declaration was extremely significant as Loux&amp;#039;s JS-Kit is currently installed on over 600,000 sites. He blames the death on social media sites like Twitter and Flickr and the rise of &amp;quot;parallel channels away from [the] product&amp;quot;. In essence, dialogue has moved from a singular destination to a series of parallel but separate social networking channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-07-09</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-links-for-2009-07-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 04:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-links-for-2009-07-09/</guid>
      <description>Blogs-on-Paper Idea Runs Out of Steam - Bits Blog - NYTimes.com Not hilarious. It makes sense. Over 90% of Politico’s revenue comes from its print edition, even though it’s only distributed in D.C. The truth is, as the CFOs of both the NYTimes and WSJ will tell you, print advertising, on a CPM basis, generates 75x more revenue than Web ads. — Patricia (tags: blog newspaper print politico revenue-model)  John Palfrey » Citizen Editors In the past several weeks, I’ve been playing with a new format that my friends at TopTenSources developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-07-04</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-04-links-for-2009-07-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 04:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-04-links-for-2009-07-04/</guid>
      <description>Lunchtime Prowl: Grandy or Charlie, Fu-Te Ni&amp;#039;s Pitches, Big Al&amp;#039;s Back, and Shaving Cream Pies Here’s one of his latest posts at The Wayne Fontes Experience, about Dave Birkett leaving the Oakland Press’s Detroit Lions beat for a gig covering the Michigan Wolverines at the new AnnArbor.com. It&amp;#039;s a big loss for Lions coverage, and it&amp;#039;s troubling to see good reporters (Danny Knobler, Jon Paul Morosi) move on. Detroit sports fans are losing out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-29</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-29-links-for-2009-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 04:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-29-links-for-2009-06-29/</guid>
      <description>20 Visualizations to Understand Crime | FlowingData While a lot of this crime data is kept confidential to respect people&amp;#039;s privacy, there&amp;#039;s still plenty of publicly available records. Here we take a look at twenty visualization examples that explore this data. (tags: crime datamining visualization journalism infographics)  Pittsburgh Needs Eated.: Rhubarb Upside-Down Cake I tried the &amp;quot;Rhubarb upside-down cake&amp;quot; on a whim, and was pleasantly surprised when the cake turned out perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-27</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-links-for-2009-06-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 04:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-links-for-2009-06-27/</guid>
      <description>Mediactive » What Pays for Newspaper Journalism? Not the “Cover Price” Cowell doesn’t mention that the advertising is the most important part of the financial equation in paying for journalism, not the cover price. It has been so for as long as he’s been a journalist. The word “Advertise” appears three times on this Web page (and “Advertisements” once), but not in Cowell’s column. (tags: newspaper journalism advertising money-its-a-gas)  Ombudsman Blog - Froomkin Departs, Leaving Angry Loyalists And Questions Froomkin acknowledges the drop but told me much of it can be blamed on a change in format and poor promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-26</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-26-links-for-2009-06-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 04:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-26-links-for-2009-06-26/</guid>
      <description>Reinventing classifieds: MinnPost launches “real-time advertising” » Nieman Journalism Lab In a phone conversation this morning, Kramer described the project as “an effort to move beyond banner ads,” which have proven lucrative for the site, but also limited. MinnPost charges, on average, $15 per thousand impressions for its display advertising, but because the ads are for local businesses, they’re only served to readers in Minnesota. (That’s one reason the CPM is so good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-25</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-25-links-for-2009-06-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 04:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-25-links-for-2009-06-25/</guid>
      <description>echovar » Blog Archive » Real-Time Writing: A Transvaluation of All Values As a story plays out across the Network, as new information is uncovered, the inputs are routed through the mixing board of the writer’s keyboard. A writer must now listen to how the whole jam is sounding— the writer is a player down in the groove with other players. As we learn to write through a real-time medium, we’ll need to look to the values, standards and practices of live performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-23</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-23-links-for-2009-06-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 04:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-23-links-for-2009-06-23/</guid>
      <description>Saxpix: Photography by Andy Sacks - Historic photos of late 1960s Ann Arbor street protests (tags: annarbor michigan party-like-its-1968 protest damn-hippies)  Adactio: Journal—Revealing Design Treasures from The Amazon For a lot of products, such as alarm clocks, you’re only going to write a review if you have a negative experience. How does Amazon get people to write reviews? Most people don’t leave reviews. About 0.7% of people who buy something leave a review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-19</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-19-links-for-2009-06-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 04:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-19-links-for-2009-06-19/</guid>
      <description>Hearings Today on Hydrogen-Solar-Maglev Supertrain for Michigan « the transport politic Poor Michigan. How they can’t see the obvious insane B.S. of this plan is beyond me. (tags: michigan maglev batshit-insane rail)  Detroit Make it Here | Blogging away the blight: Journalist starts a movement to remake Detroit neighborhood Neighborhood blogs and social media are particularly important at a time when daily and weekly papers are cutting just about everything to stay afloat, Morgan said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-03</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-03-links-for-2009-06-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 04:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-03-links-for-2009-06-03/</guid>
      <description>FOIA information -- chicagotribune.com good howto to manage FOIA requests in Illinois; many suggestions are relevant anywhere, though some of the details of the FOIA law vary from state to state (tags: howto chicago journalism tools foia government)  Social media success doesn’t start with ROI “What’s the ROI of your receptionist? What’s the ROI of your parking? What’s the ROI of the paint on the walls? What’s the ROI of the landscapers,” said Scott as he continued on his ‘I hate the ROI-obsessed business culture’ rant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-02</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-links-for-2009-06-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 04:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-links-for-2009-06-02/</guid>
      <description>VisitVineyards.com - Book review - Under Pressure: Cooking Sous Vide - Thomas Keller So, standing in a bookshop with towers of cookery books inviting me on armchair culinary tours of just about everywhere, wondering what might come after Flavours of Southern Patagonia, my eye was drawn to a cover depicting rows of bright scarlet on a black background, that looked like an oil painting but turned out to be stalks of rhubarb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-06-01</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-01-links-for-2009-06-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 04:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-01-links-for-2009-06-01/</guid>
      <description>WSJM AM 1400 &amp;amp; FM 94.9 - Ripe For The Picking It won&amp;#039;t be long before one of Southwest Michigan&amp;#039;s largest crops starts making an appearance at area farmer&amp;#039;s markets. MSU Extension District Fruit Educator Mark Longstroth says the region is one of the largest producers of strawberries in the state, and they&amp;#039;re typically ripe for picking in mid June. (tags: michigan strawberries june longstroth,mark)  Diana Dyer, MS, RD: Only 5 more months until fresh rhubarb!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2009-05-07</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-07-links-for-2009-05-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 04:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-07-links-for-2009-05-07/</guid>
      <description> How Do You Get To Work? interviews of how people get where they are going (tags: a2b3 video concentrate-media transit transportation travel interview michigan annarbor ypsilanti segway)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ed - review for August 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-25-ed---review-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 22:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-25-ed---review-for/</guid>
      <description>I get a lot of hits on this blog for the search term &amp;quot;ed&amp;quot;.&amp;nbsp; Here&#39;s something of a review of what else you would be looking for.
NYSE: ED is Consolidated Edison. When the power goes out around New York City, there&#39;s a Con Ed power outage map with details.
Ed Stevens lives on at Stuckeyville.com, though there are no plans of yet to re-release the 2000-2004 TV series on DVD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-05-22</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-22-links-for-20-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 04:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-22-links-for-20-11/</guid>
      <description>Rustbelt Intellectual: GREEN ACRES HERE I COME Brownfields are becoming greenfields, rubble strewn vacant lots are becoming gardens, and many cities now have neighborhood-based agribusinesses. Urban farmers are remaking parts of most Rustbelt cities. (tags: via:cshalizi ubifarm urbifarm deindustrialization agriculture food victory-gardens rustbelt philadelphia detroit)   Weirdness facilitation | Science Blogs &#34;bizarre behavior is just an emergent property of large groups of humans given the ability to communicate over long distances&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-04-23</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-links-for-200-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 04:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-links-for-200-8/</guid>
      <description> Mapping US news stories by state and population great distorted map showing the distortion of the news coverage in the US, using a map style via Mark Newman (tags: maps visualization cartography neogeography map strangemaps)   Mark Maynard - update on the great ypsi bike-powered movie thing emergent organization around bicycle-powered cinema (tags: bike generator green movie power ypsilanti washtenaw-wow cinema via:strudeau)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-04-22</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-22-links-for-200-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 04:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-22-links-for-200-7/</guid>
      <description> Alan’s Blogometer: Burn Your Feed Reader How to bail out of Google Reader and other news readers - avoid the feed, browse instead. (tags: feed feeds productivity reader-zero)   blog.plazes.com » Blog Archive » Plazes adds Fire Eagle Support Automated self-surveillance; never be alone, everyone knows where you are. Sure, it&#39;s a neat technology hack, but do you want to be part of it? (tags: geo mobile plazes)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 9 april 2008 (by hand this time)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 23:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-09-links-for-9-apr/</guid>
      <description>the usual deliciousing of links has paused for a while, but things still need to be linked; here&#39;s a brief narrative.
Festifools 2008 photos are up (thanks to Myra Klarman) - quite a few awesome puppet pictures.
I missed Festifools this year for a memorial service for Wilfred Kaplan, University of Michigan math professor emeritus and long time friend.&amp;nbsp; If you have a Mac with no passwords, you can still get in by booting to single user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-04-04</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-04-links-for-200-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 04:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-04-links-for-200-3/</guid>
      <description>AATA to Ypsi: Authority to cancel subsidies to city 04/03/08 The president of the Ann Arbor Transportation Authority told members of the Ypsilanti City Council Tuesday evening not to rely on subsidies from the transportation authority anymore.  (tags: annarbor ypsi ypsilanti bus transportation theride)   yarns made in Michigan An unknown reader of this blog put in a search query for &#34;yarns made in Michigan&#34; and got back a bad answer, since I didn&#39;t have a listing; here&#39;s what they should have seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-04-02</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-02-links-for-200-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 04:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-02-links-for-200-1/</guid>
      <description>Bimbo&#39;s on the Hill and other lost Ann Arbor eateries | Ann Arbor District Library photos, lists and reviews of long-gone restaurants in Ann Arbor (tags: annarbor food restauarants reviews arborwiki aadl lost-ann-arbor)   Virgle: The Adventure of Many Lifetimes &#34;luxury cruise to mars&#34; - Google has been testing this Adwords copy for a long time (tags: luxury-cruise-to-mars)   More Frog Postcards From Finland These are all Carte Blanche Greetings Ltd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-30</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-30-links-for-20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 04:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-30-links-for-20-23/</guid>
      <description>Uraku - Bowling Green, OH dol sot bi bim bop in ohio! (tags: bibimbop ohio dolsot via:choconancy food restaurant reviews)   Kanban; or, management by post-it note on using kanban as a software process management tool; note to self, review as a queue management process for proposal development (tags: kanban management 5s process systems postit software)   Economist.com - John Maeda debate on technology &#34;Having choice is good, especially when the available choices are all excellent ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-22</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-22-links-for-20-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 04:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-22-links-for-20-18/</guid>
      <description>A VC: Working On Vacation &#34;Posted from the eliptical trainer&#34; (tags: career multitasking vc)   Synthesize new ideas constantly - Google Search &#34;How to think&#34; rule from Ed Boyden (tags: thinking cognition ideas novelty process ed-boyden google-search)   Learn how to learn (rapidly) - Google Search A second &#34;how to think&#34; dictum from Ed Boyton. This search right now comes up with several page one hits on how toddlers learn language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-21</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-21-links-for-20-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 04:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-21-links-for-20-17/</guid>
      <description> Cover story: Blown away As its popularity grew, a cottage industry began to develop called &#34;search arbitrage.&#34; (On GeoSign, and how a Google change wiped out their business overnight.) (tags: google dotcom fall arbitrage seo advertising canada)   &#34;john kenneth sixpack&#34; - Google Search how do economists view the common man? (tags: economics economists blogthis)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-18</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-18-links-for-20-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 04:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-18-links-for-20-14/</guid>
      <description>Scholz - Web 2.0 from an East German point of view If the TV news reports on East German television seemed outlandish to tourists, I wonder what the precarity of the labor dynamic of Web 2.0 and its hyperlocal news would look like to a visitor from a country that is not afflicted by capitalism. They would (tags: 2008 analysis web2.0 web20 essay firstmonday ossi)   Remembering Jean-Claude Vrinat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-16</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-16-links-for-20-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 04:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-16-links-for-20-13/</guid>
      <description> the Martian Entropy Band Ann Arbor band from the early 70s, lovingly recreated as a web site with history pulled in part from the John Sinclair archives (tags: party-like-its-1974 annarbor music mp3 a2b3 mike-gould)   Social Media in the 1990’s | Copy Brighter in a comment: &#34;Internet in the 90s was like the wild west: difficult but rewarding. Present day Internet is like kill-yourself suburbia: convenient but soul-sucking.&#34; (tags: party-like-its-199x socialmedia nethistory)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-15</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-15-links-for-20-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 04:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-15-links-for-20-12/</guid>
      <description>Paleo-Future: 1980s awesome blog showing the history of the views of the future; here&#39;s the 80s. (tags: futurism retrofuturism party-like-its-198x blog)   Update: Fire destroys part of building under construction - Latest from the Ann Arbor News - MLive.com Fire destroyed part of a three-story, eight-unit apartment building under construction in the 900 block of Church Street early today. (tags: annarbor michigan campus fire)   Six-Word Reviews of 763 SXSW Mp3s by Paul Ford - The Morning News So many songs, six words each (tags: awesome sxsw mp3 sixwords music reviews)   The Big Picture | Bear Stearns Gets NY Fed, JP Morgan BAILOUT Bear Stearns (BSC) stock meltdown today (off 50%), live blog of the play by play (tags: bsc bear-stearns stocks subprime meltdown liquidity teotwawki)   Reuters/Second Life » EXCLUSIVE - Rosedale to step down as Linden Lab CEO Employees choose which projects they want to work on, and bonuses are assigned by a system called the “Love Machine,” which lets employees praise their co-workers for completed tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-14</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-14-links-for-20-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 04:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-14-links-for-20-11/</guid>
      <description>The Frozen Car Project - Michigan Tech - Houghton MI Collaborative artists Mary Carothers and Sue Wrbican have used this blog to track the progress of freezing a 1978 Chevy Nova in a block of ice during January and February 2008. (tags: yooper blog car transportation ice frozen party-like-its-1978)   Michigan Local &amp; Small Business business – Economics &amp; Finance business Articles - MLive.com The revelation that a major real estate management firm is considering acquiring Ann Arbor&#39;s Pfizer campus put a spotlight on the role the University of Michigan is playing behind the scenes in the marketing process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-06</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-06-links-for-200-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-06-links-for-200-4/</guid>
      <description>Whitesalls on the web (tags: chelsea michigan blogs)   Science Fiction Oral History Association - SFOHA awesome project to collect and digitize and distribute archives of oral histories of the science fiction world. (tags: history scifi audio recordings mp3 podcast archives)   Shorty Shorty is a simple tool for creating shorter, human- readable links from long URLs. You install Shorty on your server, so the links you create with it never go away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-05</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-05-links-for-200-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 03:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-05-links-for-200-3/</guid>
      <description>&#34;invisible collage student&#34; - Google Search college - collage + &#34;invisible college&#34; + &#34;college student&#34;. (tags: invisible college collage student)   getDowntown Blog»Blog Archive » AATA’s Most Beautiful Bus Route? On the morning commute, sometimes fog fills the river valley like a sleepy white dragon. Afternoons, the river sparkles in the lowering sun. A rider gazing at it likely will conclude that the #3 is the AATA’s most beautiful route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-03-01</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-01-links-for-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 03:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-01-links-for-2008/</guid>
      <description>Edge 238 - Social networks are like the eye We see clusters of happy and unhappy individuals in the social network like blinking lights in this complex fabric that is made up of people where some people are happy and some people are unhappy and there is a kind of gray zone between them. (tags: happiness socnet networks networking 2008 epidemiology via:heidigoseek socialnetworks)   Twitter / erica g: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-28</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-28-links-for-20-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 03:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-28-links-for-20-21/</guid>
      <description>globeandmail.com: Time to break the town-and-gown barrier It&#39;s more common for regions to export technology their universities create. (tags: academia community creativity culture development economics innovation university richard-florida town gown people-are-our-best-export)   Wooden Fleets and Star Fleet - bit.listserv.vpiej-l | Google Groups One of the things we will soon see is the rise of &#34;peripheral networked scholarship&#34; where every so often a displaced scholar will effect entire disciplines while operating almost entirely from within the networked environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-16</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-16-links-for-20-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 03:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-16-links-for-20-13/</guid>
      <description>Michigan Libraries in postcards Much information comes from a recent discovery, Carnegie Libraries in Michigan. Most of the postcards below are of Carnegie buildings. (tags: michigan library postcard superpatron)   The Inconvienent Truth About Social Media Marketing &#34;Social media traffic does not monetize.&#34; or, how people with a limited understanding of the short term and long term value they are building mis-measure the long term strategic value of being in the center of a dense network (tags: advertising media socialmedia marketing seo eyeballs party-like-its-1999)   Arbor puts the cap on Ellacoya buy - Mass High Tech: The Journal of New England Technology: Arbor Networks Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-14</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-14-links-for-20-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 03:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-14-links-for-20-11/</guid>
      <description>Blog Juice - kentbrewster.com Here&#39;s a toolbar bookmarklet that looks for a MyBlogLog identifier on the page you&#39;re on, and uses the MyBlogLog API to dig out information about its reader roll. (tags: api blog bookmarklet mybloglog awesome)   The Obvious?: How the blogosphere stays healthy Some time ago I said that the only blogging guidelines we need are &#34;Don&#39;t write crap, don&#39;t link to crap and if you see someone else writing crap take them to task about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-13-links-for-20-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 03:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-13-links-for-20-10/</guid>
      <description>The Coming Ad Revolution - WSJ.com The new model creates a more trusted environment for reaching high-value, frequent purchasers, whether of airline tickets, electronics, clothes or other items. Where does that leave the less-frequent purchasers? Probably looking to their friends rather th (tags: ads advertising agency behavioral facebook futures journalism legal newspaper privacy socialnetwork targeting tech todo toread trends wallstreet wsj)   Dalai Lama to deliver Lecture at University of Michigan The 14th Dalai Lama of Tibet will deliver a special Peter M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-11</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-11-links-for-200-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 03:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-11-links-for-200-8/</guid>
      <description>Johns Hopkins University Press | Books | The Mantra of Efficiency beneath efficiency&#39;s seemingly endless variety lies a common theme: the pursuit of mastery through techniques of surveillance, discipline, and control. (tags: efficiency productivity gtd surveillance control management disciple)   Online with Wireless Ypsi | Common Monkeyflower Of, course, now that Ed Vielmetti has picked up the scent, it should be all of five minutes before he&#39;s mobilized 1,000 Ann Arborites to do us one better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-07</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-07-links-for-200-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 03:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-07-links-for-200-4/</guid>
      <description>The Boom Was a Bust For Ordinary People - washingtonpost.com Growth, some of the economists are conceding in perplexity, has been &#34;decoupled&#34; from widely shared prosperity. (tags: economics labor dismal-science prosperity growth happiness)   Happiness: Enough Already | Newsweek Culture | Newsweek.com Wilson not only jumped off the happiness bandwagon—he also embraced his melancholy side and decided to blast a happiness movement that &#34;leads to half-lives, to bland existences,&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-06</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-06-links-for-200-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 03:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-06-links-for-200-3/</guid>
      <description>Making traditional paczkis is an all-night affair - Michigan News, Updates, Photos &amp; Video | Detroit, Lansing - MLive.com Pawel Strozynski brings out glazed prune paczki from the kitchen at Amadeus Cafe and Restaurant this morning. (tags: amadeus paczki)   Schedule &amp; Location: Anne Lamott on shitty first drafts Now, practically even better news than that of short assignments is the idea of shitty first drafts. All good writers write them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-02-02</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-links-for-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 03:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-links-for-2008/</guid>
      <description> East-cross.com » The Wireless Cool City (Reprise) Ypsilanti has a Meraki network up and running. Where are the high spots we need to hit to get it extended all the way to Ann Arbor? (tags: wireless ypsi ypsiarbor ypsilanti meraki wifi mesh networks cic community infrastructure)   599CD Tips &amp; Tricks - Excel VLOOKUP - 599CD.com damn, this is just what I needed (tags: vlookup excel howto)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-01-28</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-28-links-for-20-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 03:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-28-links-for-20-19/</guid>
      <description>NetworkX NetworkX (NX) is a Python package for the creation, manipulation, and study of the structure, dynamics, and functions of complex networks. (tags: network socnet framework python visualization graphviz)   Bubble glazing - thermal insulation using bubble wrap How about taking a product destined for a rubbish tip (disposable packaging) and turning it into window insulation that thermally outperforms double glazing at $2 per window? (tags: brrr cold bubble-wrap insulation glazing)   Digital Tools Help Users Save Energy, Study Finds - New York Times “I was astounded at times at the response we got from customers,” said Robert Pratt, a staff scientist at the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory and the program director for the demonstration project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-01-27</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-27-links-for-20-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2008 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-27-links-for-20-18/</guid>
      <description>City of Ashland, Oregon - Easement The above named Grantor grants to the City of Ashland, Oregon, &#34;Grantee&#34;, a perpetual non-exclusive easement in gross to use, operate, inspect, repair, maintain and remove and replace a public pedestrian and bicycle easement (tags: easement bicycle oregon ashland)   Digg / Criscenti Dan Criscenti on Digg (tags: digg annarbor party-like-its-4810x)   Google opens shop on Main - Ann Arbor &#34;I have the phone number of the gentleman at Google who&#39;s in charge of the new building, and I can call him anytime I want,&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-01-26</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-26-links-for-20-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 03:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-26-links-for-20-17/</guid>
      <description> Trenary Outhouse Races say ya to da UP, eh? Trenary, home of Trenary Toast and the annual Outhouse Races. Photos from Da Yoopers Tourist Trap. wish there was a downstate port-a-potty race to go with it. (tags: trenary michigan yooper outhouse race pictures awesome party-like-its-49891)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2008-01-25</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-25-links-for-20-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 03:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-25-links-for-20-16/</guid>
      <description>Own Page One - Internet Yellow Pages vs. Google AdWords: Getting the most from whole Sales Cycle Jon argues that Google has “no reason” to buy a Yellow Pages company. Actually there is a very good reason for Google to purchase a Yellow Page company: visitors coming through Internet Yellow Pages (IYP) sources have different behavioral characterist (tags: yp iyp yellow-pages adwords personas analytics web-analytics-wednesday)   New Year&#39;s Gourmet Dinner Trek - Ann Arbor to Ypsilanti trek route along the huron river from ann arbor to ypsilanti, 13 miles mostly flat, it would be a good ice bike route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-16</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-16-links-for-20-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2007 03:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-16-links-for-20-10/</guid>
      <description>T-Mobile Shows Ignorance Blocking Twitter :: Off the Top :: vanderwal.net I pay T-Mobile for service, if they decide not to provide service I decide to take my business to a company that will provide service. (tags: t-mobile twitter service lack-of-service walled-garden android-where-are-you)   T-Mobile Turns Off Twitter? ev, biz, it&#39;s time to get acquired by some big company (yahoo, e.g.) so you can fight the cell phone wars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-15</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-15-links-for-200-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2007 03:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-15-links-for-200-9/</guid>
      <description>Word-of-the-Year Ritual Pauses for Puzzlement - The Lede - Breaking News - New York Times Blog &#34;w00t&#34; is what locavores type to each other when they finally find the locally grown buttered radishes they had been craving (tags: w00t locavore wordie eat-local)   Pedal-powered Bicycle Trainer Washes Clothes, Generates Electricity - Ecofriend The design describes the mechanical and electrical capabilities of peddle power. It’s a dual pedal power system, with a pedal powered washing machine spinning clothes dry, and a separate belt going to a generator for electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-14</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-14-links-for-200-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 03:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-14-links-for-200-8/</guid>
      <description>Walker Tracker Blog » Blog Archive » Walker Tracker API + Google Charts API: Awesome. using the walker tracker api plus the google charts api, a pointer to code samples (tags: google googlecharts walk walking walkertracker api code mashup awesome)   Vacuum: A Concise Summary of the Field of General Systemantics systems create systems people. (tags: systems systems-people systemantics john-gall)   Con-Way Freight expanding, moving to Ann Arbor Twp - Michigan Local &amp; Small Business News – Economics &amp; Finance News Articles - MLive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-13</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-13-links-for-200-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 03:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-13-links-for-200-7/</guid>
      <description>Msgr. Louis Cappo: 1919-2007 obituary in soo news (tags: father-louie marquette michigan yooper obituary obits)   Vegan Chocolate Cake (Moosewood via Recipezaar, with changes) every vegan loves to have a dessert they can eat, and the carnivores in the audience won&#39;t know the difference. good holiday party food. (tags: cake chocolate recipes vegan vegetarian potluck nondairy party food)   Social software · Are discussion forums the ultimate Enterprise 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-12</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-12-links-for-200-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2007 03:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-12-links-for-200-6/</guid>
      <description>YouTube - Low-Cost Multi-touch Whiteboard using the Wii Remote cheap IR LED transmitters plus pens plus Wii sensor yields very cool whiteboard. (tags: awesome wii multitouch whiteboard remote lightpen)   DDOS attack &#39;really, really tested&#39; UltraDNS | The Register account of 2002 era attacks on the root name servers, no SLA payouts (tags: ultradns ddos bgp bgp-anycast party-like-its-2002 infrastructure infosec)   Gillig Corporation - Hybrid Bus hybrid bus technology (tags: automotive energy hybrid bus gillig via:saul)   Network Weaving: A Perplexing Economy valdis notes cleveland as a disconnected economy - no doubt SE Michigan looks the same way (tags: cleveland innovation economics socnet)   http://lol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-05</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-05-links-for-200-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 03:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-05-links-for-200-2/</guid>
      <description>pock-it : post-it note, glue on three sides = instant pocket via robotwisdom (tags: design creative post-it paper weak-adhesives)   719 West Washington Street | Ann Arbor District Library history of the property notes the presence of a chicken coop and orchards (tags: annarbor michigan history local-history chicken-coop)   Snow, sleet, snurr, floosh - Words to the Wise: Language and the Journal Sentinel Bruce Vielmetti, a city editor who hails from the Upper Peninsula of Michigan (a Yooper, as we call them), explained that sleet is frozen before it hits the ground, and freezing rain is liquid until it hits the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-04</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-links-for-200-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 03:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-links-for-200-1/</guid>
      <description>EconPapers: Agriculture, Environmental Services and Agro-Tourism in the Dominican Republic This paper analyzes the links between agriculture and tourism. A contingent valuation study assesses tourist’s willingness to pay (WTP) for agro-tourism and agriculture’s positive environmental services and related positive externalities. (tags: tourism agrotourism ecotourism dr do dominican-republic)   Meanwhile: Russia&#39;s last refuge: the blogosphere - Opinion - International Herald Tribune when a two month-old Russian start-up with the funky name of Sup (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-12-02</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-links-for-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 03:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-02-links-for-2007/</guid>
      <description> Severed Unicorn Head Superstore : For All Of Your Severed Unicorn Head Needs a mark maynard production (tags: fun funny unicorn gifts shopping)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-11-30</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-30-links-for-20-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 03:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-30-links-for-20-25/</guid>
      <description>NYSERNet:About: In June 1985, a meeting of representatives of New York State’s leading academic institutions convenes at Cornell University to discuss the creation of a statewide electronic network to connect New York’s major research universities and corporations to (tags: nysernet nsfnet history 1985 newyork internet nethistory)   Office of Science and Technology Policy - John H. Marburger III Bio John H. Marburger, III, Science Adviser to the President and Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, (tags: john-marburger nsfnet ostp)   SIGUCCS 2000 Penny Crane Award - Jane Caviness Jane Caviness has had a productive and successful career in higher education and computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-11-29</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-links-for-20-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 03:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-links-for-20-24/</guid>
      <description>Talking Back to Prozac - The New York Review of Books As the product of a guild whose members seek payment for treating whatever complaints are brought to them, the manual must be biased toward overmedicalizing so that both doctors and patients can be served under managed care. (tags: advertising marketing medical medicalization medicine mentalhealth pharma review toread)   Computer Randomly Plays Classical Music During normal operation or in Safe mode, your computer may play &amp;ldquo;Fur Elise&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a Small, Small World&amp;rdquo; seemingly at random.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links for 2007-11-28</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-28-links-for-20-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 03:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-28-links-for-20-23/</guid>
      <description>Google Apps with the Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce Two-hour interactive workshop to learn how Google Apps can transform how your organization collaborates and communicates featuring Scott Johnston from Google in Mountain View. (tags: scott-johnston event annarbor michigan google-apps wiki jotspot collaboration)   Homework Coma (Tipsy Texan) The bad news, obviously, is that I haven&#39;t had any spare time to write about drinks. Fortunately, things are not so bad that I haven&#39;t had time to drink drinks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>