<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan Spiders on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-spiders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan Spiders on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 11:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/michigan-spiders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to milk a spider</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-25-how-to-milk-a-spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-25-how-to-milk-a-spider/</guid>
      <description>http://www.sciencefriday.com/video/031507/milk.html
Ever wondered how to milk a spider? In this video, Dr. Greta Binford, a researcher at Lewis and Clark College in Portland, Oregon, extracts venom from a sleeping spider&amp;#39;s fangs. 
http://www.kgw.com/news/specialreports/stories//kgw_042707_special_news_spider_woman.146f5fbf.html
 Greta Binford, however, has slightly less cooperative subjects. Binford collects venom from the world&amp;#39;s most dangerous spiders.   Binford jokes she has &amp;quot;the dream job of most 8-year-old boys. I sit and watch spiders catch bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pictures of Michigan Spiders</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-pictures-of-mic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 21:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-pictures-of-mic/</guid>
      <description>As a part of a continuing series on Michigan spiders, here are some images.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve identified them as best I can with Latin and common names.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be adding to this from time to time to make it as complete as I can; the end of this post has some more sources.
Jumping spiders &amp;quot;Jumping Spider&amp;quot; by Hamilton Images; all rights reserved, used with permission

This jumping spider was photographed in Rockwood, MI in the Lake Erie Metropark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern Michigan spiders (and other inverts): the Backyard Arthropod Project from Atlantic Mine, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-27-northern-michig/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-27-northern-michig/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a long while, you run across something so wonderful you have to share.
I have been tracking hits to the Google search Michigan spiders, ever since an odd combination of page text about automated web browsing tools unearthed a bunch of folks trying to identify the spiders crawling across their day lilies.
Today&#39;s search logs turned up this amazing resource, the The Backyard Arthropod Project
A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>