<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Potato on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/potato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Potato on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/potato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew: six recipes to mix and match from</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</guid>
      <description>Haven&#39;t cooked any of these yet, but there&#39;s some recipes to work through:
Ricki Heller: Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew. Uses tahini to enrich the sauce.
Fit Pregnancy: Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew with Chard . With chard, paprika, parsley.
The First Mess: moroccan-style vegetable + chickpea stew . Sweet potatoes instead of potatoes, and a cinnamon+coriander+cumin spice.
The Picky Eater: Indian Chickpea and Potato Stew. Curry is the flavor here, and cilantro replaces parsley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Lemon Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</guid>
      <description>Part of a recipes collection.
This was part of dinner last week - yum! I don&amp;#39;t have the exact proportions in front of me so you&amp;#39;ll want to be prepared to improvise.&amp;#0160;
Potatoes, peeled, cut to quarters; to fill lasagna pan; redskins would do well Juice of 3 lemons,&amp;#0160;fresh squeezed&amp;#0160;juice not stuff from bottles if you have it&amp;#0160;
Greek oregano (though Mexican oregano worked OK too) Olive oil Water
Preheat oven to a good roasting temperature (450+ degrees).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven fried potato recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Writing this down so I remember this one detail: to get fries the right size, cut a medium potato into 16 pieces. (Cut in 4 equal width slices, then cut each slice into 4 parts). It works pretty quickly once you get going, and the resulting fries get crispy much more so than potatoes cut into quarters. A sweet potato yields 32 fries, cut in half and then in fours and then in fours).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato pancakes (Latkes) recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-potato-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 08:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-06-potato-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>This is the family latke recipe, perfected over time. Ten pounds of potatoes serves one neighborhood.
Warning: the following recipe may be bad for your health and completely destructive of your kitchen!
From a newspaper clipping in my recipe book, much amended by me over the years:
POTATO PANCAKES Time: 20 minutes (More like two hours, unless you have multiple griddles)
2 large eggs 3 cups grated drained, all-purpose potatoes (see below) 1/4 cup grated onion (see below) 1 teaspoon salt, more to taste (less) 2 to 4 tablespoons matzo meal, or as needed (I used whole wheat flour; you could also use breadcrumbs) Canola oil, for frying Applesauce and sour cream for serving, optional (mandatory!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>