<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Potato on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/potato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Potato on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/potato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew: six recipes to mix and match from</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haven&#39;t cooked any of these yet, but there&#39;s some recipes to work through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricki Heller: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rickiheller.com/2011/03/anti-candida-sugar-free-gluten-free-vegan-chickpea-tomato-and-potato-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Uses tahini to enrich the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fit Pregnancy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitpregnancy.com/nutrition/recipes/chickpea-potato-tomato-stew-chard&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew with Chard
&lt;/a&gt;. With chard, paprika, parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First Mess: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefirstmess.com/2013/09/26/moroccan-style-vegan-vegetable-chickpea-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;moroccan-style vegetable + chickpea stew
&lt;/a&gt;. Sweet potatoes instead of potatoes, and a cinnamon+coriander+cumin spice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Picky Eater: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pickyeaterblog.com/indian-vegetable-stew-yum/&#34;&gt;Indian Chickpea and Potato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Curry is the flavor here, and cilantro replaces parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and Wine: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodandwine.com/recipes/new-potato-chickpea-and-tomato-stew&#34;&gt;New Potato, Chickpea and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. The surprise ingredient is chorizo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally Ella: &lt;a href=&#34;http://naturallyella.com/2011/12/05/sweet-potato-and-chickpea-stew-with-quinoa/&#34;&gt;Sweet Potato and Chickpea Stew with Quinoa&lt;/a&gt;. Quinoa is the novel grain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Lemon Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of a recipes collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was part of dinner last week - yum! I don&amp;#39;t have the exact proportions in front of me so you&amp;#39;ll want to be prepared to improvise.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potatoes&lt;/strong&gt;, peeled, cut to quarters; to fill lasagna pan; redskins would do well &lt;br /&gt;Juice of 3 &lt;strong&gt;lemons,&amp;#0160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fresh squeezed&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;juice not stuff from bottles if you have it&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;Greek &lt;strong&gt;oregano &lt;/strong&gt;(though Mexican oregano worked OK too) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olive oil&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to a good roasting temperature (450+ degrees).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the potatoes in the lasagna pan. Mix lemon juice, water, oregano, oil together; you are after something like a salad dressing, but since you&amp;#39;re baking it the water will go away, so make sure there&amp;#39;s enough oil. Besides, olive oil is good for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour the dressing over the potatoes, mix until everything is coated. Put in oven. Roast until starting to turn brown, about 40-50 minutes depending on your oven and your potatoes. If you don&amp;#39;t have a lot of oil in the dressing, you may need to turn to keep things from sticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll bet it would be good to put a couple of organic lemon halves in there too to roast along with everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove from oven, test for doneness. Eat. Yum. Also good cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other lemon roasted potato recipes, for comparison: &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/unbound/corby/ct2000-12.htm&#34;&gt;Corby&amp;#39;s Table&lt;/a&gt; from The Atlantic Monthly has a patates riganates recipe from a review of Aglaia Kremezi&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Foods of the Greek Islands&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sandisrecipecorner.com/recipe488H.htm&#34;&gt;Sandi&amp;#39;s Recipe Corner&lt;/a&gt;, adds stock &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dvo.com/recipe_pages/grilln/Greek_Garlic_and_Lemon_Roasted_Potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Cook&amp;#39;n&lt;/a&gt;, adds dill and roasts over wood chips &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autumnjade.com/recipes/133.htm&#34;&gt;Autumn Jade&lt;/a&gt;, basically the same with exact proportions &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalgourmet.com/food/special/2001/greek/potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Global Gourmet&lt;/a&gt; calls these &lt;strong&gt;patates riganates&lt;/strong&gt; and adds garlic &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://creampuffsinvenice.typepad.com/cream_puffs_in_venice/2006/04/some_lemony_spu.html&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Cream Puffs in Venice&amp;quot; has some lemony spuds for you&lt;/a&gt;, adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/work/907079&#34;&gt;Cook This&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Rosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;#39;m sure there are more recipes to be had!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more recipe to go with this if you have any cold leftovers. Put a bed of spring mixed greens on a plate; I like the Asian mix we found at Farmer&amp;#39;s Market. Cut some of these potatoes up and put on top. Add diced cubed cold roasted beets for color and flavor. Dress with some of the lemon-oil mix, with a little red wine vinegar added. Yum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; font-size: 10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/lemon&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;lemon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/potatoes&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;potatoes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/recipe&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven fried potato recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing this down so I remember this one detail: to get fries the right size, cut a medium potato into 16 pieces. (Cut in 4 equal width slices, then cut each slice into 4 parts). It works pretty quickly once you get going, and the resulting fries get crispy much more so than potatoes cut into quarters. A sweet potato yields 32 fries, cut in half and then in fours and then in fours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put the raw potato strips into a big bowl, pour some olive oil on them, and mix until everything is nicely coated, then put them onto cookie sheets and cook for what seems like a long time in a 425 degree F oven. If you want equally crispy on both sides, turn them over part way through. They would be good with a sprinking of sea salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more recipes, not that you need much of a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/recipe/oven-fries/&#34;&gt;All Recipes&lt;/a&gt; uses a little sugar and a little cayenne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eatingwell.com/recipes/oven_fries.html&#34;&gt;Eating Well&lt;/a&gt; cuts into wedges (too big!) and adds dried thyme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Crispy-Oven-Baked-French-Fries/&#34;&gt;Instructables&lt;/a&gt; secret ingredient is cornstarch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, maybe you do need a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[[Category: Needs Photo]]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>