<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Advisory Committee on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/local-advisory-committee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local Advisory Committee on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 14:54:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/local-advisory-committee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AATA Local Advisory Committee meeting, unofficial notes, 2/10/2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 14:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-10-aata-local-advisory-committee-meeting-unofficial-notes-2102009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;Ann Arbor Transportation Authority&lt;br /&gt;Local Advisory Committee&lt;br /&gt;Feb 10, 2009&lt;br /&gt;unofficial notes&lt;br /&gt;Edward Vielmetti&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is my notes from the LAC meeting of 2/10/09,&lt;br /&gt;edited slightly but not intended as a faithful&lt;br /&gt;transcript of the meeting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I came in 10 minutes late; the meeting starts at&lt;br /&gt;10:00am, and the AATA #6 from downtown gets there&lt;br /&gt;at 10:01am. The meeting ends at 12:00 noon; the &lt;br /&gt;inbound #6 arrives at 11:58am.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The board discussed Tom Partridge&amp;#39;s comments and reporting on same&lt;br /&gt;in the minutes to the previous meeting.&lt;br /&gt;He was apparently somewhat disruptive in the meeting,&lt;br /&gt;and the meeting minutes attempt to reflect that. Some&lt;br /&gt;discussion among the (relatively unprepared) board &lt;br /&gt;on how to prepare an accurate reporting of this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;a lot of disorganization going on in the meeting&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;apparently tom created a lot of interruptions. he&lt;br /&gt;derailed the agenda. (was that his agenda).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a recording device at the table; is that&lt;br /&gt;going to be shared? I don&amp;#39;t know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No one has name tags or table tents showing their names.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;chris white&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;AOS calculates schedule adherence for each service at each&lt;br /&gt;bus stop. &amp;quot;from our point of view we publish a time point&lt;br /&gt;the driver can&amp;#39;t leave before that time&amp;quot;. 57 after the hour.&lt;br /&gt;can&amp;#39;t leave before 57. intermediate times keep track of it.&lt;br /&gt;trying to publish that information, in a different way,&lt;br /&gt;not guarantee . keyed to places where bus can sit. &amp;quot;not&lt;br /&gt;beyond the realm of possibility&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;real time information move to do it on cell phones. attraction&lt;br /&gt;of cell phones is to call up anywhere you want and find&lt;br /&gt;the schedule adherence of the next bus. do it in office,&lt;br /&gt;on way to office, on bus stop. difficulty of maintaining&lt;br /&gt;information at bus stops, struggling with. easier to put it&lt;br /&gt;up than it is to maintain it. schedule cases difficult to&lt;br /&gt;maintain. a few real time signs at stops, issue of getting&lt;br /&gt;power to them. solar power next thing. from our point of view&lt;br /&gt;the best option is cell phones. last survey: most riders did&lt;br /&gt;have them. limited income, almost all cell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;text &amp;#39;AATABUS 6&amp;#39; to 41411&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;detail discussion of time adherence at all stops. leave a little&lt;br /&gt;early if traffic is clear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;services with cognitive impariments, difficult time riding the bus.&lt;br /&gt;difficultiy accessing information.&lt;br /&gt;do have support systems, talk to, &lt;br /&gt;call taker on the phone, schedule in person, general training.&lt;br /&gt;one on one travel training, general mobility education.&lt;br /&gt;work with individuals with disabilities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;don&amp;#39;t even use the book, it&amp;#39;s too confusing.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;too hard to train on a timetable.&lt;br /&gt;best way tot do it is based on locatoin time to be there.&lt;br /&gt;individual schedule, prepare it for them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;alternate formats, audio cd for indivduals.&lt;br /&gt;schedule is read in audio format.&lt;br /&gt;on request.&lt;br /&gt;large print format.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;important that need to be worked on.&lt;br /&gt;meeting needs of those indivdiuals.&lt;br /&gt;systemic basis, right down to the individual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I told the story of going from mary markley to burns park elementary,&lt;br /&gt;and how my son in 3d grade was asked to help prepare&lt;br /&gt;a route for someone visiting the school. It might be&lt;br /&gt;hard if you try to mix University and AATA routes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;problem of getting buses to CIL in the middle of Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;Research Park. Nothing from the city side. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CIL, Social Security moved to research park drive just off&lt;br /&gt;of ellsworth road. No sidewalks on S side of Ellsworth,&lt;br /&gt;N side no curb and gutter. Very busy, difficult for bus &lt;br /&gt;stops, hard to cross. Cross busy road, stand on shoulder.&lt;br /&gt;city looking at a signal. S side in Pittsfield Twp no &lt;br /&gt;sidewalks until development. A lot of time to cross&lt;br /&gt;Ellsworth +5 at the corner. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stimulus package: $200k for bus stops. Added money for&lt;br /&gt;urban transit systems, amount up in the air, somewhere&lt;br /&gt;between $6 and $8 million, must be spent in 1.5 yrs.&lt;br /&gt;Short term: lead walks, benches; sidewalk design work;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Design of park and ride lot at Plymouth Road and US-23,&lt;br /&gt;in the interchange at SW quadrant. 300 spaces. P&amp;amp;R&lt;br /&gt;plan, 1st thing to do. Intercept traffic before it&lt;br /&gt;gets into the more crowded part of Ann Arbor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Internet service is back up and running. Email lost when&lt;br /&gt;provider had &amp;quot;financial difficulties&amp;quot;. Now working as&lt;br /&gt;a part of the city&amp;#39;s email and internet with the county&lt;br /&gt;as well. So far 2 weeks, things working real well. Ridetrak&lt;br /&gt;lost at the worst time possible, bad weather, snow and&lt;br /&gt;the cold. Really a terrible time, couldn&amp;#39;t have been&lt;br /&gt;worse.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Public participation at board committee meetings, PMER,&lt;br /&gt;Planning and Development, Governance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1. &amp;quot;Should not be open to the public&amp;quot;. Board did not&lt;br /&gt;adopt that as the policy. Communicate those comments&lt;br /&gt;to the board. Comment in writing? Committees new, trying&lt;br /&gt;to reorganize how the work is done. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Proposal for fare changes. Two phone calls in past three weeks,&lt;br /&gt;both not in support of the fare change proposal; affects&lt;br /&gt;the people who need the service the most. Make trips less&lt;br /&gt;frequently, take less and save up money.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Haven&amp;#39;t had any other calls. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;people&amp;#39;s express is running now&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;northfield&lt;br /&gt;salem&lt;br /&gt;superior&lt;br /&gt;ypsilanti&lt;br /&gt;pittsfield&lt;br /&gt;augusta&lt;br /&gt;york&lt;br /&gt;lodi&lt;br /&gt;bridgewater&lt;br /&gt;scio (parts of; cdbg funds; $1/ride to go anywhere)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;anyone can get. all senior centers at least once a year.&lt;br /&gt;information on aata web site? not getting the word out.&lt;br /&gt;washtenaw county commissioners, some meetings are televised.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;other places to meet?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;can aata provide added access to the meeting?&lt;br /&gt;podcast, recording, other access.&lt;br /&gt;community television network across the street.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;what would be possible?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;would podcasting be viewed by more people?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;#39;t want to spend money, just access &lt;br /&gt;for what people?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;can you take the recording? whose recording?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;--&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;end of notes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>