<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet Of Things on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/internet-of-things/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet Of Things on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>the internet of things world hasn&#39;t condensed into a single system, and because of its origins it&#39;s unlikely to do so.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-internet-of-things-world-hasnt-condensed-into-a-single-system-and-because-of-its-origins-its-unl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-internet-of-things-world-hasnt-condensed-into-a-single-system-and-because-of-its-origins-its-unl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet of things is a multi-protocol internet, with lots of legacy protocols in use as well as homemade protocols over TCP/IP and also serial port stuff and funky radio uses. Oh, and HTTP too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things in the internet of things are very small and have very low cost network capacity, which rules out using a full stack HTTP implementation. Others are not quite as small, but still don&#39;t have enough oomph to take on an Internet&#39;s worth of traffic, so you might run HTTP but still keep the devices firewalled very carefully from the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were looking at standards and formats I would look at traditional Internet protocols and formats (HTTP, JSON), at older serial data networks (like RS-232 or even MODBUS), and I&#39;d get a grasp on how you might communicate over radio networks like the 915 Mhz ISM band or Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE). I&#39;d also look at publish/subscribe systems like MQTT, and lightweight data retrieval systems like COAP, and I&#39;d be aware of all of the things you might do over a simple TCP connection. And then I&#39;d look at the security of all of this (and weep, sometimes, because it&#39;s not easy.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet of things world hasn&#39;t condensed into a single system, and because of its origins it&#39;s unlikely to do so. Picking which of three or four possible solutions could work for your application - one of which might be HTTP - is good. Deciding which fits the right sweet spot of skills, costs, and time to deploy is another good way to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Originally posted in slightly modified form to iot-craft)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Things (Marvel edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-06-28-the-internet-of-things-marvel-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 08:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-06-28-the-internet-of-things-marvel-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via Bob Dively, a Marvel Comics version of the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; The Internet of Things &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/dMvoIjbIZ0&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dMvoIjbIZ0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bob Dively (@bobdively) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bobdively/statuses/482722072205225985&#34;&gt;June 28, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 18:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73de1cff0970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73de1cff0970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2014-06-27 at 6.06.27 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2014-06-27 at 6.06.27 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a73de1cff0970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found myself thinking about things, and how to connect things to the net, quite a bit recently. I&#39;ll be blogging more about it here and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &#34;things&#34; I mean more precisely devices at the edge of the network that are not on the network in the usual way. You can&#39;t connect to them directly, but they can send and receive messages via sensors and actuators that figure out what they are doing and instruct them what to do. In the middle of this network there are message routing systems, and at the human edge there are various points where people need to make decisions about what should happen next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are fascinating in many places that the web is not. Treating web site visitors like so many pinballs through a funnel dehumanizes them, but that&#39;s a lot of what makes people focus on user behavior. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been building things out of smaller things, learning how to plumb them together, understanding message flows and designing out behaviors. It&#39;s transformative in the way that making web pages never will be transformative.  The task now is to write some of this stuff up, the late night experiments and the discovery of new hardware and the task of plugging things together and making them work. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>