<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet Of Things on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/internet-of-things/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet Of Things on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>the internet of things world hasn&#39;t condensed into a single system, and because of its origins it&#39;s unlikely to do so.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-internet-of-things-world-hasnt-condensed-into-a-single-system-and-because-of-its-origins-its-unl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-internet-of-things-world-hasnt-condensed-into-a-single-system-and-because-of-its-origins-its-unl/</guid>
      <description>The internet of things is a multi-protocol internet, with lots of legacy protocols in use as well as homemade protocols over TCP/IP and also serial port stuff and funky radio uses. Oh, and HTTP too.
Some of the things in the internet of things are very small and have very low cost network capacity, which rules out using a full stack HTTP implementation. Others are not quite as small, but still don&#39;t have enough oomph to take on an Internet&#39;s worth of traffic, so you might run HTTP but still keep the devices firewalled very carefully from the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Things (Marvel edition)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-28-the-internet-of-things-marvel-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 08:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-28-the-internet-of-things-marvel-edition/</guid>
      <description>Via Bob Dively, a Marvel Comics version of the Internet of Things.
@vielmetti The Internet of Things pic.twitter.com/dMvoIjbIZ0
&amp;mdash; Bob Dively (@bobdively) June 28, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 18:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-things/</guid>
      <description>I have found myself thinking about things, and how to connect things to the net, quite a bit recently. I&#39;ll be blogging more about it here and elsewhere.
By &#34;things&#34; I mean more precisely devices at the edge of the network that are not on the network in the usual way. You can&#39;t connect to them directly, but they can send and receive messages via sensors and actuators that figure out what they are doing and instruct them what to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>