<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crisis Informatics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/crisis-informatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crisis Informatics on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 11:37:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/crisis-informatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>crisis informatics, or the study of community emergency response</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-crisis-informatics-or-the-study-of-community-emergency-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search?q=crisis+informatics&#34;&gt;crisis informatics&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (Google search) term is new to me, but the research I&amp;#39;ve been able to find under that term is familiar.&amp;#0160; Faced with an unexpected crisis situation that is bigger than what the mainstream media and existing government organizations can easily manage the news flow from, how do communities response in emergency situations with social media and with ad hoc emergency response systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into lots of detail I do want to share one recent paper that caught my eye, via Leysia Palen: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.colorado.edu/%7Epalen/Papers/iscram08/BackchannelsISCRAM08.pdf&#34;&gt;Backchannels on the Front Lines: Emergent Uses of Social Media in the 2007 Southern California Wildfires.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Opportunities for participation by members of the public are expanding the information arena of disaster.&amp;#0160; Social media supports “backchannel” communications, allowing for wide-scale interaction that can be collectively resourceful, self-policing, and generative of information that is otherwise hard to obtain. Results from our study of information practices by members of the public during the October 2007 Southern California Wildfires suggest that community information resources and other backchannel communications activity enabled by social media are gaining prominence in the disaster arena, despite concern by officials about the legitimacy of information shared through such means. We argue that these emergent uses of social media are pre-cursors of broader future changes to the institutional and organizational arrangements of disaster response. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The term &amp;quot;crisis informatics&amp;quot; is credited to Christine Hagar (2006).&amp;#0160; If you do a proper retrospective look at the phenomenon without that term, you unearth previous discussion of the use of the net for responses in the Kobe and Northridge earthquakes, hurricanes Katrina and Rita, and various power outages and ice storms.&amp;#0160; A proper retrospective bibliography awaits someone else&amp;#39;s project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>