<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fathers Day on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/fathers-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fathers Day on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 16:09:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/fathers-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What are you doing on Father&#39;s Day in Ann Arbor? Take our poll.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-fathers-day-take-our-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 16:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-fathers-day-take-our-poll/</guid>
      <description>The poll is provided through All Our Ideas, which unlike most other polling software is actually useful for writing in that it lets readers come up with their own suggestions and not just pick from a pre-packaged list.
If you are wondering what to cook for dear old Dad, last week&#39;s Pancakes? poll might give you some recipe ideas. It generated 21 ideas with over 200 votes.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Park grand opening, June 19 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-west-park-grand-opening-june-19-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 16:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-west-park-grand-opening-june-19-2011/</guid>
      <description>More Father&amp;#39;s Day events! West Park had a major construction project over the last year, and it&amp;#39;s now being unveiled complete with a grand ribbon cutting and the unveiling of the sculpture in the park.
If you were at West Park during the recent monsoon rains you&amp;#39;ll appreciate that quite a bit of work went into stormwater handling, with very visible results.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour de Kids bicycle race, Sunday June 19, 2011, South U and East U in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-2011-tour-de-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 15:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-2011-tour-de-kids/</guid>
      <description>The Tour de Kids is an annual bicycle race for kids 3-12 held on South University on Father&amp;#39;s Day. This year it&amp;#39;s June 19. The poster and race map is below; details including registration information at www.tourdekids.org. Here&amp;#39;s a chance to run a loop around the Diag!
Sponsors include St. Joe&amp;#39;s, IHA, Ann Arbor Bicycle Touring Society, and Wheels in Motion.
 The cost is $10 for an individual and $20 for a family (up to 5 kids).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>