<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Halloween on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/halloween/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Halloween on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 08:20:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/halloween/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowtober: power outage maps for Halloween 2011 storm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-29-snowtober-power-outage-maps-for-halloween-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 08:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-29-snowtober-power-outage-maps-for-halloween-2011/</guid>
      <description>THIS WEEK IN MAPS, for Sunday, October 30, 2011: A late October snowstorm is heading up the East Coast of the United States for Halloween. Here&#39;s maps of the affected areas, showing what parts of the electrical grid have had the worst impact from the heavy, wet snow in the forecast.
New Hampshire As of 2:00 a.m. Sunday, 32% of PSNH customers are without power.

Massachusetts NSTAR list of power outages by town (PDF) for midnight, Sunday; no map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 26, 2008: Trick or Treat Down The River, Argo to Gallup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-17-october-26-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 11:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-17-october-26-2008/</guid>
      <description>Trick or Treat Down the River returns this fall ANN ARBOR, Mich., Oct. 16, 2008 — City of Ann Arbor Parks and Recreation – Don’t miss the chance to “Trick or Treat Down the River” with your family on Sunday, Oct. 26. Begin your trip from the Argo Canoe Livery anytime between noon and 4 p.m. The fee is $22/boat (no pre- registration required). Experience the Huron River in all its fall beauty while also enjoying trick-or-treating by canoe or kayak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>costume (exploding vacuum) from the Terry Jones opera &#34;Evil Machines&#34;, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-05-costume-explodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-05-costume-explodi/</guid>
      <description>In the &amp;quot;this might be too weird for this year&#39;s Halloween costume&amp;quot; department:
fromLive Design Online, &amp;quot;No One Meaner than a Vacuum Cleaner&amp;quot;
The opera (Evil Machines) features wild cars and other evil machines, pitted against friendly household appliances, including a beautiful egg whisk and the alarm clock that loves her. Veteran costume designer and Monty Python movie alum James Acheson had a hand in designing the opening chorus of six evil vacuum cleaners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween costume: vacuum with attachments</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-halloween-costu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 23:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-halloween-costu/</guid>
      <description>in some extremely silly world, here are practical ways to get dressed for Halloween as a vacuum cleaner with attachments.
From &amp;quot;coolest homemade costumes dot com&amp;quot; in their home appliances section:
My husband started with an empty box, free from the grocery store and cut it down to fit her. He then wrapped it in some black vinyl, attached some parts from old vacuums we had in the garage (handle, hose and attachment, caddy with brushes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Halloween hours and events for October 31, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 23:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</guid>
      <description>As promised here&amp;#39;s a collection of Halloween information for Ann Arbor and the area for 2008.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ll be updating this page as new stuff comes in.
City of Ann Arbor - offical hours TRICK-OR-TREATING MAY TAKE PLACE&amp;#0160; IN CITY OF ANN ARBOR NEIGHBORHOODS&amp;#0160; ON FRIDAY, OCT. 31, 2008, BETWEEN 5 AND 8 P.M. more on the halloween pdf press release for 2008 for ann arbor
Burns Park - Costume Parade from the Burns Park Elementary PTO newsletter:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>