<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.
 The news of the day is a death on State Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning polygons in R and Shapely</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:14:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-cleaning-polygons-in-r-and-shapely/</guid>
      <description>The project of the week has been an effort to generate a set of maps - 2935 of them, in fact. The source data is from the Department of Energy, listing a set of utility companies and the counties they cover; the goal is to have a boundary map generated for each utility company. I know it won&amp;rsquo;t be a perfect boundary (most utility companies have at least one county that they only provide service to part of), but as a start it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps with Leaflet and LeafletR</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-02-maps-with-leaflet-and-leafletr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 01:09:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-02-maps-with-leaflet-and-leafletr/</guid>
      <description>style leaflet(data=&#34;/Users/emv/tmp/N.geojson&#34;,dest=tempdir(),popup=&#34;*&#34;,style=style)  So, progress.
One process, written in python, takes an Excel file provided by the county and creates a GeoJSON file from it. Addresses in the file are geocoded. The original file has a set of restaurant inspection reports and three kinds of inspection problems found; I add a fourth &#34;score&#34; variable that&#39;s derived in some way from those three.
A second process (code above) is in R using the LeafletR graphing package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>