<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New York City on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-york-city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New York City on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 08:56:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-york-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo Cannonade to open the Erie Canal</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-echo-cannonade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 15:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-echo-cannonade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=y4dKAAAAMAAJ&amp;dq=%22erie+canal%22+cannon&amp;as_brr=1&amp;pg=PA70&amp;ci=534,326,463,457&amp;source=bookclip&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=y4dKAAAAMAAJ&amp;pg=PA70&amp;img=1&amp;zoom=3&amp;hl=en&amp;sig=Tt7rQvmQOf9mKfqMYjhuHxq-AS4&amp;ci=534,326,463,457&amp;edge=1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Text not available&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=y4dKAAAAMAAJ&amp;dq=%22erie+canal%22+cannon&amp;as_brr=1&amp;pg=PA70&amp;ci=534,326,463,457&amp;source=bookclip&#34;&gt;The First Book of History, for Children and Youth&amp;#38;nbsp;By Samuel Griswold Goodrich&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deadmedia.org/notes/46/466.html&#34;&gt;Source(s): Ian Frazier&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Family,&amp;rdquo; 1994 via the Dead Media Project&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
A cannon-fire relay communicates and celebrates the opening of the Erie Canal.  &amp;ldquo;In 1825, the first boat bound for New York City left Lake Erie and entered the newly completed Erie Canal. Observers at the point where the canal met the lake saw the boat and fired a cannon. Some miles to the east, people heard the shot and fired a cannon there; when sound of that shot reached a cannon farther east, someone fired that one; and so on, in a sequence of hundreds of cannon placed at intervals along the canal route, down the Mohawk River, and down the Hudson River all the way to New York City. At the final shot, an hour and twenty minutes after the first, the sequence was reversed, from the city all the way back to the lake. The Echo Cannonade (as people called it) announced the opening of the canal and began a big celebration in the city.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags start &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:right;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/erie-canal&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;erie-canal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/echo&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/ping&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;ping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/cannonade&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;cannonade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/party-like-its-182x&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;party-like-its-182x&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/1825&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;1825&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/telegraph&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;telegraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags end &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro North power outage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A power outage on a 138,000 volt line that provides power to Metro North trains in New York has snarled commutes from Connecticut to New York City and has also affected Amtrak service in the busy New York - Boston corridor. Work is underway to put in a temporary fix by diverting power from surrounding businesses and neighborhoods. A backup feeder line was offline, and full service restoration may take weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro North is responding by putting diesel trains into service and by running buses to try to accommodate the 130,000 daily commuters on the line, but this provides only about a third of the capacity needed for a normal commute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NY Times, &#34;Power Failure Disrupts Metro North’s New Haven Line; May Last Days&#34;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/09/26/nyregion/metro-norths-new-haven-line-suspended-after-power-loss.html&#34;&gt;September 25, 2013&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The disruption began after a Consolidated Edison feeder cable in Mount Vernon, N.Y., failed around 5:20 a.m., snarling service between Stamford, Conn., and Grand Central Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CT Post, &#34;Metro-North, Con Edison tested plan that led to failure&#34;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctpost.com/local/article/Metro-North-service-What-you-need-to-know-4845143.php&#34;&gt;September 26, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Though it may take officials weeks to determine the cause, it appears the 138,000 volt line that was left to bear the burden of energizing trains along an eight-mile stretch of track in Westchester County, N.Y., from Pelham to Rye became overwhelmed and superheated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg Business Week, &#34;Delayed NYC Commuters Ask Why Metro-North Power Failed Again&#34;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/news/2013-09-27/stranded-nyc-commuters-ask-why-metro-north-power-failed-again#p1&#34;&gt;September 27, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Connecticut Governor Dannel Malloy, a Democrat, said yesterday that Con Edison representatives told him the company is working to get a portion of the electricity needed to the commuter line. The power would come from three transformers to be tested this weekend, Malloy said. He said updates will be provided to residents the night before the Sept. 30 commute. “There appears to have been little plan for this type of catastrophic failure,” Malloy said during the briefing at Grand Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet - Finn Brunton - MIT Press - 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://finnb.net&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901bf3ff62970b-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Spam-shadow-history-of-internet-9780262018876&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901bf3ff62970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901bf3ff62970b-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Spam-shadow-history-of-internet-9780262018876&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Finn Brunton&lt;/a&gt; has a new book out, called &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mitpress.mit.edu/books/spam&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, published by the MIT Press. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading it this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some radio interviews about the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/05/04/179219174/please-dont-delete-this-interview-about-spam&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;An interview with NPR&amp;#39;s Scott Simon on Weekend Edition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbc.ca/spark/full-interviews/2010/11/18/full-interview-finn-brunton-on-spam-filters/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;CBC&amp;#39;s Spark, in 2010.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and some print:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radicalphilosophy.com/commentary/roar-so-wildly-spam-technology-and-language&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Roar so wildly: spam, technology and language&lt;/a&gt;. From Radical Philosophy 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the raw text output of a chat session with a bot I modified to act as an interlocutor. I use our conversation, which revolves around the history of spam, particularly algorithmic filtering, litspam, and the theories of Wiener and Turing, as a way of putting forward the outlines of new, machine-driven forms of language for which spam was the testing ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2013/05/01/spam_the_anatomy_of_violence_and_arming_mother_nature_reviewed.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A book review in Slate&amp;#39;s Future Tense.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literary lovechild of: Katie Hafner’s&lt;em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://elibrary.mel.org/record=b11038006~S15&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Where Wizards Stay Up Late: The Origins of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;and Andrew Blum’s&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1408146&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tubes: A Journey to the Center of the Internet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the most expensive parking space in Ann Arbor?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 08:56:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night was the a2civictech meetup. We met at Zingerman&#39;s Next Door, there were 9 people who showed up, some familiar faces and some new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nominal topic of the discussion was data quality, understanding how various data sets that come from civic sources have noise in them and looking at ways to deal with that. The best story was that of a well map that showed a hill in the middle of a lake, because the underlying data set had two wells with the same name and the person who built the map picked the wrong data to map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always with these discussions the question turned to what data there might be available to look at, and how to get it. That led us to questions of what other people were doing with municipal data in other cities, and to this New York City parking ticket analysis: &lt;a href=&#34;http://iquantny.tumblr.com/post/87573867759/success-how-nyc-open-data-and-reddit-saved-new&#34;&gt;Success: How NYC Open Data and Reddit Saved New Yorkers Over $55,000 a Year&lt;/a&gt;. It seems that there was a parking space in New York that looked like it was a legal spot, but turned out to be frequently ticketed because it was near a fire hydrant. After some analysis and publicity by Ben Wellington of I Quant NY, the NYC DOT repainted the stripes on the street to clearly mark this spot as a no-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question becomes, how would you repeat this analysis for Ann Arbor, and what would you look for? Where are there locations that frequently generate tickets, what do they look like on a map, and how much ticket revenue comes per space?  And in the public interest, are there any spots that generate disproportionate ticket frequencies that should be looked at carefully to improve signage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like a project. In New York there&#39;s a data catalog that includes this data set and many others; no such data has been released in Ann Arbor. So the first step is understanding what the process is for getting a year or two of ticket data to start analyzing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: here&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/ben_wellington_how_we_found_the_worst_place_to_park_in_new_york_city_using_big_data?language=en&#34;&gt;TED Talk by Ben Wellington&lt;/a&gt; on &#34;How we found the worst place to park in New York City -- using big data&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>