<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New York City on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-york-city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New York City on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 08:56:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/new-york-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the most expensive parking space in Ann Arbor?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 08:56:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-24-whats-the-most-expensive-parking-space-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Last night was the a2civictech meetup. We met at Zingerman&#39;s Next Door, there were 9 people who showed up, some familiar faces and some new ones.
The nominal topic of the discussion was data quality, understanding how various data sets that come from civic sources have noise in them and looking at ways to deal with that. The best story was that of a well map that showed a hill in the middle of a lake, because the underlying data set had two wells with the same name and the person who built the map picked the wrong data to map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro North power outage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</guid>
      <description>A power outage on a 138,000 volt line that provides power to Metro North trains in New York has snarled commutes from Connecticut to New York City and has also affected Amtrak service in the busy New York - Boston corridor. Work is underway to put in a temporary fix by diverting power from surrounding businesses and neighborhoods. A backup feeder line was offline, and full service restoration may take weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet - Finn Brunton - MIT Press - 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-08-spam-a-shadow-history-of-the-internet-finn-brunton-mit-press-2013/</guid>
      <description>Finn Brunton has a new book out, called &amp;quot;Spam: A Shadow History of the Internet&amp;quot;, published by the MIT Press. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading it this summer.
Some radio interviews about the book:
An interview with NPR&amp;#39;s Scott Simon on Weekend Edition.
CBC&amp;#39;s Spark, in 2010.
and some print:
Roar so wildly: spam, technology and language. From Radical Philosophy 2010.
This is the raw text output of a chat session with a bot I modified to act as an interlocutor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo Cannonade to open the Erie Canal</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-echo-cannonade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 15:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-11-29-echo-cannonade/</guid>
      <description>The First Book of History, for Children and Youth&amp;#38;nbsp;By Samuel Griswold Goodrich  Source(s): Ian Frazier&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Family,&amp;rdquo; 1994 via the Dead Media Project
  A cannon-fire relay communicates and celebrates the opening of the Erie Canal. &amp;ldquo;In 1825, the first boat bound for New York City left Lake Erie and entered the newly completed Erie Canal. Observers at the point where the canal met the lake saw the boat and fired a cannon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>