<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Huron River on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/huron-river/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Huron River on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:21:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/huron-river/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River: May 25, 2011 flooding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</guid>
      <description>The river is high. Will it flood? That&amp;#39;s a very good question to ask in the morning before a storm; and the answer today turned out to be yes. Roads were inundated, Lake Barracuda emerged from its stormwater geyser, Depot Street filled with water, Mullholland Creek popped a manhole cover, and S. Main Street near Michigan Stadium filled. West Park&amp;#39;s new water features get a workout.
Basements have taken on water, and the full extent of storm damage is unknown yet until we get the May 26 predicted rains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Central River flood outlook, April 3-8, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-04-north-central-river-flood-outlook-april-3-8-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-04-north-central-river-flood-outlook-april-3-8-2011/</guid>
      <description>A snapshot of the flood outlook from the North Central River Forecast Center&amp;#0160;shows what a wet spring week will do to river levels.

 The Huron River in Ann Arbor will have high water this week.
 Edward Vielmetti splashes in puddles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River water level watching: USGS National Water Information System</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 13:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</guid>
      <description>Follow the level of the Huron River as it goes through Ann Arbor&amp;#0160;with the USGS National Water Information System. On March 23, the river is rising, but it&amp;#39;s also fluctuating in levels, enough that it&amp;#39;s difficult to determine whether current trends would lead you to believe that there is any risk of flooding.
If you were to watch this closely, what would you watch?
The USGS will give you an alert if the level of the river is above or below a certain level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>