<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bitcoin on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bitcoin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bitcoin on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 02:31:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bitcoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC: &#34;Greece&#39;s bank holiday from hell&#34;; impact on Bitcoin transactions?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-29-bbc-greeces-bank-holiday-from-hell-impact-on-bitcoin-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 02:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-29-bbc-greeces-bank-holiday-from-hell-impact-on-bitcoin-transactions/</guid>
      <description>From the BBC: Greece&#39;s bank holiday from hell. Greek banks are expected to stay shuttered for more than a week, and in the meantime depositors can only withdraw 60 euros per day.
The Internet spin on this is to wonder how Bitcoin will be used to evade currency controls. From Financial Post, Bitcoin is the real winner in Greece crisis:
 The main driver for bitcoin prices seem to be Greek buyers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insane coin posse</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-insane-coin-posse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 12:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-insane-coin-posse/</guid>
      <description>The latest in cryptocurrencies is the Juggalocoin, proposed to handle the transactional needs of the fans of the Insane Clown Posse. From Billboard (because after all this is an entertainment story):
 Whoop whoop! A very tech-savvy Juggalo by the name of Papa Nutt has taken it upon himself to create a cryptocurrency specifically for Faygo-chugging devotees of &#34;the Family&#34; to buy goods and services with*, especially at the upcoming Gathering of the Juggalos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt Gox in bankruptcy court - &#34;We&#39;ve been goxed!&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-mt-gox-in-bankruptcy-court-weve-been-goxed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 01:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-mt-gox-in-bankruptcy-court-weve-been-goxed/</guid>
      <description>From Bloomberg News, March 11 2014
 Mt. Gox Inc., the American affiliate of the bankrupt Bitcoin exchange that lost track of hundreds of millions of dollars’ worth of virtual currency, had its U.S. assets frozen by a federal judge in Chicago.
U.S. District Judge Gary Feinerman today issued a temporary order tying up money and property belonging to the affiliate, its ultimate corporate parent, Tibanne KK, and principal Mark Karpeles after a hearing today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt Gox is down in Bitcoin heist, &#34;transaction malleability&#34; to blame</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-26-mt-gox-is-down-in-bitcoin-heist-transaction-malleability-to-blame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-26-mt-gox-is-down-in-bitcoin-heist-transaction-malleability-to-blame/</guid>
      <description>The latest in the Bitcoin saga is a crisis at Mt Gox, one of the major Bitcoin exchanges in the world. A few judicious news clippings will give you a sense of the chaos.

From Reuters: Bitcoin exchange Mt. Gox goes dark in blow to virtual currency
 The website of Mt. Gox suddenly went dark on Tuesday with no explanation, and the company&#39;s Tokyo office was empty - the only activity was outside, where a handful of protesters said they had lost money investing in the virtual currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin volatility after Mt Gox downtime</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-bitcoin-volatility-after-mt-gox-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 10:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-bitcoin-volatility-after-mt-gox-downtime/</guid>
      <description>Depending on the source you get a slightly different story, but the results are the same: there is a lot of volatility in Bitcoin pricing in early February 2014 because of problems at the Mt. Gox exchange. So much for a technologically pristine, mathematically pure, decentralized currency; when your &#34;foreign exchange&#34; depends on a very small number of businesses, it can have systematic vulnerabilities.

Coindesk, Why Mt. Gox, the World’s First Bitcoin Exchange, is Dying -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin at new record highs, trading in China</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-bitcoin-at-new-record-highs-trading-in-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 15:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-bitcoin-at-new-record-highs-trading-in-china/</guid>
      <description>The price of Bitcoin has soared in recent months, even though the Dread Pirate Roberts was taken offline. A recent graph shows the currency trading above $800.

What has changed that would drive the price from $140 to $800? The only simple answer (right or wrong) is China. The South China Morning Post reports -
 A US Senate hearing put bitcoin firmly in the mainstream and triggered fresh support from countries that tend to fall in line with America&#39;s financial regulatory regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin, conspicuous consumption, and conspicuous waste</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-bitcoin-conspicuous-consumption-and-conspicuous-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 01:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-bitcoin-conspicuous-consumption-and-conspicuous-waste/</guid>
      <description>From the Bitcointalk forums, 2011: &amp;quot;Bitcoins are peacock tails&amp;quot;
A series of studies, &amp;quot;Peacocks, Porsches and Thorstein Veblen: Conspicuous Consumption as a Sexual Signaling System,&amp;quot; was published recently in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology.&amp;#0160;A peacock&amp;#39;s tail is beautiful: magnificent plumage, iridescent colors. Alas, it is also wasteful. It takes a tremendous amount of energy to develop. Sound like bitcoins?
Let&amp;#39;s look at the Bitcoin as a signal of conspicuous consumption and conspicuous waste.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>