<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Floods on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/floods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Floods on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 16:01:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/floods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>April 29-30 2014 Pensacola, Florida flooding in maps</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-30-april-29-30-2014-pensacola-florida-flooding-in-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 16:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-30-april-29-30-2014-pensacola-florida-flooding-in-maps/</guid>
      <description>Life-threatening flash #flood continues in Pensacola, FL/Mobile, AL. Nearing 20&amp;quot; rain totals. pic.twitter.com/2FAISmZNiW
&amp;mdash; TWC Breaking (@TWCBreaking) April 30, 2014 

Pensacola International Airport reports 5.68” of rain in the last hour. Radar estimates are off the charts pic.twitter.com/BJgQ8fKbPw
&amp;mdash; BuzzFeed Storm (@BuzzFeedStorm) April 30, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boulder Colorado Flood of September 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-12-boulder-colorado-flood-of-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 10:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-12-boulder-colorado-flood-of-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>The city of Boulder, Colorado is flooded after several days of torrential rains. Here&#39;s some useful links if you want to get up to speed on what&#39;s going on.
Turn around, don&#39;t drown. If you&#39;re in the affected area, get authoritative news from local sources (and not this blog).
Scanner For raw unfiltered news of what is happening, listen to the emergency services scanner for the Boulder area. The Boulder County Sheriff and Fire feed has over 800 listeners as of this writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 8, 2013 Toronto flooding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-july-8-2013-toronto-flooding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 21:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-july-8-2013-toronto-flooding/</guid>
      <description>The streets of Toronto are full of water as over 100 mm of rain (about 4 inches) has fallen in some areas. Meteorologists are making comparisons with Hurricane Hazel, which flooded the area in 1954.
Some of the best brief accounts are on Twitter, using the various hashtags #TOflood, #floodTO, #TOstorm, #stormTO, and #darkTO. I listened to CBC Radio 1 Toronto for a while to get a sense for how bad it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 27, 2013 flooding in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-27-june-27-2013-flooding-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 16:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-27-june-27-2013-flooding-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>Several streets in Ann Arbor have flooded as a result of slow-moving storm cells that passed through the city on the afternoon of Thursday, June 27, 2013. Reports are still filtering in, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I know about right now.
The City of Ann Arbor is building a “Citizen Storm Corps” volunteer group to assist in stormwater/flooding data collection. Volunteers will visit Large Event Data Gathering locations after significant rain events, record visual observations about the stormwater&amp;rsquo;s behavior at that location using a LEDG Stormwater/Flooding Reporting Form, and submit the data to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 28, 2013 North Quad flood</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-march-28-2013-north-quad-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-march-28-2013-north-quad-flood/</guid>
      <description>North Quad at the U of Michigan had a flood today, causing classes to be cancelled and students to be evacuated from their rooms. There is no estimate of the damage at this time, but it&#39;s extensive.
The University of Michigan School of Information has a flood information page with reschedule and relocate information for classes and talks.
 All media inquires about the flooding should be directed to Kelly Cunningham in the UM Public Affairs Office: kecunham@umich.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>