<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Television Network on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/community-television-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Television Network on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/community-television-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers from CTN regarding City of Ann Arbor closed captioning</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</guid>
      <description>Answers to questions sent to Greg McDonald, CTN manager, regarding closed captioning at on City of Ann Arbor&#39;s Community Television Network.
Why are you providing closed captioning?
The Commission on Disability Issues made a request to add captions to their meetings to increase meeting accessibility.
Who is providing the closed captioning for CTN?
ScreenLine, L.L.C.
How much is the size of the contract, and for how long does it run?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a public meeting with five windows open to the world -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor City Council holds meetings twice each month, which are streamed online through the city&amp;#39;s CTN network. I tuned in last night on my laptop to listen and watch.
While I was listening, I had a few other windows open on my computer. First and foremost, I had a twitter stream that I was watching for the #a2council&amp;#0160;hash tag; that caught commentary from a few other people who were watching at home, plus some reporters in the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meetings now simulcast online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</guid>
      <description>Ann Arbor City Council meetings are now simulcast online, which is handy if you don&amp;#39;t get local CTN cable service. &amp;#0160;This link
http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html
goes to an experimental setup which also tracks the Twitter #aacitycouncil tag.
The CTN Meetingplace page now hosts the current broadcast (both live and delayed) for CTN Channel 16. Meetings are held the first and third Monday nights of the month starting at 7:00 p.m., unless they aren&amp;#39;t for some reason like a holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to watch on CTN, April 1-7, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-01-what-to-watch-on-ctn-april-1-7-2011/</guid>
      <description>What to watch on CTN is the City of Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s weekly programming guide to public access cable. Download this week&amp;#39;s flyer as a PDF.&amp;#0160;Here&amp;#39;s show listings for April 1-7, 2011. Note that several of these are also available on demand over the Internet at http://a2gov.org/ctn .

Edward Vielmetti is certain to make it big in television if he ever gets a chance to break in to the big time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>