<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/baseball/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/baseball/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SDR.HU to listen to AM radio sports</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-23-sdr-hu-am-dx-baseball-and-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-23-sdr-hu-am-dx-baseball-and-football/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cubs won the pennant, and the Buckeyes lost to Penn State. I was able to listen to
the radio calls of both of these through recievers connected to &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdr.hu&#34;&gt;sdr.hu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cubs radio call was from WMVP-AM, ESPN Chicago 1000. I had some practice listening
to them through the Farmington Hills, MI SDR run by KB8SPI. That system is a KiwiSDR
with a PA0RDT Mini-Whip, and it tunes from 0-30 Mhz including all of the longwave
(broadcast AM) band. I also had a chance to pull in WTAM-AM Newsradio 1100 in Cleveland
from the same receiver, though I had to work a bit to avoid adjacent channel interference
from WCAR-AM 1090 in Detroit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ohio State call was from WIMA-AM, Lima Ohio 1150. This was very easy to pick up from
KH6ILT&amp;rsquo;s KiwiSDR in nearby Elida, OH. WIMA is part of the Ohio State IMG Sports Network,
and it broadcasts all of the Buckeye football games. The signal is very strong (S9+30)
and there is no interference from other stations. I was able to find this station from
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ohiostatebuckeyes.com/sports/m-footbl/spec-rel/radio-network.html&#34;&gt;list of Ohio State Buckeye radio stations&lt;/a&gt;,
and it&amp;rsquo;s possible that this particular receiver might pick up other sports broadcasts as well;
I&amp;rsquo;m also able to pull in WMVP-AM ESPN Chicago 1000 here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chasing AM radio sports is a lot of fun. Even if the major networks broadcast their
video streams via cell phone apps for free from time to time - ESPN was showing
the Ohio State game on their app at the end for free - it&amp;rsquo;s still useful to pick
up the radio call. In this particular case the radio feed was a couple of plays
ahead of the video, so I got about 45 seconds of lead time by listening to the radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only small limitation about SDR.HU and its OpenWebRX software is that when I
try to view it on a small cell-phone sized screen it doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle it very well.
Note that these receivers are based on the Beaglebone hardware and can only handle
four simultaneous listeners. With those two constraints in mind, it&amp;rsquo;s a great way
to extend your listening reach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>