<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snow Computing on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/snow-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snow Computing on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 13:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/snow-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow computing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-08-snow-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 13:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-08-snow-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So much talk about cloud computing, so being complementary I&amp;#39;ll link to some bits on snow computing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://contrarythinking.wordpress.com/2009/02/03/snow-computing/&#34;&gt;On CRM usage on &amp;quot;snow days&amp;quot; from John Paterson:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;There has been a lot of press articles related to
computing-in-the-bad-weather, talking about rolling out VPNs to
peoples’ homes, how to protect the in-house network from home-borne
viruses, but web based CRM needs nothing so complex - just log in and
go! Sometimes life doesn’t need to be so complex.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://old.cs.ncl.ac.uk/research/pubs/articles/papers/247.pdf&#34;&gt;Dr. Richard Snow writes about fault tolerance in railway scheduling (PDF):&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;snap_preview&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The trainset is a digitally controlled model railway that have been used at the University of Newcastle for investigations, experiments and student projects in real time and distributed control [11]. The railway layout is mounted on three separate boards that can be independently controlled by separate computers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springerlink.com/content/xw34526475u18k3q/&#34;&gt;More about snow, this about modeling snow drifting from Schmidt at USDA:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;Abstract&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Abs1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;AbstractHeading&#34;&gt;Abstract&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;Transport
rates, measured by weighing snow blown into a filter fabric trap, were
greater over hard snow or ice than for the same wind speed over soft,
fresh snow surfaces. Analysis of wind speed profiles from nine
blizzards showed that friction between moving particles and the surface
was less, and particle speeds were greater over hard surfaces.
Transport rates at a given wind speed increased rapidly as aerodynamic
roughness decreased in the rough-smooth transition region. Bagnold&amp;#39;s
theory for bed load transport provided a useful framework for the
analysis.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, what we have includes modeling systems when there is inclement weather, modeling the transport of fine particles during inclement weather, and building simulators that are computer controlled to let you see how things work.&amp;#0160; All fun ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pasty.com/heikki/heikkilunta.html&#34;&gt;(More info at pasty.com)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>