<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walking on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/walking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walking on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 15:02:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Walker Tracker</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-revisiting-walker-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 15:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-revisiting-walker-tracker/</guid>
      <description>In among the pile of random things that you find when you have a teenager in the house, I located on old Omron pedometer whose battery had run down. One quick trip to CVS later, and I have a working tool to measure my physical activity.
In the winter months it&#39;s harder for me to get the outdoor exercise that I think I need. The days are shorter, the sidewalks are slipperier, and the excuses are more numerous to stay indoors where it&#39;s warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Around, a new urban walking game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 14:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m inventing a new urban game called Walking Around. I&amp;#39;m sure that someone else has invented it already, but reinvention is part of the process of creativity. Here&amp;#39;s how it&amp;#39;s played.
First, you play with a pedometer, which tells you how far you&amp;#39;ve walked during the day. There are a number of systems already for tracking your pedometer usage, including Walker Tracker, Steps, and a bunch of others. Use whatever system that gives you, or just a spreadsheet, to take care of the basic structure of making certain that you count steps daily.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>