<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calendars on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calendars on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 20:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Calendar: every year the same (1935 calendar reform proposal)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-05-the-world-calendar-every-year-the-same-1935-calendar-reform-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 20:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-05-the-world-calendar-every-year-the-same-1935-calendar-reform-proposal/</guid>
      <description>A proposal to reform the calendar system, circa 1935, would have simplified the seasons by making every single year have the same calendar, every single quarter have 91 days and 13 Sundays, and every January 1 always fall on a Sunday. Leap years are accomodated with a mid-year extra Saturday, and the end of the year is celebrated as Year End Day, also as an extra Saturday.

This image is from&amp;#0160;Why reform the calendar?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free things on your (happy) birthday in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</guid>
      <description>One of the most popular pages on Arborwiki is the Birthday deals page, which tracks the ever-changing Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti area retail landscape by looking at places which give you some kind of special deal on your birthday. If your birthday is coming up soon, give it a look, and if you need to poke someone on your favorite social network site to wish them a happy birthday, a link to this page is always appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum of Creative Calendar Design and the Chrono-Shredder by Susan Hertrich</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-11-museum-of-creative-calendar-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-11-museum-of-creative-calendar-design/</guid>
      <description>The Museum of Creative Calendar Design has a large collection of calendars created by designers, in the genre of creative work to be given as presents to your best clients. One of the works highlighted is the Chrono-Shredder by Susan Hertrich, which &amp;quot;shreds every day in real time&amp;quot;. Another set of photos of the system, as installed, is at Vvork. Core77 collects this observation:
In an exploration of fictional tools for hibernators, Susanna Hertrich developed the Chrono_shredder, a product that serves as a reminder to live one&amp;#39;s life productively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countdown clocks: Only (nn) days until Christmas</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-countdown-clocks-only-nn-days-until-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-countdown-clocks-only-nn-days-until-christmas/</guid>
      <description>There was a brief interlude after Halloween to allow for Election Season, but then all of the orange-themed holiday items were swept away from the stores and are now replaced by green and red themed holiday items.&amp;#0160; (New packaging, same stuff.)&amp;#0160; That was what it looked like both at Kroger and at Caribou Coffee yesterday, quite disconcerting to go with the 60+ degree weather.
Kroger had a large clock up in view of the checkout lanes with a countdown timer until Christmas, something like this one (except a lot cheaper).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar of the week: When do 2009 calendars go on sale?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-calendar-of-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 15:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-calendar-of-the/</guid>
      <description>In Australia, they go on sale in September (!):&amp;nbsp; From the Australian Newsagency Blog

Our calendar sales in September were up 72% at Forest Hill and 37% at Frankston.
At Forest Hill the increase is driven by having a solid range on display early in the calendar season.
At Frankston it is thanks to a new point of difference - previously this store focused on magazine distributor calendars. We are focused on a more unique range of titles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On using a wiki as a public calendar</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-on-using-a-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 23:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-on-using-a-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Every week on Thursday I host a lunch at Eastern Accents in Ann Arbor; you&#39;re invited.&amp;nbsp; One regular element of that lunch is helping figure out what events are happening the upcoming weekend and weeks ahead so that people can find help in publicizing those events or tell people about something they are looking forward to.
I&#39;ve tried a zillion difficult ways to keep the calendar for that group, none of which are ideal, mostly because they involve some kind of calendar system which requires more precision than I have time to deal with and which makes me type things into fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s October - echoes of previous years</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a review of what people were looking for to find this weblog in previous Octobers.&amp;nbsp; Some of this tells me what I should write about this year, and other parts of it tell me what fads came and went.
Ann Arbor trick or treat hours (search): Every year I try to post a complete list of trick or treat hours for the area; here&#39;s the 2005, 2006, and 2007 lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>usb powered seasonal affective disorder lamp, for your laptop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-usb-powered-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-usb-powered-sea/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t know if anyone makes this, but I think it would be helpful.&amp;nbsp; Rough specifications:
- usb powered; plugs into your laptop
- some kind of secure clip or clamp attaches to your laptop screen
- bright led lighting designed to deal with seasonal affective disorder
This product page has some plausible options from Gentron Telecom in Taiwan; I can&#39;t find ordering or pricing, so these may be designs available for use but not in actual production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>revisit this talk in 30 days</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-revisit-this-ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 11:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-revisit-this-ta/</guid>
      <description>from the Randy Pausch lecture on time management, which I looked at 100 days ago:  And do a time journal, and if that&#39;s really too much effort, just count the number of hours you watch of television in the next week. That&#39;s my gift to you.
 The last thing is, once you&amp;rsquo;ve got your day-timer, make a note for 30 days from today - it&amp;rsquo;s okay if that one goes &amp;quot;ding&amp;quot; to remind you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Trends for fall: pumpkin, halloween etc</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-google-trends-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-google-trends-f/</guid>
      <description>In the &amp;quot;How do you know that it&#39;s fall&amp;quot; issue, note this year&#39;s Google search trends for &amp;quot;pumpkin&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;halloween&amp;quot;, both trending upwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you keep your calendar?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-how-do-you-keep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 22:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-how-do-you-keep/</guid>
      <description>I try to ask this question every year at least, because the answers change all the time; it was the topic of this week&#39;s a2b3 meeting.&amp;nbsp; Here are some things people shared.
Many people were using Google Calendar for shared calendaring - not just one calendar, but multiple calendars, and someone said they had 20 different calendars.&amp;nbsp; There was one part the need to keep personal and work calendars separate, one part the desire to subdivide work calendars into multiple slices to be shared on a per-project basis, and one part to synchronize home and work and family and kids and school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groundhog Day / Candlemas 2007 roundup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-groundhog-day-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 16:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-groundhog-day-c/</guid>
      <description>Some good friends celebrate Groundhog Day, and we enjoyed their company today. Some things I learned:  You should have half your hay left on Groundhog Day People start looking for last frost dates for the season on Groundhog Day In Europe it&amp;rsquo;s Candlemas Day Traditional foods include crepes and pancakes Bellinis are delicious, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do an all-Michigan version in season  More reading and links:  Groundhog Day category on Mama Lisa&amp;rsquo;s World Blog has crepe recipes and a song:  Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous, ma mèr’ vous invite Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous, ell’ vous invite tous Un’ pour toi, un’ pour moi, un’ pour mon p’tit frèr’ François Un’ pour toi, un’ pour moi, un’ pour tous les trois.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>