<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calendars on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calendars on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 20:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Calendar: every year the same (1935 calendar reform proposal)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-05-the-world-calendar-every-year-the-same-1935-calendar-reform-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 20:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-05-the-world-calendar-every-year-the-same-1935-calendar-reform-proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A proposal to reform the calendar system, circa 1935, would have simplified the seasons by making every single year have the same calendar, every single quarter have 91 days and 13 Sundays, and every January 1 always fall on a Sunday. Leap years are accomodated with a mid-year extra Saturday, and the end of the year is celebrated as Year End Day, also as an extra Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0168e50bb871970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 1&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0168e50bb871970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0168e50bb871970c-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This image is from&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/003525873&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Why reform the calendar? : A symposium of opinion prepared for the Special Committee on Calendar Reform of the Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York&lt;/a&gt;, as found on HathiTrust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theworldcalendar.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;World Calendar Association&lt;/a&gt; is still going strong. A word from their web site on the origin of this proposal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theworldcalendar.org/ASSETS/AchelisPronunciation.swf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elisabeth Achelis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;spread the New York Times out on her desk, momentarily blanketing the plaque dear to her that bore this quote of&amp;#0160;unknown Persian origin. On that Sunday,&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;September 8, 1929&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;(a date&amp;#0160;she never forgot and one she revisited fondly in her 1961 autobiography,&lt;em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;Be Not Silent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), Elisabeth found a&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theworldcalendar.org/8September1929-NYT.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;letter to the editor of the New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;by Lewis E. Ashbaugh of Denver, Colorado. In a brief, almost casual tone, Ashbaugh suggested that the then-unofficial National Committee on Calendar Simplification should consider the adoption of a twelve-month, equal-quarter calendar (perhaps suggested as early as 1745 and published by Abbe´ Mastrofini in 1834) over that of the thirteen-month one that was rapidly gaining popular favor. Elisabeth saw much in this simply revised calendar plan, and instantaneously knew that her five-year search for something to help the world in which she lived had come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that calendar reform is no less exotic than speling reform, and that a 12 month rearranged calendar is less exotic than a 13 month calendar where every month has a Friday the 13th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0162ff15cb4c970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 2&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0162ff15cb4c970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0162ff15cb4c970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free things on your (happy) birthday in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-07-ann-arbor-happy-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular pages on &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt; is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Birthday_deals&#34;&gt;Birthday deals&lt;/a&gt; page, which tracks the ever-changing Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti area retail landscape by looking at places which give you some kind of special deal on your birthday. If your birthday is coming up soon, give it a look, and if you need to poke someone on your favorite social network site to wish them a happy birthday, a link to this page is always appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum of Creative Calendar Design and the Chrono-Shredder by Susan Hertrich</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-11-museum-of-creative-calendar-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-11-museum-of-creative-calendar-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01348819072c970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Chrono-Shredder&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01348819072c970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01348819072c970c-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Chrono-Shredder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unicorngraphics.com/calendar%20museum.asp&#34;&gt;Museum of Creative Calendar Design&lt;/a&gt; has a large collection of calendars created by designers, in the genre of creative work to be given as presents to your best clients.  One of the works highlighted is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.susannahertrich.com/html/chronoshredder.html&#34;&gt;Chrono-Shredder&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Susan Hertrich&lt;/strong&gt;, which &amp;quot;shreds every day in real time&amp;quot;.  Another set of photos of the system, as installed, is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vvork.com/?p=3825&#34;&gt;Vvork.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/object_culture/chrono_shredder_by_susanna_hertrich_6089.asp&#34;&gt;Core77&lt;/a&gt; collects this observation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;In an exploration of fictional tools for hibernators, Susanna Hertrich developed the Chrono_shredder, a product that serves as a reminder to live one&amp;#39;s life productively. The 365-day calendar is dispensed day-by-day from a single roll, each day shredded over an exact 24-hour period.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can imagine creating the counterpart to this work, a calendar which is a fax machine connected to a phone line that faxes in, slowly, line by line, the image of the next day&amp;#39;s calendar page. I&amp;#39;ll leave it as an exercise to the reader to decide what bit rate corresponds to one 8.5&amp;quot; by 11&amp;quot; calendar page per day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countdown clocks: Only (nn) days until Christmas</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-countdown-clocks-only-nn-days-until-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-07-countdown-clocks-only-nn-days-until-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a brief interlude after Halloween to allow for Election Season, but then all of the orange-themed holiday items were swept away from the stores and are now replaced by green and red themed holiday items.&amp;#0160; (New packaging, same stuff.)&amp;#0160; That was what it looked like both at Kroger and at Caribou Coffee yesterday, quite disconcerting to go with the 60+ degree weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kroger had a large clock up in view of the checkout lanes with a countdown timer until Christmas, something like this one (except a lot cheaper).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;asins=B001DUP1AK&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;lt1=_blank&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a fan of countdown timers as a personal management tool; set a widget to beep after 15 minutes and do one thing until then.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baldgeeks.com/3-2-1.htm&#34;&gt;(I&amp;#39;m using the 3-2-1 timer from BaldGeeks on my Mac.)&lt;/a&gt; It helps, for instance, to make sure that you don&amp;#39;t miss the bus for a meeting, and it helps to make sure that the kids know just how long they can stay in bed before school starts. But the xmasy themed technology goes a little too far.&amp;#0160; (Besides, I&amp;#39;m counting the days until Groundhog Day, and there is no market for marmot-themed plastic.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar of the week: When do 2009 calendars go on sale?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-calendar-of-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 15:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-calendar-of-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Australia, they go on sale in September (!):&amp;nbsp; From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsagencyblog.com.au/2008/10/03/calendar-strategy-delivers-results.html&#34;&gt;Australian Newsagency Blog&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our calendar sales in September were up 72% at Forest Hill and 37% at Frankston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Forest Hill the increase is driven by having a solid range on display early in the calendar season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Frankston it is thanks to a new point of difference - previously
this store focused on magazine distributor calendars. We are focused on
a more unique range of titles. We have given over a column at the front
of the store to promote our calendar range as well as to feature a &lt;strong&gt;Calendar of the Week&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually when people talk about a &amp;quot;calendar of the week&amp;quot;, they talk about &amp;quot;a calendar of the next week&#39;s events&amp;quot;.&amp;nbsp; Here, we have &amp;quot;an entirely new calendar of the year, so that if you gave up on last week&#39;s calendar because you got bored of seeing pictures of fuzzy bunnies, here&#39;s a new one of fuzzy kittens.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remarkable (and a great idea).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On using a wiki as a public calendar</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-on-using-a-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 23:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-on-using-a-wiki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every week on Thursday I host a lunch at Eastern Accents in Ann Arbor; you&#39;re invited.&amp;nbsp; One regular element of that lunch is helping figure out what events are happening the upcoming weekend and weeks ahead so that people can find help in publicizing those events or tell people about something they are looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve tried a zillion difficult ways to keep the calendar for that group, none of which are ideal, mostly because they involve some kind of calendar system which requires more precision than I have time to deal with and which makes me type things into fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hack (and really it&#39;s a hack) for the last few weeks has been to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/index.php/Talk:A2b3&#34;&gt;the talk page on the group&#39;s page on Arborwiki as a public calendar, &lt;/a&gt;or more precisely, to use it for me as a quick place to cut and paste things so that when the time comes I know enough to tell people about that.&amp;nbsp; An interesting advantage to doing it in wiki vs. in a calendar system is that I can hyperlink e.g. the name of a theater to the page for that theater and get (for free) all of the location and venue information along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it perfect?&amp;nbsp; No.&amp;nbsp; Is there some refinement of it which might work better?&amp;nbsp; Sure.&amp;nbsp; Is it handy?&amp;nbsp; You bet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s October - echoes of previous years</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a review of what people were looking for to find this weblog in previous Octobers.&amp;nbsp; Some of this tells me what I should write about this year, and other parts of it tell me what fads came and went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=ann+arbor+trick+or+treat+hours&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor trick or treat hours (search)&lt;/a&gt;: Every year I try to post a complete list of trick or treat hours for the area; here&#39;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/halloween_trick.htm&#34;&gt;2005,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/halloween_trick.html&#34;&gt;2006,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/09/halloween-trick.html &#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt; lists.&amp;nbsp; This year if I&#39;m ambitious I&#39;ll try to get a list of any special events by neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michigan+spiders&#34;&gt;Michigan spiders (search&lt;/a&gt;): One of the most popular October pages is a writeup I did on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/brown_recluse_s.html &#34;&gt;the brown recluse spider&lt;/a&gt; two years ago; a recent one on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/09/pumpkin-spider.html&#34;&gt;the pumpkin spider&lt;/a&gt; should be good too.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not a coincidence that spiders are part of Halloween decorations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=noguchi+filing+system&#34;&gt;Noguchi filing system (search):&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; In October 2005 I wrote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/noguchi_filing_.html &#34;&gt;Noguchi filing system&lt;/a&gt;, a time-centered approach to filing and memory by a Japanese economist that William Lise had described on his translation web site.&amp;nbsp; Interest spiked ever so briefly in August 2006.&amp;nbsp; Subsequently Lise pulled his excellent descriptive text from the net in response to piracy of his text.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noguchi.co.jp/&#34;&gt;The Yukio Noguchi web site is all in Japanese&lt;/a&gt; but may help in some way to help you reconstruct this system from his original works describing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=laszlo+bock&#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock, Google (search):&lt;/a&gt; In October 2006, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/laszlo_bock_goo.html &#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock was interviewed by the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; about changes to the hiring process at Google, describing a system that was going to be more heavily quantified and measured than before.&amp;nbsp; Interest in that clip peaked Jan 2007 and has been consistent.&amp;nbsp; A further &lt;a href=&#34;http://mba.yale.edu/news_events/CMS/Articles/6352.shtml&#34;&gt;interview with Bock by the Yale School of Management&lt;/a&gt; gives few additional insights, but this interesting tidbit: he was an actor in &amp;quot;Showtime kinds of movies&amp;quot;, yet there&#39;s no unambiguous credits for him in IMDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=book+burro&#34;&gt;Book Burro (search):&lt;/a&gt; In October 2006, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron/2006/10/book_burro_wins.html&#34;&gt;Firefox plugin Book Burro won 2d prize in a mashups for libraries contest organized by OCLC.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Book Burro watches web sites when you browse and alerts you to information about books referenced on the page, allowing you with a minimum of keyboard and mouse movement to know whether that book from Amazon is in stock at your local library.&amp;nbsp; I wrote about this as part of some broader set of library focused writing at my other blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron&#34;&gt;Superpatron.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in October 2005, I wrote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/caribou_coffee_.html&#34;&gt;Caribou Coffee opening up down the street&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s still there, and I&#39;m still a regular.&amp;nbsp; mmm coffee...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>usb powered seasonal affective disorder lamp, for your laptop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-usb-powered-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-usb-powered-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if anyone makes this, but I think it would be helpful.&amp;nbsp; Rough specifications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- usb powered; plugs into your laptop&lt;br /&gt;- some kind of secure clip or clamp attaches to your laptop screen&lt;br /&gt;- bright led lighting designed to deal with seasonal affective disorder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gentron.com.tw/yellowpage/product_cg6681.html&#34;&gt;This product page has some plausible options from Gentron Telecom in Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;; I can&#39;t find ordering or pricing, so these may be designs available for use but not in actual production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>revisit this talk in 30 days</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-revisit-this-ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 11:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-revisit-this-ta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
from the Randy Pausch lecture on time management, which I looked at 100 days ago:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And do a time journal, and if that&#39;s really too much effort, just count the number of hours you watch of television in the next week. That&#39;s my gift to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The last thing is, once you&amp;rsquo;ve got your day-timer, make a note for 30 days from today - it&amp;rsquo;s okay if that one goes &amp;quot;ding&amp;quot; to remind you! - and revisit this talk in 30 days. It will be up on the web, courtesy of Gabe, and ask: &amp;quot;What have I changed?&amp;quot; If I haven&amp;rsquo;t changed anything, then we still had a pleasant hour together. If you have changed things, then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a lot more time to spend with the ones you love. And that&amp;rsquo;s important. Time is all we have. And you may find one day you have less than you think. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/oTugjssqOT0&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/oTugjssqOT0&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Trends for fall: pumpkin, halloween etc</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-google-trends-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-google-trends-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/2008/09/22/viz.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/photos/uncategorized/2008/09/22/viz.png&#34; title=&#34;Viz&#34; alt=&#34;Viz&#34; class=&#34;image-full&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px; float: left;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the &amp;quot;How do you know that it&#39;s fall&amp;quot; issue, note this year&#39;s Google search trends for &amp;quot;pumpkin&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;halloween&amp;quot;, both trending upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you keep your calendar?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-how-do-you-keep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 22:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-21-how-do-you-keep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to ask this question every year at least, because the answers change all the time; it was the topic of this week&#39;s a2b3 meeting.&amp;nbsp; Here are some things people shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people were using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/calendar&#34;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; for shared calendaring - not just one calendar, but multiple calendars, and someone said they had 20 different calendars.&amp;nbsp; There was one part the need to keep personal and work calendars separate, one part the desire to subdivide work calendars into multiple slices to be shared on a per-project basis, and one part to synchronize home and work and family and kids and school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several of the people who used calendars to publish events for the general public talked about using an embedded Google Calendar in their blog as a quick and efficient way to share information and keep it up to date, like this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;400&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://www.google.com/calendar/embed?title=a2b3%20&amp;amp;showNav=0&amp;amp;showTabs=0&amp;amp;mode=AGENDA&amp;amp;height=400&amp;amp;wkst=1&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23FFFFFF&amp;amp;src=8d9lpkmgltprmtbkv8p0tr39co%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;color=%231B887A&amp;amp;ctz=America%2FNew_York&#34; style=&#34;border-width: 0pt;&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A possible downside to the plethora of Google calendars is that there are literally half a dozen different otherwise indistinguishable versions of e.g. the Michigan Football schedule online, none of which can be trusted to reliably get game times right (or at least I haven&#39;t found any way to predict which one will work the best).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the non-Google online calendars, &lt;a href=&#34;http://calendar.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;Yahoo Calendar&lt;/a&gt; got a vote as a family calendar, and someone was looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zimbra.com/&#34;&gt;Zimbra.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the work side of things, most people who were dealing with calendar systems mentioned Outlook at least once, not always with warmth and fuzziness.&amp;nbsp; One person had Lotus Notes running, an excellent corporate calendar but one that refuses to sync or share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those people doing project management had a bias towards Microsoft Excel as a way to keep track of shared expectations about details, and one Microsoft Project user was in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A relatively large number of people had positive things to say about synchronization of calendars to their mobile phone, more than I would have expected.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hsgconsultingllc.com/?p=86&#34;&gt;Helene Gidley did a nice roundup of mobile device calendar syncing&lt;/a&gt; which hits some of the high points; there&#39;s more than one way to do it, and some of them cost money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone noted that they use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plaxo.com&#34;&gt;Plaxo&lt;/a&gt; to sync everything, and that everything more or less just works, and that this was remarkable enough that everything worked to make it a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several people were using paper calendars as their primary daily calendar, either as a standalone calendar, a day planner style book, or a Moleskine as a GTD style capture device that got turned into calendar entries once a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of two people who used a personal wiki as a diary style calendar (I use Socialtext, the other person uses Mediawiki, both set up in private one-person-wiki mode).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The universal shared paper calendar was the fridge calendar - if anyone wants to build a high tech fridge, just do the calendar application for it.&amp;nbsp; This was the place where the family negotiated events and scheduling and changes and handoffs and other important timing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine advised living a life simple enough that you could keep track of all of it on a single piece of paper; not quite there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groundhog Day / Candlemas 2007 roundup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-groundhog-day-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 16:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-02-groundhog-day-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some good friends celebrate Groundhog Day, and we enjoyed their company today.  Some things I learned:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should have half your hay left on Groundhog Day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People start looking for last frost dates for the season on Groundhog Day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Europe it&amp;rsquo;s Candlemas Day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditional foods include crepes and pancakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bellinis are delicious, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do an all-Michigan version in season&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
More reading and links:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mamalisa.com/blog/?cat=419&#34;&gt;Groundhog Day category on Mama Lisa&amp;rsquo;s World Blog&lt;/a&gt; has crepe recipes and a song:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous, ma mèr’ vous invite
&lt;br /&gt;Quand on fait des crêp’s chez nous, ell’ vous invite tous
&lt;br /&gt;Un’ pour toi, un’ pour moi, un’ pour mon p’tit frèr’ François
&lt;br /&gt;Un’ pour toi, un’ pour moi, un’ pour tous les trois.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.groundhog.org/about/history.php&#34;&gt;groundhog.org - official site of Punx. PA Groundhog club&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
If Candlemas be fair and bright,
&lt;br /&gt;Come, Winter, have another flight;
&lt;br /&gt;If Candlemas brings clouds and rain,
&lt;br /&gt;Go Winter, and come not again.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://yourehistory.wordpress.com/2008/01/29/its-ground-hog-day/&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re History - Groundhog Day&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As the light grows longer
&lt;br /&gt;The cold grows stronger
&lt;br /&gt;If Candlemas be fair and bright
&lt;br /&gt;Winter will have another flight
&lt;br /&gt;If Candlemas be cloud and snow
&lt;br /&gt;Winter will be gone and not come again
&lt;br /&gt;A farmer should on Candlemas day
&lt;br /&gt;Have half his corn and half his hay
&lt;br /&gt;On Candlemas day if thorns hang a drop
&lt;br /&gt;You can be sure of a good pea crop
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newadvent.org/cathen/03245b.htm&#34;&gt;Catholic Encyclopedia: Candlemas&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
From Jerusalem the feast of the fortieth day spread over the entire Church and later on was kept on the 2nd of February, since within the last twenty-five years of the fourth century the Roman feast of Christ&amp;rsquo;s nativity (25 December) was introduced. In Antioch it is attested in 526 (Cedrenue); in the entire Eastern Empire it was introduced by the Emperor Justinian I (542) in thanksgiving for the cessation of the great pestilence which had depopulated the city of Constantinople. In the Greek Church it was called Hypapante tou Kyriou, the meeting (occursus) of the Lord and His mother with Simeon and Anna. The Armenians call it: &amp;ldquo;The Coming of the Son of God into the Temple&amp;rdquo; and still keep it on the 14th of February (Tondini di Quaracchi, Calendrier de la Nation Arménienne, 1906, 48); the Copts term it &amp;ldquo;presentation of the Lord in the Temple&amp;rdquo; (Nilles, Kal. man., II 571, 643).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jwz.livejournal.com/839662.html&#34;&gt;Jamie Zawinski on Bill Murray in Groundhog Day
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags start &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:right;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/clothing&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;clothing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/cold&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;cold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags end &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to keep your new year&#39;s resolution</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-03-how-to-keep-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 10:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-01-03-how-to-keep-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every year about this time, people make a bunch of promises to themselves, spurred on by blank pages in the shiny new calendar.  And every year, sometime in the next few weeks, they will be regretting all of those new commitments and will slide back to their old habits.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here&amp;rsquo;s some set of resolutions I have made for myself, and some way to keep them over time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
1.  Walk 10000 steps a day, seasonally adjusted.  I&amp;rsquo;m doing this with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.walkertracker.com&#34;&gt;Walker Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using long enough to get some sense for seasonal variation in my exercise (and my motivation to track exercise) based on the weather and the shorter days.  January is actually the easy month for this since the weather isn&amp;rsquo;t getting worse; the hard months are October and November.  Time commitment is 5-10 minutes every 2 or 3 days to upload the numbers; my pedometer has a 7 day memory so I can miss a day and still be in sync.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
2.  Remember people&amp;rsquo;s birthdays.  The current birthday-tracking tools are Google Calendar, Facebook, and the Mac OS Address Book; they all fail to notify me enough ahead of time to stick something in the mail.    Perhaps I should switch to my sister&amp;rsquo;s strategy of remembering birth months, which allows for making this a 12x/year task instead of a 365x/year task.  Time commitment is a couple of hours once or twice a month, plus eternal vigilance for keeping track of people&amp;rsquo;s birthdays.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
3.  Send a postcard.  This should be an attainable goal, but I&amp;rsquo;m currently just a tiny bit away from having all of the materials at hand to send a postcard to anyone I know at any time.  The current bottleneck is postage stamps - I have postcards a-plenty, and enough postal addresses in enough places to get by.  The Post Office has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.usps.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ProductDisplay?catalogId=10152&amp;amp;storeId=10001&amp;amp;categoryId=11833&amp;amp;productId=21414&amp;amp;langId=-1&#34;&gt;postcard stamps by mail&lt;/a&gt; subscription, which would send 100 postcard stamps per month for $26; that seems a little much, though it would force the issue.  Time commitment is about 15 minutes a card now, though it would probably be easy to get this down to 5 minutes if I got everything sorted out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
4.  Log my hours to Basecamp.  Basecamp, bless its blackened soul, lets you track every hour of the working day; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it particularly easy to report on what you&amp;rsquo;ve done so that you make sure it happens.  This Javascript bookmarket gives you in one click what it takes Basecamp 8 to do, shows you a report of hours logged to date for today.   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phpkitchen.com/index.php?/archives/766-Basecamp-Bookmarklet-Hours-Logged-Today.html&#34;&gt;Demain Turner&amp;rsquo;s Basecamp Bookmarklet: Hours Logged Today.&lt;/a&gt;  Time commitment is about 30 minutes a day in making sure that everything I do has a prescribed category.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
5.  Never eat lunch alone.  I have Thursday covered pretty well, but all of the other days are suspect.  As a family saying goes, &amp;ldquo;no meal unaccounted for&amp;rdquo;, and by sometimes not having a good lunch plan I don&amp;rsquo;t manage to eat as well as I should.   Some piece of this is technology (e.g. trying Noonhat to automate this), some of it is day-before planning (make sure to bring in a lunch to eat with coworkers), some of it is scheduling two weeks out so that you have a nice queue and some is last minute Twittering.    This should be doable in about an hour of planning a week.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These are less &amp;ldquo;new years resolutions&amp;rdquo; and more &amp;ldquo;ongoing patterns to try to maintain&amp;rdquo;.  The typical pattern follows this simple rule:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
That which is measured, improves.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
which is true so long as the tool you are using to measure does not impose its own burden of measurement.   The best measurement tools generally watch you passively as you go about your ordinary events and log quietly and unobtrusively; the worst ones attach a cognitive overhead of perpetual self-surveillance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags start &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:right;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/calendar&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/newyears&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;newyears&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/resolution&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;resolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags end &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>