<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/zemanta/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/zemanta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>make tidy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been converting over old postings on this blog from Typepad.
The data export and import was imperfect, and this meant that I&amp;rsquo;ve
been poring over the data to figure out what keeps and what goes
and what-not. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to review old words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the artifacts of the old hosting platform was a helpful at
times system called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zemanta.com&#34;&gt;Zemanta&lt;/a&gt;. Zemanta would
figure out what you were writing about and give you helpful suggestions
for related links, both to things that you had written as well as
to things other people had written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided as part of the transformation of the old weblog into
the new one to unlink those &amp;ldquo;related links&amp;rdquo;, in the hope that
eventually Hugo&amp;rsquo;s own system will create some either algorithmically
derived relations or at least an easier way to do that by hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m looking closely at what Zemanta did so I can
undo it. The first set of artifacts is a &amp;ldquo;fieldset&amp;rdquo; with its links,
and that&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to search and destroy. Occasionally but not
always I find my links decorated with a &lt;code&gt;class=&amp;quot;zem_slink&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; marker
that&amp;rsquo;s a little harder to find. Most insidious so far was exactly
one time where Zemanta (or Typepad) rewrote or wrote an Amazon link
to include an affiliate link points to Zemanta, and not to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewriting 1500+ pages is going to take a while. The biggest question
is unpublishing some of them, since time has passed and I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to republish everything. There&amp;rsquo;s conversion from HTML to Markdown
to remove the uglies, spelling errors to catch, next
categories and taxonomies to fill, layout to work on, etc. At
some point I need to sort out image management. But first I&amp;rsquo;m going
to understand the consequences of previous convenience decisions
I made to use Zemanta and to undo that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>