<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Media Upper Peninsula on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/social-media-upper-peninsula/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Media Upper Peninsula on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 20:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/social-media-upper-peninsula/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My somewhat internet-free vacation to the Upper Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-08-23-my-somewhat-internet-free-vacation-to-the-upper-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-08-23-my-somewhat-internet-free-vacation-to-the-upper-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It wasn&#39;t completely internet-free, because there was wifi at my Mom&#39;s place and wifi at McDonald&#39;s for the occasional stops and wifi at the very nice Dead River Cafe in Marquette. But for the most part the net was kept at bay, since T-Mobile data service ended at Pinconning and I was with a phone that didn&#39;t have internet-everywhere coverage for the better part of a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of places I would have liked to have captured in the moment while I was there with a camera and with Twitter to share them. For example, there&#39;s the cutest little gazebo-like structure on the Iron Ore Heritage Trail underneath the LS&amp;amp;I railroad trestle. It&#39;s cute until you realize that it&#39;s there to deflect the ore pellets off the trail and off of the heads of passing bicyclists as they go under an active set of tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also missed there being a local wiki to look things up in (and to add my own commentary to) for the Upper Peninsula, along the lines of Ann Arbor&#39;s Arborwiki. There&#39;s a lot of history in the area that&#39;s still relatively unwritten, and it would have been fantastic to have a place to store bits of commentary and observations without necessarily broadcasting a stream of social media to my long-suffering friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m back, not having missed Facebook much at all, and not having been tethered to a Twitter update stream, and only 100 messages behind in my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>