<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Illinois on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/chicago-illinois/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicago Illinois on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/chicago-illinois/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago aviation donut</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-chicago-aviation-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 10:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-chicago-aviation-donut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fire at the Chicago air traffic control center (ZAU) forced rerouting of air traffic near O&#39;Hare and Midway airports. This picture, credit to Paul Saffo via Facebook, shows the impact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d36e0970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d36e0970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 453px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Ohare-donut&#34; title=&#34;Ohare-donut&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d36e0970d-500wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This map is from the FAA - compare it for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d6ab4970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d6ab4970d img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Zau_tier&#34; title=&#34;Zau_tier&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb078d6ab4970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago postcards at the Chicago Architecture Foundation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some very nice postcards indeed from their postcard rack, at about $1 a piece. I&#39;m going to study them closely and them mail them off!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine
under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old
olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction
site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building
that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the day is a death on State Street. A young man was
climbing over the skylights at the Nickels Arcade and fell to his
death when the skylight glass gave way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 1915, the SS Eastland was packed with employees from
the Western Electric Hawthorne Works when it rolled over in
the Chicago River. 844 passengers and crew lost their lives, making
the Eastland disaster the worst shipwreck on the Great Lakes.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastlanddisaster.org/&#34;&gt;Eastland Disaster Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;
for extensive notes on and photos of the scene and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2civictech/&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt;
is coming up on Monday, July 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literatibookstore.com/&#34;&gt;Literati Bookstore&lt;/a&gt; is open
again after a water leak caused them to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote a tiny R script that generates maps. The challenge
today is to find a portable environment so that I can deploy this script
on shared infrastructure. The project took 30 minutes of MacBook Air processor
time running full blast parallel, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t care about wall clock time
to complete the effort I do care about building something that I can hand
off to someone else to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocker-org/ropensci&#34;&gt;ropensci&lt;/a&gt; Docker
package from the Rocker project is the answer, or most of the answer, for this.
Rocker has built R images where lots of useful packages have been installed,
including systems where the install directions are a little bit complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all complicated software environments the biggest challenge is dealing
with dependencies. If you want to use the latest and greatest fast algorithms,
you have to be prepared to spin up on what the cool kids are doing in the
rest of their environment. If somehow you can jump to the edge of the development
in the algorithm world without being tripped up by the hairy dependency graph
that got you there, it can be a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So; install Docker on the Mac with &amp;lsquo;boot2docker&amp;rsquo;; then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;docker pull rocker/ropensci
docker run -it rocker/ropensci R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and poof, you have an environment current to this month&amp;rsquo;s desktop of leading
R developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit to Chicago via Amtrak, 1988 - Super 8 video</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please enjoy this video from Youtube user &#34;trainluvr&#34; in glorious Super 8 showing the trip from Detroit to Chicago on Amtrak. The whole journey takes just 8 minutes, 16 seconds in time lapse. For a detailed log of every location in the trip, see this Trainsim thread, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trainsim.com/vbts/showthread.php?302402-Amtrak-Cab-Ride-Timelapse-from-1988-between-Detroit-and-Chicago&#34;&gt;Amtrak Cab Ride Timelapse&lt;/a&gt;.  Ypsilanti is at 0:58, Ann Arbor is at 1:06, Battle Creek at 2:49, Niles at 5:40 and Chicago at 7:34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/mAikJc67tO4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m heading to Chicago. I&#39;ll be near the Loop. Where should I buy postcards?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 10:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagopostcardmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Chicago Postcard Museum&lt;/a&gt; which is all online; pity that it&#39;s not in a real place or I&#39;d visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where would you go in the Loop to get good and interesting cards? I&#39;m not interested in spending lots of money per card, but I would like to have a nice variety to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0766b73970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0766b73970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Greetings_from_Chicago_04_F&#34; title=&#34;Greetings_from_Chicago_04_F&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0766b73970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from my talk on Arborwiki and Localwiki at eChicago, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 00:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the good fortune to talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.localwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Localwiki&lt;/a&gt; at eChicago in April 2013. Here are the notes that I took in preparation for the talk; the actual text of the talk varied from this, since I was speaking impromptu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Arborwiki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who: &lt;/strong&gt;More than a dozen core contributors over the lifespan of the project, plus many more who have made small edits to pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt;: Greater Ann Arbor - including Washtenaw County and the farmers who come to the Farmers Market from surrounding counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt;: Started in September 2005 as a class project at Community High School, then moved to servers at the Ann Arbor District Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: About 10,000 pages, including the most popular &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Birthday_Deals&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Birthday Deals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Volunteer_Opportunities&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Volunteer Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;, and perennial favorite &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Donuts&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Donuts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/paczki&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Paczki&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt;: To build community information about the Ann Arbor area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guiding principles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locality, not notability, is the main criterion for relevance; if it&amp;#39;s here, then it&amp;#39;s relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a local point of view, not a neutral point of view; original text and personal views welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of external links to reference sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State of the project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arborwiki is a mature system - it has over 10,000 pages in it, and thus there&amp;#39;s likely to be something about most things that people might look for that are relevant to the Ann Arbor area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One advantage to maturity is that a lot of people know about the project through a popular &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Birthday_Deals&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Birthday Deals&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; page, and we don&amp;#39;t have to explain in the abstract what we&amp;#39;re working on - that individual page gets about two hundred visits per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second advantage is that we&amp;#39;ve gotten tremendous amounts of cooperation from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://aadl.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt; system, including help with research, links, technical support, and free hosting for this community project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges of a mature system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s no &amp;quot;new wiki&amp;quot; smell, and we can&amp;#39;t count on having a barn-raising strategy for people who want to document their community for the first time. Any enthusiasm has to be in the context of a lot of things that already exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of regular contributors is relatively small compared to the number of pages in the system. It would take 30+ page edits per day of existing pages just to get enough eyes on the older parts of Arborwiki just to keep each page refreshed to be less than a year since its latest edit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many short, uninformative pages with just a single bare link and no photo, no map, no template etc. One editor - and that would be me - went through a long period of emphasizing quantity over quality. Now that the quantity is there, it&amp;#39;s time to focus on quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site needs more photos and better support from photographers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ypsiwiki problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a separate &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Ypsiwiki&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ypsiwiki&lt;/a&gt; which covered Ypsilanti. It was decided to merge those pages in because there was too much project overlap and not quite enough of a critical mass to keep the two systems separate. The Arborwiki name was retained, and as a result, there&amp;#39;s resistance overall from contributors from Ypsilanti to contribute to a project that&amp;#39;s not theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to do next&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve the most popular pages on the site. Use Google Analytics to identify the pages that get the most traffic, and go through them page by page to ensure that they are up to date, correct, accurate, and informative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create new pages based on a &amp;quot;Page not found&amp;quot; report from Google Analytics, noting where people click on terms that get them to a blank or empty page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit a random page in the site and make it better. Add a map, a photograph, a category, or a paragraph of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn the seasonal rhythms of the site. For example, the Paczki page gets traffic for about a week a year, but the Donuts page gets steady traffic year round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow public meetings like the meetings of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Ann_Arbor_City_Council&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor City Council&lt;/a&gt;, and tweet out links to projects or issues that are relevant agenda items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish someone a happy birthday by sending them a link to the Birthday Deals page on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reward new contributors by recognizing them in public through Facebook or Twitter links to their new contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognize that a Localwiki project has a natural size, and identify where you are in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay attention to traffic patterns - popular pages, referral sites, keywords used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want traffic, track the news, and befriend local media so that they are aware of the resource.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People I saw or met in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a list, so I can&#39;t forget who I saw on a very good trip to Chicago last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.megabus.com&#34;&gt;Megabus&lt;/a&gt;. Cheap and cheerful transportation, very convenient to where I was going, good drivers both ways. The return trip bus was kind of old (e.g. the power outlets didn&#39;t work) but the driver was fantastic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hichicago.org/&#34;&gt;HI-Chicago&lt;/a&gt; a hostel in the loop. Cheap and cheerful lodging, very convenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eric Sinclair and Anne Zender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food. Anne . emv. (@ The Berghoff Restaurant - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BerghoffChicago&#34;&gt;@berghoffchicago&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago, IL) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/HgdyxWVByG&#34;&gt;https://t.co/HgdyxWVByG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Eric Sinclair (@esinclai) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/esinclai/status/519260707205173249&#34;&gt;October 6, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubois.com/about-press-contact/&#34;&gt;Jeff Ubois&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jefflunt.com/&#34;&gt;Jeff Lunt&lt;/a&gt;, talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://chimesh.net/&#34;&gt;ChicagoMeshNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CivicWhitaker&#34;&gt;Christopher Whitaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/derekeder&#34;&gt;Derek Eder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://opengovhacknight.org/&#34;&gt;Open Gov Hack Night&lt;/a&gt; at 1871&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ri/Code_Island&#34;&gt;Code Island&lt;/a&gt; for Rhode Island&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chi.streetsblog.org/&#34;&gt;Streetsblog Chicago&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevevance.net/&#34;&gt;Steven Vance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JoeGermuska&#34;&gt;Joe Germuska&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.org/chicago/Google_Chicago&#34;&gt;Google Chicago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Smith talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagotribune.com/bluesky/originals/chi-paul-smith-google-affordable-care-act-bsi-20141009-story.html&#34;&gt;the healthcare.gov rescue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/trimtab2&#34;&gt;John Christensen&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cplmakerlab.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Chicago Public Library Maker Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some bits of my trip ended up as pages on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.org/chicago&#34;&gt;Chicago Localwiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chicago Sun-Times gives up on newspaper comments, for now</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-chicago-sun-times-gives-up-on-newspaper-comments-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-chicago-sun-times-gives-up-on-newspaper-comments-for-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://voices.suntimes.com/news/sick-of-web-comments-us-too-heres-what-were-doing-about-it/&#34;&gt;Chicago Sun-Times&lt;/a&gt; has given up on publishing reader comments on its stories, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Starting this weekend, the Chicago Sun-Times and the other titles in the Sun-Times Media group will temporarily cease to run comments with our articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? If you&#39;ve read newspaper comments, you&#39;ll know why already: they are awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The world of Internet commenting offers a marvelous opportunity for discussion and the exchange of ideas. But as anyone who has ever ventured into a comment thread can attest, these forums too often turn into a morass of negativity, racism, hate speech and general trollish behaviors that detract from the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes time, effort, energy, and love to engage with readers enough to make the stream of their comments to be anywhere near as worthwhile to read as the professionally produced stories that sit at the top of the page. Too often the news organization treats comments as an afterthought, or if they do think about it they are woefully unprepared to handle the burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It hasn&#39;t always been the case, of course. Once upon a time (he says, shaking his cane) the letter to the editor was carefully edited, double checked for identity, and only run with some consideration. For the most part, newspapers have given up on their opportunity to corral the best of public discussion into their own pages, leaving it instead for the idiots on parade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More about the Sun-Times decision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fark.com/comments/8218801/Chicago-Sun-Times-will-not-let-readers-comment-on-articles-because-according-to-managing-editor-internet-comments-are-a-morass-of-negativity-racism-hate-speech-Good-thing-hes-never-visited-Fark-Politics-tab&#34;&gt;Fark&lt;/a&gt; says &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As frank as FARK comments can be, the worst seen here excel far beyond the idiocy seen on newspapers. At least Farkers have brains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.poynter.org/latest-news/mediawire/247525/sun-times-kills-comments-until-it-can-fix-morass-of-negativity-racism-and-hate-speech/&#34;&gt;Poynter&lt;/a&gt; reviews other news organizations that gave up on comments, including Popular Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoist.com/2014/04/12/the_sun-times_temporarily_shuts_dow.php&#34;&gt;Chicagoist&lt;/a&gt; gives sage advice: &#34;A sage piece of Internet advice is often a simple one: don&#39;t read the comments.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagomag.com/city-life/April-2014/Turning-Internet-Comments-into-Dialogue-Isnt-Easy-or-Cheap/&#34;&gt;Chicago Magazine&lt;/a&gt; understands the cost of turning reader contributions into something useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Turning readers’ invective into smart dialogue is not a new challenge—but now, it’s a bigger problem than ever. Solving it takes a lot of manpower, and some well-designed software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at 1871 in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-at-1871-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 14:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-at-1871-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1871 is an enormous coworking and business incubator space on the 12th floor of the Merchandise Mart in Chicago. I&#39;m spending the afternoon of October 7, 2014 there, as a guest of Christopher Whitaker from Code for America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>