<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Illinois on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/chicago-illinois/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicago Illinois on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/chicago-illinois/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.
 The news of the day is a death on State Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People I saw or met in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Just a list, so I can&#39;t forget who I saw on a very good trip to Chicago last week.
 Megabus. Cheap and cheerful transportation, very convenient to where I was going, good drivers both ways. The return trip bus was kind of old (e.g. the power outlets didn&#39;t work) but the driver was fantastic. HI-Chicago a hostel in the loop. Cheap and cheerful lodging, very convenient. Eric Sinclair and Anne Zender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at 1871 in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-at-1871-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 14:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-at-1871-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>1871 is an enormous coworking and business incubator space on the 12th floor of the Merchandise Mart in Chicago. I&#39;m spending the afternoon of October 7, 2014 there, as a guest of Christopher Whitaker from Code for America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago postcards at the Chicago Architecture Foundation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Some very nice postcards indeed from their postcard rack, at about $1 a piece. I&#39;m going to study them closely and them mail them off!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m heading to Chicago. I&#39;ll be near the Loop. Where should I buy postcards?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 10:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</guid>
      <description>I found the Chicago Postcard Museum which is all online; pity that it&#39;s not in a real place or I&#39;d visit.
Where would you go in the Loop to get good and interesting cards? I&#39;m not interested in spending lots of money per card, but I would like to have a nice variety to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago aviation donut</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-chicago-aviation-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 10:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-chicago-aviation-donut/</guid>
      <description>A fire at the Chicago air traffic control center (ZAU) forced rerouting of air traffic near O&#39;Hare and Midway airports. This picture, credit to Paul Saffo via Facebook, shows the impact. 
This map is from the FAA - compare it for scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chicago Sun-Times gives up on newspaper comments, for now</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-chicago-sun-times-gives-up-on-newspaper-comments-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-13-the-chicago-sun-times-gives-up-on-newspaper-comments-for-now/</guid>
      <description>The Chicago Sun-Times has given up on publishing reader comments on its stories, at least for now.
 Starting this weekend, the Chicago Sun-Times and the other titles in the Sun-Times Media group will temporarily cease to run comments with our articles.
 Why? If you&#39;ve read newspaper comments, you&#39;ll know why already: they are awful.
 The world of Internet commenting offers a marvelous opportunity for discussion and the exchange of ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from my talk on Arborwiki and Localwiki at eChicago, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 00:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</guid>
      <description>I had the good fortune to talk about Arborwiki and Localwiki at eChicago in April 2013. Here are the notes that I took in preparation for the talk; the actual text of the talk varied from this, since I was speaking impromptu.
About Arborwiki
Who: More than a dozen core contributors over the lifespan of the project, plus many more who have made small edits to pages.
Where: Greater Ann Arbor - including Washtenaw County and the farmers who come to the Farmers Market from surrounding counties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit to Chicago via Amtrak, 1988 - Super 8 video</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-05-detroit-to-chicago-via-amtrak-1988-super-8-video/</guid>
      <description>Please enjoy this video from Youtube user &#34;trainluvr&#34; in glorious Super 8 showing the trip from Detroit to Chicago on Amtrak. The whole journey takes just 8 minutes, 16 seconds in time lapse. For a detailed log of every location in the trip, see this Trainsim thread, Amtrak Cab Ride Timelapse. Ypsilanti is at 0:58, Ann Arbor is at 1:06, Battle Creek at 2:49, Niles at 5:40 and Chicago at 7:34.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>