<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 14:47:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools respond to social media threat</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-25-ann-arbor-public-schools-social-media-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 14:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-25-ann-arbor-public-schools-social-media-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, Michigan, January 25 2016: The Ann Arbor Public Schools
issued this news release and letter to parents, signed by Superintendent
Jeanice Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday, January 25, 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear AAPS Parents,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you may have already heard, there have been threats made on social media to multiple school districts across the metro area, extending to Florida, and rumored to have occurred as far as California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be assured that in the Ann Arbor Public Schools, we take any and all threats very seriously and consistently follow established emergency procedures in cooperation with Ann Arbor Police Department and other law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received information in the early morning hours that Ann Arbor was included in this social media situation.  Police were notified immediately and we have been actively working with the AAPD since first learning of this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our principals were advised early this morning of this situation, and we continue to work with law enforcement officials as part of our safety protocol. We will continue to monitor this situation very closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the use of social media for posting threats against schools seems to be increasing, I would like to ask all parents to talk to their children about using social media and instruct them that if they see anything on social media that is a concern, to immediately report it to an adult, such as a parent, principal or teacher.  If they re-post or pass on the threat, they can also be held responsible for issuing a threat and can receive disciplinary action as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be assured that we take every threat seriously as safety for our students and staff is our first priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeanice K. Swift, Ph.D.
Superintendent of Schools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###
&lt;/hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M7.1 earthquake felt in Anchorage, Alaska</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-24-alaska-earthquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 05:42:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-24-alaska-earthquake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, 6:35 a.m. Eastern, 2:35 Anchorage time:
Local news coverage of the earthquake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adn.com/article/20160124/strong-earthquake-felt-throughout-southcentral-alaska&#34;&gt;Strong earthquake felt throughout Southcentral Alaska&lt;/a&gt;, Alaska Dispatch News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AKearthquake&#34;&gt;Alaska Earthquake Center&lt;/a&gt; is @AKearthquake on Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MLandP&#34;&gt;Municipal Light and Power&lt;/a&gt; @MLandP is an area electric utility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ktuu.com/news/news/strong-earthquake-with-initial-magnitude-of-about-71-hits-south-alaska/37610068&#34;&gt;KTUU Channel 2&lt;/a&gt; reports &amp;ldquo;Strong earthquake with initial magnitude of about 7.1 hits near Pedro Bay&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, 6:30 a.m Eastern. A note on time zones: Anchorage is GMT-9,
or 4 hours behind Ann Arbor time. The current time there is 2:30 a.m.,
and the quake hit at about 1:30 a.m. local time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, 6:20 a.m. Eastern:
The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chugachelectric.com/outage/outage_map.html&#34;&gt;Chugach Electric power outage map&lt;/a&gt; shows 3858 subscribers without power out of 28112 served
mostly to the south of Anchorage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/matanuska.electric/posts/954599307926593&#34;&gt;Matanuska Electric Association&lt;/a&gt; is reporting via Facebook that about 4000 customers are without power due to the quake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earthquake at 1:30 am caused several outages including our entire Douglass substation in Willow and several other feeder outages, especially impacting the Palmer area. Crews have been called in from home to assess the situation and restore power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, 6:01 a.m. Eastern: The quake is now reported
as a M7.1 - 83km E of Old Iliamna, Alaska, according to the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/us10004gqp#general_summary&#34;&gt;USGS report&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/us10004gqp#impact_dyfi&#34;&gt;did you feel it report&lt;/a&gt; from USGS notes that the quake
was felt most strongly in Anchorage, Homer, and Kenai AK,
and could also be felt by some as far away as Fairbanks AK
and Whitehorse, Yukon, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor, MI, Sunday, January 24, 2016, 5:43 a.m. Eastern: A magnitude 6.4 earthquake
was felt in Anchorage, Alaska. The quake&amp;rsquo;s epicenter was located
162mi SW of the city, according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/eventpage/at00o1gd6r#general_summary&#34;&gt;USGS report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My high school classmate Mary Beth Hammerstrom alerted me to the
quake &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/marybeth.hammerstrom/posts/10208839138682711&#34;&gt;on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Holy hell that was a big one!!!!!!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NWS PACIFIC TSUNAMI WARNING CENTER &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tsunami.gov/product.php?id=TIBPAC.20160124.1044.001&#34;&gt;reports in a bulletin of 1043 UTC&lt;/a&gt; that
&amp;ldquo;BASED ON ALL AVAILABLE DATA&amp;hellip; THERE IS NO TSUNAMI THREAT
BECAUSE THE EARTHQUAKE IS LOCATED TOO DEEP INSIDE THE EARTH.&amp;rdquo;
The quake was reported by USGS to have been at a depth of
65 miles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing things down</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-writing-things-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-writing-things-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a series of paper notebooks that I keep meeting notes in. I&amp;rsquo;ve settled
on the Roaring Spring 100pp 5 to 1&amp;rdquo; quad ruled book, which I can get for $2.68
at the Barnes and Noble in the U of Michigan Union. The book goes with me
everywhere, and I treat it like a classic lab notebook - date and time stamp
all the pages, write things down when you possibly can, never tear a page out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that writing things down makes a huge difference in how I remember them.
The a2b3 lunch non-summary that I posted earlier today was written in a first
draft in the notebook. The practice is informed a lot by writing things into
Twitter - you don&amp;rsquo;t have much space so you have to be crisp and concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Twitter, I also get to do little sketches and drawings in the notebooks.
I miss that ability to do freehand drawings in a quad ruled environment where
it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make a shape that makes sense. My hand-drawing skills are much
better than my computer drawing skills, and that means that some part of things
I want to capture have to be written down with ink on paper first (and maybe
later or maybe never digitized).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 3d week of January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-22-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for coming to lunch. We had 16 people, and complete introductions in 23 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of the question was &amp;ldquo;repair&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lindadianefeldt.com/&#34;&gt;Linda Diane Feldt&lt;/a&gt; is repairing her side door, original equipment on a 90 y/o house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathryn-sanderson-13134b13&#34;&gt;Kathryn Sanderson&lt;/a&gt; darns socks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DanF1739&#34;&gt;Dan Friedus&lt;/a&gt; wants to know if you want to repair his 1980s Bolens garden tractors. (Make an offer.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medicine.umich.edu/dept/biochem/ruthann-nichols-phd&#34;&gt;Ruthann Nichols&lt;/a&gt; teaches &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lsa.umich.edu/UMICH/students/Home/Academics%20and%20Requirements/CourseSelection%26Scheduling/CourseGuide%28PostersandDocuments%29/Winter2014/1970CHEM120001.pdf&#34;&gt;Science and Wine&lt;/a&gt; as a freshman seminar at the U.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnbarrie.com/&#34;&gt;John Barrie&lt;/a&gt; recommends Fix It Friday at Maker Works, and is repairing an Advent 300 stereo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josephine (sp?) is repairing a sense of community and interviewing a new boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/missingnewmexico&#34;&gt;Lou Leone&lt;/a&gt; likes not having to repair things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soe.umich.edu/people/profile/linda_rayle/&#34;&gt;Linda Rayle&lt;/a&gt; is decluttering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rmrayle&#34;&gt;Roger Rayle&lt;/a&gt; says &amp;ldquo;ideas get repaired&amp;rdquo; by his efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/lsiden&#34;&gt;Larry Siden&lt;/a&gt; is fixing code and got a rattling guitar amp repaired in Keego Harbor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hsgidley&#34;&gt;Helene Gidley&lt;/a&gt; is also darning socks and saved some wall paper for years for a successful repair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panoramio.com/photo/91151775&#34;&gt;Keith Alexander&lt;/a&gt; is repairing blank surfaces by painting murals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KathyGriswold&#34;&gt;Kathy Griswold&lt;/a&gt; repaired some household lighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kaipetainen&#34;&gt;Kai Petainen&lt;/a&gt; is repairing computer models for picking stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Athan is a forensic engineer and does failure analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed Weiss is looking for help to repair help files for a music synth program written in Japanese for Windows 98.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed Vielmetti has successfully repaired two shortwave radios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kai Petainen for his contribution and new membership to the Meetup group.
The nominal dues are $20/yr which covers the costs of hosting on Meetup.
Dues are completely voluntary and we always welcome everyone who comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events coming up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;22&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt; Ann Arbor Farmers Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arrl.org/hamfests/hazel-park-w8hp-50th-annual-swap&#34;&gt;Hazel Park Hamfest&lt;/a&gt; 8a-noon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt; &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor Cocktail Coven&amp;rdquo;, talk to Lou Leone for details, Facebook group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt; a2civictech w/s/g Kathy Grisworld on SeeClickFix and civic engagement, at AADL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;26&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;27&lt;/sub&gt; Agile Groupies w/s/g Helene Gidley at Pillar, &amp;ldquo;Lean Coffee&amp;rdquo; format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;27&lt;/sub&gt; Zoning Board of Appeals; no agenda yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; a2b3 lunch at Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; IOT Detroit in Allen Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fri-Sun &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt;-&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;31&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mpowered.umich.edu/makeathon&#34;&gt;Makeathon&lt;/a&gt; at UM Stamps School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some future Friday: Fixit Friday at Maker Works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;end of June: Michigan Energy Fair w/s/g John Barrie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events in the past&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt; Ann Arbor City Council. What do we want? DRAFT MEETING MINUTES. When do we want them? EIGHT BUSINESS DAYS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt; a2newtech; Roger Rayle has video, I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I take notes in my notebook, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long to write this up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some highlights of MLK Day 2016 on the U of Michigan campus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-18-mlk-day-on-umich-campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-18-mlk-day-on-umich-campus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few notes from MLK Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A morning trip to Roos Roast, enjoying a cup of Portland in the 90s coffee
and a hard boiled egg from Farmer John&amp;rsquo;s Our Family Farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Michigan Men&amp;rsquo;s Glee Club, singing at the annual
MLK Day symposium at the U of M, monitored via a remote video feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bus trip to the UM Computer and Video Game Archive, in the basement
of the Duderstadt Center, for some quality time with my 10 yo and a
chance to play Centipede and Driver San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A walk across the N Campus Diag (under construction) to the W8UM shack
in the EECS building, where I talked to Steve K8QKY who was working
a station that was on a DXpedition to the S Sandwich Islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus trip was fine business as well - on the way there I talked to
W8TAM and the return trip was a QSO with KB6NU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QSO on redditnet via Geekshed IRC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-17-qso-on-redditnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-17-qso-on-redditnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The #redditnet channel on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekshed.net/&#34;&gt;Geekshed IRC network&lt;/a&gt;
is full of amateur radio operators from the /r/amateurradio network on Reddit.
People seem to be friendly and knowledgable and more likely than not
to be actually doing digital modes on their radio rather than talking
about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The channel practice is tolerant of people treating it as thought
it were a CW or RTTY frequency, complete with contest style behavior
and reception reports (you are always 59 on #redditnet). I haven&amp;rsquo;t
ever done contesting myself for lack of appropriate gear, but I&amp;rsquo;m
starting to see the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRC was formally defined by RFC 1459 in 1993, but it dates from 1988
and was inspired by the earlier BITNET Relay network of 1985. Unlike
the Unix based Usenet network, which focused on email-sized messages,
the IRC network is fundamentally about short messages and also about
considerable autonomy among separate non-federated servers. It&amp;rsquo;s because
of this that IRC has been relatively resistant to the spam that overran
Usenet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Thom &lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/W8TAM-1&#34;&gt;W8TAM&lt;/a&gt; for alerting me to this net,
and Dan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/&#34;&gt;KB6NU&lt;/a&gt; has a nice writeup
of this few other social media nets for hams on his article
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/social-media-meets-ham-radio/&#34;&gt;Social Media meets ham radio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letterpress QSL cards</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-letterpress-qsl-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 21:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-letterpress-qsl-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qsl.net/wd4nka/form.html&#34;&gt;WD4NKA&lt;/a&gt; is a ham radio operator and a letterpress printer.
Those worlds intersect in the form of QSL cards printed on a
letterpress. His weblog All Things Wireless and Letterpress
has a nice post on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://q5letterpress.blogspot.com/2013/11/qsl-cards.html&#34;&gt;QSL cards&lt;/a&gt;
with examples of the letterpress craft in the form of the
postcards that hams would send each other in the 1920s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area APRS network status, January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APRS is the &amp;ldquo;Automatic Position Reporting Service&amp;rdquo;, a
system for sharing information about the position of
participating amateur radio stations. Clients transmit
position reports on 144.39 Mhz; digipeaters repeat
these reports to other monitoring stations; and various
IGate sites monitor transmissions and send their findings
to &lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi&#34;&gt;aprs.fi&lt;/a&gt; which collects worldwide data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent memory there has been an APRS digipeater in
Chelsea, Michigan with wide area coverage, good enough
to pick up travellers on I-94 west of Ann Arbor.
The Chelsea digirepeater is currently off the air,
which leaves a coverage gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one station within the city of Ann Arbor.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/KD8TDF&#34;&gt;KD8TDF&lt;/a&gt; is in southeast
Ann Arbor (EN82dg). Its coverage is enough to pick up
part of I-94 right adjacent to town. A second station,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/AB3DC-1&#34;&gt;AB3DC-1&lt;/a&gt; is the
Ann Arbor/Ypsi Rx-iGate, w8pgw.org, right near St.
Joe&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (EN82eg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussion at last night&amp;rsquo;s ARROW meeting included a
desire to experiment on 2 meters with digital modes.
Dave New &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qrz.com/DB/N8SBE&#34;&gt;N8SBE&lt;/a&gt; talked
about software defined radio and GNU Radio, and demonstrated
monitoring car key-fobs on UHF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APRS is a very old and useful digital mode, and I
am hopeful that local network conditions will improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2016 Ann Arbor Building Board of Appeals lacks a quorum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-building-board-of-appeals-lacks-quorum-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-building-board-of-appeals-lacks-quorum-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor Building Board of Appeals will not meet today, January
13, 2016, for lack of a quorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to know the following to help understand more about this group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is on the board, and how long have they been on it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have there been any recent changes to board membership?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is eligible to be appointed to the board, and what does that process entail?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to decisions that the board needs to make if a quorum cannot be met?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the status of the search for a full-time building official?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When does the board next anticipate meeting with a quorum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who has been nominated to serve on this board?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why did the board not make quorum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com/MeetingDetail.aspx?ID=452565&amp;amp;GUID=F55A2A53-26AB-404B-9A59-8A9FCD92EE39&amp;amp;Options=info&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;agenda for the meeting&lt;/a&gt; has been
posted, which gives you an idea of what is not being done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 325 W Liberty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 215 N Maple&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 121 W Kingsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Show Cause Hearing for 2001 Commerce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Show Cause Hearing for 111 S Main St&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last of these, 111 S Main St, is a building on the city&amp;rsquo;s
Dangerous Buildings list right on Main Street. The building
has a tree growing out of the roof, spongy floors due to water
infiltration, and mold everywhere according to the building
inspector&amp;rsquo;s report. The unavailability of the Building Board
means that the owner of 111 S Main doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to face a
public hearing for another month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave New N8SBE to speak at ARROW on Software Defined Radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dave New N8SBE will be speaking at the January 2016 meeting of
the ARROW radio club on the topic of Software Defined Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will present an introduction to GNU Radio and the GNU Radio
Companion visual programming environment, and the HackRF One Software
Defined Transceiver from Great Scott Gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo will include a disucssion of receiver and transmitter flow
graphs, as well as resources to learn more about
digital signal processing using the HackRF One and GNU Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARROW meets Wednesday, January 13, 2016, from 7:00 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. at
Washtenaw Community College, room BE-172 or nearby room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details contact ARROW at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w8pgw.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.w8pgw.org/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Michigan University spokesman responds to Morning Sun editorial regarding WCMU-TV spectrum auction</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 17:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 8, 2016, 5:30 pm (Ann Arbor time): Central Michigan University
spokesman Steve Smith answered questions today by telephone regarding
a Morning Sun editorial, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themorningsun.com/opinion/20160108/editorial-status-quo-cmu-mum-on-talk-of-shutting-tv-station&#34;&gt;Status quo: CMU mum on talk of shutting TV station&lt;/a&gt;, published in this Digital First Media newspaper
from Mt. Pleasant, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the lede, the newspaper writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Central Michigan University considers whether or not to shut
down its Public Broadcasting television network, the silence is
deafening.  CMU trustees almost a month ago voted to consider
shutting WCMU-TV and its three sister stations in exchange for up
to $726 million from the Federal Communications Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith poined out that the University had only approved to &amp;ldquo;apply
for eligibility&amp;rdquo;, which is not binding on CMU to proceed, and that
all options were open. In addition, he noted a Federal anti-collusion
rule that restricts the rights of potential auction participants
to speak freely about their intent leading up to the auction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Michigan University invites public comment on its decisions
to sell part or all of its broadcast spectrum back to the FCC, in an
auction that is scheduled to begin on March 29, 2016. Address your
comments in email to trustees@cmich.edu or by postal mail to
106 Warriner Hall, Central Michigan University, Mt. Pleasant, MI 48859.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmich.edu/bot/Pages/default.aspx&#34;&gt;The next public meeting of the Trustees is on February 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;,
and with prior arrangement there is time for the public to provide
comment on agenda items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for the Federal Communications Commission, which
manages this auction, was not available for comment at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference see the following FCC documents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://transition.fcc.gov/Daily_Releases/Daily_Business/2015/db0806/DOC-334756A1.pdf&#34;&gt;FCC ESTABLISHES BIDDING PROCEDURES FOR
2016 INCENTIVE AUCTION
Auction Scheduled to Begin March 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;, August 6, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.fcc.gov/edocs_public/attachmatch/DA-15-1129A1.pdf&#34;&gt;GUIDANCE REGARDING THE PROHIBITION OF CERTAIN COMMUNICATIONS DURING
THE INCENTIVE AUCTION, AUCTION 1000&lt;/a&gt;, FCC Public Notice DA 15-1129.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council Liquor License Review Committee report, 8 January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-a2council-liquor-license-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-a2council-liquor-license-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Hall, January 8, 2016 - A brief report from a jammed
Council committee meeting held in the council workroom. The committee
moved public comment time to the begining of the meeting to hear
concerns of citizens who objected to a previous decision of the committee,
memorialized as follows on Legistar as 15-1179 enacted on October 16, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution to Approve a Request from Aquamarine Springs, LLC for a New Micro-Brewer, Small Wine-Maker, Small Distiller Liquor License and Dance/Entertainment Permit, to be Located at 507 S. Ashley Street Sponsors: Council Liquor License Review Committee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee noted that the building is located in the floodway and is also part of the Old West Side Historic District. Committee members discussed the fact that any renovation to the building would require further review by the Fire and Building Departments and may also require site plan approval. It was noted that this approval was only for the applicant to proceed with the liquor license application process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A motion was made by Councilmember Kailasapathy, seconded by Councilmember Lumm, that the Resolution be recommended for approval to the City Council on 10/19/2015. On a voice vote, the Chair declared the motion carried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The citizens at the meeting objected to this decision, both
that they were not properly informed of the decision making
at the time as well as the observation that there is a preschool
nearby that should have the right to object to the decision.
Several people at this meeting had gone to Lansing to register their
complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also on the docket was a proposal from Glass House Brewing LLC for
a &amp;ldquo;New Micro-Brewer Liquor License to be Located at 2350 W. Liberty
Street&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More later as time and space warrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Arborwiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Aquamarine_Springs&#34;&gt;Aquamarine Springs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Glass_House_Brewing&#34;&gt;Glass House Brewing&lt;/a&gt;,
both are just the start of the articles at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Flood Network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-oxford-flood-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-oxford-flood-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Oxford Flood Network is making a flood detection network in
the UK, using low cost sensors and volunteers. They are sharing
their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oxfloodnet&#34;&gt;code on Github&lt;/a&gt; and their
results on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flood_network&#34;&gt;Flood_Network&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They encourage you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://flood.network/join&#34;&gt;join their effort&lt;/a&gt;,
and no high technology is necessary. The network incorporates
both readings from automated sensors (about £250) as well as
manual readings from gaugeboards or photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New as of December 2015 is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nominet.uk/iot-technology-powers-an-interactive-flood-map-and-sensor-network/&#34;&gt;interactive flood map&lt;/a&gt;.
A post from Nominet describes the effort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominet, in association with the Flood Network, is today launching an interactive, online map which visualises river and stream levels around Oxford. The map, showing how technology can be a part of flood defence systems anywhere, has been developed following a successful pilot project with the Oxford Flood Network. The project has been focused on exploring the potential of the Internet of Things (IoT) to create an extensive, localised, early-warning system for flood-prone areas for the first time in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is using TVWS (&amp;ldquo;TV white space&amp;rdquo;) as its wide area backhaul
network for these sensors for hard-to-reach devices that are outside
of the range of wifi. Cost-effective and reliable access to remote
small sensors is one of the tough spots in Internet of Things development,
it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see TVWS as a possible solution to this issue.
The other relevant technology for low-cost metro area networks for
sensors is Lorawan, more about which later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire on Inverness in Dexter, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-dexter-fire-inverness-condo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 21:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-dexter-fire-inverness-condo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A condo on Inverness in Dexter, Michigan was on fire on
Thursday evening, January 7, 2016. A first report came
in at about 7:24 p.m. via MEI Dispatch.
Dexter Area Fire Chief Robert Smith said no one was injured in the fire,
according to MLive.
Reports were monitored on Twitter,
Facebook, and the Washtenaw County scanner on Broadcastify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least five fire departments - Scio Township, Putnam Township,
Chelsea, Ann Arbor Township and Ann Arbor City - came to the
aid of Dexter in fighting the blaze, according to reports
monitored on Facebook by MEI Dispatch. MLive reported that
Hamburg Township also assisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLive reporter Darcie Moran and photographer Melanie
Maxwell are at the scene and have filed this story,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2016/01/fire_tears_through_dexter_cond.html&#34;&gt;Fire tears through Dexter condo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt King, 23, was finishing up dinner in his ground-level condo on Jan. 7 in the 4500 block of Inverness Street in the Huron Farms development when he heard &amp;ldquo;explosions&amp;rdquo; in the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A photo from the scene was provided by ABC 7 (Washington DC)
meteorologist Steve Rudin on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/psa2&#34;&gt;@psa2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/a2kelly&#34;&gt;@a2kelly&lt;/a&gt; My longtime childhood friend posted this from her backyard. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9jkyXtUWga&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9jkyXtUWga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steve Rudin ABC7 (@SteveRudinABC7) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SteveRudinABC7/status/685282625657946112&#34;&gt;January 8, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WXYZ 7 Action News reported live from the scene,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wxyz.com/news/region/washtenaw-county/residents-of-dexter-condo-complex-homeless-after-their-units-are-destoyed-by-fire&#34;&gt;Residents of Dexter condo complex homeless after their units are destoyed by fire&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly Palkowski, Lorrie Shaw, Kelly Ann Arnold, and Rich Landskroener Jr.
contributed to this report. Special thanks to Paul Zekas of MEI Dispatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updated 10:52 p.m. with MLive story. Reports differ on the full
composition of the mutual aid team. Updated 11:30 p.m. with WXYZ story.
Some reports have &amp;ldquo;Huron Farms&amp;rdquo; as the condo complex, others have
&amp;ldquo;Huron Commons&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washtenaw County Health Department delays food inspection reporting from November 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-county-health-food-inspection-delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 08:15:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-07-county-health-food-inspection-delays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing this message from the Washtenaw County Health Department
regarding their delayed publication of restaurant inspection reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Angela Parsons
12/22/15

Greetings all,

Sincere apologies, but we are experiencing technical difficulties
with our inspection software and I am unable to retrieve the
restaurant inspection list for November. Kristen is currently on
vacation and will return on December 29th. I am hoping that she
will be able to remedy the issue and will be able to send along the
results at that time.

So sorry for any inconvenience!!

Angie

Angela Parsons, MA Environmental Health Education Coordinator
Washtenaw County Public Health - Environmental Health Division 705
N. Zeeb Rd., P.O. Box 8645 Ann Arbor, MI  48107-8645 Zeeb Office:
(734) 222-3869 Towner Office: (734) 544-6862 Cell: (734) 320-0094
parsonsa@ewashtenaw.org

Confidentiality Notice: This message, including any attachments is
intended solely for the use of the named recipient(s) and may contain
confidential and/or privileged information. Any unauthorized review,
use, disclosure, or distribution of this communication(s) is expressly
prohibited. If you are not the intended recipient, please contact
the sender by reply e-mail and destroy any and all copies of the
original message, including attachments.  

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>