<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 9999 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About this weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/about-this-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 9999 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/about-this-weblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Vielmetti has been writing the Vacuum weblog
since 1999 from Ann Arbor, Michigan. The topics vary
widely, with over 2000 entries in the whole collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of simplifying the presentation, some
parts of this collection are currently offline, and the
front page has some mix of meditation and detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current set of systems that are an area of focus -
and the places I draw from for inspiration on each -
are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/a&gt;.
Self-reflective thoughts about producing a bunch
of work through the medium of this weblog, and through
other writing outlets that are less satisfying. Trying
as best I can to write more letters and postcards and
not spend as much time on instachirp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/radio&#34;&gt;Radio&lt;/a&gt;.
Software defined radio, listening to far-off stations,
operating 2 meter ham radio, various ways to listen to
baseball online, and the like all capture my attention.
One nice thing about radio is that you can listen to it
while doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/rpi/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;. This little ARM based single board computer
is a launching point for small scale situated experimental
computing interfaces to the outside world. I&amp;rsquo;m running
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; distribution on my
systems, which provides infrastructure to run Docker.
Pis are cheap and cheerful, and the ARM chips they are
built from have applications all the way from disposable
embedded computers to data center scale power efficient compute farms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/docker&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. This tool allows you to encapsulate system dependencies
so that even complex software can be launched and run
without going through an extensive installation process.
Run this on small systems like the Raspberry Pi, for development on OS X or Linux,
and on bare-metal servers like Packet. Container technology
and cluster technology are still changing rapidly, with
every new release offering new functions (and the risk of
a smattering of interesting new bugs).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 28, 2017 AWS S3 downtime</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W09-3-aws-s3-downtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W09-3-aws-s3-downtime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services had downtime yesterday. Their
S3 storage service had what was described as elevated
error rates in the US-East zone, and as a result failures
started in other AWS services in US-East that depended
on S3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The failures were reminiscent of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/&#34;&gt;DynamoDB downtime of September 20, 2015&lt;/a&gt;,
in that seemingly unrelated services share a common failure
mode because of unforeseen interdependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A distributed system is one in which the failure of a computer you didn’t even know existed can render your own computer unusable. Leslie Lamport, 1987&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techmeme.com/170228/p20#a170228p20&#34;&gt;Techmeme roundup&lt;/a&gt;
has a good summary of the impacts on the net. Notably,
Twitter was unaffected, but some elements of Slack like
file sharing failed to work. And crucially Amazon&amp;rsquo;s own
ability to communicate with its many customers was the
first system to be noticably affected; their status page
showed all green checkmarks for more than an hour after
the problem was noticed, with the explanation coming that
the status page was itself dependent on services that were
down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The dashboard not changing color is related to S3 issue.  See the banner at the top of the dashboard for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Amazon Web Services (@awscloud) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/awscloud/status/836656664635846656&#34;&gt;February 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some news media sites were also down or running
in impaired service, prompting the
Associated Press wire service to use Facebook to issue
its news story about the AWS outage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Amazon Cloud server problems affecting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AP&#34;&gt;@AP&lt;/a&gt; which is now posting some of its content to its Facebook page &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MQZrMKOQfv&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MQZrMKOQfv&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/k7kPTX8m9k&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/k7kPTX8m9k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Oliver Darcy (@oliverdarcy) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/oliverdarcy/status/836665007408578560&#34;&gt;February 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For severe weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-5-for-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-5-for-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m setting aside this evening in anticipation of severe weather.
Unseasonable warmth has meant that southeastern Michigan is at
risk for a rare February tornado. Ever since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crh.noaa.gov/news/display_cmsstory.php?wfo=dtx&amp;amp;storyid=80731&amp;amp;source=0&#34;&gt;tornado hit Dexter&lt;/a&gt;
a few years ago, people in the area have had some focus
on their storm preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s some ways to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Best potential for severe storms Friday in the evening and first half of the night, roughly 6PM to midnight. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/miwx?src=hash&#34;&gt;#miwx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/dtKqAeBqQh&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dtKqAeBqQh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; NWS Detroit (@NWSDetroit) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NWSDetroit/status/834864557441028096&#34;&gt;February 23, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, charge all of the devices that you
care about well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is always a good place to watch for news. The hashtag
used by weather watchers in Michigan is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/miwx&#34;&gt;#miwx&lt;/a&gt; , and the National
Weather Service Detroit uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NWSDetroit&#34;&gt;@NWSDetroit&lt;/a&gt; twitter
feed to keep people informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I count on my amateur radio station at home to stay
connected to the Skywarn network. Locally this net uses
the 145.15 Mhz frequency on the N8DUY repeater, which
is located in Scio Township near I-94 and M-14. I spent
a little time tonight tuning up and making sure that
could get into the repeater OK, and I was successful,
thanks to a rig on long-term loan from W8TAM and an antenna that
KB6NU helped me build last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the power goes out it&amp;rsquo;s good to have a backup radio. I have
a couple of inexpensive Baofeng rigs that have pretty good
battery life and can tune not just to amateur bands but also
to broadcast FM and to the weather bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for signs of storm damage, the power outage
maps provide a 30 minute delayed detailed track of where
weather has impacted the power grid. I put together a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-09-power-outage-maps/&#34;&gt;list of outage maps&lt;/a&gt;
a few years ago, which is still generally useful; locally,
the maps from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dteenergy.com/map/outage.html&#34;&gt;DTE Energy&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.consumersenergy.com/outagemap&#34;&gt;Consumers Energy&lt;/a&gt; cover
most of the Lower Peninsula. Both companies have mobile
phone apps that allow you to log outages and view maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When weather hits, public safety traffic monitored by scanners
can also be of interest. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.broadcastify.com/listen/top&#34;&gt;Broadcastify&amp;rsquo;s list of top feeds&lt;/a&gt;
is worth checking when dispatchers are handling weather-related calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several sites that have radar feeds, and of those,
I have a fondness for the reporting from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderground.com&#34;&gt;Weather Underground&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m missing some AA batteries for a dedicated weather radio
that runs on AC power but that can run from batteries; that
would be good to sort out before the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dogfooding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-4-dogfooding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-4-dogfooding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To &amp;ldquo;dogfood&amp;rdquo; comes from the phrase &amp;ldquo;to eat your own dogfood&amp;rdquo;,
giving the sense that you are not only producing a product
but also consuming it as well. This is intended to show that
you care so much about your customers success in using that
product that you are willing to use it the way they are
intended to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dogfooding&amp;rdquo; is thus shorthand for actually depending
on something that you make yourself for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dude, they should have spent more time dogfooding that app!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newrepublic.com/article/115349/dogfooding-tech-slang-working-out-glitches&#34;&gt;The New Republic&lt;/a&gt;
has a good take on the phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is it that you do?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-what-is-it-that-you-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-what-is-it-that-you-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question &amp;ldquo;What is it that you do&amp;rdquo; is a peculiarly
Midwestern one, which admits most easily as an answer
&amp;ldquo;I work in the mines&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I work at Fords&amp;rdquo;. Much more
interesting is the expected response to the California version of the query, which lets you
talk about the places that you used to work so that you
can put together a story that matches not only what you&amp;rsquo;re
doing now but also selective bits and pieces of a work
history to back it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The west coast question allows for lots of selectivity
in producing an on-the-spot narrative that backs up your
qualifications for whatever you happen to be focusing on
now, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t require you to dig a small narrow niche
and occupy only that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing that you can do is become pigeonholed as
that person who does that thing. If you bring your whole
person to the job, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to describe yourself
so narrowly even if the task at hand is quite specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Inspired by Bill Tozier and by Alan Gutierrez, both of
whom have amusing and informed answers to this question.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters to self</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-letters-to-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-letters-to-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded that the biggest use I have of bloggging is to write
notes to myself that I&amp;rsquo;ll review later, either deliberately or
accidentally as I look for some authority on a topic that I temporarily
mastered well enough to write down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is an increasingly
solitary affair and its golden age is over.
But self-adddressed envelopes for bits
of things that you notice are fun to open later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And now I am distracted by some project I want to
try out, and will thus finish this thought half way
to completion.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite weblogs are very focused. With them you can count on
every post having something narrowly on the theme of the blog, with
variety within a certain limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a focused weblog, except that I write all of it, and
that it reflects my varied interests which don&amp;rsquo;t lend themselves to
a narrow bead on a single topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to reconcile this contradiction? Very well then, I contradict myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to try to cope with having a wide range of interests
is to be honest
about it, and to try to limit what you want to say right now.
I have tried to do that with my introductory
post, but even that seems like it&amp;rsquo;s been overtaken by events. I&amp;rsquo;ll
refine that statement of purpose to be clear what it is
that I could and should write about daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second approach is to be generous in linking out to what I read,
so that it&amp;rsquo;s more obvious by reference what has my attention.
So the &amp;ldquo;radio&amp;rdquo; section should mention London Shortwave, the RTL-SDR
weblog, and KB6NU&amp;rsquo;s amateur radio blog as three sources - not the
only three, but a representative sample of interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I write more, I can go back and unpublish the bits
that are off-topic, so that the long-term publication stream fits some
more processed and refined notion of self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better idea simply is to write more, and to write more often, and
to be less telegraphic and more epistolary in my typical communications.
140 characters is not enough, and when I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to
instachirp something, better to
get it out in long form than squeezed into a tiny box.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every day</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-3-every-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I had a daily deadline to write 500 words. Anything
was fair game as long as it was spelled correctly and included the
two words &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor&amp;rdquo; prominently in the lead paragraph. Those days
are gone, but the memory of them reminds me of just how much hard work
it is to have something new to say every day that&amp;rsquo;s worthy of publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a certain rhythm to writing every day. I appreciate it for
what it requires of you, that daily dose of composing yourself to the
point of putting something down on paper that you&amp;rsquo;re willing to review the
next day and not run shrieking from in horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from blogging for a while is that
not everything that gets written down and published needs to stay
published forever. The every day publication doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be
a permanent totem. It can live for a few days or a few weeks and
then silently disappear, leaving room for something that matters more
or that&amp;rsquo;s more on topic for some value of topic that you want to
present yourself as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still I write. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to, but it&amp;rsquo;s also hard not to, and the
only way to get a few good words on the page is to produce a lot
of words and then be selective about what to keep around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning analytics</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-2-abandoning-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-2-abandoning-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped for the most part watching and caring about
how many people view the various bits of writing I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analytical tools out there for measuring
the net have their primary impetus the selling of advertising,
and as such they have slowly but surely morphed to be less
and less useful for the discovery of non-commerical intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that Google Analytics would tell you the
exact search terms that someone used to get to your page.
That&amp;rsquo;s gone now, unless you&amp;rsquo;re buying ad keywords. Every
system still gives raw page counts, but who cares about
eyeballs if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are focusing on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the tactics of gathering and spreading attention have
to shift. Search is no longer the only currency of value,
and Facechat and Snapbook and Instachirp all proclaim
that they can measure engagement (and buy attention for
a low, low price). Be that as it may, it&amp;rsquo;s much less
important for me right now to collect lots of viewers.
Much more important for any given piece of work is exactly
who sees it, what they see in it, and whether it gets
past the initial flip, flip, flip through the infinite
net to have someone actually read to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can pretty much predict what kind of Twitter behavior
generates a lot of page views - the tweetstorm! - but
who needs to do that all the time? Especially when
sometimes the goal is not to have a lot of random
people see something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this for you, you see; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just for
me, time-shifted into the future, looking backwards on
the day and understanding why measurement of readership
is not the only metric of interestingness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That new system smell</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-that-new-system-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 23:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-that-new-system-smell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That new system smell is what you smell when there&amp;rsquo;s a
brand new blank page and you have a ready approach to fill
it up. It&amp;rsquo;s the well-worked out technique just waiting for
some new set of tasks to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some times new systems present as &amp;ldquo;greenfield&amp;rdquo; opportunities,
with brand-new things to do that don&amp;rsquo;t require much in
the way of adherence to what&amp;rsquo;s gone on in the past.
Others show up as &amp;ldquo;brownfields&amp;rdquo;, with their fair share
of underground surprises and an acrid or pungent smell
of previous toxins or old tailings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it surprise you that I am writing this page on a
screen with no other words on it except this post? Strip
a problem down to its bare essence and hide all of the
gewgaws and gimcracks that enliven and distract from its
true nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musings on the language of Silicon Valley, the site of
a recent visit, and what sorts of language gets used
to talk about opportunity and to qualify the difference
between the world of incremental change versus the
world of radical reinvention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send a postcard</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-send-a-postcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-send-a-postcard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On my recent trip to California I wrote a few postcards. It
was harder to do that on the plane than it used to be back
in my days of frequent travel. The seats are much more cramped
than they once were, and there&amp;rsquo;s a distraction of Internet on
the airplane that is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of sending postcards on today&amp;rsquo;s Internet is that
everyone thinks that snapbooking or facechatting or whatever is
a sign of a connection. There is no viral postcard craze, not
yet in this century. You end up being a bit quirky just for
remembering what someone&amp;rsquo;s postal address is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that I love postcards so much is that I&amp;rsquo;ve
collected some good ones to send and made a few of my own.
The QSL card is one example of this, made by and sent to ham
radio operators as a souvenier of a contact made. I&amp;rsquo;m always
happy to send a QSL card even if my response rate in getting
cards in return is sporadic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I know your postal address,
there&amp;rsquo;s some finite chance that instead of getting an
instachirp message from me, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a postcard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small wins</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-small-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W08-1-small-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am reminded again of Karl Weick&amp;rsquo;s work on &amp;ldquo;small wins&amp;rdquo;,
the observation that large problems are so large that we
are overwhelmed just in thinking about them. It
can be incredibly powerful to have a series of small wins
that provide some momentum and that set you up for
increasing confidence and capability to tackle bigger issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My small win of the moment is getting this blog post up,
reminding myself that once upon a time I met a writing
deadline every day for publication, and knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s
not necessary for every single post to be a big thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISO 8601 date format and keeping track of weeks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W03-5-iso-date-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-W03-5-iso-date-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warning: objects in calendar are closer than they appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can never keep track of the day of the month, it seems.
The watch on my wrist has a day marker, but it wants to have
a 31 day month, and when we have 30 or 28 day months the
day has to be manually adjusted. On the other hand, I have
a keen sense for what day of the week it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calendar for me is the ISO 8601 date format that supports calendaring
by day of week and week of the year. Today is 2017-W03-5,
which is conveniently and readily read as the Friday (5) of the
third week of 2017. There are rules from ISO 8601 about when
to start the year and what to do when weeks cross year boundaries,
but other than that small confusion it&amp;rsquo;s a very straightforward
calendar to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest bonus of it is just how readily you can plan for events
months in the future, because rather than thinking by month and
having to compute odd distances, you can think by weeks and simply
subtract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some background: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.staff.science.uu.nl/~gent0113/calendar/isocalendar.htm&#34;&gt;The Mathematics of the ISO 8601 Calendar&lt;/a&gt;,
R.H. van Gent 2005; &lt;a href=&#34;http://calendarswamp.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Calendar Swamp&lt;/a&gt;,
a weblog by Scott Mace; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calconnect.org&#34;&gt;CalConnect&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;The Calendaring and Scheduling Consortium&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy leap second (or mostly happy) and happy new year for 2017</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-01-01-leap-second/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 10:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-01-01-leap-second/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year, and from a technology perspective, also happy leap second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[image: timekeeping for the leap second, from FSM Labs]
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a complete picture of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/leapsecond?src=hash&#34;&gt;#leapsecond&lt;/a&gt; 2016. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/DFp6XgnPig&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DFp6XgnPig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; FSMLabs (@FSMLabs) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/FSMLabs/status/815589123121618944&#34;&gt;January 1, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, when there&amp;rsquo;s a leap second, people get a chance to debug their
timekeeping code. I guess if they happen frequently enough the code will
get better exercise and some bugs will be shaken out. Every time
some government messes with timekeeping, a small army of programmers gets
a few hours of work to adjust their systems, with some occasional unplanned downtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsmlabs.com&#34;&gt;FSMLabs&lt;/a&gt; watched the time change closely, and their image above
shows one peculiarity of reported time: Google&amp;rsquo;s NTP servers
returned a time that was up to half a second off, slowly creeping
out of sync with real time and then back into sync. They write
in a recap, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fsmlabs.com/news/2017/01/01/2leapsecondskew2016.html&#34;&gt;Leapsecond 2016 complete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that Google starts its 20 hour leap-second “skew” 10 hours before the event and then skews back to the real time. Everyone else stays correct and then has a short error as they “leap” the second and then come back into correct time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSMLabs sells precision timekeeping equipment aimed at the financial
industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leap-second-bugs&#34;&gt;Leap second bugs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue identified was at Cloudflare, a distributed system
for web cachine.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/1fczgjmknplp&#34;&gt;Some DNS lookups causing 5xx errors due to leap second bug&lt;/a&gt;
is the incident report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at 00:00 UTC on January 1, 2017, CNAME resolutions on some machines stopped working due to a bug triggered by the universal addition of one leap second, which affected both some authoritative DNS and origin DNS lookups, causing 5xx errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the real world, the biggest reported issue that could be
suspicious was reported by the BBC as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-38482746&#34;&gt;London ambulance service hit by new year fault&lt;/a&gt;,
an account of computer system crashes at London Ambulance Service (LAS)
that are peculiarly synchronized with the appearance of the leap second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is understood the computer system crashed, so calls had to be recorded by pen and paper for nearly five hours on one of the busiest nights of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;systemd-is-eating-the-world&#34;&gt;Systemd is eating the world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally in timekeeping news and notes, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/os/docs/latest/configuring-date-and-timezone.html&#34;&gt;CoreOS help pages for timekeeping&lt;/a&gt;
illustrate the importance of keeping good time within a computing cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CoreOS clusters use NTP to synchronize the clocks of member nodes, and all machines start an NTP client at boot. CoreOS versions later than 681.0.0 use systemd-timesyncd(8) as the default NTP client. Earlier versions used ntpd(8). Use systemctl to check which service is running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Systemd is eating the world&amp;rdquo;, and one of the things it has eaten is timekeeping.
One of the old CoreOS bugs, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coreos/bugs/issues/391&#34;&gt;systemd-timesyncd not as precise as ntpd&lt;/a&gt;,
reports that because of systemd-timesyncd&amp;rsquo;s less precise timekeeping there
are problems with Deis and Ceph. The bug report is from 2015 and was closed
due to inactivity, but if you have weird problems with CoreOS, Deis, and Ceph,
check your clocks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes-and-references&#34;&gt;Notes and references&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future timekeeping bug that&amp;rsquo;s most likely to create worldwide
angst on the scale of Y2K is the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Year_2038_problem&#34;&gt;Year 2038 problem&lt;/a&gt;,
which I&amp;rsquo;m counting on helping fix to fund my retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TimeAndDate News has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.timeanddate.com/news/time/&#34;&gt;time zone news&lt;/a&gt; feed,
which is useful to track worldwide adjustments to and from Daylight Savings Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://community.ntppool.org/t/leap-second-2017-status/59&#34;&gt;NTP Pool leap second 2017 status&lt;/a&gt;
reported that as of a few hours before the leap second, 3463 servers in the pool system were announcing the leap second and 933 were not.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://community.ntppool.org/users/ask/activity&#34;&gt;Ask Bjørn Hansen&lt;/a&gt; maintains the pool since 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hail truechimers, exit falsetickers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;updated-2017-01-01t16-07-00-to-add-fsm-labs-london-ambulance-notes-headers&#34;&gt;Updated 2017-01-01T16:07:00 to add FSM Labs, London Ambulance notes, headers&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching containers with Portainer and Sysdig</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-28-watching-containers-with-portainer-and-sysdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-28-watching-containers-with-portainer-and-sysdig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[screen capture: csysdig running inside Portainer]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-partner=&#34;tweetdeck&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Run &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sysdig&#34;&gt;@sysdig&lt;/a&gt; CLI tool &amp;quot;csysdig&amp;quot; inside of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/portainerio&#34;&gt;@portainerio&lt;/a&gt; console window. Nice way to watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/docker&#34;&gt;@docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/coreos&#34;&gt;@coreos&lt;/a&gt; cc &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mckartha&#34;&gt;@mckartha&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/hJGiHuJwKs&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/hJGiHuJwKs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Edward Vielmetti (@vielmetti) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti/status/814320562294181888&#34;&gt;December 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question to be answered is how to manage Docker containers - not
just how to get them running, but also how to poke inside them while
they are running to see what they are doing and make sure that you
can make sense of what is happening while you develop or run in production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-12-19-tectonic-2016-trip-report/&#34;&gt;Tectonic&lt;/a&gt; I was introduced to one tool that handles Docker
and Kubernetes container introspection, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sysdig.com&#34;&gt;Sysdig&lt;/a&gt;. From Twitter I
also discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://portainer.io&#34;&gt;Portainer&lt;/a&gt;, a nice system for container management.
Having installed both Portainer and Sysdig, the interesting bit
happens when you connect the together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portainer provides a very high level view of your container
infrastructure, with an easy browser level access to see what
containers you have loaded on the system, what&amp;rsquo;s running, and how
to start or restart or pull new containers. Sysdig on the other
hand has a very low level kernel&amp;rsquo;s eye view of the system, watching
every system call and timing it and providing a system browser (with
&amp;ldquo;csysdig&amp;rdquo;) that is reminiscent of faithful Unix tools like &amp;lsquo;htop&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install each of them according to package instructions.
As of this writing (December 2016) Portainer will run on Intel
and ARM platforms, but Sysdig really wants to run on Intel only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://portainer.readthedocs.io/en/latest/deployment.html&#34;&gt;Portainer install instructions&lt;/a&gt;
will want you to pull the latest version (v1.11) and then
set a password. The vision for Portainer product direction
is full role based access control, so expect developments
here; just know that for now, if you want an admin password
to persist, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to persist the data in the filesystem
or in a Docker storage volume. As installs go, this is pretty
easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sysdig.org/install/&#34;&gt;Sysdig install instructions&lt;/a&gt;
for installing Sysdig in a container. We&amp;rsquo;re monitoring CoreOS,
which makes the effort directly supported; I haven&amp;rsquo;t done Ubuntu yet.
Sysdig wants to have a kernel module installed, and the CoreOS
install effort takes advantage of automated new kernel builds whenever
CoreOS does a new release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once both systems are up, connect them together. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to
connect to a running sysdig container through the console, via
the navigation path dashboard / containers / sysdig / console.
Launch a console window on your Sysdig container, and in that console
run &amp;ldquo;csysdig -pc&amp;rdquo;. You&amp;rsquo;ll have a view on the innards of your containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the biggest missing piece is the amount of this narrative
given over to install instructions, rather than use instructions.
Portainer has some very nice ways to install a variety of containerized
applications, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to launch Sysdig in a single
click, nor is it reasonable to naively assume that it can. Even once
you get the command line invocation right there may be a pesky
requirement to get kernel headers all exactly correct. Still, if
possible that would be the direction I&amp;rsquo;d give to both organizations -
make it easier to embed Sysdig tools and functions inside a Portainer framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>