<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing in vim with vsplit and multiple windows</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-vsplit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-vsplit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I imagine a digital writing
environment that mimics how I write
in my paper notebooks. On paper I use multiple columns,
with parallel writing across the columns and the
ability to go back and forth rather than just reading
up and down. A recent discussion of a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-01-three-column-writing-style/&#34;&gt;three column writing style&lt;/a&gt; describes how and why
this works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An approach new to me is to use very large windows in &amp;ldquo;vim&amp;rdquo;, with
the &amp;ldquo;vsplit&amp;rdquo; command to split the screen into three very tall
windows. I don&amp;rsquo;t manage to get a full 80 column width out of each
of them, but 65 columns is close enough that it feels like a
workable writing environment. Moving between windows isn&amp;rsquo;t
quite as easy as guiding the pen across the printed page, but
it&amp;rsquo;s much easier than trying to do a fancy layout in a markup
language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to translate the writing environment directly to the
screen for display. This post will be on the right two-thirds of
the blog with a relatively static left sidebar (which no one ever
clicks on, but that seems obligatory for the design).  At some point
I might do a redesign, and then who knows what the left and right
context will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a brief moment when my writing environment was mostly
wiki with special purpose (read: hacked in) commands for maintaining
a separate sidebar for each file, displayed adjacent to the main
text. This was a personal wiki so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to negotiate
appropriate activity by any other users. The perpetual connected
side display allows you to have a little negotiation with yourself
about things that aren&amp;rsquo;t quite ready to put into the main text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vim is a very powerful environment, perhaps too powerful.
Some key combinations have profound and unexpected power over the
command buffer, and you get lost. I find
it easier to cope with, though, than the even more powerful emacs.
I used GNU Emacs for a while in college but never managed to keep
up with it, in large part because the strange key combinations of
alt-meta-control-coke-bottle would strain my wrists. At least with
vim, I can keep my fingers on the home row for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing context is important, and too often lost. You
don&amp;rsquo;t see the right sidebar where I have notes about
the Internet of Things and the sorts of interesting equipment
that might mount on a sign post. My notes about a mysterious vim
&amp;ldquo;E212&amp;rdquo; error in the left sidebar are gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like the vsplit windows on this particular screen, when
filled, hold about 450 words. Fully loaded, that means that a
page properly laid out might have more than 1300 words of usable
typing space. I could get used to this layout - not just because
it lets me see the whole work, but also because it admits a
couple of productive distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor quiet writing escapes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-ann-arbor-writing-escapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-ann-arbor-writing-escapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where to go in Ann Arbor to do some quiet writing, without distractions.
There are plenty of cafes where there are lots of people around; this
list looks for the empty places where you won&amp;rsquo;t have your attention broken
quite so easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a much easier task in the summer time than it is during the school
year, as the students thin out and University buildings are much quieter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Campus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackham.umich.edu/rackham-building/study-halls&#34;&gt;Rackham Building reading rooms&lt;/a&gt;, second floor. Very lovely, very quiet, recommended by many.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lib.umich.edu/hatcher-graduate-library/carrels-hatcher-graduate-library&#34;&gt;Hatcher Graduate Library study carrels&lt;/a&gt;, especially on the higher floors. You&amp;rsquo;ll have a little room of your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law Library reading room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan League, upper floors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Museum of Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palmer Commons, where the upper floors have writing desks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Work Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan Union first floor reading rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downtown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor City Hall, council chambers (not during a meeting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweetwaters, Liberty or Washington St&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor District Library, third floor (periodicals) or fourth floor (administration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s Next Door, upstairs in one of the smaller rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mighty Good Coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthaei Botanical Gardens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duderstadt Center library, second floor (periodicals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Municipal Airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roos Roast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ypsilanti&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate in Depot Town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, external distractions are only one part of the complex question of
&amp;ldquo;why are no words appearing on the page&amp;rdquo;. There are some a few tricks that I
use to minimize distractions coming from the computer itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in a big &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo; window. Open up Terminal, maximize a window,
and then fire up &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m managing to get 62 lines on the screen without
having to squint, and the browser is not on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go offline. If your writing environment allows, do your writing without
a connection to the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you must stay online, mute notifications. On my Mac that&amp;rsquo;s a
&amp;ldquo;Do not disturb&amp;rdquo; setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a big screen up another functional way to avoid a distraction
is to keep sitting until the screen is full. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to
actually want to keep all of the words that you write - it&amp;rsquo;s OK to
discard some of them in a subsequent editing session - but the self
imposed constraint to fill the page all the way to the bottom on a 62
line screen produces a substantial quantity of work in a single sitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A useful quality to cultivate is &amp;ldquo;sitzfleisch&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Germans have aptly called Sitzfleisch the ability to spend endless hours at a desk doing grueling work. Sitzfleisch is considered by mathematicians to be a better guage of success than any of the attractive definitions of talent with which psychologists regale us from time to time.  Gian-Carlo Rota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull up a seat, open up the screen, start typing. Don&amp;rsquo;t look up until the page is full.
Set yourself a time limit and a word count and aim for that. The time limit can
be enforced by parking in a space where your time is limited, which reminds
me that I must be going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A commonplace reader</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-a-commonplace-reader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easier and faster to fill a page by quoting from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace book is the annotated scrapbook, carefully collecting
bits from other writers with just enough commentary and selection to
make them your own. If these were written in this era you&amp;rsquo;d call it
&amp;ldquo;curation&amp;rdquo;, though I can only think of that word in the context of
&amp;ldquo;curated meats&amp;rdquo;, somewhat salty and dry and meant to be preserved for
some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the commonplace book. Why write your own words, when there are
so many other good ones already written to quote from? As it is said,
though &lt;a href=&#34;http://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/03/06/artists-steal/&#34;&gt;no attribution is reliable&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immature artists copy, great artists steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artist steal from tonight is Brian Eno, in particular his &lt;a href=&#34;http://oblicard.com/&#34;&gt;Oblique Strategies&lt;/a&gt;,
which I now have as three lines of shell script plus 128 lines of text. A sample, intended
to be drawn at random:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not building a wall but making a brick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to brick-machines, this from Popular Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bricks are fairly easy to make, but in the developing world, traditional fired bricks are sometimes weak and crumble-prone, while cement ones are often unaffordable. The Vermeer BP714 is the first compressed-earth-block machine that makes strong air-dried bricks out of dirt. Its bricks don&amp;rsquo;t just exceed U.S. cement-code strength requirements—they&amp;rsquo;re 20 to 30 percent stronger, and cheaper than other machines&amp;rsquo; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course that&amp;rsquo;s the story you want to tell when someone else
has a lot of mud and you have a lot of machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonplace style of writing allows you to fill a page
with text faster, since you&amp;rsquo;re cutting and pasting it in
rather than sweating to find the exact words yourself. The
downside is that you might sometimes have to hunt for the
correct word, and it will be obvious that it&amp;rsquo;s someone
else&amp;rsquo;s correct word. There is no question of plagiarism,
just of assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious crimes in terms of writing are that of plagiarism and copyright violation. (Reality Studio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long as we are going down this route, it&amp;rsquo;s worth rejecting
plagiarism as a thought-crime. From Kenneth Goldsmith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems an appropriate response to a new condition in writing: With an unprecedented amount of available text, our problem is not needing to write more of it; instead, we must learn to negotiate the vast quantity that exists. How I make my way through this thicket of information—how I manage it, parse it, organize and distribute it—is what distinguishes my writing from yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make patchworks. Most two word phrases can be easily found on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most two-word phrases are not produced under unpleasant stress, but in interest or excitement. (Penelope Leach, &amp;ldquo;Babyhood&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to provide the reader with enough information so that the article can be easily found on the References page. (Communication Research Methods in Postmodern Culture)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists of real-world materials and their refractive indexes are easily found on the Internet.  (Lanier, &amp;ldquo;Maya Studio Projects Texturing and Writing&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retroactively we can construct some level of patchwork that we can crib from, in interest or excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Zingermans Coffee for an afternoon of writing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-24-zingermans-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-24-zingermans-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A daily coffee and wifi report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At times I get frustrated by my ability to sit down and produce words on a page.
The challenge is not to keep going once I get going, but in the very act of
getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do best at writing when I have a prompting question that allows me
to go on and on at least to get to the point where the screen is full
and ready to be edited down to size. The prompt doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be
the words that eventually get onto the page; it&amp;rsquo;s at least as likely
that you discover what you sat down to do only &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of the way down
the screen, and then&amp;rsquo;t it&amp;rsquo;s time to shuffle the page around to save
what&amp;rsquo;s savable and refocus what you had dealt with into a smaller spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prompting questions are fun (and hard). I once wrote for AnnArbor.com, a
semi-lovable job which was equal parts delight and horror. The delight
was that the prompt only was to keep the phrase &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor&amp;rdquo; in the first
paragraph. The horror was the task of reading all of the comments
on all of the stories written. Since then, I never read the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to be distracted while writing in such a way that the start
never happens. Deadlines and word counts have a way of sharpening the
mind, and that helps. The trick is to realize that you have to trick
yourself sometimes into starting, and once the words start to flow
it is not so difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there&amp;rsquo;s all of the other windows that you might have open that have
little bubbles protesting that you can&amp;rsquo;t close them until you empty out
that bubble. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to count how many alternative rounded rectangles there
are hiding on-screen that all demand some measure of attention. It&amp;rsquo;s
not just that there are non-zero numbers on the inbox, that&amp;rsquo;s normal;
it&amp;rsquo;s also that every other communications channel seems to be wide open.
To close them you either deal with the system or ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next of course since it&amp;rsquo;s Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s there&amp;rsquo;s almost always someone
I know to reacquiaint myself with, or someone I don&amp;rsquo;t know to be
introduced to. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how they managed to make a non-descript
entrance in an industrial park into Grand Central Station, but they
did, and I appreciate the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally there&amp;rsquo;s the notifications coming from various systems - Slack,
or Facebook, or email. I&amp;rsquo;d be remiss in not suggesting to myself
that I shut them off, but they persist, and because they are handy
sometimes I let myself get noise in the upper right hand corner of the
screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of late the &amp;ldquo;screen is full&amp;rdquo; challenge has gotten harder, since I&amp;rsquo;m
using as big a text window to type into as I can - 60+ lines tall, and
more than 200 characters wide. A 500 word essay fits in one column
of that page and can easily be seen on a single screen. Divide the
screen in two, and 1000 words come to view. What you can do when
the whole argument comes into sharp focus, and you can see that the
excuses that you are making in the middle of it don&amp;rsquo;t need to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day trips from Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-23-day-trips-from-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-23-day-trips-from-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some suggestions for places to go for same-day destination trips from Ann Arbor.
I&amp;rsquo;m collecting up ideas suitable for rides in support of driver&amp;rsquo;s ed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East via M-14&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Oak: &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitzoo.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novi: 12 Oaks Mall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;East via I-94&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belleville: &lt;a href=&#34;http://yankeeairmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Yankee Air Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dearborn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehenryford.org/&#34;&gt;Greenfield Village&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dearborn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehenryford.org/&#34;&gt;Henry Ford Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dia.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Institute of Arts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroithistorical.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Historical Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michigan.org/property/belle-isle-park/&#34;&gt;Belle Isle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motownmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Motown Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windsor: Via tunnel or bridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point Pelee: Bird sanctuary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marine City: ferry to Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South via US-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carleton: Calder Dairy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monroe: 1812 National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.toledomuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Toledo Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt; (45 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: Toledo Mud Hens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toledo: Toledo Zoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port Clinton: birdwatching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southwest via US-12&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tecumseh:  Michigan State Univ &lt;a href=&#34;http://hiddenlakegardens.msu.edu/&#34;&gt;Hidden Lake Gardens&lt;/a&gt;, (one of the better kept State secrets) &amp;hellip;beautiful trails, Hosta Garden and conifer collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishhillsrecreation.com/&#34;&gt;Irish Hills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West vis I-94&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kalamazoo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airzoo.org/&#34;&gt;Air Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;St Joseph: beaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northwest via US-23 and I-96&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Rapids: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meijergardens.org/&#34;&gt;Frederik Meijer Gardens &amp;amp; Sculpture Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;East Lansing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dairystore.msu.edu/&#34;&gt;MSU Dairy Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North via US-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durand: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.durandstation.org/&#34;&gt;Union Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frankenmuth:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bronners.com/&#34;&gt;Bronners&lt;/a&gt; / Outlet Shopping at Birch Run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bay City: Polish food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midland: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dowgardens.org/&#34;&gt;Dow Gardens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumb: Port Crescent State Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to members of the a2b3 mailing list for suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bots are hot - again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-18-bots-are-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title of the post is taken from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/1996/04/netbots/&#34;&gt;1996 Wired article&lt;/a&gt;
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/koxinga21&#34;&gt;Andrew Leonard&lt;/a&gt;
describing the state of automated systems in the dot-com
era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web robots – spiders, wanderers, and worms. Cancelbots, Lazarus, and Automoose. Chatterbots, softbots, userbots, taskbots, knowbots, and mailbots. MrBot and MrsBot. Warbots, clonebots, floodbots, annoybots, hackbots, and Vladbots. Gaybots, gossipbots, and gamebots. Skeleton bots, spybots, and sloth bots. Xbots and meta-bots. Eggdrop bots. Motorcycle bull dyke bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots are hot today in part because natural langauge processing
has improved to the point where &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/05/Google-supercharges-machine-learning-tasks-with-custom-chip.html&#34;&gt;Google can build hardware&lt;/a&gt;
to speed up their software algorithms and run their immense
training corpuses through it quickly to fine tune their approach.
The output of this effort is ASICs that speed up their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/&#34;&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/a&gt;
algorithm for machine learning. Thus Google can safely give away
their software, knowing that anyone else running it will use
a multiple of the energy that it takes Google to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s instructive to look at the changes throughout the years and
how bots have co-evolved with the networks and computer systems
that they inhabit. Early AIs like ELIZA and PARRY lived on
mainframes connected to very slow wide-area networks, and it
was years before the two of them talked to each other online.
The 1980s and 1990s brought Usenet and the automation that could
live on store-and-forward networks. AOL Instant Messenger&amp;rsquo;s
ubiquitous chat met popular culture and the emergence of
advertising bots like GooglyMinotaur, which promoted the music
of Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing what I think is some kind of manuscript about
bots and their personalities, a biographical dictionary of
emerging intelligences. I&amp;rsquo;m at about 10,000 words. It&amp;rsquo;s a challenge
to try to corral that much quasi-intelligence onto the page, including
trying as best I can to characterize some systems that are
known only by people&amp;rsquo;s memories of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three column writing style</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-01-three-column-writing-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-01-three-column-writing-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The elements of a three column writing style:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a broad center, with sidebars left and right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The left sidebar is labelled &amp;ldquo;Do&amp;rdquo;, and it contains a
record of the things that were done; sit in a chair,
drink a cup of coffee, do laundry between writing bits,
make the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right sidebar contains snippets or longer of things
that were read, since you are expected when writing to
have reading materials nearby to crib from or to be
inspired by. Tonight I have the Taschen postcardbook &amp;ldquo;Barkitecture&amp;rdquo;,
and a postcard from Syracuse Cultural Workers on
&amp;ldquo;How to create community&amp;rdquo;, to guide me along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves the middle main column for thoughts, impressions;
&amp;ldquo;writing&amp;rdquo;, not that the other bits are any fewer words on
the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge overall is how to represent this on the
computer screen. When you write in this style, the page
can be read top to bottom or left to right or in any
diagonal direction, and it will still make some sense.
Short of typing words into cells of a spreadsheet, or
composing in a monospaced font with exact word counts,
it&amp;rsquo;s hard to recreate precisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked writing in the sidebar, sometimes more
so than the writing in the middle. Quadrille paper helps
to keep the margins aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note that the blogging format is essentailly a one-column
style with some static sidebars, and I have never managed
to compose anything suitable that really captures my notebooks.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Day at Roos Roast with Burroughs and Polya</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-01-roosroast-may-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-01-roosroast-may-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An account of
the trip;
what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egg and a shot
at &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/roosroast&#34;&gt;Roos Roast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AVOID GRINDING
OVER STEAMING POT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking the
espresso shot,
with an increasing
titration of milk.
Reading Twitter.
Sunday a.m.
tweeting is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anker battery
plugged in to
75% Macbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avantgarde
Design &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.taschen.com&#34;&gt;postcard&lt;/a&gt;
book, UM
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umcu.org&#34;&gt;Credit Union&lt;/a&gt;
pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reqeusted &amp;ldquo;When
We Are No
More&amp;rdquo; Abby
Smith &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rumseywrites.com&#34;&gt;Rumsey&lt;/a&gt;.
Deliver to
Pittsfield (?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was thinking at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading a &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinboard.in/u:vielmetti/t:burroughs&#34;&gt;Burroughs&lt;/a&gt; interview, on
his multicolumn notebooks, cut ups,
and fold-ins. Writing technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reread How To Solve It when
I am looking for work. Does it
work? Is there some better text?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grand Hotel serving sushi, says
Crain&amp;rsquo;s Detroit. Do they also
serve smelt? What happened
to the smelt runs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/chairkicker&#34;&gt;Brian Kerr&lt;/a&gt; writes of the
intricate ritual of being
dependent on electronica, and
the daily or more frequent need to
recharge batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abby Smith Rumsey on
prserving history in a
digtial age;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pondering that my digital
ephemera are dependent on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typepad.com&#34;&gt;monthly subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, and
could fade in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace, remember that,
data gloves and VRML and
the metaverse and all that?
Yeah. There.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quotations from any book I take with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the
unknown?
What are the
data?
What is the
condition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second rule
of discovery
is to sit tight
and wait until
you get a
bright idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variation of
the problem
is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any relation
to the adding
machine firm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandfather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The International
Style that developed
as a result marked
the breakthrough
of functional design
suited to the
technical requirements
of mass production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;end note&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Burroughvian three column style is
very sutiable for the (illeg.) Read across,
or down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor hydrant flushing maps</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-25-hidden-water-flush-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 16:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-25-hidden-water-flush-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor has maps showing you where the hydrants
are being flushed. If your water turns brown, the most likely
cause of it is sediment being disturbed by hydrant flush tests.
Run your cold water for a bit until it clears. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t
clear promptly, call the city. A secondary source of sediment
is unexpected water main breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to get notified of hydrant flushing in your
neighborhood, but it&amp;rsquo;s not easy. The city sends out an email
through GovDelivery alerting you that there is hydrant flushing
somewhere in the city:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routine fire hydrant flushing continues in Ann Arbor next week, April 25-29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That email contains a link to a news release at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/news/pages/article.aspx?i=252&#34;&gt;http://www.a2gov.org/news/pages/article.aspx?i=252&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which doesn&amp;rsquo;t say anything about where the flushing is going to take
place, except to say that there&amp;rsquo;s a map. You click on
the page that says there&amp;rsquo;s a map&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/departments/field-operations/Pages/hydrantflush.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.a2gov.org/departments/field-operations/Pages/hydrantflush.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and it reiterates that there&amp;rsquo;s a map, and one more click hopefully
finally connects you to the map itself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/annarborhydflush&#34;&gt;http://www.a2gov.org/annarborhydflush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s three clicks to get to the page, with no hints anywhere
along the way about where the hydrant flushing actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there were ever a reason to put in an embedded map on any
of these pages, it would be that people are unlikely to click
through three times just in case their neighborhood is affected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan DEQ with misleading graphic on progress in Flint Water Crisis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-25-mdeq-flint-water-graphic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-25-mdeq-flint-water-graphic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As originally posted, the Michigan DEQ&amp;rsquo;s graph purports to show that
progress towards reducing lead levels in Flint is rapid. Chris Dzombak
redrew the graph to show that indeed the progress is slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;ICYMI: Final round of Sentinel Site results shows gradual improvements in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Flint?src=hash&#34;&gt;#Flint&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MtpFEC0J1w&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MtpFEC0J1w&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/EZxgObftHs&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/EZxgObftHs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Michigan DEQ (@MichiganDEQ) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MichiganDEQ/status/724661270956351489&#34;&gt;April 25, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MichiganDEQ&#34;&gt;@MichiganDEQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chronicallydave&#34;&gt;@chronicallydave&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; corrected graph: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/WnYxGwP7Wf&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/WnYxGwP7Wf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chris Dzombak (@cdzombak) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cdzombak/status/724668957756551169&#34;&gt;April 25, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The incomplete image</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-incomplete-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 23:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-incomplete-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a great Michelle Shocked song off her Texas Campfire Tapes
album called the &lt;a href=&#34;http://michelleshocked.com/ears/lyrics/the-44-troubador/&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Troubador&lt;/a&gt;
The lyrics you can find don&amp;rsquo;t capture
it all because the song has a prelude of Michelle talking about how
most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put together a song that has so many incomplete
images and that seemingly stops half way through with all of that
unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s all&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually that&amp;rsquo;s not quite all - I have this song on cassette
tape, but you won&amp;rsquo;t find it on Youtube. Michelle doesn&amp;rsquo;t
believe in Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Music is a lot like politics — too important to be left to professionals.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical slaves and the Californian ideology</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-mechanical-slaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-mechanical-slaves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Noted elsewhere, saved here for reference, from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Barbrook and Andy Cameron,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imaginaryfutures.net/2007/04/17/the-californian-ideology-2/&#34;&gt;THE CALIFORNIAN IDEOLOGY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If human slaves are ultimately unreliable, then mechanical ones
will have to be invented. The search for the holy grail of Artificial
Intelligence reveals this desire for the Golem a strong and loyal
slave whose skin is the colour of the earth and whose innards are
made of sand. As in Asimov’s Robot novels, the techno-utopians
imagine that it is possible to obtain slave like labour from inanimate
machines. Yet, although technology can store or amplify labour, it
can never remove the necessity for humans to invent, build and
maintain these machines in the first place. Slave labour cannot be
obtained without somebody being enslaved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this and then think about Siri, Cortana, &amp;ldquo;Amy Ingram&amp;rdquo; and other
long-suffering inanimate machines that we imbue so much personality
into that some of us unknowingly
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/amy-ingram-personal-assistant-2015-7&#34;&gt;flirt with a robot&lt;/a&gt; because we are so charmed by their devotion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game of Fail - HBO Now unable to host Game of Thrones premiere</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-game-of-fail-hbonow-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 21:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-game-of-fail-hbonow-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HBO Now is experiencing technical difficulties in hosting the premeire
of the popular Game of Thrones season, according to multiple reports
monitored on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our team is working to resolve as soon as possible. Check back
soon for updates.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HBONowHelp/status/724409299770982403&#34;&gt;@HBONowHelp, 9:26 p.m.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More news on this at &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.fastcompany.com/game-of-thrones-fans-getting-error-message-on-hbo-now-4004496&#34;&gt;Fast Company&lt;/a&gt;
and (of course, where else) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/gameofthrones/comments/4gb0j1/no_spoilers_hbo_now_blackout_error_message/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reddit thread has lots of suggestions, some pointing the failure
at HBO&amp;rsquo;s geolocation technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a break from Facebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-facebook-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-24-facebook-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m taking a temporary break from Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably won&amp;rsquo;t read this message in time to switch any of your
normal communciations paths with me; indeed, unless I had told you
that I was leaving Facebook idle for a while you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t notice at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d prefer it if more people were blogging, and more to the point if
I were blogging more. I miss the olden days when you could count on
people updating their blogs more than once a month and when it made
sense to make the rounds of blogrolls. But I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s just
net.nostalgia for the olden days, the same way you might say that
Flickr was better the first few years, and oh we don&amp;rsquo;t have anything
quite like the Napster that we once had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do have is Facebook, and plenty of it. A recent story somewhere
that I read somewhere (see, this media makes our brains mush) was that
people with Facebook accounts are dying, and that the Facebook we know
now will be dominated some time soon by memorials to the dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faced with that grim promise, what to do instead? Twitter is my
solace, the endless stacatto chatter punctuated by weird Unicode
glyphs, with cryptic tendencies and self-contained non-sequiturs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break. How can you tell? I&amp;rsquo;m writing again. I don&amp;rsquo;t
write on Facebook, so much as scroll endlessly and leave little
obscure comments made out of mostly-remembered lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roos Roast to add downtown Ann Arbor location</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-23-roos-roast-downtown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 13:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-23-roos-roast-downtown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roos Roast is adding a downtown Ann Arbor location, due to open
spring of 2016. The roastery on Rosewood will expand to a
second location on E Liberty St, where Elixir Vitae used to be.
Elixir will keep its Maynard St store open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interior construction in the store is going well,
as far as it&amp;rsquo;s possible to determine from looking at
the permit process and poking my head inside the door.
So far the following permits have
been pulled, according to the city&amp;rsquo;s eTrakit system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BLDG16-0317 for demolition in the existing site, approved
3/7/2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ELEC16-0449 for internal electrical wiring, approved 4/18/2016;
work by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bremray.com/&#34;&gt;Bremray Electrical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HDC16-062 to the Historic District Commission for a sign,
applied 4/18/2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLUM16-0551 for plumbing, work by Chelsea Plumbing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://etrakit.a2gov.org/etrakit3/viewAttachment.aspx?Group=PERMIT&amp;amp;ActivityNo=SIGN16-0050&amp;amp;key=WMN%3a1604190852460942&#34;&gt;SIGN16-0050&lt;/a&gt;
for an aluminum sign showing a hand holding a
cup with the Roos Roast logo, applied 4/18/2016; the sign
review is due 5/5/2016. Sign by &lt;a href=&#34;http://prototypedesigninc.com/&#34;&gt;Prototype Design&lt;/a&gt; in Tecumseh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOCC16-0024 for sidewalk occupancy, issued 4/21/2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only piece of this process that looks like it could possibly go to
a public hearing is the Historic District Commission determination
of appropriateness of signage. If this were to be the case,
a large orange poster would go up in front of the store to
announce the meeting date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sign had been approved previously for the site in 2009 when the
storefront housed &amp;ldquo;Organic Bliss&amp;rdquo;; at that point there was no
requirement for anything more than staff approval of the signage.
AnnArbor.com&amp;rsquo;s story about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/business-review/organic-bliss-to-shut-down-blaming-downtown-ann-arbors-independent-retail-environment/&#34;&gt;Organic Bliss closing in 2012&lt;/a&gt; has a photo of the storefront at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously in the news, see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roosroast.com/2016/02/deep-er-local/&#34;&gt;Deep-er Local&lt;/a&gt; on the
Roos Roast website, February 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/business/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2016/03/deep_local_comes_downtown_roos.html&#34;&gt;MLive story&lt;/a&gt;, March 1, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborobserver.com/articles/____as_john_roos_arrives_full_article.html&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Observer story&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Roos Roast finds new roost&amp;rdquo;, April 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>