<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit to the Computer and Video Game Archive, @umcvga</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-18-a-visit-to-um-cvga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-18-a-visit-to-um-cvga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/&#34;&gt;University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) Fifth Anniversary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a chance to spend some time at the U of Michigan
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guides.lib.umich.edu/cvga&#34;&gt;Computer and Video Game Archive&lt;/a&gt;
tonight, with J in tow (or perhaps I was in tow).
We played for about two hours in total, and then adjourned
for dinner to talk about new and classic gaming and game emulation.
He snuck in a few games of Tetris on his phone afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a few game reviews and observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first game I turn to at the UMCVGA is an arcade version of
Centipede. The archive has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arcadelegends.com/&#34;&gt;Arcade Legends&lt;/a&gt;
cabinet that has real arcade controls, and then emulated games
running on some kind of Linux system running MAME inside.
&amp;ldquo;Legendary arcade games authentic in every detail&amp;rdquo; says the pitch,
and the game comes with the crucial trackball that makes the
arcade version of Centipede a singular experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an Atari game, Centipede is also available on other systems, and
I looked at it on the Atari 2600, running on original hardware
including a vintage analog television set for the display. Centipede
is not very complex, and the 2600 version is faithful to the original
gameplay for the most part. The graphics are as flickery as I had
ever remembered, especially when you hit your target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reasonable life goal is to play Centipede on as many systems as
the Archive supports. The Mirlyn catalog currently suggests
that there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirlyn.lib.umich.edu/Search/Home?type%5B%5D=all&amp;amp;lookfor%5B%5D=centipede%20game&amp;amp;filter%5B%5D=format%3AVideo%20Games&#34;&gt;eight versions of Centipede&lt;/a&gt; available, on platforms including
Sega Dreamcast,
the TI-99,
Atari 2600,
Sega Genesis,
Playstation Portable (PSP),
Windows 95 / 98,
Playstation, and
Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animal Crossing on the Nintendo 3DS was new to me, though I had
heard &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chairckicker&#34;&gt;Brian Kerr&lt;/a&gt; talk about it
for quite some time. Animal Crossing is really fun in a quirky little
way that a social casual game that&amp;rsquo;s age-appropriate for seven year
olds can be. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get very far into the game, but it was clear
that every character in the game that interacted with me was super
happy to see me back in the system, and that kind of welcoming
reunion greeting was something I want to emulate myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent (January 2015) interview with David Carter (superman) on PRX
was a good 17 minute listen about the current state of the archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On PRX: &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.prx.org/stories/141395&#34;&gt;Six Years Inside the Computer &amp;amp; Video Game Archive with David Carter&lt;/a&gt; from Radio Free Culture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Carter of the Computer &amp;amp; Video Game Archive at University of
Michigan tells us about the collection, how it&amp;rsquo;s used in an academic
setting, and a little about the care and feeding of elderly video
game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a next visit already scheduled for January.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa visiting Swede&#39;s Diner, Ann Arbor, December 1950</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-santa-at-swedes-diner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 23:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-santa-at-swedes-diner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/taxonomy/term/617000&#34;&gt;Santa visiting Swede&amp;rsquo;s Diner&lt;/a&gt;, Ann Arbor, December 1950. From the
Ann Arbor District Library &amp;ldquo;Old News&amp;rdquo; collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://oldnews.aadl.org/files/imagecache/800_width/photos/N021_0585_001.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original caption: Stockings wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hold the Christmas cheer served
up by Leonard Carlstrom, proprietor of a lunch counter at 208 S.
Fifth Ave., so he used cups. Carlstrom played his own version of
Santa Clause this morning when he hung up the &amp;ldquo;free coffee&amp;rdquo; sign
to old customers and newcomers alike. &amp;ldquo;Business kind of picked up
a little,&amp;rdquo; Carlstrom noted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platforms for the Internet of Things, 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A discussion on one of the lists I follow covers the question
of &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; support for the Internet of Things. Since consumer
IoT is a kind of squooshy market right now with rapid changes
in prices and no one obvious choice for what technology to adopt,
it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile taking some kind of review of the landscape for
2015 and sort out what to watch for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is organized by vendor, and loosely grouped so that similar
systems are next to each other. It&amp;rsquo;s a highly dimensional space, but
all elements have something in common: engineers are trying to
change how we interact with simple devices like light bulbs through
our hand-held phones, and no one has the full correct answer that&amp;rsquo;s
obviously right. Indeed it&amp;rsquo;s not clear at all that there is
a right answer for some of these controls; the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/internetofshit&#34;&gt;Internet of Shit twitter account&lt;/a&gt;
collects with some glee the number of devices that emphatically should
not be on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the platforms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon&lt;/em&gt; is hard to ignore. Many smaller cloud platforms are
built on top of its AWS computing platforms, and Amazon has
entered the fray with its AWS IoT service that offers a hosted
MQTT message server. In addition Amazon has the Echo product
that does voice recognition. Nearly impossible to ignore, Amazon
is a clear central player in the IoT consumer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; is a distant second in the IoT world, mostly because
the Google Compute Engine isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a compute
platform, and the Android phone isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a top
end phone. Google does have the moxie to make it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Internet Thing&amp;rdquo;
be a self-driving car. The Nest thermostat is the most obvious
home point-of-entry for Google, and the platform and brand extension
to watch is more stuff that works with Nest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple&lt;/em&gt; has the phone to want, and the assistant (Siri) that people
have learned how to talk to to get things done. If the Internet of
Things is going to be controlled from an app, it&amp;rsquo;s an app that&amp;rsquo;s going
to run on an Apple phone, and you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to talk to it.
Less clear is Apple&amp;rsquo;s in-home device hub strategy - the AppleTV never
really has had that open platform feel to attract the first-mover developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft&lt;/em&gt; would dearly love to play in this world, but Windows 10
on ARM and the Raspberry Pi is a disappointment, and &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; is mostly
defined by problems too big for Excel. The Microsoft cloud platform,
Azure, mostly seems to be used by organizations that treat it as
a second or third data center, or who are locked in to Azure for
business and partnership reasons. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Cortana is capable, but
hardly anyone has Windows phones to talk with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IBM&lt;/em&gt; is the wild card here. Their Bluemix hosted platform service is
interesting if unusual and not really aimed at the consumer space. A
very interesting Node-RED project has extended IBM influence into
the Raspberry Pi and Bluetooth BLE sensor space, but it feels like
an interesting technology play and not a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, to major players with hardware. &amp;ldquo;How many engineers does it
take to change a lightbulb?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philips&lt;/em&gt; has the Hue line of home products, mostly lighting focused.
There was a hue and cry about the Philips decision to disable support
for some compatible products that did not have explicit partnership
agreements in place, and the nature of the complaining made it clear
that there&amp;rsquo;s an active hobbyist community around this product space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flex&lt;/em&gt; is the new player, with its recent acquisition of the
assets of Wink from the bankruptcy of Quirky.  Flex, formerly known
as Flextronics, is a large contract manufacturer, and it knows how
to build quite a few things; look for Wink&amp;rsquo;s technology to make its
way into a wider range of products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung&lt;/em&gt; and their SmartThings brand has enough market share to make
interesting efforts, but again to that point there&amp;rsquo;s no one breakout
product in their portfolio that brings that brand much to mind unless
you are using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest winner in the IoT space for this year and probably for
next year is an Internet tool with the unlikely name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifttt.com&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;ldquo;If this, then that&amp;rdquo; is the level of control you get with IFTTT,
and surprisingly enough that&amp;rsquo;s enough to do all sorts of things -
mostly because IFTTT speaks just enough of the protocols of over 100
systems that you can glue together a recipe that does something
when something else happens even when the two vendors you are dealing
with have never heard of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interoperability is the bugaboo of Internet of Things systems development.
Many vendors want you to sign up to their big bear hug of a partnership
agreement and work solely within their ecosystem. Others have narrow
APIs and proprietary protocols that discourage casual reuse. Where
IFTTT fits in is as a universal connector kit that lets you explore
how parts fit together.  The IFTTT
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/recipes/collections/32-recipes-for-the-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;recipes for the Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt; captures some of the essence of what
can be done right now without much of a fuss if you have wide protocol
support, even if it&amp;rsquo;s only very simple support.
Many vendors in the &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things&amp;rdquo;
space could benefit from thorough understanding of simple connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas E. Vielmetti, plant engineer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-douglas-vielmetti-plant-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-douglas-vielmetti-plant-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My grandfather, Douglas E. Vielmetti (center), a plant engineer at the
Alberta Saw Mill. &amp;ldquo;Ford supervisory men assemble in the engine room
on the first floor of the Alberta Mill. (L to R) John Picardat,
maintenance supt.: Alex Boivin, sawmill foreman; Douglas Vielmetti,
plant engineer; Leo Doyle, sawmill supt., and John Ryan, lumber
sales department agent.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://digarch.lib.mtu.edu/showbib.aspx?bib_id=781348&#34;&gt;http://digarch.lib.mtu.edu/showbib.aspx?bib_id=781348&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://digarch.lib.mtu.edu/images/12283_l.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alberta was a Ford saw mill from 1936 to 1954. The clothing is
timeless UP lumber gear.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN scaling</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/&#34;&gt;OpenVPN in a container&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/&#34;&gt;Split tunnels considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this running in a staging environment and a test
environment; it properly isolates OpenVPN from the underlying
operating system, and seems to do the right thing performing
rather well. However, its biggest limitation is that
it runs on a single host &amp;amp; thus provides neither
high availability in the case of Amazon &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/&#34;&gt;funkiness&lt;/a&gt;
nor scalability to handle lots of clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting this to be more reliable was a matter of tracking
down the right systemd configuration. I&amp;rsquo;ll save systemd
commentary for a separate post, saying only that it&amp;rsquo;s new,
it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily better for managing single machines,
but I can see the advantages for consolidated management of
big collections of machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some OpenVPN config alternatives to pursue that look like they might do
the right thing are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudcoreo.com&#34;&gt;CloudCoreo&lt;/a&gt; has a setup based on the Amazon Elastic Load Balancer.
They say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an OpenVPN config up and running in AWS is difficult. We&amp;rsquo;ve already done it for you in an HA, durable, self-healing way. This blog post details how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog post is in two sections.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cloudcoreo.com/single-points-of-failure-openvpn/&#34;&gt;Part one&lt;/a&gt; details how they
configured autoscaling, elastic load balancing, name service, S3
storage and policies, and security and IAM policies to set things
up the way that you would want them within Amazon&amp;rsquo;s AWS.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cloudcoreo.com/single-points-of-failure-openvpn-part-2-of-2/&#34;&gt;Part two&lt;/a&gt; goes on to describe the particular OpenVPN policy
and routing setup, and there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of policy there particularly
with the use of split tunnels that you want to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their claim that they have
&amp;ldquo;done it all for you&amp;rdquo; reflects a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hub.cloudcoreo.com/stack/servers-vpn_c6a65&#34;&gt;complete configuration&lt;/a&gt; available
through their CloudCoreo system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second approach is detailed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.zalando.com&#34;&gt;Zalando&lt;/a&gt;, a Berlin based retail fashion platform.
Their article &lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.zalando.com/blog/building-an-openvpn-cluster-zalando-style/&#34;&gt;Building an OpenVPN Cluster, Zalando-Style&lt;/a&gt;
uses dynamic routing to distribute routes, and the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga&lt;/a&gt; system as their software based router. This setup
does not particularly depend on AWS features, and they
claim that
&amp;ldquo;With this set up, we have about 800 users (150 in parallel) and haven’t faced any performance issues at anytime, from anywhere!&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more complex to set up, though the writeup
makes it clear that because of the flexibility that dynamic
routing gives you there&amp;rsquo;s the opportunity to construct
firewall policies that follow the user quite independent
of how they are connecting to the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complex system that works is invariably found to have evolved from a simple system that worked. A complex system designed from scratch never works and cannot be patched up to make it work. You have to start over, beginning with a working simple system. (John Gall, Systemantics)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am eating a sandwich, with a recipe in Github</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-14-i-am-eating-a-sandwich-github-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-14-i-am-eating-a-sandwich-github-recipes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter is, of course, for telling people that you are eating a sandwich.
That&amp;rsquo;s been the point of the system the whole time - long before selfies,
even long before it took pictures at all, you might get a proper narrative
of what people are eating for lunch or a snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the net to keep track of food is an old tradition; I need
only point you at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lysator.liu.se/etexts/recept/main.html&#34;&gt;Usenet Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;,
developed from 1985 to 1987 by Brian Reid, as an archetype.
&amp;ldquo;I had a lettuce and tomato sandwich Saturday with mustard instead of mayonnaise. Better than I would have feared.&amp;rdquo; But that collection is
weak on sandwiches, lending itself more to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lysator.liu.se/etexts/recept/us/SP-menu.html&#34;&gt;soups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remedy this need I have started a small and pitiful but
hopefully growable sandwich recipe collection, using Github
as the hosting place of choice. See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vielmetti/sandwich&#34;&gt;the vielmetti/sandwich repository&lt;/a&gt;
for the first start. As it happens, I am clearly not the only person
to think this way; herewith some collection of sandwich collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barrie Turner (@bazbt3) came up with roughly the same idea at the same
time, and you might see his &lt;a href=&#34;http://bazbt3.re-app.net/2015/12/10/git-sandwiches/&#34;&gt;git sandwiches&lt;/a&gt; blog for the proper inspiration for collection
development. Thanks to @ellemef for connecting us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Single sandwiches in git include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/magnus919/grilledcheese&#34;&gt;grilled cheese&lt;/a&gt;, from Magnus Hedemark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pcon/recipes/tree/master/meals/fried_chicken_sandwich&#34;&gt;gluten free fried chicken sandwich&lt;/a&gt; from Patrick Connelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and certainly many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are ill-equipped in your kitchen
to make your own sandwiches, this command line tool will
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/travist/makemeasandwich.js&#34;&gt;order you a sandwich from Jimmy John&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;. It comes with a makefile so that you invoke it as
&lt;code&gt;sudo make me a sandwich&lt;/code&gt; and it will do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to everyone for birthday wishes, 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-10-thanks-for-birthday-wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 14:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-10-thanks-for-birthday-wishes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for birthday wishes this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is increasingly clear that the place to go for birthday greetings
is Facebook, which is absurdly efficient both at providing
&amp;ldquo;happy birthday&amp;rdquo; messages as well as acknowledging them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional greetings came in via email, Skype, Twitter, and
paper mail (hand written!, complete with reply postage!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch at a2b3 was a Thursday event, with 14 at the table at Blue Nile.
The topic of the conversation was roughly &amp;ldquo;places to take a walk
outside in the winter&amp;rdquo;, and the dog-owners among us amended to include
&amp;ldquo;with a dog&amp;rdquo;, and we got a pretty good list that I want to get
onto Arborwiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always the Arborwiki &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Birthday_Deals&#34;&gt;birthday deals&lt;/a&gt;
page came through, and I scored freebies or discounts at
Northside Grill (breakfast sandwich), Roos Roast (mocha),
Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s Bakery (bread) and Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s Coffee (coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical commentary of the year is that Twitter has an
opportunity to step up its birthday game, and it would seem
that that&amp;rsquo;s a chance to do things right (or do things differently
from Facebook, at least).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the next time around the sun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requesting meeting minutes under the Open Meetings Act</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-08-open-meetings-act-minutes-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-08-open-meetings-act-minutes-request/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated in the past at the slow pace of getting meeting minutes
through Freedom of Information Act requests. Queries to the City of Ann Arbor
routinely get the full round of routine delays, with several cases where I&amp;rsquo;ve
had to wait 15 business days to get routine meeting minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, there&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to asking for minutes, using the
Michigan Open Meetings Act directly as your guide. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recent request
that gave me same-day results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello, this is a request under the Michigan Open Meetings Act.

Please make available for inspection the draft minutes of the (named)
Committee meeting of today, December 8, 2015.

Under the terms of the Act, draft minutes are to be made available
for inspection within 8 business days of the date of the meeting,
or by my calendar December 18, 2015.

(Name) is listed as the staff contact for this board.

Thank you for your cooperation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The request was routed to the staff member, and the minutes were prepared
and ready and shared with me the same day that the meeting was held.
Same day service!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodi, formerly XMBC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-07-kodi-formerly-xmbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-07-kodi-formerly-xmbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kodi.tv&#34;&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt; as a possible software
core for home media player for the living room. We have a whole
rack of CDs and a shelf of LPs from our music-buying days, and I
miss being able to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kodi is the software formerly known as XMBC, and XMBC is still
the name of the foundation that supports the work. It runs on
most systems, and there are several distributions of it specifically
for systems like the Raspberry Pi. in particular the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.openelec.tv/index.php/OpenELEC_FAQ&#34;&gt;OpenELEC&lt;/a&gt;
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a review or a how to, just some notes so that when
I come back to the task I will have a better running start at it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Farber talk at Stanford</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-dave-farber-stanford-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-dave-farber-stanford-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk at Stanford, &amp;ldquo;Backwards towards the Future&amp;rdquo;,
Dave Farber goes over some Internet history on the way to
suggesting some necessary features of the future network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wCl-bKaER-s&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split tunnels considered harmful</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://meyerweb.com/eric/comment/chech.html&#34;&gt;Considered harmful essays considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;, Eric Meyer, 2002; also Go To Statement Considered Harmful, CACM, 1968; also &lt;a href=&#34;http://harmful.cat-v.org/&#34;&gt;Encyclopedia of things considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;, from cat-v.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split tunnels are a VPN construction where instead of
sending all of your traffic for the network in a single
encrypted tunnel that collects everything, you instead
route some traffic down the encrypted link and other traffic
goes in the clear through your default connection. It&amp;rsquo;s
possible that you might have a tunnel configuration with
multiple splits if e.g. you needed to get to private
address space at two or more organizations simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a choice, don&amp;rsquo;t use a split tunnel. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost are security considerations. The user of
the split tunnel introduces a possible forwarding path between
the outside Internet world (full of nefarious intent) and
the inside Internet world that you have a secure path to and
its chewy center. If an attacker knows that you are using a
split tunnel, they can put something on the public Internet
that causes you to send their traffic directly through to your private
network while you have all your trust relationships intact.
This could be bad, and if your security instincts trend towards
professional paranoia, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand that there&amp;rsquo;s a real risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second security consideration is unplanned leakage of private
information into the Internet. The split tunnel in its ordinary
configuration expects that you can distinguish protected traffic
from unprotected traffic by its IP address. The nature of
the modern Internet is that a browser can and will connect to
dozens or hundreds of hosts on its way to filling out a web page,
and any one of those connections might expose or leak some
information about what you were doing on the &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; link
that could be of use to an adversary or snoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, split tunnels are difficult to verify as correctly
configured. The managed endpoint of the tunnel can only see
traffic destined for it, and can only verify that what&amp;rsquo;s
there is going to the endpoint. With a split, the managed
endpoint doesn&amp;rsquo;t have visibility into all traffic destinations
and thus is completely unaware of any exfiltration attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there may be reasons that a split tunnel is unavoidable.
Here are some considerations to balance against the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A split tunnel is more versatile than a full tunnel. If your
users need to connect to more than one administrative domain
simultaenously, they may need to configure their local host
setup to have two or more split tunnels running at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the tunnel endpoint is at the long end of a slow connection,
or if the trusted managed endpoint is bandwidth or CPU constrained,
performance through a full tunnel may be unacceptably bad.
Splitting the tunnel means that only necessary traffic goes through
it, allowing better use of network resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s the cost. If the user is going to be a typical
Internet use and do simultaneous Spotify or Netflix or other
streaming media, it seems insane to pay VPN charges or engineer
your own VPN endpoint to handle that full stream of data when it
could very easily go over a lowest-cost unencrypted link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The productivity oscillator</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-the-productity-oscillator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Github issues for a long time as a todo list
tracking and general productivity tool. It works well enough that
I&amp;rsquo;ve opened over 4000 issues and have closed most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perpetual management challenge is in deciding how many issues
is OK to leave open. Put too few in, and it feels like you have
things to do that are not written down; put in too many, and you&amp;rsquo;re
likely to have duplication and you forget what it is that you were
trying to do in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of the challenge is having some illusion of
control over what is going on. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to work the queue
this way. Some times my goal will be to create more open issues,
putting things on the list to increase it up to a target goal.
Other times the goal will be to reduce the size of the list by
finishing tasks, clearing duplicates, or deciding not to get things
done. By framing it as a deliberate game of &amp;ldquo;add tasks up to a
target&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;clear tasks down to a target&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to trick
myself into taking on the easy things that I wrote down a month
ago that will take a minute to do but are off my immediate radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The productivity oscillator suggests both a pattern of work and
the illusion that whatever you are doing is the right thing to do.
If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck trying to get stubborn things accomplished, write
done some new easy goals and get those taken care of. It&amp;rsquo;s
a quantified form of &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/04/marginally_usef.html&#34;&gt;structured procrastination&lt;/a&gt; - which it turns out
I&amp;rsquo;ve been talknig about for 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if there&amp;rsquo;s anything still on my todo list from 2005!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicked out of Nextdoor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-kicked-out-of-nextdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 19:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-02-kicked-out-of-nextdoor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Subject: Recent Tweet about Nextdoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Ed,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Michael and I work at Nextdoor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently it has come to our attention that there isn’t a Nextdoor
for your neighborhood, and that you have registered in a nearby
Nextdoor neighborhood. Thank you for your interest in joining
Nextdoor and becoming part of your community on our website. However
we do need people to register at their real addresses, as it helps
us add a sense of accountability, security and transparency to the
website. Due to privacy concerns, I am forced to place a hold on
your account. However, this need not be a long hold! If you give
me your address, you and I can work on building a neighborhood for
you together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know how you would like to proceed. I am excited to
get you started on your new Nextdoor neighborhood soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your day,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Michael [Last name redacted for privacy]
Nextdoor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Wanted, Ann Arbor City Administrator, via Craiglist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-30-ann-arbor-city-administrator-craigslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 20:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-30-ann-arbor-city-administrator-craigslist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://annarbor.craigslist.org/gov/5338653370.html&#34;&gt;As seen on Craigslist.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City Administrator (Ann Arbor) compensation: $150K/yr employment type: full-time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Administrator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job Responsibilities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed Council Members information on a bi-weekly schedule, sometimes more frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind Council Members of basic stuff like how object permanence is an actual thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond appropriately when Council Members insist &amp;ldquo;I can do it all by my self.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond appropriately when Council Members say &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how, you do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let Council Members feel they&amp;rsquo;re in control, but not so much that they wreck stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10-15 years experience in child care setting, with increasing responsibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to feign genuine interest in oddball ideas of Council Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversant in full range of ways Ann Arbor residents feel superior to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability look at a roomful of white people and remark on amazing diversity of perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attached to your resume, please respond with an essay on the topic
of: Is Public Engagement for the Birds, or for the Deer or for the
Dog Parks? Into the natural flow of your essay, please integrate
an answer to the question: If you were a dog, what kind of tree
would you choose to pee on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dave Askins for noticing this (via Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2015 food inspections for Washtenaw County</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-27-october-2015-food-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-27-october-2015-food-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month or so the Washtenaw County Health Department releases the previous month&amp;rsquo;s
health inspection reports. These are published to the county&amp;rsquo;s contracted web service,
and a copy of those is extracted for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/&#34;&gt;Food Inspections&lt;/a&gt;
service designed by Wayne Eaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 272 inspections for October 2015 and 50 more for November 2015 available. Here
are some of the low lights of this month&amp;rsquo;s round of inspections, places where you might
want to think about twice before making a visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-11-03-dalat-restaurant&#34;&gt;Dalat&lt;/a&gt;,
Ypsilanti, inspected on November 3. &amp;ldquo;Observed sewage backing up to
the floor underneath the food prep sink.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Raw chicken and beef
boxes being used to store other ready to eat foods (i.e. vegtables)
in various coolers in the facility.&amp;rdquo; 12 violations total, 8 critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-11-02-melting-pot&#34;&gt;Melting Pot&lt;/a&gt;,
Ann Arbor, their last inspection on November 2 before the restaurant closed
for good later in the month. &amp;ldquo;Observed the dishwasher go from loading soiled dishes to putting away clean dishes without washing hands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-21-great-plains-burger-company&#34;&gt;Great Plains Burger Company&lt;/a&gt;,
Ann Arbor, inspected on October 21 with 14 total violations.
&amp;ldquo;Observed many small flies (fruit flies) around prep sink where french fries are prepared.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Containers used to store french fries observed soiled. A cleaned inverted container observed with many flies trapped under it and were seen landing on container.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-29-shalimar-restaurant&#34;&gt;Shalimar Restaraunt&lt;/a&gt;
on Main Street in Ann Arbor, inspected on October 29 with 3 total violations.
&amp;ldquo;Observed 4 bottles of liquor with flies inside.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-10-21-haabs-restaurant&#34;&gt;Haab&amp;rsquo;s Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;
in Ypsilanti with 15 violations on October 21.
&amp;ldquo;Observed the hand sink for the basement kitchen wrapped in plastic wrap to avoid using due to unrepair leaking.
The only available hand sink is in another area through a door and significant distance away from this kitchen.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Observed severe infestation of drain flies noted at bar and main kitchen.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Observed drain flies in the bottom of open bottle of scotch at bar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check out your favorite destination before visiting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>