<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Write one paragraph, floss one tooth</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-write-one-paragraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-write-one-paragraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The a2b3 lunch today was at Madras Masala, we had a crowd of 10.
I had a question about productivity - &amp;ldquo;what do you do every day&amp;rdquo; -
and the answers were a good mix of attempts to be diligent and
questions about whether narrowly focused productivity was even
a good goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The small productivity approach that has stuck with me is BJ Fogg&amp;rsquo;s
&amp;ldquo;Tiny Habits&amp;rdquo; approach, which he writes about on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyhabits.com/&#34;&gt;http://tinyhabits.com/&lt;/a&gt; .
The focus is not on New Years Resolution style &amp;ldquo;be a better person&amp;rdquo; goals,
but on very small and attainable accompishments which you can use
to build upon. &amp;ldquo;Floss one tooth&amp;rdquo; is the smallest example goal I can give,
with the understanding that if you can build up a solid habit to do
that every day then there&amp;rsquo;s lots more you can do for better dental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing equivalent of that is &amp;ldquo;write one paragraph&amp;rdquo;. I know that
trying to blog every single day is a task I&amp;rsquo;ve tried and failed before,
but I also know that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take forever to write a paragraph, and
you don&amp;rsquo;t have to have more than one idea to express to make that paragraph
worthwhile. Faced with an impossibly big deadline for an impossibly big
project, the thought goes, you might break down your resistance to working
on the effort by declaring victory at the paragraph level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week&amp;rsquo;s lunch (the day after Thanksgiving 2015) is at Morgan and York,
hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine, old school email</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-alpine-old-school-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-19-alpine-old-school-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;alpine is an old school Unix mail user agent. It first arrived
on the scene as pine in 1992, and when it appeared I remember
how happy I was that there was finally a mailer that I could
hand to people who had never seen Unix before and that they
would get it and be productive on their 14.4 kb/sec dialup
modems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alpine appeared in 2007 as a rewrite of pine with Unicode
support and a new Apache license. The version of it I&amp;rsquo;m running
advertises itself as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Alpine 2.20 (OSX 67 2015-01-07) built Fri Oct 2 21:36:59 EDT 2015 on Edwards-MacBook-Air.local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and seems to work just fine. I&amp;rsquo;ve got it pointed at the
old-school shared multiuser mail system that I&amp;rsquo;ve had
for a long time at monkey.org and all is well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rubenerd weblog has a nice
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/p3302/&#34;&gt;guide to installing alpine on OS X&lt;/a&gt;
using your favorite package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of alpine over all web-based
mail systems is just how fast you can delete mail.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to select by pattern, sort, refile and
especially delete. In comparison, Google&amp;rsquo;s GMail
feels clumsy and slow and impossibly mouse-dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I moved all my email over to alpine? No. There&amp;rsquo;s
a very small number of people who I prefer to send
mail to that way, and it&amp;rsquo;s always good to have a
fully functional backup email system that works
perfectly well on a low-bandwidth setup. My workflow
inside GMail is pretty fine tuned at this point and
very different from how I used to use pine, and I&amp;rsquo;m
not willing to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does remind me of the days before spam, and of the
days when you were actually happy to get messages!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2016 construction plans for M-14 near Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-m-14-summer-2016-construction-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-m-14-summer-2016-construction-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MDOT plans to do major road construction work on M-14 in Ann Arbor
between Main Street and Miller Road during the spring and summer of 2016.
A construction start date has not been set yet as of November 2015.
In addition, bridge work will reduce M-14 to one lane between I-94
and Miller Road, and betwen Main Street and US-23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed set of plans is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.gov/mdot/0,4616,7-151-9621_11008_74324---,00.html&#34;&gt;on the MDOT web site&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigan.gov/documents/mdot/MDOT_M14AnnArborBrochure_504933_7.pdf&#34;&gt;in a helpful brochure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posted detour for M-14 will follow US-23 and I-94 around the freeway
loop around Ann Arbor. The following bridges will also have work done on
that that will close them for some amount of time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over the Huron River, the railroad tracks and Bandemer Park,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over Beechwood Drive,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newport Road over M-14,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M-14 over Maple Road, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miller Road over M-14.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was talk of a part of Bandemer Park to be used as a staging area
for MDOT construction equipment. A review of the city&amp;rsquo;s Legistar system
did not unearth anything that would have been a necessary city review or
approval of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Chuck Warpehoski for the heads up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I give up on LinkedIn yet?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-can-i-give-up-on-linkedin-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-18-can-i-give-up-on-linkedin-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about deleting my LinkedIn account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an early adopter of LinkedIn back when it first got started.
It was interesting, fun, cool to collect all your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my sense is that my LinkedIn profile is useless at best and
actively unhelpful at worst. Why would I want to publish a standardized
autobiography of work experience in a medium that doesn&amp;rsquo;t reward
complicated life histories? It&amp;rsquo;s not helpful - what&amp;rsquo;s more, it&amp;rsquo;s
not clear that it&amp;rsquo;s ever been helpful for the narrowly defined task
of getting work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in hearing from you if you have deleted your LinkedIn
(or have stayed away from it).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Localwiki for Jackson, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-17-a-localwiki-for-jackson-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 23:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-17-a-localwiki-for-jackson-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is now a Localwiki instance up and running for Jackson, Michigan. See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/jackson/&#34;&gt;https://localwiki.org/jackson/&lt;/a&gt; for the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any Localwiki just starting out, it is woefully incomplete. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome
to contribute to it, especially if you have some local knowledge of the area.
The site was seeded with a handful of articles that had been created from the
adjacent Arborwiki, and while it&amp;rsquo;s starting up we&amp;rsquo;re using the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/268836399886132/&#34;&gt;Arborwiki Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; to help
push things along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to discover a new place is through the restaurants that have
some local notability but that aren&amp;rsquo;t at the usual highway exits. The first
discovery from the Jackson Localwiki is the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/jackson/West_Texas_BBQ&#34;&gt;West Texas BBQ&lt;/a&gt; on Brooklyn Rd
south of the city. &amp;ldquo;Authentic Texas pit style barbeque&amp;rdquo; is the attraction. Haven&amp;rsquo;t
been there myself, but now that I know it&amp;rsquo;s there it will be worth a detour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor&#39;s The Melting Pot is closing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-melting-pot-closing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-melting-pot-closing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Melting Pot in downtown Ann Arbor is closing as of today, November 16, 2015,
according to a post on the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s web site and a story in MLive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last regular inspection of The Melting Pot by the Washtenaw County Health
Department was on May 26, 2015. It turned up 11 violations, and some of them
would be the sort of problems that would make you not want to go back.
A &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-05-26-melting-pot&#34;&gt;copy of the inspection report&lt;/a&gt; makes for tough reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observed the following: 1. Blackberries with mold like growth. 2. Mascapone: 2 - &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;27&lt;/sub&gt;. 12 &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt;. - Past date. 3. 3 butter milks &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt;. - Past date. 4. Prosciutto 10/13/2014.- Past date. 5. Two half &amp;amp; half &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt;.- Past date. 6. Two whole milks &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt;.- Past date. 7. Bush mills whiskey had fly&amp;rsquo;s floating around in bottle. 8. Dewars white label scotch had fly&amp;rsquo;s floating around in bottle. 9. Cutty Sark Whisky had fly&amp;rsquo;s floating around in bottle. FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED, and, as specified under # 3-601.12, honestly presented. (P) To correct discard all noted items into the garbage. Corrected: Person in charge discarded all noted items into the garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The restaurant should be inspected every 6 months, which means that their
routine inspection should be in November 2015. I&amp;rsquo;ve sent a query to the
county health deparment to determine if the restaurant was inspected yet
this month, and if so what the results were.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA update for tonight&#39;s City Council meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-foia-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-foia-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that my pattern of going to public meetings includes writing FOIA
requests during the meeting, to try to unearth some details of a matter observed
at that meeting. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief update on some FOIA requests in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washtenaw County Health Department. I&amp;rsquo;m temporarily stymied in my quest to
determine how often restaurants ask the county to change their inspection reports
before they are published. An initial request came back with an estimate of $6000
to comb through every file in the department; an amended request looking for only
30 days of records only limited the cost to $1000. The issue at hand is that the
county routinely delays publication of inspections by a month (or more), making it
likely that restaurants with really bad inspections can put the public at risk
for days before anyone is notified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority. I asked for details on a FOIA fee appeal
that was on the agenda for the November 4, 2015 meeting. This came back on November 12.
Dave Askins requested a set of documents from the DDA and was presented with an
estimate for the cost of those records; he chose not to pay that amount, preferring
instead to appeal the decision on fees to the board. The draft minutes of the
November 4, 2015 meeting are not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City of Ann Arbor, Executive Committee of the City Planning Commission. I requested
meeting minutes and agendas for this board and the names of the members of this board.
My request of November 2, 2015 was responded to with a delay to November 24, 2015.
The Open Meetings Act requires that draft minutes be available within 8 days of
a meeting, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be appealing this delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City of Ann Arbor, Advisory Development Committee. This committee has meetings that
are open to the public regarding development matters, but the meetings themselves
are not advertised through the usual channels of publication for meetings. I&amp;rsquo;ve asked
for records of this group and was given a similar 15 business day delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOIA is the world&amp;rsquo;s worst search engine - results come back very slowly, and they
are not always the same as the question you asked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every day people</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-every-day-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-16-every-day-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I admire people who can tackle an ambitious task every single day. Heck,
I even admire them for doing some kind of nuisance task that still needs
to be done every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My every day challenge is to write. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get off that habit if you
make too much of it, and it&amp;rsquo;s way too easy to endlessly read the endless
Internet, mutter under your breath about how foolish it all is, and not
write down your bit of foolishness in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: write something, publish it, call it a success for today. The next
day, reset the counters all to zero, and do the same. You don&amp;rsquo;t hope to
have any dramatic results on day one, but maybe over time the results add up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the FOIA request costs too much, ask for less</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-09-foia-ask-for-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-09-foia-ask-for-less/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked for some documents from Washtenaw County, and they estimated that
it would cost over $6100 to produce the records. Apparently the nature of
the request was such that they would have had to review 1200 separate
files each individually on paper to determine a response. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have
a $6100 line item in my budget to pay for it, so the best charitable
response is &amp;ldquo;no thanks&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a question that I want to get at, though, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s attainable
for less than $6100. How frequently does a restaurant owner appeal or
protest the results of an inspection, and what sorts of things do they
complain about? To get some idea of what&amp;rsquo;s going on I don&amp;rsquo;t need two years
of inspection disputes; 30 days would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how frequent these appeals are, whether there&amp;rsquo;s a form that
gets filled out of if it&amp;rsquo;s done by phone or email, and what the results
are. I do know that Washtenaw County routinely delays publication of routine
inspections by 30 days or more to allow time for appeals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the bother? Well, when a restaurant gets an awful inspection, it&amp;rsquo;s in
the public interest to publicize that promptly rather than wait weeks for
resolution. We saw this in Philadelphia, in this
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.philly.com/beta?wss=/philly/health/special_reports/clean-plates&amp;amp;id=339602512&#34;&gt;philly.com story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city Health Department, which has had a long-standing policy of keeping restaurant inspection reports secret for 30 days, announced Monday that it will move to publicly post the reports &amp;ldquo;as quickly as possible.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 30-day delay meant that diners could unknowingly patronize restaurants cited for serious hygiene problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that 30 days worth of county records will be enough to discern
a pattern. Do restaurant owners routinely challenge the results of inspections?
Does the county modify their reports based on these challenges? Without
knowing anything about how the process goes, the inclination I have is to
want to have the same changes that were recently put in place in Philadelphia:
prompt publication of serious hygeine problems is a benefit to public health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes and agendas</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-06-minutes-and-agendas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-06-minutes-and-agendas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor planned 49 public meetings last month; 5 of them
were cancelled. Of the remaining 44, 25 have meeting details posted to
the city&amp;rsquo;s Legistar calendar, and 19 have no record of the meeting
beyond its date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City boards and commissions and committees that routinely meet without publishing
minutes or agendas to Legistar include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cable Communications Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commission on Disability Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Council Administration Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Council Rules Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downtown Area Citizens Advisory Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downtown Development Authority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Dean Fund Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Rights Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Park Advisory Commission Dog Park Subcommittee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, the Downtown Area Citizens Advisory Council and the Downtown Development
Authority post minutes to the DDA&amp;rsquo;s web site. The remainder have no obvious
record or trail of their activities, decision making, or agendas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The omission of minutes from two of these boards is particularly
distressing. The Human Rights Commission labors in obscurity, not
reporting out any of its meetings to the public, even as it is a
focal point for the response to the shooting of Aura Rosser last year.
And the Commission on Disability Issues doesn&amp;rsquo;t manage to produce
a record that is accessible by people whose preferred medium is written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been through the long, slow, drawn out ritual of asking the city
for minutes of meetings before. In 2010, I sent in a series of FOIA
requests that prompted the city&amp;rsquo;s Historic District Commission to produce
meeting minutes from that year, after being originally told that those
minutes did not exist. The city rectified that problem eventually, and
now those minutes routinely show up on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agendas of city meetings are key to understanding when you might
want to lift yourself up from your easy chair and get downtown to
weigh in on decision making at the city level. Minutes are important
as a record of what actually happened. Groups like the Human Rights
Commission, which is actively looking to advance its agenda, should
be working harder to make sure that the people can see what they are
up to. Otherwise you hold a meeting and spend time away from your
kids and there&amp;rsquo;s no record of it - why did you bother?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Github issues and open source projects</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-04-open-github-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-04-open-github-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a first approximation, the number of open issues on an open source
project that uses Github to track its issues is a metric of software
complexity and project maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always worrisome to look at a project that has very few issues,
because that&amp;rsquo;s usually a signal that no one else is using the code.
Every bit of software has incomplete features that prompt a request,
and bugs looking for a fix. No open issues at all suggest a dead
project, or at least one that&amp;rsquo;s not actively attracting development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many issues, on the other hand, suggest a system that&amp;rsquo;s so
complex that no one person has a complete understanding of how
the project works. The number of issues can grow beyond the point
where a person could read and understand all the incoming bug
reports and feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every successful open source project deals with the struggle between
adding new features to fill out the original vision of the designers
and fixing enough bugs to make the system stable enough that it
can be used in production without undue fears. This tug-of-war between
features and bug fixes plays itself out over time, and sometimes
difficult and complex bugs that only affect a few users get
deprioritized over shiny new features that will attract a lot of
new people to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many open issues can one person track? I&amp;rsquo;ll estimate that the
number is about 100, plus or minus. So when a two person project
has 50 open issues, it seems like it&amp;rsquo;s under control. A project
that has over 1000 open issues (e.g. docker) can only raise some
warning flags - how did it get to be so big? What sorts of issues
can stick around for years and not get resolved? How on earth does
one profess to have any overall understanding of a system that
complex, short of devoting themselves to it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.abevoelker.com/why-i-dont-use-docker-much-anymore/&#34;&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t use Docker much anymore&lt;/a&gt;, Abe Voelker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open City Hall and government by survey</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-open-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 21:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-open-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Open City Hall&amp;rdquo; is a survey instrument used to gather answers to
multiple choice questions. Municipal officials - it&amp;rsquo;s not clear who - put
together questions, and citizens are encouraged to tell the city what they
think by providing answers. It&amp;rsquo;s run by Peak Democracy, which provides this
same service to a number of municipalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current question under review is development on the Library Lot in downtown
Ann Arbor. The city has narrowed down the question to proposals from two
developers, and then posts questions like these gems to try to gauge public
sentiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CA Ventures&#39; proposal has an attractive, aesthetically-pleasing
design and/or conveys an iconic image suitable for a site that is
in the core of downtown.

Core Ventures&#39; proposal articulates a commitment to developing,
maintaining and managing an attractive public open-space.

Core Spaces&#39; proposed development will provide a return on the
City’s investment in the Library Lot parking garage and contribute
to the tax base in Ann Arbor.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far a grand total of 19 people have filled out this form, ticking
one of the boxes (ranging from &amp;ldquo;strongly disagree&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;strongly agree&amp;rdquo;)
giving their opinion. There&amp;rsquo;s no spot in the survey form for any kind of
open-ended response about the proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it make sense for a citizen to spend the time filling out these
(poorly constructed) survey forms, or would it be better to spend
your civic engagement time elsewhere? Checking check-boxes is about
as weak a signal of engagement as I can imagine, and the low turnout
means that the survey itself is not likely to be listened to very closely.
You&amp;rsquo;d be better off writing a thoughtful letter and addressing it to
someone - anyone, really - to share your opinion. Or show up at a public
meeting (there are many of them) and say your 3 minutes when public
comment time is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checking check-boxes on survey forms is a far cry from citizen engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Twitter vs Facebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-halloween-twitter-vs-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 16:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-halloween-twitter-vs-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The two online social networks that consume idle cycles for me are Twitter and
Facebook. They really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be all that different, but of course they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halloween Twitter for me was full of football, ranging from idle banter about
the score to full-on intense #goblue insanity as the game went down to its
final moments. (The Team won, 29-26, after The Other Team made a crucial mistake
at the end). You didn&amp;rsquo;t have to have a radio or television to know the score
and all of the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halloween Facebook was full of faces of cute kids and sharp-looking costumes
and accounts of how many trick-or-treaters showed up at the most popular spots.
(1,036 pieces of candy given out, one per kid, at the hotspot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter works best when there are a lot of people all synchronized on the same
event - it&amp;rsquo;s a remarkably good companion to television or broadcast radio in that
way. Unlike the dreams of &amp;ldquo;Interactive Television&amp;rdquo; of the 1990s, the broadcast
channel and the return channel are completely different, but the effect is the
same: the audience is connected to what it&amp;rsquo;s listening to and to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook doesn&amp;rsquo;t have that same everyone-is-watching feel, but it makes up for
it by biasing the feed that you get towards pictures of faces of friends and family.
Even though there&amp;rsquo;s generally plenty of real-time content to go around, Facebook
makes sure you&amp;rsquo;re not lonely by encouraging you to post more pictures from years gone
by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to disconnect more from both networks - they absorb time without suitable
compensation - and write more elsewhere. We spend too much of our time looking
for favorites, thumbs up, and likes on both networks, calibrating the success of
our writing by how many random people in the random world clicked a certain button
in response. Still they both provide a measure of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium, pretty but disappointing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-medium-pretty-but-disappointing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-medium-pretty-but-disappointing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Medium is a hosted blogging and discussion board at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.medium.com&#34;&gt;http://www.medium.com&lt;/a&gt; .
It&amp;rsquo;s run by Evan Williams, who built Blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is very pretty and functional, both for writers and for readers.
Authors get a lovely HTML based editor to write their text in, and readers
can do highlights and annotations. From a purely technical point of view it&amp;rsquo;s
one of the better systems for typing into on the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, the promise of a pretty system does not extend the promise
that everything that&amp;rsquo;s written there will be smart and interesting.
One recent essay posted to the site complains that it&amp;rsquo;s been &amp;ldquo;hijacked
by life-hack gurus, designers and San Francisco people&amp;rdquo;. The page that
Medium provides as a home page for me bears this out - there&amp;rsquo;s an
extended discussion of &amp;ldquo;MCT Oil&amp;rdquo; (whatever that is, some diet fad),
advice about venture capital, &amp;ldquo;8 steps for &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;23 great places for &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;,
and &amp;ldquo;How You Train Your Brain To Get What You Really Want&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the pretty in the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help if you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded
by life-hack, growth-hack, *-hack content, which all smell like
thinly veiled self-promotion or advertising pitches. A steady diet
of this kind of writing is soul-killing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in the end, disappointing. Shiny on the outside, nice fonts, good
use of whitespace, but uninspired content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack vs IRC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-slack-vs-irc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-01-slack-vs-irc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IRC is an old-school multi-system, multi-channel, multi-network chat infrastructure.
It dates from the 1980s, and was inspired in part by the BITNET RELAY systems that
effectively sent messages from mainframe to message over virtual punch cards.
RFC 1459 described the protocol in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack is a shiny new system also providing multi-channel, multi-network chat.
It&amp;rsquo;s very much a product of the 2010s, emerging in 2013 after being used for
an internal communications channel at a games company. It&amp;rsquo;s currently valued
at a bazillion dollars in the frothy VC environment of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRC is open, reasonably well documented, and available to all through a plethora
of servers, clients, and web gateways. If you want to set up an IRC network
no one will get in your way, except perhaps your own ability to determine
which version of which server will work best with which version of which other
server. Once you build an IRC network out you have no one standing in your way
of doing whatever you want to do except your own technical capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack, by contrast, is completely and thoroughly a 2010s private company. There
are private Slack networks that cost real money ($x/user/mo), and public Slack
networks which are free but only free because Slack-the-company has decided that
they want to provide some free usage tier to help kickstart their growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest different between the two systems is ease of use. You can get up and
running with Slack by just providing a credit card, and all of the details are
taken care of for you complete with tech and developer support. For IRC you are
totally on your own, and the DIY denizens of that network are mostly friendly
but not always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most old-school of old-school Unix people I know still use
private IRC running on a local server, accessable only via SSH
with all members of the network personally vetted by the cadre
of sysadmins who run it. I like it that I have access to that
brain trust, but the more typical use of Slack for me this year
is the relatively large mostly public networks that have been
set up to support an event or keep a community together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much has been made of how incorrect it is for open source projects
to use a closed-source system for discussion. A few projects using
Slack have discovered that they are too big for the free services
that Slack is willing to provide, and they are looking for new homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike most of the late-1980s public systems (eg. Usenet or Gopher)
IRC is still alive and mostly vigorous. But IRC will never be
pretty or cuddly or ironic in the way that a venture-funded Slack
seems to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>