<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy: Greystone Jazz rescue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Detroit Sound Conservancy went to the vacant Book Building
in Detroit on July 7, 2015 to salvage the collection of the
defunct Graystone International Jazz Museum. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice
writeup in MLive, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/detroit/index.ssf/2015/07/non-profit_group_salvages_detr.html&#34;&gt;Graystone jazz artifacts, forgotten in Detroit skyscraper, now being preserved&lt;/a&gt;. Photographer Doug Coombe went along
to document the effort with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.896394770433897.1073741832.170165396390175&amp;amp;type=3&#34;&gt;photo set on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&#34;&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/images/greystone-salvage.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Doug Coombe and Carleton Gholz at the Graystone Jazz salvage, July 7, 2015&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We knew that things were bad,&amp;rdquo; said DSC&amp;rsquo;s Founder and President
Carleton Gholz about the neglected collection, but Gholz didn&amp;rsquo;t
know how bad until he discovered many of the former museum&amp;rsquo;s records
were broken and strewn across the floor. Historic band stands thrown
into a pile and historic concert posters and sheet music left
unprotected to the elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the DSC and its work and to get involved, see the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitsoundconservancy.org/&#34;&gt;Detroit Sound Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;
web site, or join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DetroitSoundConservancy&#34;&gt;DSC on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/detroitsound&#34;&gt;@detroitsound&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>valuable archives or just fishwrap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-valuable-archives-or-just-fishwrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 22:33:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-valuable-archives-or-just-fishwrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re writing away, and you hit &amp;ldquo;publish&amp;rdquo;, and the thing
you pieced together flings its way through the ether to some
audience, real or imagined. The next day it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible
to find again unless you manage to produce the precise incantation
into a search engine. There is some long-lasting trail, to be sure,
easy enough to dredge up if someone is motivated by money or curiousity,
but for the most part the social networks of today (Facebook,
Twitter) generate most of their energy from capturing the attention of the
moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of what I write here is
worthwhile to save for longer than a day, and
some would be best to be deleted and never seen again.
I&amp;rsquo;m happy though that I have it all in one place that I
can grep through, happy that I can make changes to it
easily enough, and happy that it can be deleted or unpublished
without much fuss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custom views of taxonomies</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the motivation ideas behind going to the work to move
a big weblog to a new platform is to get better control over
categories. With Typepad, every category looks about the same;
the idea now is with Hugo I can have separate categories that
look different. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of recipes in the collection, which should
be sorted alphabetically or by key ingredient, not chronologically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of posts about books in the collection, which
should be connected to a lookup for that book in your favorite
bookstore or my favorite library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of people mentioned, and a people index would
be great so you can browse and not just search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly I&amp;rsquo;m after improving the browsing experience, as much for
me as for anyone else. If you have to find things with a search
engine, you are stuck in a world where you have to know that something
has a particular name. By offering a browsing infrastructure first,
you cherrypick the best search terms and put them up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of this will need pen and paper design&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight of us met for lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aysesturkishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; today. It was a normal
Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for
the lunch group these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time
to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning
or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a
remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make
sure that the things that needed to get done got done. Among the
tasks that took up lots more time than they deserved included
dealing with the health insurance marketplace and with other
healthcare providers for dealing with billing and accounting problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the people at lunch were new to the table, but since Ann
Arbor is bascially a small town, it was not a surprise to me that
I had easily identifiable mutual friends with two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was delicious, well prepared and well presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll be back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Madras_Masala&#34;&gt;Madras Masala&lt;/a&gt;, as art fair will have
ended and town will be more back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big event coming up is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makerfairedetroit.com/&#34;&gt;Maker Faire Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, to be held at The
Henry Ford in Dearborn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>diligently editing and converting for production</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to get this blog ready for production.
The tasks remaining include the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a reasonable home page with pagination. Somehow I need
to provide some kind of access to almost 2000 posts, and they
don&amp;rsquo;t all fit on a single page. Sort through the design to make
old things reachable, and then worry next about the formatter.
(This is done at least minimally, though the provided paginator
interface uses a list structure that&amp;rsquo;s not nice. Still, it gets
me to what I need to in a ping.) Open discussion on gohugo is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/pagination-and-group-by-date/1441/3&#34;&gt;Pagination and group by date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish to Github Pages, using vielmetti.github.io. I did this
once (using Octopress) so it should be straightforward to do it again.
I already do have a proper github repo (or nearly proper, it may
be missing some key bits). Done; don&amp;rsquo;t have a perfect build script
yet, but there&amp;rsquo;s at least a start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import all sorts more nonsense here, including a bunch of Superpatron
and Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Secret and FOIA Coordiator weblogs. There&amp;rsquo;s no particular
reason not to make it all one big soup. Import from Typepad is problematic
but not impossible and that would be a good addition to the supported work;
in particular it&amp;rsquo;s not evidently possible to export Markdown from Typepad,
just HTML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sort out theme issues so that I get a reasonable display for category
and subcategory pages. I may have to write some things down by hand
to get an understanding of what I really want. As it is right now
those pages render as blank, in part because I need to convert a bunch
of data imperfectly imported, which was throwing errors in my
templates, which in turn was breaking the build. Dealing with the
errored out builds is a question again for gohugo,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/taxononomy/1445&#34;&gt;taxononomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal with the date problems. Lots of dates got imported without a timezone,
but that was not the real issue; the real issue was also that lots got
imported with &amp;ldquo;layout: post&amp;rdquo;. Take that out and it seems to fix things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Request a dump of the image cache from Typepad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implement, somehow, &amp;ldquo;edit on github&amp;rdquo; so that my workflow is easier.
This might only be on the preview version. Some notes on the Hugo discussion
forums
describing how to do that are on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-to-implement-edit-this-page-on-github/1166&#34;&gt;How to implement “edit this page on github”?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a great many things</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-a-great-many-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 22:26:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-a-great-many-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weblog, which may or may not ever see the
light of day, is about a great many things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other blogs waiting to be written that
don&amp;rsquo;t have that infinite vista; they could easily
be much more narrow. What, then, do you write about?
Let&amp;rsquo;s count some of the options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker on the Raspberry Pi, following Hypriot&amp;rsquo;s lead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just Docker in general, and Dockerizing various things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes, since I have a bunch already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Outage Maps, in particular try to wrangle data from OpenEI here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOIA, espeically Michigan FOIA, to follow my book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily Coffee and Wifi, the usual random walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civic Technology, in whatever format that takes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more it&amp;rsquo;s the case that the old &amp;ldquo;Vacuum&amp;rdquo; weblog is
feeling vacuous - not enough interaction with people, and not
the right platform to go deep on anything. And &amp;ldquo;Typepad&amp;rdquo; feels
really old, especially compared to everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately if I&amp;rsquo;m writing in Markdown I can mostly drop anything
I want anywhere it wants to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other great weird idea of course is to mimic the old print
notebook with all kinds of nifty sidebars, one sidebar per item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I want to have happen as a result of all of this not
inconsiderable effort? Creative control to be sure, to be able
to type something and see it appear exactly as desired on the
screen. Community engagement is another, to be part of a group
of people all working toward a common goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the other thing that I could do is take some old weblog,
revisit it, and republish it in some other format. Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Secret
is the reasonable one to do that to. It has virutally no traffic
now, but if I re-serialized it, it might do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the hugo cookbook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-the-hugo-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:55:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-the-hugo-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every technology for publishing eventually gets used to publish
recipes. This collection of mine here is not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve marked up the recipes with the &amp;ldquo;recipe&amp;rdquo; category, and also
created a &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; taxonomy with ingredients. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of like
a subcategory but not really&amp;hellip;well it is as long as I am careful
about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous attempts to do this include The Usenet Cookbook (from
mod.recipes), alt.gourmand, and most favorite in my book the use
of Gopher as a cookbook. It is said that an old Mac was portable
enough to be set up in the kitchen to look up recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to do is set things up so that if the post is from the
recipes category, then the recipes list will show up in the sidebar
of that post, sorted alphabetically. I think I can make that work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sweet potato cauliflower soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 18:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some sweet potato cauliflower soup recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allyson Kramer likes hers with a bit of garam masala:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Three Peas wants carrots and celery and chicken stock:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food.com and &amp;ldquo;Kelly in TO&amp;rdquo; calls for curry and cinnamon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&#34;&gt;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our meal plan pairs this with biscuits and kale, and it was delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing from Hugo to Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-publishing-from-hugo-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 17:20:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-publishing-from-hugo-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges in getting things started is figuring
out where the end product is going to live. Hugo has its own
web server which is pretty nice, but since it generates static
pages, the results can really go anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial goes through the process in excruciating detail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but somehow fails to make it easy. What I&amp;rsquo;d like is a publishing
workflow that just like the normal Hugo workflow puts things online
instantly once they are built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one deploys with CodeShip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2015/hugo-deployment-via-codeship/&#34;&gt;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2015/hugo-deployment-via-codeship/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this one deploys with Wercker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/automated-deployments/&#34;&gt;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/automated-deployments/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet one more, with Github hooks and S3/Cloudfront; it depends on s3cmd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/imperialwicket/imperialwicket.com&#34;&gt;https://github.com/imperialwicket/imperialwicket.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one that focuses on the github side of things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/chrisjacob/825950&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/chrisjacob/825950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach I have runs like so, it assumes that you have
a working directory &amp;ldquo;~/src/hugo&amp;rdquo; with your blog in it, and
a target directory &amp;ldquo;~/src/vielmetti.github.io&amp;rdquo; set up for
github pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/src/hugo
hugo -d ../vielmetti.github.io --theme=vacuum
# wait to build, then
cd ../vielmetti.github.io
git add -A .
git commit -m &amp;quot;build complete&amp;quot;
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By having separate build directories like this you can keep the
continuous build on your draft setup going, and then push a
working version whenever you&amp;rsquo;re perfectly happy with the result.
Not like anyone is really perfectly happy with any blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac and Goat</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/Mac-and-Goat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/Mac-and-Goat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/strong&gt; calls for goat cheese; we generally use a goat gouda or
a goat cheddar, both of which are usually available at the local
Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s. Feel free to substitute any hard cheese that melts
well in your recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dish also calls for rice pasta, but again feel free to substitute;
you&amp;rsquo;re aiming for something like a rotini which handles the sauce well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Take out a lasagna pan, which is
what you&amp;rsquo;re going to assemble the dish in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-and-goat:b7d41359d960c78f56dcc5a9d35b0ec6&#34;&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb. pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb. goat gouda, goat cheddar, or a nice aged gouda or cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large can crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;romano cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil water for pasta; cook a pound or so of your favorite pasta,
we use a rice rotini pasta in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shred the cheese fine in a food processor or with a hand grater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pasta is done, drain it, and then put about half of it
in the lasagna pan. Cover with about half of the cheese and half of
the tomatoes. Put the rest of the pasta in, then more tomatoes and
more cheese. Top with breadcrumbs and then sprinkle a little romano
cheese on top and a few pinches of nutmeg for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook 20-25 minutes, until the top is lightly browned and the
tomato sauce is bubbling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>customizing a theme</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-customizing-a-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 14:32:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-customizing-a-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Themes can be customized by editing the top matter, or by
directly changing the theme. The challenge is understanding
enough of how the moving parts interconnect to make it do what
you want it to do, or at least enough of them so that you don&amp;rsquo;t
have a blog that just looks like a weak ripoff of someone else&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/creating-a-minimal-working-template/135/13&#34;&gt;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/creating-a-minimal-working-template/135/13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;does a very nice job of helping you walk through the simple
bits. It does not get far enough to give you a sense for how
to get pagination working but that&amp;rsquo;s at least a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be a super easy way to iterate through all
of the themes. I&amp;rsquo;m looking for one that already nicely has
some way of doing categories or tags or some kind of metadata.
It would be extra super swell to find one that has a sidebar
and footer structure to so that I can (finally) recreate notebook
pages. I think I have someone that goes OK as a start - it
wants to insert dynamic content into the sidebar for the home page,
and then also to insert content that depends on the categories
or tags for individual pages, so that the whole thing feels more
like a carefully constructed notebook and less like a simple blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point you can iterate endlessly on appearance and completely
lose track of contents. Fortuantely I have a body of work that I really
want to see in this, so that motivates some level of forward progress.
For instance, I&amp;rsquo;d love to see categories actually work here, since I
have some content that belongs together. I also have sidebar ideas
that really want to be exercised again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>converting typepad to hugo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-converting-typepad-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:33:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-converting-typepad-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task of the night was getting a few years worth of Typepad posts
into Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first step was to convert to Jekyll format, which I did using this
typepad_to_jekyll Ruby gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/koozie/typepad_to_jekyll&#34;&gt;https://github.com/koozie/typepad_to_jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then need to do a few things to get the Jekyll files exactly right
for Hugo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the date format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite the Categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and relink all of the images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the format for &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; was a one-liner in perl with the -i (&amp;ldquo;edit in
place&amp;rdquo;) flag.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the category rewrite or the image rescue yet.
The approach I took was to simply hack on the output files, rather than
change the source code to the typepad_to_jekyll program, but if you were
serious about it you&amp;rsquo;d do the latter and fork it until it did the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relinking all of the images requires opening a support ticket because Typepad
does not have an easy image export. Actually image hosting is a real
challenge and I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly the right way to do it inside Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll need to adjust the theme or pick a new theme so that it only shows
the first n posts on a page and then paginates, and I also need to adjust
it so that it shows categories. The show everything approach is unreasonable
when you have 1000s of pages to show off. On the other hand, the most
reasonable themes that I can find that look nice don&amp;rsquo;t have pagination
turned on by default. There&amp;rsquo;s some learning curve to roll my own, maybe
one that has some kind of reasonable sidebar structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lunch with jonathan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:30:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-lunch-with-jonathan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan and I went to Paradise, a Vietnamese place in the
Colonade that also serves Chinese food. He got Mongolian Beef,
and I got pho deluxe. It was perfectly adequate if not spectacular.
The topic of conversation was an elaborate storyline in a game
that involved animatronics in a creepy Chuck E. Cheese type
abandoned pizza parlor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the Malletts Creek library, until about 4:00 p.m.
I worked on Hugo and constructed a theme from scratch.
At the end he got bored.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wow that is fast</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/wow-that-is-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 03:25:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/wow-that-is-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So 634 pages from my Github Gollum based Wiki markup all got imported
into Hugo and it rendered all of them in 828 ms, or basically under
a second to pull in everything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. Astonishingly fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, those files while they are in Markdown are not really ready for
direct import, since they have [[double brackets]] everywhere that
get uglified. The other limiting factor is the date marker that&amp;rsquo;s not
included with them so they all show up as January 1, 0001 which is
funny the first few times and then not funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Hugo have an import function? It does, for converting front
matter. The closest for importing other things are the various Jekyll
converters which aren&amp;rsquo;t really the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing up Node-RED and mosquitto under &#34;docker compose&#34; on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 02:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-13-bringing-up-node-red-and-mosquitto-under-docker-compose-on-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Progress, actually quite a lot of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, neatly stated. Docker is good for bringing up single services (&#34;microservices&#34;), but sometimes your application needs more than one thing running for the whole thing to work. Enter &#34;docker compose&#34;, formerly &#34;fig&#34;, which automates the process of running various Docker commands in the right order with the right arguments all driven from a configuration file. As described by their documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular task I have in front of me is launching Node-RED and mosquitto (an MQTT broker) together on a Raspberry Pi 2 which is running Hypriot and Docker. Most of the background for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; that&#39;s a relevant task is at this post on Hypriot, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;How to use Docker Compose to run complex multi container apps on your Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, which I dutifully and successfully managed to run all of the examples from. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emboldened by this I tried to get Wordpress running with MySQL but got stuck because of a variety of things (not the least of which was some over-enthusiastic documentation that downplayed the complexity of that task, and the lack of a Pi-specific Wordpress Docker images). But having had the taste of what might be I carried on until I managed to get something to work for what I really wanted: Node-RED running alongside mosquitto so that I could have a local MQTT broker to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
nodered:
  image: nieleyde/rpi2-nodered
  command: flows.json
  volumes:
    - /home/pi/node-red:/root/.node-red
  ports: 
    - &#34;1880:1880&#34;
  links:
    - mosquitto

mosquitto:
  image: nieleyde/rpi-mosquitto
  ports:
    - &#34;1883:1883&#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some subtleties to note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nieleyde/rpi2-nodered runs on the Pi 2; there&#39;s a corresponding nieleyde/rpi-nodered for the Pi. Both are ARM images. I haven&#39;t yet tweaked this to run on x86, but if you do, you&#39;ll need to update the &#34;image&#34; stanzas everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;command&#34; and &#34;volumes&#34; stanzas in the nodered configuration serve to make Docker mount a subdirectory on the host machine where the flows.json file is stored; this makes changes to the configuration persistent. If you want a read-only configuration, you&#39;ll need to change this; I haven&#39;t gotten that far yet. It might also make sense to have a data volume container, but again I&#39;m not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;mosquitto&#34; configuration is extremely bare bones and runs the default config, which is wide open. I haven&#39;t gotten far enough to replace the config file with something better, but that&#39;s an obvious next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From within Node-RED you refer to this internal MQTT server at hostname &#34;mosquitto&#34;, port &#34;1883&#34;. If the links stanza was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; and the mosquitto section was changed to &#34;mqtt&#34; you&#39;d then refer to the MQTT server at hostname &#34;mqtt&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An issue open on Niel Eyde&#39;s rpi-nodered Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/issues/5&#34;&gt;documentation for how to extend this image with your own nodes and flows&lt;/a&gt;, where I&#39;m working some of this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Node-RED Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/node-red/node-red/issues/603&#34;&gt;Support for Docker install for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;, which is epic and helpful in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essential &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/&#34;&gt;Hypriot weblog&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/docker-compose-nodejs-haproxy/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose examples&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/compose&#34;&gt;Hypriot Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>