<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>mitmproxy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-mitmproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-mitmproxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyber.jotwell.com/an-internet-x-ray-machine-for-the-masses/&#34;&gt;An internet x-ray machine for the masses&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Ohm writes a lucid introduction to
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;mitmproxy&lt;/span&gt;,
a man-in-the-middle proxy server that allows you to
get between your browser and the Internet and poke at
(and change) the traffic going between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mitmproxy.org&#34;&gt;http://mitmproxy.org&lt;/a&gt; is the home of mitmproxy. It&amp;rsquo;s
the work of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Aldo Cortesi&lt;/span&gt; and a cast of
hundreds of contributors on github at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mitmproxy/mitmproxy&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mitmproxy/mitmproxy&lt;/a&gt; .
I used the OS X binary distribution from the download page.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a nifty Dockerized version on
Dockerhub as &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/u/mitmproxy/mitmproxy/&#34;&gt;docker pull mitmproxy/mitmproxy&lt;/a&gt;
to get you started quickly too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man-in-the-middle (or monkey-in-the-middle) systems are not
new, of course, and Dug Song&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monkey.org/~dugsong/dsniff/&#34;&gt;dsniff&lt;/a&gt;
package dates to 1999. What we&amp;rsquo;ve learned in a decade and a half
is that security through obscurity vanishes in the face of better
tools for looking at network traffic as it&amp;rsquo;s going by with high
level tools for making sense of what&amp;rsquo;s there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ever, all of these tools have both benign and malicious uses.
If you can trick someone into using your proxy server for their
traffic, all kinds of foolishness can result. Better is the use
that you proxy your own traffic and behold all of the cookies,
beacons, and ads that sneak into your everyday browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soundcloud, now and in the future</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have exactly one copy of something and it&amp;rsquo;s only on Soundcloud,
this would be an opportune time to make a backup. That&amp;rsquo;s always a good
idea anyway not to rely on single web servers for anything, but it&amp;rsquo;s
especially notable in the light of these articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the upbeat &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2015-07-10/can-soundcloud-be-the-facebook-of-music-&#34;&gt;Bloomberg Business&lt;/a&gt; article of July 10, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; SoundCloud’s potential is fascinating, and perhaps unique.
The founders have ambitious goals that respond to changes in the
way music and sound are created and consumed. It’s a beautiful
dream. So long as all the crucial participants—labels, publishers,
artists, SoundCloud itself—can agree on how to share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, the downbeat &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techtimes.com/articles/72325/20150729/soundcloud-losing-money-fast-as-record-labels-apply-licensing-pressure.htm&#34;&gt;Tech Times&lt;/a&gt; on July 29, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently reported on rumors that popular music streaming service
SoundCloud is planning on adding a subscription-based tier to its
currently all-free streaming service, and that rumor was just
confirmed by company co-founder Eric Wahlforss in a conversation
with the Wall Street Journal. Now, it appears that the impetus
behind the development of the subscription tier is clear: the company
is in dire need of cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dire need of cash&amp;rdquo; because record labels are not thrilled with
the beautiful dream of listening to the world&amp;rsquo;s music for free.
Remember how Napster turned out? It was a beautiful dream, too,
but labels and publishers just saw it as piracy. This from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmtunes.com/2015/06/editorial-believe-it-or-not-soundcloud-is-fighting-the-good-fight/&#34;&gt;EDM Tunes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2015 SoundCloud controversy is Napster all over again. We
aren’t sharing files anymore, we’re sharing sound. 15 years ago
record labels objected to us downloading their music, now they
object to us streaming it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Napster, SoundCloud is a goldfish that’s been unwillingly
thrust into battle with three super-wale companies. Just for a
matter of reference, consider that SoundCloud has about 200 employees,
while the Sony, Universal, and Warner corporate networks employ
more than 200,000. At this point, SoundCloud is fighting to survive,
and unfortunately has received a lot of critical media attention.
Since its 2007 inception, SoundCloud has served as a haven for
electronic music producers and fans; allowing sound to be seamlessly
shared from artist to listener. This luxury is being threatened,
and we’re all pissed about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enjoy Soundcloud while you can, and when you are producing things
for it make sure you keep a backup on your own machines!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite times for twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-favorite-times-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-favorite-times-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Favorite times to twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late evenings (basically, now) when the West Coast early evening
crew comes to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early mornings, when Europe is awake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Least favorite is mid-day Eastern time, when there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of noise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First round of postcards</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-first-round-of-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-first-round-of-postcards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A first round of postcards sent via Lob.com have arrived or are
nearly arrived at their destinations. The initial experience of
sending them made it clear that I need to do some simple user
interface improvements. I think I can cope with the current situation
on producing the card back photo, but again there&amp;rsquo;s more work to be
done making the text on the page wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reasonable question is, why do you send them? Why not send
email or a Facebook message? The answer is fairly simple, no one
ever remarks on my email prowess but even an ordinary card
elicits a response.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We should do more blogging</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-28-we-should-do-more-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blog every day, whether you want to or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick a topic, learn it well, and write about it as you learn it.
Or pick a topic you know really well already and teach to it.
Sometimes you can do both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time spent blogging can&amp;rsquo;t be any less worthwhile than time
spent on Facebook or Twitter. The exchange is, instead of clicking
the like button and the favorite button, you actually have to think
a little bit and write something down that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department does a round
of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;restaurant inspections&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Wayne Eaker&lt;/span&gt; built
an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zengenuity/food-inspections&#34;&gt;importer&lt;/a&gt; that
pulls in data from the site that hosts the official county inspections,
and is storing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zengenuity/food-inspections-data&#34;&gt;inspection data&lt;/a&gt;
on Github to make it easier for the next person who wants to build
a nice interface to all the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne was good enough to find a spot to host an interface to this data
that lets you browse through it; you can find it at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&#34;&gt;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are permalinks to each inspection so that you can link to them.
See e.g. recent inspections for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-06-17-slurping-turtle&#34;&gt;Slurping Turtle&lt;/a&gt;, June 17, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-04-27-china-chef-restaurant&#34;&gt;China Chef&lt;/a&gt;, Ypsilanti, April 27, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-06-22-nu-wave-fish-chicken&#34;&gt;Nu Wave Fish and Chicken&lt;/a&gt;, June 22, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for three examples of places where I want to see a clean inspection on a followup
visit before I go or go back to there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomatillo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-tomatillo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a little box of
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;tomatillos&lt;/span&gt;
from Argus Farm Stop. The question now is what to do with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions so far include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fried like green tomatoes, slice thin, coat with a thin batter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roasted them with onions and jalapenos and make into a salsa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rickbayless.com/recipe/raw-tomatillo-salsa/&#34;&gt;raw tomatillo salsa&lt;/a&gt; a la Rick Bayless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fried with onions and then add to scrambled eggs for tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;baked shrimp with tomatillos, feta, and cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carne en su jugo, a la La Fiesta Mexicana in Ypsilanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in pastel de Montezuma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I ended up making was a very simplified version of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eatingwell.com/recipes/tomatillo_breakfast_tacos.html&#34;&gt;Tomatillo Breakfast Tacos&lt;/a&gt;,
reducing the recipe to just onions, tomatillos, and eggs.
Cook chopped onions and chopped tomatillos over medium
heat (6 of 10) until the tomatillos are soft and the
onions are browned, about 12 minutes. Crack some eggs over the top of the
mixture and cover. Cook without stirring until the eggs are
set to your desired doneness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More discussion and commentary on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/edward.vielmetti/posts/10105504923525943&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Note that Twitter did not
supply a good stream of answers, but it did unearth
the one recipe I actually used, so there&amp;rsquo;s that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Eby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julie Weatherbee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patricia Anderson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kate Remen-Wait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cendra Lynn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joanna Hastings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathie Kroll Weinmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Trudeau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linda Diane Feldt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruth Scodel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feral Foods, the grower of said tomatillos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>make tidy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-make-tidy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been converting over old postings on this blog from Typepad.
The data export and import was imperfect, and this meant that I&amp;rsquo;ve
been poring over the data to figure out what keeps and what goes
and what-not. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to review old words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the artifacts of the old hosting platform was a helpful at
times system called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zemanta.com&#34;&gt;Zemanta&lt;/a&gt;. Zemanta would
figure out what you were writing about and give you helpful suggestions
for related links, both to things that you had written as well as
to things other people had written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided as part of the transformation of the old weblog into
the new one to unlink those &amp;ldquo;related links&amp;rdquo;, in the hope that
eventually Hugo&amp;rsquo;s own system will create some either algorithmically
derived relations or at least an easier way to do that by hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m looking closely at what Zemanta did so I can
undo it. The first set of artifacts is a &amp;ldquo;fieldset&amp;rdquo; with its links,
and that&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to search and destroy. Occasionally but not
always I find my links decorated with a &lt;code&gt;class=&amp;quot;zem_slink&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; marker
that&amp;rsquo;s a little harder to find. Most insidious so far was exactly
one time where Zemanta (or Typepad) rewrote or wrote an Amazon link
to include an affiliate link points to Zemanta, and not to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewriting 1500+ pages is going to take a while. The biggest question
is unpublishing some of them, since time has passed and I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to republish everything. There&amp;rsquo;s conversion from HTML to Markdown
to remove the uglies, spelling errors to catch, next
categories and taxonomies to fill, layout to work on, etc. At
some point I need to sort out image management. But first I&amp;rsquo;m going
to understand the consequences of previous convenience decisions
I made to use Zemanta and to undo that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 09:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-24-daily-coffee-wifi-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily coffee and wifi at Argus Farm Stop, outside in the sunshine
under a lovely red umbrella canopy. Espresso over ice and a day-old
olive twist. The view is of a Sky Trak lift at the construction
site across moving materials to the back of The Mark, a building
that&amp;rsquo;s going up where the car wash used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the day is a death on State Street. A young man was
climbing over the skylights at the Nickels Arcade and fell to his
death when the skylight glass gave way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 1915, the SS Eastland was packed with employees from
the Western Electric Hawthorne Works when it rolled over in
the Chicago River. 844 passengers and crew lost their lives, making
the Eastland disaster the worst shipwreck on the Great Lakes.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastlanddisaster.org/&#34;&gt;Eastland Disaster Historical Society&lt;/a&gt;
for extensive notes on and photos of the scene and its aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2civictech/&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt;
is coming up on Monday, July 27, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literatibookstore.com/&#34;&gt;Literati Bookstore&lt;/a&gt; is open
again after a water leak caused them to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote a tiny R script that generates maps. The challenge
today is to find a portable environment so that I can deploy this script
on shared infrastructure. The project took 30 minutes of MacBook Air processor
time running full blast parallel, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t care about wall clock time
to complete the effort I do care about building something that I can hand
off to someone else to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocker-org/ropensci&#34;&gt;ropensci&lt;/a&gt; Docker
package from the Rocker project is the answer, or most of the answer, for this.
Rocker has built R images where lots of useful packages have been installed,
including systems where the install directions are a little bit complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all complicated software environments the biggest challenge is dealing
with dependencies. If you want to use the latest and greatest fast algorithms,
you have to be prepared to spin up on what the cool kids are doing in the
rest of their environment. If somehow you can jump to the edge of the development
in the algorithm world without being tripped up by the hairy dependency graph
that got you there, it can be a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So; install Docker on the Mac with &amp;lsquo;boot2docker&amp;rsquo;; then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;docker pull rocker/ropensci
docker run -it rocker/ropensci R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and poof, you have an environment current to this month&amp;rsquo;s desktop of leading
R developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a trial of Little Bird</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-little-bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Little Bird is a system that helps you discover influencers
and experts in any topic. I&amp;rsquo;m at the very start of a 7 day trial.
Marshall Kirkpatrick is CEO of Little Bird, and he has been
active on Twitter posting interesting ideas about influence
marketing - and given that it seemed prudent to give the product a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing is aimed at agencies, not individuals, so I&amp;rsquo;m going
to look at this product through the eyes of people doing
&amp;ldquo;social listening&amp;rdquo; for a living, tracking the messages that
appear on a topic and either quietly making sense of what
is happening or actively engaging with those people to try
to influence their opinions. The single user price is out of
my reach for an annual commitment, though I might keep it up
for another month if I can find a specific task that warrants
the extra tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first test with any social software is to point it at a domain
that I know (Ann Arbor) and see what it unearths. Little Bird
found for me 1000 influential accounts having to do with Ann Arbor,
and in a boost to my ego it puts me in the top 50. Without understanding
how the algorithms work it seems that it biases towards identifying
busy accounts that post a lot of news, vs. the clever individual
whose every post is good but who doesn&amp;rsquo;t post that often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a style of posting which I would have to describe as
&amp;ldquo;thinkfluential&amp;rdquo; which Little Bird has a nose for. The thinkfluencer
will post frequently on a given topic, and a lot of people will
retweet them and they will retweet a lot of people. Every message
is relentlessly on message and you won&amp;rsquo;t find cat pictures or
meeting banter mixed in. More often than not you&amp;rsquo;ll see the
thinkfluence augmented by robots that post newsy things day and
night, even when the thinkfluencer is away from the keyboard.
There doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be any interaction at all with this
&amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo;, just a never-ending confluence of thinkfluence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wish that Little Bird had another round of filters, to help me
understand the question at scale &amp;ldquo;is this person really a bot&amp;rdquo;.
The real utility for me of identifying expertise is not to pick
out the high-frequency posting bot, but to suss out who on a topic
is good at engaging on the things they know about. Bot identification
is the Turing Test at work, and maybe just maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a set of
computable metrics that you can build across a corpus of Twitter
users to pull that out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of
BBQ at Ricewood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting
an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately
cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command
line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately
sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and
manual file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I know doesn&amp;rsquo;t work is upload via Twitter, because the series of
resizings generate visible compression artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can upload from the phone to OneDrive, which gives me a photo of size
2592 × 1456 pixels (1.78:1, 16:9). The target size is 1875 x 1275
(1.47:1, 25:17), which is postcard format. I can keep all of the pixels
in the image by letterboxing it, or I can crop off the edges. What I
can&amp;rsquo;t really do is stretch the image to fit because it&amp;rsquo;s too far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking further at my camera software (Lumia Camera) it appears
that I can also take photos at 4:3. There&amp;rsquo;s more experimenting to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more documentation, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/06/efficient-image-resizing-with-imagemagick/&#34;&gt;Efficient Image Resizing With ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt;,
Dave Newton in Smashing Magazine, June 25, 2015. Dave goes through a
professionally thorough view of resizing and resampling images for the web,
comparing his results against Photoshop. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested 31 different settings for &lt;code&gt;-filter&lt;/code&gt; and got the best results
with &lt;code&gt;Triangle&lt;/code&gt;. The Triangle resampling filter is also known as
bilinear interpolation, which I discussed above. It determines pixel
color by looking at a support area of neighboring pixels and produces
a weighted average of their colors. I found it best to specify this
support area at two pixels using the &lt;code&gt;-define filter:support=2&lt;/code&gt;
setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave uses DSSIM from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pornel.net/dssim&#34;&gt;https://pornel.net/dssim&lt;/a&gt; to test his results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool computes (dis)similarity between two PNG images using
(my approximation of) algorithms approximating human vision.
Comparison is done in L&lt;em&gt;a*b&lt;/em&gt; color space using a multi-scale variant
of the SSIM algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are sites that have automatic crop algorithms, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet found a package that&amp;rsquo;s usable without licensing. The interactive
web site of &lt;a href=&#34;http://croppola.com/&#34;&gt;Croppola&lt;/a&gt; is one useful example of
this genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pittsburgh&amp;rsquo;s smallest jazz club is installed in a bus stop on Liberty
Avenue, across from 9th Street.  The shelter was installed on July
6 and will remain until late August 2015. From the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://newpittsburghcourieronline.com/2015/07/09/the-worlds-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;New Pittsburgh Courier Online&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://awesomepgh.com/2015/01/15/award-36-pittsburghs-smallest-jazz-club/&#34;&gt;Awesome Pittsburgh&lt;/a&gt;’s trustees smiled unanimously when they decided
to choose the proposal for one of 2014’s $1000 grants, envisioning
a bus patron who pushes a button, only to have an iPod play jazz
music from one of MCG Jazz’s Grammy Award winning recordings. The
interior walls of a bus shelter will feature images of Pittsburgh’s
jazz legends, and a blank “Your Face Here!” space to take a picture
of yourself at “Pittsburgh’s Smallest Jazz Club.” Lamar Outdoor,
owner of the bus shelters in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, is
already on board to help make the project happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was done by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcgjazz.org/&#34;&gt;MCG Jazz&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Amy_MCGJazz&#34;&gt;Amy Kline&lt;/a&gt; is their marketing manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network issues at Malletts Creek branch were a good reason to exit back
towards town.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Detroit, Wednesday July 22, 2015, 6:00 pm, Troy, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-docker-detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope to see you at Docker Detroit&amp;rsquo;s kickoff meeting, to be held
at RIIS, 1250 Stephenson Highway, Suite 200 in Troy, MI starting
at 6:00 p.m. tonight July 22 2015.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming in from Ann
Arbor. The venue is between 14 Mile and Maple behind Beaumont Hospital.
Google Maps suggests that because of construction on I-75 in that
area you might want to head north on Campbell instead of taking
the I-75 / I-696 interchange north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading the meeting tonight is Pepijn Bruienne from the University
of Michigan. He will be speaking about &amp;ldquo;Docker in production&amp;rdquo;
and organizing a group discussion with Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Docker-Detroit/events/223111645/&#34;&gt;meetup announcement&lt;/a&gt;
for more details, refreshments will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meetup is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.riis.com&#34;&gt;RIIS&lt;/a&gt; a boutique web
and mobile development house. Hope to see you there!  I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking
notes and plan to do a writeup of the event, as well as sharing my
own experiences running Docker for ARM on a Raspberry PI 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Coffee and Wifi, Roos Roast Wednesday edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Roos, an espresso over ice with a little half and half and a hard
boiled egg. It&amp;rsquo;s a very compact breakfast. The espresso is served in
an appropriately sized glass mug and tastes like the strongest little
iced latte you will ever have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Mac, run &amp;lsquo;boot2docker upgrade&amp;rsquo;. That gets me up to current 1.7.1
revision of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Edwards-MacBook-Air:~ emv$ docker version
Client version: 1.7.1
Client API version: 1.19
Go version (client): go1.4.2
Git commit (client): 786b29d
OS/Arch (client): darwin/amd64
Server version: 1.7.1
Server API version: 1.19
Go version (server): go1.4.2
Git commit (server): 786b29d
OS/Arch (server): linux/amd64
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue that 1.7.1 resolves for me is certificate support - if I
understand the bug right, the Docker daemon was creating a key for
each interface it had, but not all of the interfaces were up at key
init time. The fix was to move DHCP init earlier in the start sequence
so that everything was initialized by the time key creation took place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker team is trying to improve code quality by having their
code base pass the &lt;code&gt;golint&lt;/code&gt; test. The open issue,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/pull/14784&#34;&gt;fix golint errors/warnings #14784&lt;/a&gt;,
has attracted a swarm of contributors, and a lot of them have
proposed changes that don&amp;rsquo;t pass the automated tests. The build
farm is managed with Jenkins, and you can see the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.dockerproject.org/&#34;&gt;status of every build of Docker&lt;/a&gt; on their
dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a full lintable codebase is a great goal. The challenge comes when
the suggested changes by lint send you in the direction of making an
incompatible change to some interface that has the &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; name but that
people were relying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps importantly for the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that currently
all of these tests are done on x86 platforms (Linux and Windows) and there
isn&amp;rsquo;t an official automated build on ARM. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;Docker distribution from Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; as my
baseline for working on the Raspberry Pi, with good success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction on I-75 at 13 Mile Road! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theoaklandpress.com/general-news/20150715/traffic-delays-expected-for-6-weeks-on-i-75-and-13-mile-during-mdot-project&#34;&gt;Expect major delays&lt;/a&gt; at this
project in Madison Heights. From the Oakland Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the construction project, there will be lane closures on both I-75 and 13 Mile Road in Madison Heights, said Diane Cross, a spokeswoman for the Michigan Department of Transportation, which is doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(insert map here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the alternative routes look any good, allow extra time for travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components of the postcard project are coming together. So far I have little
pieces that put and get addresses from a database, resize pictures to the
correct size, and generate test and live cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I lob a single thoughtful card out every time I have an espresso, there
will be some steady stream of cards going out. Next piece of the checklist is
pulling a report showing which cards are in flight and which ones just arrived
so that I can schedule followups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key bits of sending cards is that your recipient doesn&amp;rsquo;t get them
right away. That gives you a chance to refine your thinking and contemplate
what you have to say when you do follow up when they do get it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bocker is a subset of Docker in 100 lines of shell script</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-docker-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/p8952/bocker&#34;&gt;bocker&lt;/a&gt; is Docker (or at least
a good sized subset of it) in 100 lines of shell script.
I suppose the point is that even though there&amp;rsquo;s a huge
world of hype surrounding containerization as a next step
of systems management, when you get down to it, it&amp;rsquo;s just not
that complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>