<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flooding on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/flooding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flooding on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/flooding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor flooding on Sunday, June 14, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-14-ann-arbor-flooding-on-sunday-june-14-2015/</guid>
      <description>A severe storm dumped a bunch of water on Ann Arbor on Sunday, June 14, 2015. Here are reports of flood locations as monitored on Twitter. All times Eastern.
6:09 p.m. Huron River well down from its crest at 14.95 feet; flood stage is 16 feet, last observation is 13.57 feet at 5:15 P.M.

4:28 p.m. Huron River downstream from Allen Creek surged from about 700 cfs to over 2200 cfs in the span of less than an hour at about 2:00 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wet West Michigan: maps of flooding, April 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-wet-west-michigan-maps-of-flooding-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 15:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-wet-west-michigan-maps-of-flooding-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>This map from MLive shows roads closed due to flooding in Western Michigan. (Turn around, don&amp;#39;t drown). Click through for the interactive version.
 
A similar map from NOAA shows flood gauge readings across the area.
 
The purple gauge in this above map is Grand Rapids at Comstock Park, which is showing flooding at almost 6 feet above flood stage.
 
The historical big flood in Grand Rapids is from 1904; this collection rephotographs scenes from that flood in 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Isaac flood maps and flooding predictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-hurricane-isaac-flood-maps-and-flooding-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-30-hurricane-isaac-flood-maps-and-flooding-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Isaac brought with it high winds and a substantial amount of rain, and both of those combined has led to a lot of flooding. Here are some maps I&amp;#39;ve collected while the storm is still underway. You should know that for each of them I&amp;#39;ll also give a link to the underlying mapping source so that you can get current information.
If you are in the affected area and need details about flooded roads or the risk of dams or levees bursting or anything else, do not trust this weblog for current information; seek out official and up to date sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duluth floods of June 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-21-duluth-floods-of-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 00:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-21-duluth-floods-of-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>The city of Duluth, Minnesota has flooded after torrential rains. This map shows the rain intensity, with some areas getting more than 6 inches in a day.

For local coverage, the Duluth News Tribune&amp;#0160;(Twitter: @duluthnews) is a good source for detail. Minnesota Public Radio put together a stunning set of photos of the Duluth floods, including a picture of a seal that washed away from the Duluth Zoo (the seal is OK).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2011 flooding on the Susquehanna River basin after Tropical Storm Lee</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-08-september-2011-flooding-on-the-susquehanna-river-basin-after-tropical-storm-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 10:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-08-september-2011-flooding-on-the-susquehanna-river-basin-after-tropical-storm-lee/</guid>
      <description>The remnants of Tropical Storm Lee have made their way slowly from the Gulf of Mexico to the northeastern United States, bringing a storm with a slow-moving heavy rain. There is widespread flooding in the Susquehanna River basin and flash floods across the area. The Weather Underground&amp;#39;s Jeff Masters has commentary on the storm from the morning of September 8, 2011, saying
 An extreme rainfall event unprecedented in recorded history has hit the&amp;#0160;Binghamton, New York&amp;#0160;area, where 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Vermont flood maps after Irene</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-08-30-2011-vermont-flood-maps-irene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 02:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-08-30-2011-vermont-flood-maps-irene/</guid>
      <description>Vermont was hard hit by Irene. There are lots of photos and videos out there showing some of the devastation and flooding; here are maps that give some sense for the area involved.&amp;#0160;
Vermont Flooding 2011 on Facebook&amp;#0160;is a good community resource, as is Mad River Valley Hurricane Irene. For volunteer coordination, see the VTResponse weblog.
Detailed city maps showing flooded areas are not yet available. FEMA maps show the most vulnerable areas, and are available for Burlington,&amp;#0160;Montpelier, Waitsfield, and other cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minot, North Dakota flooding information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-22-minot-north-dakota-flooding-information-minotflood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-22-minot-north-dakota-flooding-information-minotflood/</guid>
      <description>Updated again 10:00 a.m. ET, Friday, June 24, 2011
Updated throughout at 9:00pm Eastern Time, June 22, 2011
How many people are affected by the flooding?
12,000 people are in the evacuation zone anticipating an alert for immediate evacuation on June 22, 2011 (Reuters). Evacuations started June 1. The population of Minot is about 40,000.
Among the organizations affected by the flood is the Minot Air Force Base, which has opened a 24x7 emergency center to assist military families (MAFB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River: May 25, 2011 flooding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</guid>
      <description>The river is high. Will it flood? That&amp;#39;s a very good question to ask in the morning before a storm; and the answer today turned out to be yes. Roads were inundated, Lake Barracuda emerged from its stormwater geyser, Depot Street filled with water, Mullholland Creek popped a manhole cover, and S. Main Street near Michigan Stadium filled. West Park&amp;#39;s new water features get a workout.
Basements have taken on water, and the full extent of storm damage is unknown yet until we get the May 26 predicted rains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River water level watching: USGS National Water Information System</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 13:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-23-huron-river-waterwatch/</guid>
      <description>Follow the level of the Huron River as it goes through Ann Arbor&amp;#0160;with the USGS National Water Information System. On March 23, the river is rising, but it&amp;#39;s also fluctuating in levels, enough that it&amp;#39;s difficult to determine whether current trends would lead you to believe that there is any risk of flooding.
If you were to watch this closely, what would you watch?
The USGS will give you an alert if the level of the river is above or below a certain level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia flood map, January 10, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-09-australia-flood-map-january-10-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 22:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-09-australia-flood-map-january-10-2011/</guid>
      <description>Source is the Australia River and Rainfall Conditions page from the Australia Bureau of Meteorology.
 Also of note is the 1 week rainfall map from the Climate page on the same source
 More maps and map collections:
VerySpatial: Australian flood maps. A very good comprehensive collection of flood maps, from which several of the maps below are sourced.
Larvatus Proveo: Brisbane flood maps and up to date flood information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>