<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Arborwiki on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-arborwiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Arborwiki on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-arborwiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>thank you for supporting arborwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time people ask questions about Ann Arbor, and from time to time there are what appear to be encyclopedic responses to them.  Part of the reason for this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://Arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, a wiki that covers information about Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, Washtenaw County and the rest of the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://matth.org/&#34;&gt;Matt Hampel&lt;/a&gt; runs this with an ad hoc collective doing editorial direction and the Ann Arbor District Library providing hosting. It&#39;s not advertising driven, and while is has a lot of information about businesses any obviously marketing copy gets edited out pretty quickly.  I use it to do everything from keeping track of where black raspberries are available for picking in parks to noting &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Birthday_Deals&#34;&gt;which Ann Arbor restaurants give great deals on your birthday (&lt;/a&gt;the most popular page on the site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt recently sent out a call for contributions for the site for one infrastructure expense not otherwise covered, domain registration.  I&#39;m happy to say that within a few days he raised enough to renew arborwiki.org for 10 years, and to leave a little bit left over for printing stickers.  (because, as you well know, any real project generates stickers.)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;arborwiki.org&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://zme.amazon.com/exec/varzea/pay/T1CKFIX9Y6QODG/104-3796538-4237557&#34;&gt;call for contributions&lt;/a&gt; is still online for now.  There&#39;s a longer piece &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.concentratemedia.com/blogs/posts/EdwardVielmetti2011.aspx&#34;&gt;about arborwiki at Concentrate&lt;/a&gt;.  From time to time the local wiki crowd meets for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Wiki_Wednesday&#34;&gt;wiki wednesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edward Vielmetti is a resident of Ann Arbor, MI.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>