<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:48:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10/4 4-5p FLY Art Center volunteer orientation, FLY Creativity Lab, Ypsilanti</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</guid>
      <description>Christine Bruxvoort sent me these details on the FLY Art Center&#39;s upcoming volunteer orientation.
When the volunteer orientation is going to be: Oct 4, 2014 4:00 p.m. - 5:00 p.m.
Where it&#39;s going to be: FLY Creativity Lab, 40 N. Huron, Ypsilanti, 48197 (between Michigan and Pearl). Contact: Chris at 734-217-2228 or info@flyartcenter.org.
Who is invited: Any interested adult or teen. Come to find out what we are about or sign up that night on our volunteer list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Around, a new urban walking game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 14:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m inventing a new urban game called Walking Around. I&amp;#39;m sure that someone else has invented it already, but reinvention is part of the process of creativity. Here&amp;#39;s how it&amp;#39;s played.
First, you play with a pedometer, which tells you how far you&amp;#39;ve walked during the day. There are a number of systems already for tracking your pedometer usage, including Walker Tracker, Steps, and a bunch of others. Use whatever system that gives you, or just a spreadsheet, to take care of the basic structure of making certain that you count steps daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpolished writing in the open notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Steve Crocker, Internet Request for Comments 3, from 1969: &amp;quot;There is a natural hesitancy to publish something unpolished, and we hope to ease this inhibition.&amp;quot;
From time to time, someone reads Vacuum and comments that the writing looks unpolished and incomplete. Why would you publish this kind of work, which obviously isn&amp;#39;t up to the standards that would let you sell it to someone for use in print? Why wouldn&amp;#39;t you hide it in your notebooks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from a construction project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 18:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</guid>
      <description>An old bicycle wheel makes a good pulley wheel.
An old modem, of any sort, can be repurposed by attaching a single RJ-11 cord to both ends of it; you now have a loop, and the RJ-11 threads through the bicycle wheel.
An RS-232 cable should be thought of as a very strong wire rope with helpful screw connectors.&amp;#0160;
A transformer makes an excellent counterweight.
There is no piece of old electronic junk that doesn&amp;#39;t have some possible usefulness as a part of a kinetic sculpture, whether it works or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mindless mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>I used this phrase in my meaningless indicators of progress post.
Some other uses of it, just so I manage to put it in an appropriate context:
Chronicle of Higher Education has a story called The Art of Living Mindfully on the work of Ellen Langer. Her blog is not frequent but it is thoughtful.
 We have been explicitly and implicitly taught by our culture to be mindless. We have been taught absolutes when none really exist independent of context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity, a collection</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</guid>
      <description>Some collected thoughts on serendipity.
serendipity in book-finding: (via if:book)
the pinpoint accuracy of computer-searches, leaves those of us lucky enough to have spent time in library stacks, nostalgic for the unexpected discovery of something we didn&amp;#39;t know we were looking for but which just happened, serendipitously, to be on a nearby shelf.
Lindsay Marshall on serendipity:
We are not, I believe, looking for tools to record our thoughts or to provide them with structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>outside.in &#34;top local blog&#34; roundup: what exactly am i writing about here?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-what-exactly-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 09:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-what-exactly-am/</guid>
      <description>outside.in is a blog aggregator; it scoops up posts from around the net, codes them by geography, and then presents you the reader with a feed that&#39;s local to whatever you want it to be local about.&amp;nbsp; Here is the outside.in Ann Arbor page .&amp;nbsp; I get their newsletter sent to me which ends up being a good day&#39;s local news clippings.
Here&#39;s their roundup of top Ann Arbor blogs and bloggers; Vacuum is listed as a top local blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creativity vs productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-12-creativity-vs-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 10:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-12-creativity-vs-p/</guid>
      <description>Merlin Mann has relaunched 43 Folders; he doesn&#39;t want to be the productivity guy any more, he wants to be the creativity guy.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a good choice.
He notes some essential tension between the demand of professional bloggers to produce immense quantities of on-topic dreck that generates a lot of page views, vs the wise craft of intense creative types who sweat the details to edit things down to a fine polish.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>