<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/creativity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10/4 4-5p FLY Art Center volunteer orientation, FLY Creativity Lab, Ypsilanti</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Christine Bruxvoort sent me these details on the FLY Art Center&#39;s upcoming volunteer orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the volunteer orientation is going to be: Oct 4, 2014 4:00 p.m. - 5:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where it&#39;s going to be: FLY Creativity Lab, 40 N. Huron, Ypsilanti, 48197 (between Michigan and Pearl). Contact: Chris at 734-217-2228 or info@flyartcenter.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is invited: Any interested adult or teen. Come to find out what we are about or sign up that night on our volunteer list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of commitment is asked for: on going opportunities that are posted through the volunteer sign up page. Adults can also sign up for committees like fundraising and marketing that meet monthly. Other opportunities involve working with kids or in the community at events. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why you&#39;re so awesome: FLY is awesome because we are dedicated to our community and to our FLY kids! FLY means FOR the LOVE of YOUTH and we are proud to serve our area with quality arts programming that can transform our neighborhoods, develop confidence skills in our young ones, and expand the opportunities for arts and culture in our community. Our caring volunteers and staff are essential to making this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much! We haven&#39;t worked much yet with teens but I am excited about the possibilities of using youth as mentors to our children. Please let me know if you have anymore questions about FLY. We really appreciate your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Fly&#34; title=&#34;Fly&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Around, a new urban walking game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 14:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m inventing a new urban game called Walking Around. I&amp;#39;m sure that someone else has invented it already, but reinvention is part of the process of creativity. Here&amp;#39;s how it&amp;#39;s played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you play with a pedometer, which tells you how far you&amp;#39;ve walked during the day. There are a number of systems already for tracking your pedometer usage, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://walkertracker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Walker Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://swellnessresearch.wordpress.com/projects/steps/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/a&gt;, and a bunch of others. Use whatever system that gives you, or just a spreadsheet, to take care of the basic structure of making certain that you count steps daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second - and here is what is novel, at least to me - is that there&amp;#39;s a bonus structure in the game designed to award bonuses for when you have accomplished tasks. The first bonus award that I&amp;#39;m awarding myself looks at constructing a walk so that you make an orbit around the biggest possible chunk of territory; that is to say, repeated walks along the same path will get you zero bonus, but going out of your way on a detour will add to your score, and trekking through unfamiliar territory in a big loop is the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far this is a pen and paper game and I haven&amp;#39;t fully worked out the point structure. I have a notion that you capture territory every time you orbit it, so that you might win a park by going all the way around it, and you might win a political ward or precinct by capturing a loop around it. To simplify greatly, since I am trying to keep record of this in a small book, I&amp;#39;m just drawing a graph with destinations rather than tracking every street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some idea sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/node/18868&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Riverwalks Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is a book of walking loops along the Huron River, written by&amp;#0160;Brenda E. Bentley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://laketrek.blogspot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Lake Trek&lt;/a&gt; is the weblog for&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://laketrek.blogspot.com/search/label/Loreen%20Niewenhuis&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;Loreen Niewenhuis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;who wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brilliant-books.net/product/1000-mile-walk-beach&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A 1000-Mile Walk on the Beach&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;about her circumnavigation on foot of Lake Michigan. I don&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;m going to beat that top score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Graham wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2005/12/18/PKG7DG81961.DTL#ixzz0YAiHcOQj&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Walking The World&lt;/a&gt;, and his quest to walk every street in San Francisco, in 2005 for SF Gate; his web site is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfwalkingman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;SF Walking Man&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.aadl.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AADL Summer Reading Game&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;has points for reading books and badges for doing various other tasks, and the gamers there know how to make a game that will make you read. There should therefore be points in my Walking Around game every time you complete part of a circuit that connects to a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allcitynewyork.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;All City New York&lt;/a&gt; is the work of Moses Gates, whose game board includes the challenge of visiting all of the census tracts of New York City. Thanks to Ruth Kraut for the link.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Tacoma, &lt;a href=&#34;http://xca2.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Brian Kerr&lt;/a&gt; is getting bonus points in his version of the game for elevation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now pardon me while I connect some dots in my game map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpolished writing in the open notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Crocker, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Internet Request for Comments 3&lt;/a&gt;, from 1969: &amp;quot;There is a natural hesitancy to publish something unpolished, and we hope to ease this inhibition.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time, someone reads Vacuum and comments that the writing looks unpolished and incomplete. Why would you publish this kind of work, which obviously isn&amp;#39;t up to the standards that would let you sell it to someone for use in print? Why wouldn&amp;#39;t you hide it in your notebooks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m using this weblog as a notebook, and publishing my notes for myself instead of always as a tightly edited, polished, finished work. By exposing this part of a process I hope to be prepared to find some way to make myself understood, even if I don&amp;#39;t completely understand myself immediately as I write through an issue or question. Thoughts go in, get refined as far as they need to be to make them coherent, and then go onto the net and into the world so that there&amp;#39;s room for the next piece to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open notebook is going to be messy, but it also means that I have some hope of finding my own half-finished work and revisiting it years later; when I don&amp;#39;t do that, there&amp;#39;s always something lost. Writing this way lets me tune into ideas, spin them around for a bit until I have a clearer focus, and move on. In most cases, I&amp;#39;m not ready to make things shiny and neat, and I&amp;#39;m content to explore facets of an unpolished gem over a series of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously, because I put it out there in first draft format so that I could find it again: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/03/first-version-coherent.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;make the first version coherent&lt;/a&gt; (from 2011); &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/09/creativity-vs-p.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;creativity vs productivity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(from 2008); on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/04/shitty_first_dr.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;shitty first drafts&lt;/a&gt; (from 2007); &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/05/my_quadrille_no.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;wishing that my weblog looked more like my quadrille notebooks&lt;/a&gt; (from 2004).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from a construction project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 18:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An old bicycle wheel makes a good pulley wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old modem, of any sort, can be repurposed by attaching a single RJ-11 cord to both ends of it; you now have a loop, and the RJ-11 threads through the bicycle wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An RS-232 cable should be thought of as a very strong wire rope with helpful screw connectors.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A transformer makes an excellent counterweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no piece of old electronic junk that doesn&amp;#39;t have some possible usefulness as a part of a kinetic sculpture, whether it works or not. Remember, kids, &lt;strong&gt;the connector is the artwork&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mindless mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used this phrase in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/03/meaningless-indicators-of-progress.html&#34;&gt;meaningless indicators of progress&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other uses of it, just so I manage to put it in an appropriate context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronicle of Higher Education has a story called &lt;a href=&#34;http://chronicle.com/article/The-Art-of-Living-Mindfully/63292/?sid=at&#34;&gt;The Art of Living Mindfully&lt;/a&gt; on the work of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ellenlanger.com/&#34;&gt;Ellen Langer&lt;/a&gt;. Her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ellenlanger.com/blog/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is not frequent but it is thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
We have been explicitly and implicitly taught by our culture to be mindless. We have been taught absolutes when none really exist independent of context. When we think we know something absolutely, we have learned that it is reasonable never to question it, nor to pay attention to how it may be otherwise. Beliefs and behavior always make some kind of sense from the actor’s perspective or else the actor would have done otherwise. Blame suggests mindlessness on the part of the blamer who does not recognize this. We are not at fault for what we do not know just because someone else can see a way we could have known it.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1550775&#34;&gt;Just Breathe: Meditation as Organizational Slack&lt;/a&gt; is a paper by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/pub/kaisa-holloway-cripps/3/ba7/b62&#34;&gt;Kaisa G. Holloway Cripps&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;Mostly a literature review, it looks at meditation inside an organization and identifies ways where it may be useful to engage human resources that are slack. &amp;#0160;The discussion reminds me of MBA consultants who work like dogs for months and then are periodically &amp;quot;on the beach&amp;quot; for a while when their gig is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly hit Buddhism when I look up this phrase, the parts of Buddhism that I haven&amp;#39;t lived close enough to that I appreciate all of the subtleties of the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;within&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;without&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;with&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;,” he&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindlessly&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;chants. “Shut up just shut it up already,” ... (&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=J5PXLLQ5ADsC&amp;amp;dq=subject:fiction+mindless+mindfulness&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;source=gbs_navlinks_s&#34;&gt;Circle This Mountain&lt;/a&gt;, mercifully abbreviated by Google Books)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity, a collection</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some collected thoughts on serendipity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/06/serendipity_in_.html&#34;&gt;serendipity in book-finding&lt;/a&gt;: (via if:book)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;the pinpoint accuracy of computer-searches, leaves those of us lucky
enough to have spent time in library stacks, nostalgic for the
unexpected discovery of something we didn&amp;#39;t know we were looking for
but which just happened, serendipitously, to be on a nearby shelf.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/Lindsay/Writing/serendip.html&#34;&gt;Lindsay Marshall on serendipity:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We are not, I believe, looking for tools to record our thoughts or to
provide them with structure. What we seek is something that leads us to
the unforeseen collisions, the copulations that lead to new thoughts,
new connections and yet more new meetings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron/2008/06/photo-credit-fr.html&#34;&gt;Moyra Davis on the problem of reading:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Both books are filled not only with Davey&amp;#39;s moody photos of bookshelves
in various states of disarray and transition but also with her thoughts
on the place of reading in a creative life, and the difficulty, in
managing the habit, of striking the right balance between purpose and
serendipity, and between work and pleasure. &amp;quot;&amp;#39;What to read?&amp;#39; is a
recurring dilemma in my life,&amp;quot; she admits in The Problem of Reading,
which has, among other images, a great close-up of her mother&amp;#39;s
annotations of Swann&amp;#39;s Way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chacocanyon.com/pointlookout/020925.shtml&#34;&gt;Rick Brenner on serendipity in project management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Serendipity in project management is rare,
in part, because we&amp;#39;re under too much pressure to see it. If we can
reduce the pressure, wonderful things happen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/Lindsay/&#34;&gt;Lindsay Marshall&lt;/a&gt; for the original spur to this line of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>outside.in &#34;top local blog&#34; roundup: what exactly am i writing about here?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-what-exactly-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 09:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-22-what-exactly-am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;outside.in is a blog aggregator; it scoops up posts from around the net, codes them by geography, and then presents you the reader with a feed that&#39;s local to whatever you want it to be local about.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://outside.in/Ann_Arbor_MI&#34;&gt;Here is the outside.in Ann Arbor page&lt;/a&gt; .&amp;nbsp; I get their newsletter sent to me which ends up being a good day&#39;s local news clippings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.outside.in/2008/10/21/dept-of-blogiology-101-ann-arbor/&#34;&gt;Here&#39;s their roundup of top Ann Arbor blogs and bloggers; Vacuum is listed as a top local blog. &lt;/a&gt; They describe what I write about as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/&#34;&gt;Vacuum &lt;/a&gt;-
A love of the neighborhood library and awareness of local school news,
political happenings, tech updates and the occasional recipe make this
eclectic blog a must read. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s always interesting to figure out what other people thing you are doing - if you are trying to maintain a laser-like coherent focus on being eclectic, it&#39;s hard to know what to do next.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m happy that recipes make for good filler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give credit where credit is due, here&#39;s perhaps better sources for any of the components that go into this effort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries: my main library blog is &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron&#34;&gt;Superpatron&lt;/a&gt; which spun out of Vacuum about two years ago.&amp;nbsp; Locally the &lt;a href=&#34;http://aadl.org&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt; site has a bunch of blogs inside it including &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/taxonomy/term/302&#34;&gt;a good one on local history&lt;/a&gt;, Globally my short list for library inspiration includes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theshiftedlibrarian.com/&#34;&gt;Jenny Levine&#39;s The Shifted Librarian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tametheweb.com/&#34;&gt;Michael Stephens writing Tame The Web&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blyberg.net/&#34;&gt;self-described library geek John Blyberg&#39;s eponymous blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local school news: the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burnsparkpto.org/&#34;&gt;Burns Park Elementary PTO has a web site and newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; which I clip from regularly (mostly, it seems, to remind myself of things in the future).&amp;nbsp; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; has good coverage of school meetings which I am never ever likely to attend regularly.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/arborparents&#34;&gt;very busy arborparents mailing list &lt;/a&gt;connects parents across town and across the area - more news than I can readily absorb but always something of interest and a very helpful bunch for asking questions of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Political happenings:&amp;nbsp; I think the outside.in people were keyed on to my elections coverage; rather than take any kind of political stance visibly here at all in any tedious partisan way, I try to always collect &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/10/ann-arbor-michi.html&#34;&gt;as much details as I can on elections including sample ballots and polling place locations and times.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The best sources for that are &lt;a href=&#34;http://potifos.com/polygon/&#34;&gt;county clerk Larry Kestenbaum&#39;s occasional blogging&lt;/a&gt;, plus a certain degree of digging through municipal web sites.&amp;nbsp; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/services/Pages/E-mailAlertSubscription.aspx&#34;&gt;City of Ann Arbor&#39;s email alert service&lt;/a&gt; helps a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech updates: This leaves broad room for interpretation.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;In the useful but sometimes tedious realm, &lt;a href=&#34;http://techmeme.com/&#34;&gt;techmeme is the only tech news tracker you need to listen to the silicon valley echo chamber&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Collecting more local tech news is helped by&lt;a href=&#34;http://concentratemedia.com/&#34;&gt; Issue Media Group&#39;s Concentrate&lt;/a&gt; and by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wwj.com/pages/317228.php&#34;&gt;Matt Roush&#39;s Great Lakes IT Report&lt;/a&gt;, both of which are eager to write about local stuff.&amp;nbsp; My &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 weekly lunch group and the mailing list that goes with it&lt;/a&gt; are my local collection source for interesting people and projects and tech (and note that quite a bit of this is pre-market projects not yet in the Silicon Valley radar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The occasional recipe: The relentlessly practical answer to how this gets done is &amp;quot;blog what you eat&amp;quot;; if you are persistent about that, you get ready-made menu plans for next year around the same time.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Locally, I turn to &lt;a href=&#34;http://4obsessions.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Kate Remen-Wait&#39;s Four Obsessions blog&lt;/a&gt; when I need a menu idea,&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kitchenchick.com&#34;&gt;Kitchenchick for reviews of local restaurants&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefarmersmarketer.com/&#34;&gt;The Farmer&#39;s Marketer for a market list from the Ann Arbor Farmers Market&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Globally the technique is &amp;quot;google cooking&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;twitter cooking&amp;quot; where you simply type in a list of ingredients into either search box and hope someone has something inspiring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eclectica.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s imporant to be fed a steady diet of things which are interesting; if &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/09/creativity_is_a.html&#34;&gt;creativity is an import-export game&lt;/a&gt;, then this is the import side of that.&amp;nbsp; Reliably I pull from&lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/network/vielmetti&#34;&gt; my network on delicious&lt;/a&gt; for great weird ideas.&amp;nbsp; There are a few weblogs that specialize in the eclectic, most notably &lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/bifurcated/rivets/&#34;&gt;Lindsay Marshall&#39;s Bifurcated Rivets: A Compendium of Eclectica for Epopts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so there you go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creativity vs productivity</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-12-creativity-vs-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 10:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-12-creativity-vs-p/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Merlin Mann has relaunched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.43folders.com/&#34;&gt;43 Folders&lt;/a&gt;; he doesn&#39;t want to be the productivity guy any more, he wants to be the creativity guy.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s a good choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He notes some essential tension between the demand of professional bloggers to produce immense quantities of on-topic dreck that generates a lot of page views, vs the wise craft of intense creative types who sweat the details to edit things down to a fine polish.&amp;nbsp; (Or something like that; it probably overstates the issue.)&amp;nbsp; And he bemoans the tendency of people to consume an endless stream of shitty first drafts as if that was the only thing worth doing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What worries me are the consequences of a diet comprised mostly of
fake-connectedness, makebelieve insight, and unedited first drafts of &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.
I think it’s making us small. I know that whenever I become aware of
it, I realize how small it can make me. So, I’ve come to despise it.&amp;nbsp; (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/48588149/better&#34;&gt;better)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since this post itself is a shitty first draft of a summary of what is probably 100 other things I&#39;ve thought about, I&#39;ll keep it short.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes, when you want to have deep insight into a topic, you have to immerse yourself in the details.&amp;nbsp; Your makebelieve insight and fake-connectedness are exercises in helping you understand the world, and even though sometimes the explanation that comes up doesn&#39;t really sound any more insightful than what your wikipedia-quoting eight year old can come up with, it came from you.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes, if you are really lucky, you get to reflect on a bunch of first drafts and turn them into second and third drafts - hurray!&amp;nbsp; But at least you got that thinking out into public in a format that can get some feedback.&amp;nbsp; The best way to have one good idea is to have a thousand ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended reading: Alex Osborn&#39;s 1949 &amp;quot;Your Creative Power: How To Use Imagination&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>