<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pedometer on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/pedometer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pedometer on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 15:02:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/pedometer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Walker Tracker</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-revisiting-walker-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 15:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-revisiting-walker-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In among the pile of random things that you find when you have a teenager in the house, I located on old Omron pedometer whose battery had run down. One quick trip to CVS later, and I have a working tool to measure my physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the winter months it&#39;s harder for me to get the outdoor exercise that I think I need. The days are shorter, the sidewalks are slipperier, and the excuses are more numerous to stay indoors where it&#39;s warm. That all said, there&#39;s no less need to be mindful of how much exercise you are getting when it&#39;s cold out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In days past, I was able to predict my mood rather accurately by checking how many steps I got on my pedometer. If the number was below 5000 you could count on me to be grouchy, and those rare days when the count exceeded 20000 were days when I couldn&#39;t concentrate on much of anything except moving. There&#39;s a seasonally adjusted optimum of approximately 10000 steps - minus a few in winter, plus a few in summer - that I think of as a target that if I happen to move that much in a day that everything else works out OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.walkertracker.com&#34;&gt;Walker Tracker&lt;/a&gt; on and off since 2006, or so the stats tell me, and in that time I&#39;ve logged over 7 million steps. Though the site interface has changed a little bit and my old crowd of fellow pedestrians has mostly moved on from the site, there are still a few familiar faces of people more industrious than I am in logging their activity. I&#39;m looking forward to revisiting it and being a bit more diligent about getting out and about in the winter time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: buy new mittens, ideally ones that let me have at least one index finger free to work my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self 2: the battery is said to last 6 months, whether you use the system or not, so be prepared to change it on the summer solstice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtastic and Cardiotrainer for Android, a brief review</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-runtastic-and-cardiotrainer-for-android-a-brief-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 22:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-runtastic-and-cardiotrainer-for-android-a-brief-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Runtastic is a workout tracking program for Android. It lets you keep track of where you have gone on your run, bike ride, or walk (or a bunch of other means of locomotion) and using the GPS in the phone makes some estimate of how far you&amp;#39;ve gone and how much effort you have expended.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve also used Cardiotrainer for this purpose, which has a similar reason for being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s really handy to have your device track where you go so that you get a nice map of your journey. Those trips where you&amp;#39;re trying to find your way through an unfamiliar neighborhood generate a trail of breadcrumbs you can follow, and it&amp;#39;s really helpful to have a good sense for how far away a mile is while walking. (For me, it&amp;#39;s a mile to the Michigan Union.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Runtastic and Cardiotrainer have a synthesized voice to give you details of your progress as you go. Runtastic is rather more sparing in its narration, which I find just fine. Both systems allow you to log your progress to a variety of online media like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out using Cardiotrainer, and it wanted me to log a trip every day and keep track of myself. When I used to wear a pedometer, that was really easy to do, and I could type in a few numbers every few days and feel like I was keeping up with myself. It doesn&amp;#39;t make sense to have any of these running all the time, and so I was fine with Runtastic keeping that detail in the background for me rather than the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Runtastic also has a feature, as of yet incompletely tested, that lets you know where your friends are right now on the map. That&amp;#39;s actually the feature I want more than any to test out, because it points to the possibility that you could use this for something even a little more like a real time channel for careful coordination of where people are and what they&amp;#39;re doing. I&amp;#39;m imagining getting lost and having this be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Runtastic:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.runtastic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://www.runtastic.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardiotrainer:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.worksmartlabs.com/cardiotrainer/about.php&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://www.worksmartlabs.com/cardiotrainer/about.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both apps are free, and both have Pro or Paid versions that unlock a few more features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>