<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>October on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/october/</link>
    <description>Recent content in October on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 22:45:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/october/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Lake Orion Pumpkin Launch was a blast!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-08-2012-lake-orion-pumpkin-launch-was-a-blast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 22:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-08-2012-lake-orion-pumpkin-launch-was-a-blast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark this down under &amp;quot;things to be sure to do next October&amp;quot; -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5th annual, 2012 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oaklandballistics.com/lopl.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Lake Orion Pumpkin Launch&lt;/a&gt; was a blast. It was held at Orion Oaks park, about 90 minutes from Ann Arbor. Five teams competed to launch pumpkins with trebuchets out into a field. The winning team, the Masters of Mayhem, lobbed a pumpkin over 1300 feet (a quarter of a mile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures when I have them...for now you can see the winner&amp;#39;s Facebook page, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Masters-of-Mayhem/325481651884&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Masters of Mayhem&lt;/a&gt;, for some videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 26, 2008: Japanese kids culture at Ann Arbor Art Center</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-october-26-2008-japanese-kids-culture-at-ann-arbor-art-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-october-26-2008-japanese-kids-culture-at-ann-arbor-art-center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;this is pulled from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.burnsparkpto.org/files/BP_Press_2008_11.pdf&#34;&gt;Burns Park Press newsletter for November 2008.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What:&amp;#0160; The Art Center has partnered with volunteers from the Center for Japanese &lt;br /&gt;Studies at the University of Michigan to offer an afternoon of family friendly programming &lt;br /&gt;that celebrates Japanese culture.&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;When: Sunday, October 26, 1:00 – 5:00 pm&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;Where Ann Arbor Art Center, 117 W. Liberty &lt;br /&gt;Schedule of Events: &lt;br /&gt;1 – 1:30 pm Japanese Singing Circle: Learn Japanese children’s songs taught by Stacey &lt;br /&gt;Pratt from the Center for Japanese Studies. &lt;br /&gt;1:30 - 2.30 pm Origami Workshop: Make Samurai helmets, cranes and more. Taught by &lt;br /&gt;Naomi Fujimoto from the Center for Japanese Studies. Recommended for ages 8+. &lt;br /&gt;2:30 – 4pm&amp;#0160; Japanese Arts and Crafts for Children!: In Japan they even have a special &lt;br /&gt;Children’s Day which is celebrated with arts and crafts and games. Join the Art Center’s &lt;br /&gt;instructors in making a Japanese doll bookmark, a Gyotaku fish print and a koi fish &lt;br /&gt;windsock! &lt;br /&gt;3:30 – 4:30 pm – Story Time – Sadako and the Paper Crane: Learn the true story of &lt;br /&gt;Sadako Sasaki, the brave heroine of Hiroshima and her lasting legacy as a child of peace. &lt;br /&gt;The story of Sadako &amp;amp; The Paper Cranes will be read by Heather Littlefield from the &lt;br /&gt;Center for Japanese Studies. Recommended for children ages 6-10 years old. &lt;br /&gt;Throughout the day, sample Japanese candy, make candy “sushi” and try your skill at the &lt;br /&gt;Japanese board game of Go.&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;All programs are free thanks to a generous contribution from Masco.&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;Drop in for one program or make a day of it. For more information, visit &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarborartcenter.org%20&#34;&gt;www.annarborartcenter.org &lt;/a&gt;or call 734 994-8004 x114. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Halloween hours and events for October 31, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 23:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As promised here&amp;#39;s a collection of Halloween information for Ann Arbor and the area for 2008.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ll be updating this page as new stuff comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;City of Ann Arbor - offical hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRICK-OR-TREATING MAY TAKE PLACE&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;IN CITY OF ANN ARBOR NEIGHBORHOODS&amp;#0160; &lt;br /&gt;ON FRIDAY, OCT. 31, 2008, BETWEEN 5 AND 8 P.M. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;more on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/news/Documents/2008_News_Releases/Halloween_2008.pdf&#34;&gt;halloween pdf press release for 2008 for ann arbor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Burns Park - Costume Parade&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from the Burns Park Elementary PTO newsletter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our annual Halloween Costume Parade is a much-awaited event in the&amp;#0160; neighborhood. The parade will begin at 2:15 on Friday, October 31.&amp;#0160; Weather permitting, we will parade into the park and around the block. Students bring costumes to change into at the end of the day for the parade. We encourage you to come and enjoy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celebrate Halloween all week at AADL: Kids in grades 4-5 can join us for an alien autopsy at our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=2163&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34; title=&#34;reference on Weird Science Halloween party&#34;&gt;Weird Science Halloween party&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday, Oct. 26, from 3-4 p.m. at the Pittsfield branch or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=2188&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34; title=&#34;reference on make pirate costumes and treasure maps&#34;&gt;make pirate costumes and treasure maps&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, Oct. 28, from 4-5:30 p.m. at the Traverwood branch. Grades 6-adult will hear &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=2478&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34; title=&#34;reference on chilling tales of investigations&#34;&gt;chilling tales of investigations&lt;/a&gt;
by the SouthEast Michigan Ghost Hunters Society on Thursday, Oct. 30,
from 7-8:30 p.m. in the Downtown Library Multi-Purpose Room, and
younger kids can dress up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=2106&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34; title=&#34;reference on our annual Halloween Party&#34;&gt;our annual Halloween Party&lt;/a&gt;
on Friday, Oct. 31, with stories, songs and treats at 9:30-10:00 a.m.
or 10:30-11 a.m. in the Downtown Multi-Purpose Room (just prior to the
Main Street Area Association&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://mainstreetannarbor.org/newsdetail.asp?id=45&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;reference on Downtown Treat Parade&#34;&gt;Downtown Treat Parade&lt;/a&gt; at 11:00 a.m.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Halloween stores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year-round costume stores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Packard and Platt: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fantasyattic.com/&#34;&gt;Fantasy Attic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy these temporary stores, temporarily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W Stadium near Pauline (in the former Ace Barnes Hardware): &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.halloweenusa.com/cgi-bin/stores/show.cgi?storenum=4&#34;&gt;Halloween USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.halloweenusa.com/cgi-bin/stores/show.cgi?storenum=4&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other event listing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://activerain.com/blogsview/750082/Halloween-Events-around-Ann-Arbor-Saline-and-Washtenaw-County&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor realtor Missy Caulk&lt;/a&gt; has a list of events around the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s October - echoes of previous years</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a review of what people were looking for to find this weblog in previous Octobers.&amp;nbsp; Some of this tells me what I should write about this year, and other parts of it tell me what fads came and went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=ann+arbor+trick+or+treat+hours&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor trick or treat hours (search)&lt;/a&gt;: Every year I try to post a complete list of trick or treat hours for the area; here&#39;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/halloween_trick.htm&#34;&gt;2005,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/halloween_trick.html&#34;&gt;2006,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/09/halloween-trick.html &#34;&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt; lists.&amp;nbsp; This year if I&#39;m ambitious I&#39;ll try to get a list of any special events by neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michigan+spiders&#34;&gt;Michigan spiders (search&lt;/a&gt;): One of the most popular October pages is a writeup I did on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/brown_recluse_s.html &#34;&gt;the brown recluse spider&lt;/a&gt; two years ago; a recent one on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/09/pumpkin-spider.html&#34;&gt;the pumpkin spider&lt;/a&gt; should be good too.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s not a coincidence that spiders are part of Halloween decorations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=noguchi+filing+system&#34;&gt;Noguchi filing system (search):&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; In October 2005 I wrote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/noguchi_filing_.html &#34;&gt;Noguchi filing system&lt;/a&gt;, a time-centered approach to filing and memory by a Japanese economist that William Lise had described on his translation web site.&amp;nbsp; Interest spiked ever so briefly in August 2006.&amp;nbsp; Subsequently Lise pulled his excellent descriptive text from the net in response to piracy of his text.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noguchi.co.jp/&#34;&gt;The Yukio Noguchi web site is all in Japanese&lt;/a&gt; but may help in some way to help you reconstruct this system from his original works describing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=laszlo+bock&#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock, Google (search):&lt;/a&gt; In October 2006, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2006/10/laszlo_bock_goo.html &#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock was interviewed by the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; about changes to the hiring process at Google, describing a system that was going to be more heavily quantified and measured than before.&amp;nbsp; Interest in that clip peaked Jan 2007 and has been consistent.&amp;nbsp; A further &lt;a href=&#34;http://mba.yale.edu/news_events/CMS/Articles/6352.shtml&#34;&gt;interview with Bock by the Yale School of Management&lt;/a&gt; gives few additional insights, but this interesting tidbit: he was an actor in &amp;quot;Showtime kinds of movies&amp;quot;, yet there&#39;s no unambiguous credits for him in IMDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=book+burro&#34;&gt;Book Burro (search):&lt;/a&gt; In October 2006, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron/2006/10/book_burro_wins.html&#34;&gt;Firefox plugin Book Burro won 2d prize in a mashups for libraries contest organized by OCLC.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Book Burro watches web sites when you browse and alerts you to information about books referenced on the page, allowing you with a minimum of keyboard and mouse movement to know whether that book from Amazon is in stock at your local library.&amp;nbsp; I wrote about this as part of some broader set of library focused writing at my other blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron&#34;&gt;Superpatron.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in October 2005, I wrote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/caribou_coffee_.html&#34;&gt;Caribou Coffee opening up down the street&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s still there, and I&#39;m still a regular.&amp;nbsp; mmm coffee...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>