<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>October on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/october/</link>
    <description>Recent content in October on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 22:45:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/october/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Lake Orion Pumpkin Launch was a blast!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-08-2012-lake-orion-pumpkin-launch-was-a-blast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 22:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-08-2012-lake-orion-pumpkin-launch-was-a-blast/</guid>
      <description>Mark this down under &amp;quot;things to be sure to do next October&amp;quot; -
The 5th annual, 2012 Lake Orion Pumpkin Launch was a blast. It was held at Orion Oaks park, about 90 minutes from Ann Arbor. Five teams competed to launch pumpkins with trebuchets out into a field. The winning team, the Masters of Mayhem, lobbed a pumpkin over 1300 feet (a quarter of a mile).
Pictures when I have them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 26, 2008: Japanese kids culture at Ann Arbor Art Center</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-october-26-2008-japanese-kids-culture-at-ann-arbor-art-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 16:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-24-october-26-2008-japanese-kids-culture-at-ann-arbor-art-center/</guid>
      <description>this is pulled from the Burns Park Press newsletter for November 2008.
What:&amp;#0160; The Art Center has partnered with volunteers from the Center for Japanese Studies at the University of Michigan to offer an afternoon of family friendly programming that celebrates Japanese culture.&amp;#0160; When: Sunday, October 26, 1:00 – 5:00 pm&amp;#0160; Where Ann Arbor Art Center, 117 W. Liberty Schedule of Events: 1 – 1:30 pm Japanese Singing Circle: Learn Japanese children’s songs taught by Stacey Pratt from the Center for Japanese Studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Halloween hours and events for October 31, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 23:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-ann-arbor-hallo/</guid>
      <description>As promised here&amp;#39;s a collection of Halloween information for Ann Arbor and the area for 2008.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ll be updating this page as new stuff comes in.
City of Ann Arbor - offical hours TRICK-OR-TREATING MAY TAKE PLACE&amp;#0160; IN CITY OF ANN ARBOR NEIGHBORHOODS&amp;#0160; ON FRIDAY, OCT. 31, 2008, BETWEEN 5 AND 8 P.M. more on the halloween pdf press release for 2008 for ann arbor
Burns Park - Costume Parade from the Burns Park Elementary PTO newsletter:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s October - echoes of previous years</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-01-its-october---e/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a review of what people were looking for to find this weblog in previous Octobers.&amp;nbsp; Some of this tells me what I should write about this year, and other parts of it tell me what fads came and went.
Ann Arbor trick or treat hours (search): Every year I try to post a complete list of trick or treat hours for the area; here&#39;s the 2005, 2006, and 2007 lists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>