<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games Great Weird Ideas Maps Neighborhoods Networks Pedometer on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/games-great-weird-ideas-maps-neighborhoods-networks-pedometer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games Great Weird Ideas Maps Neighborhoods Networks Pedometer on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 14:26:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/games-great-weird-ideas-maps-neighborhoods-networks-pedometer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Around, a new urban walking game</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 14:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-28-walking-around-a-new-urban-walking-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m inventing a new urban game called Walking Around. I&amp;#39;m sure that someone else has invented it already, but reinvention is part of the process of creativity. Here&amp;#39;s how it&amp;#39;s played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you play with a pedometer, which tells you how far you&amp;#39;ve walked during the day. There are a number of systems already for tracking your pedometer usage, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://walkertracker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Walker Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://swellnessresearch.wordpress.com/projects/steps/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/a&gt;, and a bunch of others. Use whatever system that gives you, or just a spreadsheet, to take care of the basic structure of making certain that you count steps daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second - and here is what is novel, at least to me - is that there&amp;#39;s a bonus structure in the game designed to award bonuses for when you have accomplished tasks. The first bonus award that I&amp;#39;m awarding myself looks at constructing a walk so that you make an orbit around the biggest possible chunk of territory; that is to say, repeated walks along the same path will get you zero bonus, but going out of your way on a detour will add to your score, and trekking through unfamiliar territory in a big loop is the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far this is a pen and paper game and I haven&amp;#39;t fully worked out the point structure. I have a notion that you capture territory every time you orbit it, so that you might win a park by going all the way around it, and you might win a political ward or precinct by capturing a loop around it. To simplify greatly, since I am trying to keep record of this in a small book, I&amp;#39;m just drawing a graph with destinations rather than tracking every street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some idea sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/node/18868&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Riverwalks Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is a book of walking loops along the Huron River, written by&amp;#0160;Brenda E. Bentley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://laketrek.blogspot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Lake Trek&lt;/a&gt; is the weblog for&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://laketrek.blogspot.com/search/label/Loreen%20Niewenhuis&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;Loreen Niewenhuis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;who wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brilliant-books.net/product/1000-mile-walk-beach&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A 1000-Mile Walk on the Beach&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;about her circumnavigation on foot of Lake Michigan. I don&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;m going to beat that top score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Graham wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2005/12/18/PKG7DG81961.DTL#ixzz0YAiHcOQj&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Walking The World&lt;/a&gt;, and his quest to walk every street in San Francisco, in 2005 for SF Gate; his web site is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfwalkingman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;SF Walking Man&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.aadl.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AADL Summer Reading Game&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;has points for reading books and badges for doing various other tasks, and the gamers there know how to make a game that will make you read. There should therefore be points in my Walking Around game every time you complete part of a circuit that connects to a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allcitynewyork.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;All City New York&lt;/a&gt; is the work of Moses Gates, whose game board includes the challenge of visiting all of the census tracts of New York City. Thanks to Ruth Kraut for the link.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Tacoma, &lt;a href=&#34;http://xca2.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Brian Kerr&lt;/a&gt; is getting bonus points in his version of the game for elevation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now pardon me while I connect some dots in my game map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>