<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Analytics Writing on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/google-analytics-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Analytics Writing on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:55:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/google-analytics-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis paralysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 14:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-19-analysis-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Right-now-0-active-visitors-on-site&#34; title=&#34;Right-now-0-active-visitors-on-site&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51124a97a970c-800wi&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a bunch of tools that tell me what people have looked at on the net, including Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools, Clicky, and some Twitter tools. It&#39;s fascinating to see people&#39;s attention move around and occasionally reanimate something that I wrote months or years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What these tools don&#39;t easily do is tell me what to write about next. Yes, sometimes they suggest missing things that should be expanded on, and looking at Twitter stats is endlessly fascinating. But that&#39;s a large part of the problem - the endless fascination gets in the way of applying fingers to the keyboard and creating something brand new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s easy to get distracted by the sorts of things that are meant to help you out. It&#39;s hard to be analytical and dispassionate about your past work while at the same time you&#39;re trying to create new work. Not everything worth writing has to rank highly on a search engine or get lots of referral traffic; sometimes, you just need to create something even if it&#39;s only for you to stretch your fingers. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>