<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apples on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/apples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apples on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 10:10:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/apples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 is a record apple crop for Michigan growers, but migrant labor is hard to find</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-28-2013-is-a-record-apple-crop-for-michigan-growers-but-migrant-labor-is-hard-to-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 10:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-28-2013-is-a-record-apple-crop-for-michigan-growers-but-migrant-labor-is-hard-to-find/</guid>
      <description>2012 was a disaster for Michigan apple growers, but 2013 has been a good year. From Capital Press:
 Michigan apple industry set new shipment records two weeks in a row in October — with the second and highest week being 414,702 boxes the week ending Oct. 12.
Michigan and New York are experiencing bumper crops following severely reduced crops in 2012 from spring freezes.
“Our growers, packers and shippers are working seven days a week, day and night, to move this crop,” said Diane Smith, executive director of the Michigan Apple Committee in Lansing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prime Red apples are in at Farmers Market (August 24, 2013)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</guid>
      <description>We got some Prime Red apples at Farmer&#39;s Market from Wasem&#39;s Fruit Farm.
Prime Red is also known as Akane or Tokyo Rose. From Orange Pippin, an encyclopedia of apples:
 Akane was developed in Japan in the 1930s, and represents an unusual marriage of the classic English early variety, Worcester Pearmain, and the high quality American heritage apple variety, Jonathan - and it is a marriage that works very successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>