<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Arborwiki University Of Michigan Wiki on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-arborwiki-university-of-michigan-wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Arborwiki University Of Michigan Wiki on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 09:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-arborwiki-university-of-michigan-wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Wikipedians - U of Michigan student Wikipedia association</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-10-01-michigan-wikipedians-u-of-michigan-student-wikipedia-association-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 09:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-10-01-michigan-wikipedians-u-of-michigan-student-wikipedia-association-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan Wikipedians is a University of Michigan student association. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Michigan Wikipedians (or MWiki) is a Wikipedia student organization at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor. The group was the first student Wikipedia club in the United States. The club is open to all students and faculty of the University of Michigan, as well as community members who are interested in Wikipedia. It meets every Monday at 8:00PM at the Language Resource Center in the basement of North Quadrangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to an organizing meeting Monday 30 September 2013, here&#39;s a few things I saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:ArborWiki&#34;&gt;ArborWiki template&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Use this template to link Wikipedia articles to their ArborWiki counterparts, especially if the ArborWiki articles contain more information (including information of local interest more appropriate to ArborWiki than Wikipedia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine this with the corresponding &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Template:ArborWiki&#34;&gt;pages that link to this template&lt;/a&gt; and you get a short list of forward links from Wikipedia to Arborwiki. There&#39;s a similar page of &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Entries_with_pages_in_Wikipedia&#34;&gt;Arborwiki entries with pages in Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; that completes the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wikimedia Commons has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Buildings_in_Ann_Arbor,_Michigan&#34;&gt;Buildings in Ann Arbor, Michigan&lt;/a&gt; category with more than 100 photos of the area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to be a member of the Michigan Wikipedians group, simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Michigan_Wikipedians/Members&#34;&gt;add your name&lt;/a&gt; to the roster of active members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetings are every Monday on the U of Michigan campus. I&#39;m hoping to make it there 2d Mondays - 1st and 3d Mondays are Ann Arbor City Council, and 4th Mondays are a2civictech - and hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>