<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 10:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>converting vision into reality - don&#39;t give the whole thing away in the first meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-03-converting-vision-into-reality-dont-give-the-whole-thing-away-in-the-first-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-03-converting-vision-into-reality-dont-give-the-whole-thing-away-in-the-first-meeting/</guid>
      <description>I have been in too many meetings where the first part of the meeting is the brainstorm of what we might do to address the opportunity at hand, and the remainder of the meeting is the long, tedious process of turning that vision into a project plan with dates and deliverables and milestones and activities that can be resolved into auditable checkboxes on a spreadsheet. And you know what? I hate the work that turns vision into process before the vision has had a chance to see how things actually are for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get invited to conferences</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-how-to-get-invited-to-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 21:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-how-to-get-invited-to-conferences/</guid>
      <description>Brian Marick on How to get invited to conferences:
Someone asked me for advice on how to get invited to speak at conferences. &amp;#0160;Key advice:
 become a valuable participant in a niche field, grow along with the niche, become a good speaker.   &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;There&amp;#39;s more, of course; there&amp;#39;s always more; it&amp;#39;s a good discussion of how he found a growing niche and helped popularize it in part by viewing things from a novel perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>