<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>July on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/july/</link>
    <description>Recent content in July on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 17:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/july/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Violin Monster has been kicked off the streets for Ann Arbor&#39;s Art Fair (UPDATE: He&#39;s Back)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-the-violin-monster-has-been-kicked-off-the-streets-for-ann-arbors-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 17:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-the-violin-monster-has-been-kicked-off-the-streets-for-ann-arbors-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR, JULY 18, 2013 - Find the Violin Monster at the corner of Liberty and Main at the Art Fair on Main Street, he&#39;s a guest there of the Main Street Area Association.
@jhritz I&amp;#39;m heading out to Liberty and Main right now. The Main Street area saw my Facebook post, and welcomed me to their turf!
&amp;mdash; Violin Monster (@ViolinMonster) July 18, 2013  ANN ARBOR, JULY 17, 2013 - The &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art Fair Bingo, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-art-fair-bingo-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 14:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-art-fair-bingo-2013/</guid>
      <description>This graphic is making the rounds; original artist Katy McGrady (happy to give credit where credit is due). And of course it&amp;#39;s hot for the Ann Arbor Art Fair, and there&amp;#39;s a bit of rain.
More Art Fair bingos, courtesy of Damn Arbor, from Osric; some more commentary from Reddit /r/annarbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Fourth of July parade, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-04-ann-arbor-fourth-of-july-parade-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 13:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-04-ann-arbor-fourth-of-july-parade-2013/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Fourth of July 2013 parade was this morning. Some brief highlights, so I don&#39;t forget them; I&#39;ll include pictures if I have them. In approximate order of the parade route.
Lots of candy, lots of politicians, lots of kids on bikes.
The Star Wars marching band playing the Imperial March, and a bun-headed Leia. Darth Vader was driving the car that towed an R2D2 float.
A Star Wars band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early July berry picking report, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-05-early-july-berry-picking-report-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 10:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-05-early-july-berry-picking-report-2011/</guid>
      <description>U-Pick Strawberry season in the Ann Arbor area is over; it ended June 29 at Rowe&amp;#39;s, and June 26 at Whittaker&amp;#39;s.
Juneberries are still on the trees, but they are overripe and best left for the birds.
Mulberries are out in full force on the trees and on the sidewalks. Look down for black blotches, then look up for ripe berries.
Blackberries and black raspberries can be found in parks or in the yards of helpful neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>