<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linda Diane Feldt on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/linda-diane-feldt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linda Diane Feldt on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 16:36:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/linda-diane-feldt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expect the 2013 crop of juneberries to be a good one in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-23-expect-the-2013-crop-of-juneberries-to-be-a-good-one-in-ann-arbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 16:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-23-expect-the-2013-crop-of-juneberries-to-be-a-good-one-in-ann-arbor/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;#39;s the word from Ann Arbor Chronicle contributor Linda Diane Feldt:
 Service berries (aka June berries) appear to be on schedule. They taste like blueberries. Very edible. They will be ripe in two to three weeks [from May 23, 2013].&amp;#0160;
 That puts a projected juneberry first picking date at about June 7, after the peonies start but before the u-pick strawberries are ready.
More details on the Arborwiki Juneberries page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurodiversity and the advantages of autism-spectrum disorders in network building</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-20-neurodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-20-neurodiversity/</guid>
      <description>Neurodiversity means accepting those whose various nervous system components behave as generally expected (neurotypical), as well as those whose nervous systems don&amp;#39;t (autism, migraines, scotopic sensitivity, sensory hyperacuity, parkinson&amp;#39;s, ALS, etc.).
 One of the challenges in building an effective team and a useful network of people to work with is to reach out widely enough to reach some people who have a diversity of background and experience. Seek representation from all corners including people from large and small cities, from a variety of ethnic and racial backgrounds, and with diverse religious, cultural, and economic backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>