<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinking on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinking on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:23:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 09 05 thinking in graphs vs thinking in lists</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-thinking-in-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-05-thinking-in-graphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing at the Biggby by the dog park with a 20 oz coffee close at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thinking style one&amp;rdquo; comes up with a topic with crisp edges,
and then enumerates a set of carefully constrained and
largely self-similar elements within that topic. You can
be sure at the end that the question at hand has been
thoroughly plumbed, and that nothing is missing because
you went through diligently to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thinking style two&amp;rdquo; starts with a topic, really anything,
and moves laterally and tangentially from one to the next.
The cafe reminds you not of other cafes but of the dog park
across the street and the converstaions there, but also of
the day that you set up a radio at the cafe to listen to
airplanes, and that moves tangentially along a trajectory
towards radio listening in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can do crisp edges and careful enumeration, but pretty soon
I get distracted by the butterfly and then reminded of places
in the world that I love where the butterfly lands on milkweed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging for me has been a process of catching thoughts as
they go by, writing them down thoroughly enough that I can
reconstruct the mindset at a later date, and then moving on
to the next butterfly. Faced with that ephemeral corpus, who
can complain that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to organize? There&amp;rsquo;s no one overarching
theme to anything, just ideas flitting from here to there
along a long migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have had good luck writing on a topic for a long time, it
has been the discipline of ensuring that the lead paragraph always
had a specific word. I could write anything I wanted to with the
words &amp;ldquo;Ann Arbor&amp;rdquo; in the lead paragraph for AnnArbor.com; I can
write anything with &amp;ldquo;FOIA&amp;rdquo; or something similar and get neatly
pigeonholed there. But I don&amp;rsquo;t and won&amp;rsquo;t write about butterflies
often enough to make a &amp;ldquo;butterfly blog&amp;rdquo;, even if that&amp;rsquo;s my style,
flitting from one place to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Biggby is open until 6pm, even on Labor Day. Meijer is the
next stop, for back-to-school lunch shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some ideal size for a collection of posts that are all
related - if you can really write 150 separate things that are 500
words each and are all related, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a substantial body of work.
It may make sense to partition my blogging output into several
smaller batches and work from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day when listening to airplanes using dump1090 at this Biggby
I managed to pick up a plane over Indianapolis. I have a feeling
I&amp;rsquo;ll be buying more SDR radio gear in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milkweed grows at Michigania and at the Vielmetti-Peters Conservation
Reserve. It likes old fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to take some care when you have thoughts that go from one
idea to the next to explain the transition slowly and clearly
for the person listening to you. Sometimes you need to pretend like
your mind is grinding slowly and deliberately through a set of
predetermined tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>