<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Womack on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/people/jason-womack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jason Womack on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 09:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/people/jason-womack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of the hand-written note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 09:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2007/2007-12-04-the-power-of-th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I used to send a lot more postcards, back in the day when I was on airplanes all the time.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jasonwomack.com&#34;&gt;Jason Womack&lt;/a&gt; sends this out in his newsletter recently, about holiday cards and card writing in general:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Chances are however you celebrate the closing of one year and the opening of another, you will connect with more people in your network during the holiday season.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;People wonder how I have time for it all. They ask me, &#34;You REALLY write handwritten cards weekly?&#34; My answer is yes...and I love it.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Here&#39;s how I do it:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;    * I buy a 5-10 cards at a time. I write my return address and put a first class stamp on it, so it&#39;s ready to go. I put those cards into an &#34;action&#34; folder that goes into my briefcase. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;    * Whenever I have some down time like when I&#39;m early to a meeting, sitting at an airport, waiting for a seminar to begin, or on a break while coaching, I simply open that folder. Really, all I need is 4 minutes, and I can get it done quickly and easily!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;    * For the holidays, I prefer to write a personal note, rather than just sign my name. If you&#39;re going to make the effort to reach out, say something!
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/09/send_a_postcard.html&#34;&gt;I learned to write postcards from my grandfather Marshall Kay&lt;/a&gt;, a geologist who would send appropriate ones from his field trips.  Perhaps the solution is more field trips to exotic locations (or more locations that provide postcards as handy self-promotional materials).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- technorati tags start --&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:right;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/postcard&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;postcard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/writing&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- technorati tags end --&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>