<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/keyphrases/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/keyphrases/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>diligently editing and converting for production</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to get this blog ready for production.
The tasks remaining include the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a reasonable home page with pagination. Somehow I need
to provide some kind of access to almost 2000 posts, and they
don&amp;rsquo;t all fit on a single page. Sort through the design to make
old things reachable, and then worry next about the formatter.
(This is done at least minimally, though the provided paginator
interface uses a list structure that&amp;rsquo;s not nice. Still, it gets
me to what I need to in a ping.) Open discussion on gohugo is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/pagination-and-group-by-date/1441/3&#34;&gt;Pagination and group by date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish to Github Pages, using vielmetti.github.io. I did this
once (using Octopress) so it should be straightforward to do it again.
I already do have a proper github repo (or nearly proper, it may
be missing some key bits). Done; don&amp;rsquo;t have a perfect build script
yet, but there&amp;rsquo;s at least a start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import all sorts more nonsense here, including a bunch of Superpatron
and Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Secret and FOIA Coordiator weblogs. There&amp;rsquo;s no particular
reason not to make it all one big soup. Import from Typepad is problematic
but not impossible and that would be a good addition to the supported work;
in particular it&amp;rsquo;s not evidently possible to export Markdown from Typepad,
just HTML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sort out theme issues so that I get a reasonable display for category
and subcategory pages. I may have to write some things down by hand
to get an understanding of what I really want. As it is right now
those pages render as blank, in part because I need to convert a bunch
of data imperfectly imported, which was throwing errors in my
templates, which in turn was breaking the build. Dealing with the
errored out builds is a question again for gohugo,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/taxononomy/1445&#34;&gt;taxononomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal with the date problems. Lots of dates got imported without a timezone,
but that was not the real issue; the real issue was also that lots got
imported with &amp;ldquo;layout: post&amp;rdquo;. Take that out and it seems to fix things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Request a dump of the image cache from Typepad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>