<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Munnecke on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-munnecke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tom Munnecke on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-munnecke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>System mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s always good to collect a lot of examples as you look to map out a system. For that you want to have generative tools that suggest the kinds of examples that you want to look for.
The power outage maps I have been collecting started with the generative system of making a blank entry for each of 50 states, and looking to collect one in each state. I&amp;#39;ve done similar exercises where the generator is the first letter of the alphabet collecting examples A-Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknowledge management</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</guid>
      <description>From The Unknowledge Pattern Language, on Nooron:
 Unknowledge Patterns describe ways of talking about that which is unknown. For example, the discovery of the periodic table of the elements created a pattern of information about what we didn&amp;#39;t know about the elements, until we &amp;quot;filled in the blanks.&amp;quot; These &amp;quot;named voids&amp;quot; in our knowledge were powerful attractors, and shaped the discourse of science. Are there other ways of naming voids which shape our discovery?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow conversations with a daily deadline and an unanswered question</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-16-slow-conversations-with-a-daily-deadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 22:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-16-slow-conversations-with-a-daily-deadline/</guid>
      <description>Tom Munnecke reminds me of a slow conversation we have been having for a few years. &amp;#0160;I noted it here about five years ago.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Five years is a pretty good time to stretch out a single line of thinking, so it&amp;#39;s worthwhile reflecting on how much current writing structure allows for some amount of leisurely conversation in the face of a daily deadline.
The hard part about taking a question slowly is that most of what I end up writing for AnnArbor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>