<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-munnecke/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/tom-munnecke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>System mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s always good to collect a lot of examples as you look to map out a system. For that you want to have generative tools that suggest the kinds of examples that you want to look for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/06/power-outage-maps.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;power outage maps I have been collecting&lt;/a&gt; started with the generative system of making a blank entry for each of 50 states, and looking to collect one in each state. I&amp;#39;ve done similar exercises where the generator is the first letter of the alphabet collecting examples A-Z. You are looking for breadth in your view, and something that constrains the search so that you don&amp;#39;t spend too much time in one place before going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to have some kind of rudimentary ranking algorithm when wrapping up your search, so that you can look for gaps into which another example will fit. The utility map effort looks like it&amp;#39;s going to generate a simple checklist for each map, so that I can give each one a score on completeness (0 = no map, add 1 for county by county stats, add 1 for city by city stats, add 1 for zoom to the outage, add 1 for systemwide counts etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the things you collect into categories that have names, so that you can start working with abstractions instead of concrete instances. The list of categories becomes another place to generate a bounded set of additional elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have all of these you can start to think about plausible things that might be in the system that you haven&amp;#39;t found yet. My piece on &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/06/unknowledge-management.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;unknowledge management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (the phrase is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.munnecke.com/papers/dragons.htm&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;from Tom Munnecke&lt;/a&gt;) where the task becomes looking for names for things that don&amp;#39;t exist yet but that might plausibly exist given the system that you have described. This means that you end up with something peculiar to search for, and either it doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, it can&amp;#39;t exist (and your models are off), or you find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the iterative process looks like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;describe a search space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;collect examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;rank along common attributes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;categorize into abstractions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;synthesize the undiscovered instances&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that seems to be as good a plan as any for survey of the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jhsph.edu/clf/programs/eating/proj_foodsystem.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;food system map of Baltimore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;looks like an instance of the structure of this work. In academia, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.com/scholar?q=survey+article&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0&amp;amp;as_vis=1&amp;amp;oi=scholart&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;survey article&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(Google Scholar) is structured in much the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknowledge management</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nooron.org/know/uplift_linguistic_shell/unknowledge_pattern_language&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Unknowledge Pattern Language&lt;/a&gt;, on Nooron:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unknowledge Patterns describe ways of talking about that which is unknown. For example, the discovery of the periodic table of the elements created a pattern of information about what we didn&amp;#39;t know about the elements, until we &amp;quot;filled in the blanks.&amp;quot; These &amp;quot;named voids&amp;quot; in our knowledge were powerful attractors, and shaped the discourse of science. Are there other ways of naming voids which shape our discovery? The discovery of zero, a &amp;quot;missing nothing,&amp;quot; was one of the turning points in Western thought. Are there other missing nothings lurking about, waiting to be discovered? If so, how do we name these voids, and to what end? This is the stuff of unknowledge management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving a name to something is a powerful act of creation. The ability to describe the unknown and nonexistent with words that are suggestive of its qualities creates a new universe of the plausible alternatives to the way that things are right now, and gives a way forward either to discover the absent or to rename existing concepts as though they were brand new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first hand experience in this world is in the world of wiki, where any name can be the target of commentary. Your wiki link to &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Price_of_a_cup_of_coffee&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Price of a cup of coffee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is real, even if the page that answers that query is currently blank. At a later time you can bind the name to its commentary, and use the statistics you get from watching people explore the unknowledge of the world to decide which of it to bring to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A counterpoint to this line of reasoning is the periodic need to unname things which have names, so that they can grow new names that are newly reflective of the current observation. We didn&amp;#39;t know that we had land-line phones and terrestrial radios until cell phones and satellite radios forced the use of distinctive nomenclature. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit to Pete Kaminski, who has used the word &amp;quot;incipient links&amp;quot; to describe the deliberate use of wiki pointers to nowhere, and to Tom Munnecke for Nooron and the phrase &amp;quot;unknowledge management&amp;quot;. Pete also gave me &amp;quot;great weird ideas&amp;quot;, where this clearly fits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow conversations with a daily deadline and an unanswered question</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-16-slow-conversations-with-a-daily-deadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 22:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-16-slow-conversations-with-a-daily-deadline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://munnecke.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tom Munnecke&lt;/a&gt; reminds me of a slow conversation we have been having for a few years. &amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/10/slow_conversati.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;I noted it here about five years ago.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;Five years is a pretty good time to stretch out a single line of thinking, so it&amp;#39;s worthwhile reflecting on how much current writing structure allows for some amount of leisurely conversation in the face of a daily deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part about taking a question slowly is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;most of what I end up writing for AnnArbor.com&lt;/a&gt; is done with a short deadline. A daily column gets written the same day, much of the time, and the hours spent reading and following up on comments are as near real time performance art as anything else. How on earth do you have leisurely conversations when there&amp;#39;s always the next thing to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, perhaps, is to leave open questions which are unanswered, and don&amp;#39;t try to seal off the end of each piece of writing with a neat and tidy finish. By leaving open ended questions which would take much more time than could be answered inside the scope of the words you have to produce today, you get the hopeful opportunity to revisit that same topic knowing a bit more about what you don&amp;#39;t know when it&amp;#39;s time to look again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This echoes, in part, one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dangillmor.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Dan Gillmor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s suggestions for journalism: that readers and writers &lt;a href=&#34;http://personaldemocracy.com/blog-entry/using-distributed-media-and-people-ask-hard-questions&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;collect unanswered questions&lt;/a&gt; as a part of the process of addressing complicated issues, and that the collected set of questions gets raised not only by the author but also by anyone else who wants to take up the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a good question is difficult, and knowing when and where to pose it is a challenge. Some questions are better spoken, and others better written down. If the questions are difficult enough, you might spend most of the time looking to see who will answer them sensibly. &amp;#0160;Yet it may be that only by raising more questions than you are able to answer that you will get forward progress on complicated issues at a pace that doesn&amp;#39;t lend itself to instant answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>