<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>V. Zorba on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/v.-zorba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in V. Zorba on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/v.-zorba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink. Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong iced latte, just add a little half and half.
The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence of mind seven years ago to write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick for image manipulation and that helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Alfio Vielmetti (1911-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</guid>
      <description>This eulogy was read for my great-uncle Alfio (Auch) by his nephew Zorba. Alfio Vielmetti died in 2008 at the age of 96. I think of him when I am out on my walks, and I miss him when I wish I had someone like him to talk to about city council.
AUCH
My uncle Alfio lived a life centered on family and community, with lessons learned hard in early years, and applied for a very long lifetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eulogy for Alfio (Auch) Vielmetti</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-eulogy-for-alfi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 21:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-eulogy-for-alfi/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Zorba wrote a eulogy for my great uncle Auch, who died last week at the age of 96. The whole thing is a bit too much to share right now, but there was one paragraph that really spoke to me about the sort of family I come from (and perhaps some insight into who I am)  In his later years Auch did a lot of walking. I mean a LOT of walking, some of it right below us when the weather was bad, and I am convinced that his amblings had a lot to do with the length of his stay with us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>