<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chirp on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/chirp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chirp on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 16:45:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/chirp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming your new radio with CHIRP</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-programming-your-new-radio-with-chirp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-programming-your-new-radio-with-chirp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chirp.danplanet.com/projects/chirp/wiki/Home&#34;&gt;CHIRP web site&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CHIRP is a free, open-source tool for programming your amateur radio. It supports a large number of manufacturers and models, as well as provides a way to interface with multiple data sources and formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is that rather than learning the peculiarities of your radio&#39;s programming interface, you use CHIRP which has access to databases like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radioreference.com&#34;&gt;Radio Reference&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.repeaterbook.com/&#34;&gt;RepeaterBook&lt;/a&gt; to find the channels you want to have easy access to. Programming the device should just be a matter of loading in the set you want, attaching your radio to your computer via a programming cable, and selecting &#34;Upload to Radio&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new radio is on its way, so I&#39;ll update this when I get it to work! So far the application was easy to install (you have to install a Python runtime on OS X before it works) and it was easy to get the Washtenaw county repeater list from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.repeaterbook.com/&#34;&gt;RepeaterBook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATED: It worked the first time! Here&#39;s what I did to make it go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, before you upload channels to your radio, you have to download its current configuration. This gets all of the settings out of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, after you are done uploading the channels, unplug the programming cable from the radio. This should be obvious? but somehow it wasn&#39;t. Once I unplugged things everything worked just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, make sure that you pick the right radio that you are connecting to or else unpredictable things can happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the walk-through at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miklor.com/COM/UV_CHIRP.php&#34;&gt;Miklor&#39;s CHIRP Software Guide&lt;/a&gt; to be useful and helpful, and it suggested some additional features (like setting channels to be receive-only) that will probably get me to re-program the radio a few times before I&#39;m done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>