<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newspapers on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/newspapers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newspapers on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 23:35:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/newspapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council proposes, but does not vote on, anti free newspaper distribution law</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-21-ann-arbor-city-council-anti-free-newspaper-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 23:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-21-ann-arbor-city-council-anti-free-newspaper-law/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (December 5, 2011): There are a number of neighborhoods in Ann Arbor where there are citizens who receive newspapers, and &#34;newspaper-like items&#34;, where the citizen does not pay for the newspaper. We receive a free copy of the Ann Arbor Journal, and there are some neighborhoods where a number of students receive the Wall Street Journal gratis.
Alas, not everyone who gets a free paper opens it up in time for it to be useful, and some of it turns into litter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit Daily Press not off to a great start</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-28-detroit-daily-press-not-off-to-a-great-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 11:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-28-detroit-daily-press-not-off-to-a-great-start/</guid>
      <description>This is such a curious story that I want to preserve bits of it as they appeared, to help better make sense of it.
The back story is that some veterans of the &amp;quot;strike newspaper&amp;quot; industry decided they could make a go of doing a new daily Detroit paper, with delivery.
They launched to the point of being able to print a week&amp;#39;s worth of paper, then abruptly shut down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on the email interview and the validity of written communications</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-02-on-the-email-interview-and-the-validity-of-written-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-02-on-the-email-interview-and-the-validity-of-written-communications/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a wide variety of quality in people&amp;#39;s ability to express themselves in written form, and an &amp;quot;email interview&amp;quot; is one way of assessing this.&amp;#0160; This generally takes the form of a set of questions provided to the interviewee to be answered by them using whatever means they have to prepare a suitable answer.&amp;#0160; You will often find that it takes some time to get a response back, especially if there are a lot of questions or if the questions are hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bat Boy Lives: The Weekly World News on Google Books</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-bat-boy-lives-the-weekly-world-news-on-google-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 14:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-22-bat-boy-lives-the-weekly-world-news-on-google-books/</guid>
      <description>Happily for the process of scholarly research, a good sized run of the Weekly World News has been digitized and is up on Google Books.
 The New York Post reported in 2008 that Bat Boy LLC was going to take over publication of the Weekly World News, and sure enough there&amp;rsquo;s a fresh web site at weeklywordnews.com .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 years ago today, or the value of newspaper archives</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-04-30-years-ago-today-or-the-value-of-newspaper-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-04-30-years-ago-today-or-the-value-of-newspaper-archives/</guid>
      <description>The Marquette Mining Journal printed this today, in their &amp;quot;30 Years Ago&amp;quot; column:
Marquette Serior High School freshman Ed Vielmetti, 14, son of Mrs Katherine Vielmetti, 415 E. Michigan St., won honorable mention in the 22nd annual Michigan Mathematics Prize Competition. &amp;#0160;For his showing, Vielmetti received a certificate and copy of &amp;quot;Mathematics Gems,&amp;quot; from the Michigan Council of Teachers of Mathematics.

The Michigan Math Prize Competition has a storied history:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>