<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newspapers on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/newspapers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newspapers on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 08:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/newspapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>on the email interview and the validity of written communications</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-11-02-on-the-email-interview-and-the-validity-of-written-communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-11-02-on-the-email-interview-and-the-validity-of-written-communications/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a wide variety of quality in people&amp;#39;s ability to express themselves in written form, and an &amp;quot;email interview&amp;quot; is one way of assessing this.&amp;#0160; This generally takes the form of a set of questions provided to the interviewee to be answered by them using whatever means they have to prepare a suitable answer.&amp;#0160; You will often find that it takes some time to get a response back, especially if there are a lot of questions or if the questions are hard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frankly, I&amp;#39;m disappointed that more people don&amp;#39;t spend the time on getting better at both writing written questions and in responding to them.&amp;#0160; A well-written set of questions, thought through in advance, can give a candidate or any other interview subject time to prepare and reflect on the tone they wish to project.&amp;#0160; This can be very instructive when compared to the same person&amp;#39;s behavior in an unreflective, spontaneous, unscripted moment.&amp;#0160; In addition, email leaves a trail and a public record and you know how useful it is to have a public record to refer to from time to time rather than private, unreliable personal notes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know that the stereotype is the ink-stained reporter clutching the steno pad grabbing a good phrase here and there.&amp;#0160; But there needs to be more attention to how people present themselves in email, especially given how much municipal business is transacted through the email.&amp;#0160; I am certain that a reporter is capable of being just as tough and as hard-nosed via written form to members of government and candidates for elected office - just as good elected officials are skilled in the art of writing pointed requests for information from agencies and departments in order to get at the details they want.


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>