<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>diligently editing and converting for production</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:47:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-15-diligently-editing-and-converting-for-production/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to get this blog ready for production. The tasks remaining include the following.
 Get a reasonable home page with pagination. Somehow I need to provide some kind of access to almost 2000 posts, and they don&amp;rsquo;t all fit on a single page. Sort through the design to make old things reachable, and then worry next about the formatter. (This is done at least minimally, though the provided paginator interface uses a list structure that&amp;rsquo;s not nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>write every day</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-write-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 09:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-write-every-day/</guid>
      <description>How do you produce so much writing? It is simple. All you have to do is sit down every single day and write.
There is nothing like a daily deadline to focus the mind.
Weblogs do not impose an external deadline. No editor is asking you when your work is going to be ready, and no producer is going to feed you copy. It is just you up against the elements, bravely typing away alone and hoping that your focus is not distracted by systems problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>750words.com - a writing environment for a daily writing exercise</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750wordscom-a-writing-environment-for-a-daily-writing-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 02:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-28-750wordscom-a-writing-environment-for-a-daily-writing-exercise/</guid>
      <description>This system has you writing 750 words each day.   I&amp;#39;ve already written 750 words today, a long essay on blogging, forgetting, and remembrance. It was pretty good, and I was pretty happy with it. At one point it was 830 words but I cut it down to size, removing a paragraph and tightening up a few phrases.  The goal of the 750 words site is to get you into a habit of writing that many words each and every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpolished writing in the open notebook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-24-unpolished-open-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Steve Crocker, Internet Request for Comments 3, from 1969: &amp;quot;There is a natural hesitancy to publish something unpolished, and we hope to ease this inhibition.&amp;quot;
From time to time, someone reads Vacuum and comments that the writing looks unpolished and incomplete. Why would you publish this kind of work, which obviously isn&amp;#39;t up to the standards that would let you sell it to someone for use in print? Why wouldn&amp;#39;t you hide it in your notebooks?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>