<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apples on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/apples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apples on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 12:46:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/apples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Applesauce recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-applesauce-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 12:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-01-applesauce-recipe/</guid>
      <description>APPLESAUCE At farmer&#39;s market, ask the farmer for a half a peck or a peck of &#34;mixed seconds for sauce&#34;. Use whatever apples they give you. In November 2014 I paid $7 for a peck of mixed seconds at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market.
Quarter and core many apples; do not peel. Cover bottom of pot with water, put in the apples, half (or a whole) orange (pref. organic, with seeds removed), one (or two) cinnamon sticks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kohlrabi and apple slaw - a study in comparative literature</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-21-kohlrabi-and-apple-slaw-a-study-in-comparative-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2013 11:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-21-kohlrabi-and-apple-slaw-a-study-in-comparative-literature/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is assembled from a variety of sources; I&#39;ll update when I&#39;ve actually made it myself to report back.
The basic idea is that you make a dressing of mayo thinned with a little vinegar, and you use equal part shredded kohlrabi and shredded apple in the salad. Mustard is a common seasoning.
Some variations on the theme, with links to recipes:
 AllRecipes adds prepared mustard, lemon juice, and sugar to the dressing Epicurious replaces the mayo with heavy cream and adds some chopped parsley and mustard Boston Organics follows Epicurious but replaces parsley with mint The Floating Kitchen adds carrots, and replaces the mayo with Greek yogurt Martha Stewart dresses the slaw with olive oil and lemon juice and skips the mayo Edible Twin Cities adds some fennel to the salad  I could continue but this is enough meta-information to head to the kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prime Red apples are in at Farmers Market (August 24, 2013)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-24-prime-red-apples-are-in-at-farmers-market-august-24-2013/</guid>
      <description>We got some Prime Red apples at Farmer&#39;s Market from Wasem&#39;s Fruit Farm.
Prime Red is also known as Akane or Tokyo Rose. From Orange Pippin, an encyclopedia of apples:
 Akane was developed in Japan in the 1930s, and represents an unusual marriage of the classic English early variety, Worcester Pearmain, and the high quality American heritage apple variety, Jonathan - and it is a marriage that works very successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Story of the Apple&#34;, Barrie Juniper on the history and evolution of apples</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-the-story-of-the-apple-barrie-juniper-on-the-history-and-evolution-of-apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-the-story-of-the-apple-barrie-juniper-on-the-history-and-evolution-of-apples/</guid>
      <description>The Story of the Appleby Barrie Juniper (ISBN 0881927848) is a 2006 book which traces the evolution of the apple through time and tries to answer the question why of all things natural evolution resulted in a widely palatable fruit, where the natural variation of apple varieties gives only about 1% of the total being tasty.&amp;#0160; Barrie&amp;#39;s daughter, Sarah Juniper, runs The Apple Factor, an antique apple consultancy in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>