<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/curry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 13:38:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/curry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower Curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-06-cauliflower-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 13:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-06-cauliflower-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cauliflower Curry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1 Tbs canola oil&lt;br /&gt;1 large onion, chopped&lt;br /&gt;2 8 oz packages savory baked tofu&lt;br /&gt;curry powder&lt;br /&gt;1 head cauliflower, cut into florets, steamed&lt;br /&gt;coconut milk, about half a can&lt;br /&gt;diced tomatoes, one small can&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heat the canola oil over medium heat (&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;).&amp;#0160; Add chopped onion.&lt;br /&gt;Cook until fragrant.&amp;#0160; Add curry powder - I generally sprinkle it&lt;br /&gt;lightly over the top - and stir until even more fragrant and colorful.&lt;br /&gt;Add diced tofu, stir so that the curry powder is equally mixed in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don&amp;#39;t cook so hot that the onions brown, but get everything hot&lt;br /&gt;enough that if you stopped you could eat the mixture right there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Add steamed cauliflower, stir until everything is coated with the curried&lt;br /&gt;onion.&amp;#0160; Adjust the seasonings so that the color is right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Add the coconut milk and diced tomatoes.&amp;#0160; If you are using canned&lt;br /&gt;tomatoes, consider reserving some of the liquid so that the curry&lt;br /&gt;is not too soupy.&amp;#0160; Stir, bring to heat at &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt;, then reduce the heat&lt;br /&gt;to &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; and cook until the color is right.&amp;#0160; (At the start, you will&lt;br /&gt;have a pinkish tone because the tomatoes are raw; you are aiming for&lt;br /&gt;a more curry color, which will happen when the tomatoes are cooked&lt;br /&gt;through).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With the right amount of liquid, this can be served over rice or with&lt;br /&gt;rice on the side to sop it up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Serves as many people as you make it for; I allow 4 oz of tofu per&lt;br /&gt;family member.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It could probably have peas added to it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Freeze the other half a can of coconut milk for the next time you&lt;br /&gt;do this recipe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even better the next day if there&amp;#39;s any left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We like the &lt;em&gt;Panda&lt;/em&gt; brand savory baked tofu from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Michigan%20Soy%20Products&#34;&gt;Michigan Soy Products&lt;/a&gt; in Royal Oak, MI, available in Ann Arbor at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/PFC&#34;&gt;People&amp;#39;s Food Coop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>