<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rawsonville Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/cities/rawsonville-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rawsonville Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/cities/rawsonville-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2009 strawberry season delayed by cold weather</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 23:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-06-14-michigan-2009-strawberry-season-delayed-by-cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s some reports from around the state of the strawberry crop.&amp;#0160; (We&amp;#39;re planning a trip to Rowe&amp;#39;s in Rawsonville for Father&amp;#39;s Day).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshplaza.com/news_detail.asp?id=45468&#34;&gt;From the Detroit Free Press via FreshPlaza:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;At DeGroot&amp;#39;s Strawberries in Gregory, 16 acres of lush plants are close to ripening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s
not too hot and could be a little warmer,&amp;quot; says Marsha DeGroot, who
with her family has owned the Livingston County farm since 1978. &amp;quot;But
the lovely winter with lots of snow made for a nice insulating blanket
for the plants.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pick-your-own strawberries will be $1.20 a
pound at DeGroot&amp;#39;s this year. Whittaker&amp;#39;s strawberries sell for $1.25 a
pound. And at Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm in Ypsilanti, the cost is $1.46 per
pound, up 3 cents from last year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshplaza.com/news_detail.asp?id=45470&#34;&gt;From mlive.com again via FreshPlaza&lt;/a&gt; on the season in mid-Michigan:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Geri R. Hingston and her husband, James H. Hingston, own Hingstons
Country, 18670 Dice in Merrill, a 4-acre you-pick farm with
strawberries and other produce.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Customers usually begin
harvesting the fruit about June 14, but she said she probably will
delay by five or more days because of cooler weather, frost warnings
and bees not coming out to pollinate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/528487.html&#34;&gt;A June 8 story in the Marquette Mining Journal (via the Escanaba Press) about UP strawberries:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;There were also a few days where overnight lows dropped close to
the freezing mark at the Delta County Airport, however, it is possible
inland areas did drop to or below freezing,&amp;quot; said Fleegel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;A call by the Daily Press to Victor Ledvina, owner of Ledvina&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm in Flat Rock was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;There was also no indication of when picking would begin at Ledvina&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Dave
Pellegrini, operator of Pellegrini&amp;#39;s Strawberry Farm said they had been
irrigating five out of the past eight nights to prevent the fragile
blossoms from frosting over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;The full moon in June is called the strawberry moon; it was on June 7.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan u-pick strawberry season opens June 3, 2009 in Rawsonville, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 22:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-06-02-michigan-upick-strawberry-season-opens-june-3-2009-in-rawsonville-mi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We haven&amp;#39;t scheduled our visit yet to &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowesproducefarm.com/&#34;&gt;Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm in Rawsonville, MI&lt;/a&gt;, but as a public service you should know that they are open.&amp;#0160; From the mailing they sent out:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;il&#34;&gt;STRAWBERRY&lt;/span&gt; SEASON TO BEGIN SOON !!!!!!
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first day of the 2009 &lt;span class=&#34;il&#34;&gt;strawberry&lt;/span&gt; season will be Wednesday June 3rd.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As usual, when we first open not all of our varieties of berries are&amp;#0160;
ready to pick. If you are looking to pick massive amounts to freeze or
make jam it would be better to wait until they are more plentiful. With
the cool temperatures predicted the berries may not ripen that quickly.
It is advisable to call the farm before you come out to make sure we
are not closed to let them ripen up.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The price of the berries is $1.46 per pound and we furnish the
containers for free.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We are open 7 am to 8 pm daily (weather permitting).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did I find out about this, you ask?&amp;#0160; &amp;quot;The List&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;UpickText blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We at Rowes have been compiling lists of customer
addresses over the years and been sending postcards to our customers
when the strawberry and raspberry seasons are at their peak. Our
strawberry list has over 12,000 addresses and the raspberry list has
over 4,500. Due to rising costs of printing and postage we are no
longer taking addresses for our lists. Instead we have started an email
list. You can sign up for &amp;quot;The List&amp;quot; by sending us an email via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowesproducefarm.com/contact.html&#34;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/a&gt;
page. Once you send us an email the email address you send from will be
added to our new list. This way instead of getting one notice we are
able to send updated information on picking conditions more often,
better serving our customers. If you are on the &amp;quot;old&amp;quot; postcard list it
would be appreciated if you would sign up for the email list and tell
us your street address so we can remove it from the old list. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12000 strawberry pickers!&amp;#0160; wow.&amp;#0160; you should get on The List if you want more updates.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t see any current info on their web site (other than &amp;quot;get on The List&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>