<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipe on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipe on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:30:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Kale with corn and green onions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe for kale with corn and green onions works well enough with frozen corn, but I&amp;#39;m sure it would be better with fresh. You cook with the ingredients you have, not the ingredients you want to have. We&amp;#39;re lucky to have fresh kale at the farmers market!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bag kale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;corn - frozen, if you must, but fresh would be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green onions - chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash and spin-dry the kale, being careful to get dirt out of the center rib. We had a very nice bag of small kale from market that didn&amp;#39;t require much more than this, but if you have older, tougher kales, trim them of their tough bits and cut them into pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in a large pot on medium high to high. Chop some garlic into big pieces. Fry the garlic until light brown and it smells good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the kale and cook, stirring frequently, until the kale has cooked down to a fraction of its original size. Add some corn and the chopped green onions; stir. Cook until the corn is warmed through, then add some soy sauce and cover and turn down the heat to low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bag of kale served the family, with one person not eating it; there were a few leftovers. This recipe would multiply quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more kale recipes, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.365daysofkale.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;365 Days of Kale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>