<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/a2b3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/a2b3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for August 6, 2015 at Mi Compadre</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</guid>
      <description>The a2b3 lunch this week was at Mi Compadre, a Mexican place on Packard. We had a good turnout. I recommend the lengua tacos.
I was inspired this week for the lunch question by going to the Workantile lunch on Wednesday, which followed the same general pattern - sit down, introduce yourself around the table, and answer some simple question. At Workantile the prompt was simply &amp;ldquo;share something nice that happened to you this week&amp;rdquo;, and that was enough of a prompt for everyone to be brief and cheery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away. I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).
The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch a postcard from the command line of my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>Eight of us met for lunch at Ayse&amp;rsquo;s today. It was a normal Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for the lunch group these days.
We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make sure that the things that needed to get done got done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>A nice lunch at Argus Farm Stop. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from Harnois Farm, and we had 9 at the table.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>