<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ypsilanti-michigan/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ypsilanti-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10/4 4-5p FLY Art Center volunteer orientation, FLY Creativity Lab, Ypsilanti</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-21-104-4-5p-fly-art-center-volunteer-orientation-fly-creativity-lab-ypsilanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Christine Bruxvoort sent me these details on the FLY Art Center&#39;s upcoming volunteer orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the volunteer orientation is going to be: Oct 4, 2014 4:00 p.m. - 5:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where it&#39;s going to be: FLY Creativity Lab, 40 N. Huron, Ypsilanti, 48197 (between Michigan and Pearl). Contact: Chris at 734-217-2228 or info@flyartcenter.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is invited: Any interested adult or teen. Come to find out what we are about or sign up that night on our volunteer list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of commitment is asked for: on going opportunities that are posted through the volunteer sign up page. Adults can also sign up for committees like fundraising and marketing that meet monthly. Other opportunities involve working with kids or in the community at events. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why you&#39;re so awesome: FLY is awesome because we are dedicated to our community and to our FLY kids! FLY means FOR the LOVE of YOUTH and we are proud to serve our area with quality arts programming that can transform our neighborhoods, develop confidence skills in our young ones, and expand the opportunities for arts and culture in our community. Our caring volunteers and staff are essential to making this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much! We haven&#39;t worked much yet with teens but I am excited about the possibilities of using youth as mentors to our children. Please let me know if you have anymore questions about FLY. We really appreciate your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Fly&#34; title=&#34;Fly&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d070161e970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>