<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/go-pass/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/go-pass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Expense report: Cafe Ambrosia, 3/28/11, $1.00; support the go!pass program!</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-cafe-ambrosia-go-pass-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 11:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-cafe-ambrosia-go-pass-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87055b23970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG00870&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87055b23970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87055b23970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;IMG00870&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Cafe_Ambrosia&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Cafe Ambrosia&lt;/a&gt; is located on &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Maynard_Street&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Maynard Street&lt;/a&gt; in Ann Arbor, across the street from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Nickels_Arcade&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Nickels Arcade&lt;/a&gt; and adjacent to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Maynard_Street_parking_structure&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Maynard Street parking structure&lt;/a&gt;. A cup of coffee is $0.95 with your &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/gopass&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;go!pass&lt;/a&gt; discount. &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Ed_Renoullet&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ed Renoullet&lt;/a&gt; runs the cafe. This photograph captures the morning sunlight that reaches the cafe&amp;#39;s front window on a late March morning in Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambrosia is distinctive for having one of the best events bulletin boards in town (another story), for having power outlets at every table, and for its relatively new front seating arrangement. The couch in the front has been removed in favor of tables looking out over the street, which makes it a nice place to read the morning &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Michigan_Daily&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Michigan Daily&lt;/a&gt; or any of your other favorite newspapers and to catch up on morning email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed asked me to note the daily specials, which are difficult to read on this photograph. Monday, $1 tea; Tue-Thu, specials on Chai Latte, Cafe Latte, and Cafe Mocha; and Friday, free flavor shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti wants a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/02/the_coffeepot_s.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;proper cup of coffee&lt;/a&gt;, made in a proper copper coffee pot. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory FTC disclosure: I paid $1 for my cup of coffee, which is the standard price available to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getdowntown.org/bus/gopass/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;go!pass&lt;/a&gt; card holders.&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;My go!pass is from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Workantile_Exchange&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Workantile Exchange&lt;/a&gt; on Main Street in Ann Arbor, who provide my current membership to their coworking space (valued at $160 per month) in exchange for valuable considerations. Links in this post point to the not for profit&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, an encyclopedia of local information about the Ann Arbor area which anyone can edit; it is hosted at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: The go!pass is funded by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2dda.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority&lt;/a&gt;. The members of the DDA are appointed by the Ann Arbor mayor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/John_Hieftje&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;John Hieftje&lt;/a&gt;, and approved by the Ann Arbor City Council. It&amp;#39;s DDA and City of Ann Arbor budget season, and funding for the go!pass is subject to budgetary approval in the 2011-2012 budget cycle. &amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I support the go!pass program, and ask for your support for it in this year&amp;#39;s municipal budget.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please tip your barista generously, even if you have to go back and add some tip in because you didn&amp;#39;t have change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This message paid for by Edward Vielmetti with personal funds. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The support of Ed Renoullet, Bill Tozier, Matt Hampel, Joe Morehouse, Ryan Eby, Brian Kerr and the editors of the Michigan Daily are acknowledged. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any errors are the responsibility of my editor (hey, that&amp;#39;s me!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>