<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Washtenaw County Health Department on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/washtenaw-county-health-department/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Washtenaw County Health Department on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/washtenaw-county-health-department/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>restaurant inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-25-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department does a round of restaurant inspections. Wayne Eaker built an importer that pulls in data from the site that hosts the official county inspections, and is storing the inspection data on Github to make it easier for the next person who wants to build a nice interface to all the data.
Wayne was good enough to find a spot to host an interface to this data that lets you browse through it; you can find it at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vellum, a downtown Ann Arbor restaurant, has closed</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-12-vellum-a-downtown-ann-arbor-restaurant-has-closed/</guid>
      <description>Vellum closed in January 2015. The Ann Arbor News story tells the part of the story of an innovative kitchen that was &#34;like a laboratory&#34;, and a subsequent format change to a more mainstream menu. The restaurant had a two year run.
What&#39;s missing from the narrative is the prompt from the county health department that forced the change. Vellum&#39;s menu at the outset used the &#34;sous vide&#34; cooking technique to produce its most innovative dishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2013 Washtenaw County Restaurant Inspections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-october-2013-washtenaw-county-restaurant-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 12:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-26-october-2013-washtenaw-county-restaurant-inspections/</guid>
      <description>These documents (in CSV and Excel format) provide a list of restaurants in Washtenaw County that were inspected in October 2013, as well as a count of violations. Also accompanying this data is a press release from the county describing how to interpret the data. I&#39;ve put copies on a2docs.
This was prompted in part by the latest Ann Arbor News publication of this data, which did not have the whole list visible or sortable in any useful way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>