<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/books/a-sand-county-almanac/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/books/a-sand-county-almanac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand County Almanac, June: &#34;The Alder Fork - A Fishing Idyl&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-sand-county-almanac-june-the-alder-fork-a-fishing-idyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 14:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-sand-county-almanac-june-the-alder-fork-a-fishing-idyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;We found the main stream to law that the teeter-snipe pattered about in what last year were trout riffles, and so warm that we could duck in its deepest pool without a shout. Even after our cooling swim, waders felt like hot tar paper in the sun.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aldo Leopold, A Sand County Almanac. This 1989 Oxford Paperbacks edition, ISBN 0-19-505928-X, as an introductory essay from Robert Finch commemorating the 100th anniversary of Leopold&#39;s birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We see Leopold, the rural sage, tracking a sunk in January, cutting a venerable dead oak, stalking a legendary fish on Alder Fork or an elusive grouse on an abandoned farm, surveying his private unofficial domain before dawn, wrestling with god-like decisions about tree-thinning, or experiencing a &#34;curious transfusion of courage&#34; from his pines in deep winter.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sand County Almanac is a good book to come back to every month year round.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aldo Leopold, A Sand County Almanac - grandfather of the Leopold Bros.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-aldo-leopold-a-sand-county-almanac---grandfather-of-the-leopold-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 16:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-aldo-leopold-a-sand-county-almanac---grandfather-of-the-leopold-bros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This 1948 collection of essays about the changing of the seasons in Wisconsin was on my parents bookshelf, and sits on mine in the dining room where various bits of natural history live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;asins=0345345053&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;lt1=_blank&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an essay or three for each month.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s some part of November captured in words as &amp;quot;If I Were The Wind&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The wind that makes music in November corn is in a hurry.&amp;#0160; The stalks hum, the loose husks whisk skyward in half-playful whirls, and the wind hurries on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;In the marsh, long windy waves surge across the grassy sloughs, beat against the far willows.&amp;#0160; A tree tries to argue, bare limbs waving, but there is no detaining the wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;On the sandbar there is only wind, and the river sliding seaward.&amp;#0160; Every wisp of grass is drawing circles on the sand.&amp;#0160; I wander over the bar to a driftwood log, where I sit and listen to the universal roar, and to the tinkle of wavelets on the shore.&amp;#0160; The river is lifeless: not a duck, heron, marsh-hawk, or gull but has sought refuge from wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aldoleopold.org/&#34;&gt;Aldo Leopold Foundation&lt;/a&gt; carries on his conservation work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;padding&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt; Leopold defined conservation as a way of life in
which land does well for its inhabitants, citizens do well by their
land, and both end up better by reason of partnership. Aldo Leopold
recognized that no matter how sophisticated we become, people will
always depend on the land—“the land” being shorthand for the community
that not only includes and values people but also plants, animals,
soils, and waters, from the highest strata of the atmosphere to the
depths of the ocean. We often take natural resources and ecosystems for
granted, but, ultimately, the planet’s natural communities and natural
functions are what sustain our economy and enrich our lives. “That land
is a community,” Leopold wrote, “is the basic concept of ecology, but
that land is to be loved and respected is an extension of ethics.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;padding&#34;&gt;Aldo is the grandfather of Scott and Todd Leopold, who ran the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/index.php/Leopold_Bros&#34;&gt;Leopold Bros&lt;/a&gt; brewpub and distillery from a converted brake factory on Main Street in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://homelessdave.com/tt20060906toddleopold.htm&#34;&gt;(Here&amp;#39;s an interview of Todd Leopold on Teeter Talk.)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leopoldbros.com/Leopold_Bros./Welcome.html&#34;&gt;Scott and Todd have relocated to Colorado, where they have focused on their small batch, hand distilled spirits.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>