<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rolodex on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/rolodex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rolodex on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 17:41:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/rolodex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A random walk through the address book</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-25-a-random-walk-through-the-address-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-25-a-random-walk-through-the-address-book/</guid>
      <description>Did I just complain about address books? Well let me complain again.
My addressbook asks for a random() function. It needs to surprise me from time to time, showing me individuals who aren&#39;t going to show up in a search, but who nonetheless are worthy of remembering right now.
My addressbook needs a search by location function, so that I can pan and zoom over geography and figure out who I know where and who&#39;s nearby enough but not in the same city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rolodex Era</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-05-the-rolodex-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 12:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-05-the-rolodex-era/</guid>
      <description>The phrase &amp;quot;the Rolodex era&amp;quot; popped into my head this morning, and here&amp;#39;s some results I get when I search for it.
What the digital age can learn from the Rolodex era, Full Contact:
 Old school salesmen took notes on business cards, but you can enter your notes electronically. Did your new contact mention their hobbies? &amp;#0160;Their blog? &amp;#0160;Their personal Twitter and Facebook pages that weren’t on their business card?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey, you could do that even on paper rolodex cards! Giving up on Contactually for now</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-12-giving-up-on-contactually-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 20:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-12-giving-up-on-contactually-for-now/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an early review of Contactually, and I signed up for their pro service after the trial period expired. I used the system for a couple of months, but have decided to back down from the pro version back to the free version for a while. Here are some reasons for that.
First and perhaps foremost, Contactually is relatively expensive at $20/mo. I looked at what I was spending (or not spending) on other internet services that I use and like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>graph-structured rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-15-graph-structured-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 19:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-15-graph-structured-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>Facebook announced a new search tool today that lets you search through your &amp;quot;social graph&amp;quot;. Techmeme&amp;#39;s front page has plenty of commentary.
I wrote myself this unpublished note about it a few years ago, which looks pretty much spot-on now:
 For each person in your rolodex, draw a little graph of how they are related to others. There might be a few or there might be a dozen links you&amp;#39;d want to make explicit, and each link would have a name so the edges of the graph are also labeled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mental rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 21:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a great use of the term in an LA Magazine review of &amp;quot;Run Lola Run&amp;quot;:
Lola tosses her red phone up in the air and instantly goes through her mental Rolodex of possibilities. Faces flash on the screen. She decides to hit up her banker father and darts out of the house. Credits: the &amp;quot;mental rolodex&amp;quot; term is one I heard first from&amp;#0160;Terry Bean, who used it at an LA2M presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>