<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Irc on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/irc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Irc on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 10:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/irc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>QSO on redditnet via Geekshed IRC</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-17-qso-on-redditnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-17-qso-on-redditnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The #redditnet channel on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekshed.net/&#34;&gt;Geekshed IRC network&lt;/a&gt;
is full of amateur radio operators from the /r/amateurradio network on Reddit.
People seem to be friendly and knowledgable and more likely than not
to be actually doing digital modes on their radio rather than talking
about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The channel practice is tolerant of people treating it as thought
it were a CW or RTTY frequency, complete with contest style behavior
and reception reports (you are always 59 on #redditnet). I haven&amp;rsquo;t
ever done contesting myself for lack of appropriate gear, but I&amp;rsquo;m
starting to see the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRC was formally defined by RFC 1459 in 1993, but it dates from 1988
and was inspired by the earlier BITNET Relay network of 1985. Unlike
the Unix based Usenet network, which focused on email-sized messages,
the IRC network is fundamentally about short messages and also about
considerable autonomy among separate non-federated servers. It&amp;rsquo;s because
of this that IRC has been relatively resistant to the spam that overran
Usenet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Thom &lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/W8TAM-1&#34;&gt;W8TAM&lt;/a&gt; for alerting me to this net,
and Dan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/&#34;&gt;KB6NU&lt;/a&gt; has a nice writeup
of this few other social media nets for hams on his article
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb6nu.com/social-media-meets-ham-radio/&#34;&gt;Social Media meets ham radio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>