<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/vacuum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vacuum on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:04:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/vacuum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Phys.org: ephemeral vacuum particles and the fluctuating speed of light</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-27-from-physorg-ephemeral-vacuum-particles-and-the-fluctuating-speed-of-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-27-from-physorg-ephemeral-vacuum-particles-and-the-fluctuating-speed-of-light/</guid>
      <description>Do I understand this? No. But this is a blog called Vacuum, and this is my service to that task.
Two forthcoming European Physical Journal D papers challenge established wisdom about the nature of vacuum. In one paper, Marcel Urban from the University of Paris-Sud, located in Orsay, France and his colleagues identified a quantum level mechanism for interpreting vacuum as being filled with pairs of virtual particles with fluctuating energy values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lego vacuum, patent 6048249 : Plastic building block toy cleanup vacuum attachment</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-legolego-vacuum-patent-6048249-plastic-building-block-toy-cleanup-vacuum-attachment-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 14:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-30-legolego-vacuum-patent-6048249-plastic-building-block-toy-cleanup-vacuum-attachment-/</guid>
      <description>if you have too many legos on the floor, here&amp;#39;s the patented design for picking them up:
A toy cleanup vacuum attachment which can be used easily by attaching to household vacuum hose for the quick and efficient clean up of a plurality of different size and shape plastic building block toys. The toy cleanup vacuum attachment compromises: a curved suction channel for sucking up plastic toy building blocks; a convex plate guide with vent holes which guides the plastic building block toys within a suction channel into a drop channel while allowing the passage of vacuum current and dust; a rectangular drop channel through which plastic building block toys pass from the force of vacuum momentum and gravity; a transparent collection container for housing the plastic building block toys during cleanup and an air-tight bottom, hinged lid for conducting quick and simple dropping of plastic building block toys back into a toy box; a spring loaded push/twist thumb button agitator for dislodging clogged or stuck plastic building block toys; a grip handle for ease of use and.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This cat does not abhor a vacuum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-21-this-cat-does-not-abhor-a-vacuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 09:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-21-this-cat-does-not-abhor-a-vacuum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>