<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Detroit Maps on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/detroit-maps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Detroit Maps on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 23:58:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/detroit-maps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DETROITography, a weblog of maps about Detroit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-detroitography-a-weblog-of-maps-about-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 23:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-detroitography-a-weblog-of-maps-about-detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;File under &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/detroit&#34;&gt;Detroit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/maps&#34;&gt;maps&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitography.com/&#34;&gt;detroitography.com&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maps and geography of Detroit – that’s what we are all about. We like to write about maps that other people make about the city as well as create our own maps of Detroit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This map (one of many on the site) shows the overlap of what people map out when they say they are from Detroit. The densest is the downtown region only; the most generous encompasses a 9-county region. From Alex B. Hill, &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroitography.com/2013/11/29/100-maps-of-detroit/&#34;&gt;100 Maps of Detroit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b02ad9dec970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b02ad9dec970d&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;100-maps-of-detroit-alex-b-hill-detroitography-detroit100&#34; title=&#34;100-maps-of-detroit-alex-b-hill-detroitography-detroit100&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b02ad9dec970d-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I chose to look at the first 100 images that appeared in a Google image search for “map of Detroit” and overlay the results. Many corporations based in Southfield, Warren, or Dearborn choose to say they are based in “Detroit,” Likewise, most regional organizations (Detroit Chamber, Detroit Water &amp;amp; Sewage, SEMCOG, etc.) represent Detroit with boundaries that extend into surrounding municipalities, most commonly the tri-counties (Wayne, Oakland, Macomb). A number of the 100 maps show urban sprawl to varying degrees while some maps categorize municipalities around the city as “Detroit.” Some maps even included parts of Windsor, Ontario in the “metro Detroit” area. The larger boundaries match the Combined Statistical Area (CSA) and the Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA) as outlined by the federal Office of Management and Budget (OMB), which represent “Detroit” as either a 6 county area (MSA) or a 9 county area (CSA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/detroitography&#34;&gt;@detroitography&lt;/a&gt; for news of site updates and more Detroit map infos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>