<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baseball Detroit Detroit Tigers Power Outages on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/baseball-detroit-detroit-tigers-power-outages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Baseball Detroit Detroit Tigers Power Outages on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:01:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/baseball-detroit-detroit-tigers-power-outages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE statement on power outage at beginning of 3d game of 2013 ALCS at Comerica Park in Detroit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-10-15-dte-statement-on-power-outage-at-beginning-of-3d-game-of-2013-alcs-at-comerica-park-in-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-10-15-dte-statement-on-power-outage-at-beginning-of-3d-game-of-2013-alcs-at-comerica-park-in-detroit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From DTE Energy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;DTE Energy addresses temporary lighting failure at Comerica Park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DETROIT, Oct. 15, 2013 /PRNewswire/ -- DTE Energy&#39;s preliminary investigation of the temporary lighting failure that occurred at Comerica Park during Major League Baseball&#39;s American League Championship Series (ALCS), has found there was a cable failure in the area near the stadium, which caused the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lights in the stadium were out for approximately 20 minutes beginning at approximately 4:41 p.m. Power was restored in the stadium at around 5:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cable failure caused a voltage reduction, which tripped the lights in the stadium. The momentary sag in voltage was an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DTE Energy maintains two independent electrical feeds for precisely this kind of an event. Both feeds to the park continued to provide power during the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#34;We&#39;ve identified the cause of the disturbance and we worked with officials at Comerica Park to resolve the issue quickly,&#34; said Steve Kurmas, President and Chief Operating Officer for DTE Electric, a unit of DTE Energy. &#34;We regret the interruption.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DTE Energy (NYSE:DTE) is a Detroit-based diversified energy company involved in the development and management of energy-related businesses and services nationwide. Its operating units include an electric utility serving 2.1 million customers in Southeastern Michigan and a natural gas utility serving 1.2 million customers in Michigan.  Information about DTE Energy is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://dteenergy.com&#34;&gt;dteenergy.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/dte_energy&#34;&gt;twitter.com/dte_energy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com/dteenegy&#34;&gt;facebook.com/dteenergy&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOURCE DTE Energy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>