<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Power Outages on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-power-outages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Power Outages on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-power-outages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area closings for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High winds took down trees and knocked out power to thousands in Washtenaw County the night of 17 November 2013, and the next morning a number of schools and government offices closed because of lack of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From various sources including email and twitter; this is surely incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools: Tappan and King are closed today due to power outages at both schools. Tonight&#39;s Listen and Learn at Tappan will be rescheduled. Bryant Elementary now closed in Ann Arbor due to power outage-caused heating failure. Students that arrived at school sent back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor District Library: &#34;The power is out at Malletts Creek Branch, it is currently closed. All other @aadl locations will open at 10 AM. Stay tuned for updates!&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ypsilanti Township offices are closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14-B District Court is closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eastern Michigan University: Rec/IM: Due to technical problems, the Jones Pool will be closed until further notice. We apologize for the inconvenience. (via @EMU_Swoop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chelsea Police say power is still out and is expected to be out for &#34;the next several hours,&#34; as of 8:15 a.m. Chelsea schools have also been closed. (Heritage News) Chelsea Center for the Arts will be closed today, Monday, November 18, 2013 due to a citywide power outage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>