<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wildfire on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/wildfire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wildfire on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 17:19:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/wildfire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Duck Lake Fire, north of Newberry MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</guid>
      <description>Some sources for information on the Duck Lake Fire, which started on Wednesday, May 23, 2012 and is burning rapidly in Luce County, north of Newberry, MI. The fire is dangerous and has caused evacuations; if you are reading this and you are in the area, seek authoritative and current information from official sources.
The fire brings to mind the 2007 Sleeper Lake Fire&amp;#0160;which burned over 18,000 acres in Luce County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australia (Victoria, Melbourne area), February 2009 fire map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-08-australia-victoria-melbourne-area-february-2009-fire-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 10:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-08-australia-victoria-melbourne-area-february-2009-fire-map/</guid>
      <description>As pulled from the Google Australia weblog on the fires in Australia goes into detail and has a live map of the fires, included below.
 As a snapshot of this here&amp;#39;s what it looked like when I grabbed it this morning: 
There&amp;#39;s more maps of fire in Australia at aus-emaps; this is a link to static copies of maps, which is better than the live image because of heavy server load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Barbara and Montecito &#34;Tea Fire&#34;, November 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-14-santa-barbara-and-montecito-t-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-14-santa-barbara-and-montecito-t-fire/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: the latest Santa Barbara fire is the &#34;White Fire&#34; in May 2013. Twitter: #whitefire.
UPDATE: the below post refers to the Tea Fire of late 2008; there&#39;s a new Jesusita fire page for May 2009 fire,for anyone coming here by search.
NOTE: Comments on this item are open again, links updated to noon PST Friday
&amp;nbsp; Jason Fox of Seattle, WA writes:
My brother is a musician and lives less than 2 miles south of the fire , he has lost power here is a picture he just took beforehand , feel free to post it on your blog, or to fwd it to news agencies , his name is Justin Fox, of the band Tripdavon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire maps - Michigan, California, and global</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-fire-maps---mic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 18:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-fire-maps---mic/</guid>
      <description>Drought Severity Index by Region from NOAA for the week ending 21 June 2008
It&#39;s fire season (at least in the places where it isn&#39;t flood or landslide season) and the best way to be ready for a fire is to not have the fire start at all.
Here&#39;s a collection of Michigan fire maps, and some additional resources to help get to current information about what&#39;s going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeper Lake Fire mushroom hunting near Newberry, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-sleeper-lake-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 14:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-sleeper-lake-fi/</guid>
      <description>Last year there was a fire near Sleeper Lake in Newberry, MI in the UP; when I wrote about it, I collected fire maps of the Sleeper Lake area showing where the fire lines were. That fire is out now, but that page where I had those maps is still getting a steady stream of page views. So, I have to ask, why?
The other popular seasonal page is my annual Michigan morel map, which I pull an excerpt from the morel progression sightings map and highlight the appearance of these tasty mushrooms in the Michigan woods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>