<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Defined Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/software-defined-radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Defined Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:50:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/software-defined-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dipole antenna for your SDR tuner stick from an old set of headphones</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:50:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes before I try to do the build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts I have or know I can get: cheap earbud headphones, NooElec NESDR Mini 2 SDR tuner stick with whip antenna, Nokia 635 phone, antenna from an older NESDR Mini SDR tuner stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parts I need: a short adapter cable that provides antenna in for the SDR stick as a headphone jack socket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SDR tuner comes with an antenna, but I want to replace it with a dipole - especially one cut to have a center point for FM broadcast on 88.3 (WCBN) and a second one for 2 meter ham radio on local repeaters (W8UM on 145.23 and N8DUY on 145.15). Some sort of adapter jack (or alligator clips) should be all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can test the antenna on my Nokia 635 which has an FM tuner connected with the headphone jack as the antenna, and the ideal situation will be to have an antenna that I can just plug either into my phone or into my SDR tuner interchangeably. Once I figure all that out, the next next step is to make these antenna inputs for other radios. One step at a time though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be working from the tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;http://willus.com/author/antenna.shtml&#34;&gt;Making a Dipole FM Antenna&lt;/a&gt; on willus.com .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plane spotting; some quick notes on a new software-defined radio setup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 18:50:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-29 at 9.50.47 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-29 at 9.50.47 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0f877ad970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 490px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-30 at 11.35.53 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-03-30 at 11.35.53 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c76ed742970b-500wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I got one of the first-generation RTL-SDR USB software defined radio units. These inexpensive devices are originally designed as TV tuners, but clever radio hackers figured out how to turn them into software-defined radios that tune to a broad spectrum of radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some experimental use I managed to cook the original unit which in its death throes no longer listened. The vendor (Nooelec) generously offered a modest discount on my next purchase, so I took them up on the 2d generation unit. Same form factor, bright blue in color, and the supplied antenna is a retractable whip with a magnetic base. As always it comes with no documentation and no software (you are expected to provide those).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had previously used a version of &#34;gqrx&#34; as a radio receiver, in a package that had been built for the Mac. This time I thought I&#39;d build from source. I went to the &#39;homebrew&#39; port system and found a version that said it worked for OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), but I&#39;m on OS X 10.9 (Mavericks) and the build didn&#39;t work (it crapped out in building scipy). Reading the documentation more closely the distribution says it&#39;s available through Macports, so I installed that and did &#34;sudo port install gnuradio&#34; and &#34;sudo port install gqrx&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macports is one of those amazing feats of modern software engineering where someone (or really a lot of people) have carefully and meticulously figured out how to take a package of source code and make it build, including tracing all of the dependencies upon which everything else needs to be built. For gqrx and GNU Radio this means (at the very bottom) that I had to have a working FORTRAN compiler so that I could compile the FORTRAN code hiding in the numerical analysis libraries. This brings me right back to the 1970s learning FORTRAN at Michigan Tech in their Summer Youth Program. I can&#39;t even imagine how old the code was that I compiled but it might actually date from then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything did build just fine, and then I had a radio. The first test is always to tune into WCBN, which came in with a strong signal, and to key up my ham radio transmitter via Echolink to make the W8UM repeater make some noise, and to get some weather radio going. Everything I tried worked just fine and passed with flying colors, the gqrx software is more modern than it once was in a couple of very helpful ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was to grab one of the many versions of &#34;dump1090&#34; which uses the SDR radio to tune to aircraft ADS-B broadcasts that give you a version of aircraft radar. This also worked well, perhaps better than I could have expected. From home with an antenna in the middle of the house I could hear airplanes just north of Jackson, MI from Ann Arbor, MI (about 40 miles). I relocated to a cafe near the dog park (Ellsworth at Platt) that has a good view of the southern sky, and the same little bitty antenna pulled in reception from airplanes near Fort Wayne, IN (about 120 miles). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s always more to try, of course. GNU Radio is a full toolkit for building your own radio design, complete with FM decoders and the like, and it has a fairly simple to understand user interface compared to how complex the underpinnings are (remember, FORTRAN). There&#39;s lots more software that uses the RTL-SDR libraries and even a port to the Raspberry Pi which I&#39;d like to try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>decoding radio digital modes without a radio, using WebSDR and fldigi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 02:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m interested in decoding radio digital modes without actually having a radio. The idea is that by using a web-based software defined radio (to tune in the signals) and the fldigi program (to decode the signals) that I should be able to &#34;listen&#34; to digital modes and start to explore the digital parts of the amateur and broadcast radio bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Fldigi-HB9ERN&#34; title=&#34;Fldigi-HB9ERN&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a51167efb3970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I have all of the components, but I have yet to be able to get everything to work as expected. Here&#39;s what I have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/&#34;&gt;WebSDR&lt;/a&gt; from http://websdr.ewi.utwente.nl:8901/ . This is a software-defined radio tuning  to the radio airwaves at the University of Twente in the Netherlands; it runs in your browser. There are 87 of these systems running around the world, listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://websdr.org/&#34;&gt;websdr.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w1hkj.com/Fldigi.html&#34;&gt;fldigi&lt;/a&gt; from http://www.w1hkj.com/Fldigi.html . This software for Windows, Linux and OS X, runs on your local system and takes an audio signal and decodes it in one of many digital modes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/soundflower/&#34;&gt;Soundflower&lt;/a&gt; from https://code.google.com/p/soundflower/ . This is a Mac system extension that allows you to redirect the audio output of one program (e.g. your browser) into the audio input of another program (e.g. fldigi). Not strictly necessary because the fldigi can also just decode whatever it hears through the computer&#39;s built in microphone. I picked up the recommendation from an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hamradioandvision.com/websdr-digital-modes/&#34;&gt;HamRadioAndVision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of people have done Youtube videos describing what they are doing to make this work. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oz9aec.net/index.php/component/content/article/63-sdr/290-fun-with-websdr-and-fldigi&#34;&gt;OZ9AEC&lt;/a&gt; has a 6 minute Youtube from 2009 shows reception in single channel and multichannel mode. He doesn&#39;t use Soundflower, just the built in mic of his Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not described here - and probably what I need to figure out next - are two key bits of information. Where do you tune to pick up digital signals? And, more importantly, which decoder do you use? It&#39;s not hard to pick out which modulation is being used if you have some practice, but as of this writing I couldn&#39;t readily tell you what WEFAX sounds like compared to RTTY. Still sorting through those details before I can claim to have mastered this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note also that this should work with a local software-defined radio as well, or even with a &#34;hardware-defined radio&#34; placed near your mic or patched in with a mic cable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software defined radio (SDR) for Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-20-software-defined-radio-sdr-for-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 23:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-20-software-defined-radio-sdr-for-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve started looking into software defined radio for Mac OS X. The goal is to take a cheap USB stick, plug it in to the Mac, and have it connect to software that will decode radio signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far there&amp;#39;s nothing obvious that&amp;#39;s packaged as a single collection of software plus hardware, but that&amp;#39;s not surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best notes to date are from &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinboard.in/t:sdr&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Pinboard&amp;#39;s t:sdr tag&lt;/a&gt;, which looks like it has a few dozen people sharing links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll update this when I get more working details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>