<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Hritz on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hritz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in John Hritz on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hritz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson. Ann captured the opening slide. There was a nifty online multiplayer game (can&#39;t recall the site it was built on) which had 95 people playing along from their smart phones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skywarn Spotter Training in A2 now! Hanging w/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jhritz&#34;&gt;@jhritz&lt;/a&gt; Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NWSDetroit&#34;&gt;@NWSDetroit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/0X078Jl5Dg&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/0X078Jl5Dg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; annyhanny (@annyhanny) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annyhanny/status/586890972371386368&#34;&gt;April 11, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My spotter ID good for 2 years is 242.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought my radio to the event and made a contact from the car with Marty KD8RGL from Canton MI. We were both using 5 watt radios contacting the W8UM repeater in Ann Arbor - I&#39;m always surprised how well things work when they do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered that it works a lot better to identify myself as &#34;Eddie&#34; when on the air. This because &#34;Ed&#34; gets misinterpreted as &#34;Andy&#34; all too often, and &#34;Edward&#34; seems awfully formal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arborbike, a first review</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 10:42:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;arborbike&#34; title=&#34;IMG_0636&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d12974a7970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus: fun to ride, big front basket. It&#39;s a very nice bike that you&#39;re riding, with a good 3 speed shifter and a very sturdy construction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minus: no lights, no bell, no helmets. More specifically, I am told that the lights come on automatically, and that there is a bell somewhere, but I didn&#39;t find it and it wasn&#39;t labelled. I did have a helmet with me so I wore that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborbike.org/&#34;&gt;arborbike.org&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to John Hritz - photo credit Ryan Stanton.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban; or, management by post-it note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 21:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wrote a few years back about a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jhritz/6225044/&#34;&gt;mini-kanban that John Hritz had put together to remember to refill washer fluid&lt;/a&gt;.  There are a lot of colorful sticky notes around my workplace these days, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d read up on how kanban-inspired systems are being used for process management in the software development and other non-manufacturing worlds.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some inspiring examples (with post-its to illustrate):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Corey Ladis on &lt;a href=&#34;http://leansoftwareengineering.com/2007/08/29/kanban-systems-for-software-development/&#34;&gt;Kanban systems for software engineering:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
A perfect state of flow may be very difficult, or at least uneconomical, to achieve in a robust product development process. But we can get pretty close with a well-tuned kanban pull system. We have managed to combine most of the flexibility of craft production with most of the control of a pipeline. Work-in-process is limited, and cycle time can be managed. Most importantly, it is a highly transparent and repeatable process with all of the right conditions for continuous improvement.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
oh, wait a second, this is starting to be spooky: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ourfounder.typepad.com/leblog/2008/02/modus-cooperand.html&#34;&gt;Jim Benson&amp;rsquo;s notes on the new people at his Modus Cooperandi:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Corey Ladas - Corey has been a proponent of iterative and evolutionary design methods since the early 1990’s, and was an early practitioner and vocal promoter of Agile methods at Microsoft. Corey began collaborating with David Anderson at Microsoft in 2004, united by a common interest in the application of Lean, Theory of Constraints, and Statistical Process Control methods to software development. In 2007, Corey joined David at Corbis to implement kanban systems for the development of enterprise IT projects.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Time to talk to Jim&amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags start &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:right;font-size:10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/kanban&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;kanban&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/management&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; technorati tags end &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent
spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of
text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories
and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which
tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or
lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into
a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time. A good algorithm
will catch minor deviations from the norm and advise you when you
should go back with a fresh pair of eyes and do an edit.
The bigger problem is
deduplication
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first pass at a proposed solution was to look for a version of
the old Unix program &amp;ldquo;uniq&amp;rdquo; that would have an approximate match.
There is also an old Unix program &amp;ldquo;agrep&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;approximate grep&amp;rdquo;) from
Udi Manber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[WM92a]
Wu S. and U. Manber, &amp;ldquo;Agrep - A Fast Approximate Pattern-Matching
Tool,&amp;rdquo; Usenix Winter 1992 Technical Conference, San Francisco (January
1992), pp. 153-162.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these first lines of attack to see if someone had
completely solved the problem before did the trick, but some
searching around and a conversation with
John Hritz

hit the neuron that remembered the algorithm called the
Levenshtein distance
.
That led me to
Wikibook: Algorithm Implementation
,
and its set of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Algorithm_Implementation/Strings/Levenshtein_distance&#34;&gt;Levenshtein distance code&lt;/a&gt;. It so happened that there
was a very slow implementation in the bash shell included
in that collection that was a cut and paste and two lines of
code from being exactly what I needed. A little bit of glue
code in awk and I was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the problem with cut and paste two lines of code is that this
particular implmentation is very slow, albeit correct. Given the
choice between slow correct code and fast code that&amp;rsquo;s wrong (because
of the bug that you don&amp;rsquo;t yet understand), I&amp;rsquo;ll take the slow code
plus a comment and a writeup that describes how to make it faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m really after is just the pairwise comparison of a set
of words where the two words are close to each other. If the
distance between two words is greater than some threshhold, I don&amp;rsquo;t need
to go any further. That algorithmic shortcut isn&amp;rsquo;t in the library
codes that I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger question is how to write a
checklist
and implement it in code to make sure that a big body of work stays
internally consistent. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to have a
categorization
rule for your writers that says &amp;ldquo;always use the
singular&amp;rdquo;, but very much something different to have Test 38 in
your automated test corpus apply that rule and notice when it&amp;rsquo;s
wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>