<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Hritz on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hritz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in John Hritz on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-hritz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arborbike, a first review</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 10:42:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-17-arborbike-a-first-review/</guid>
      <description>Plus: fun to ride, big front basket. It&#39;s a very nice bike that you&#39;re riding, with a good 3 speed shifter and a very sturdy construction. Minus: no lights, no bell, no helmets. More specifically, I am told that the lights come on automatically, and that there is a bell somewhere, but I didn&#39;t find it and it wasn&#39;t labeled. I did have a helmet with me so I wore that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.
I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban; or, management by post-it note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 21:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a few years back about a mini-kanban that John Hritz had put together to remember to refill washer fluid. There are a lot of colorful sticky notes around my workplace these days, so I thought I&#39;d read up on how kanban-inspired systems are being used for process management in the software development and other non-manufacturing worlds.  Some inspiring examples (with post-its to illustrate):  Corey Ladas on Kanban systems for software engineering:  A perfect state of flow may be very difficult, or at least uneconomical, to achieve in a robust product development process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>