<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rrdtool on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/rrdtool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rrdtool on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 17:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/rrdtool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>RRDTool v1.5.4 on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-26-rrdtool-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 17:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-26-rrdtool-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second in a series of efforts to get a suitable database for
the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of data out there that changes
all the time, and you want to gather it, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s sane, squirrel
it away for later analysis, put together a pretty chart so that you
can spot check it, feed it into other systems not yet fully dreamed
of to cause actions, and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; problem in that
you have sensors that throw off a lot of data exhaust, and it&amp;rsquo;s the
&amp;ldquo;internet of things&amp;rdquo; problem because mostly you&amp;rsquo;re looking at things
with data and not say imagery or lots of freeform text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phase one of this effort was wrestling MongoDB into service, which
ended up being only a handful of lines of code; but the concern expressed
was the Mongo though fun and easy for small projects gets messy for
big ones, and there&amp;rsquo;s good reason not to succumb to its siren song.
The other reason to stop using Mongo when I did was that it really
doesn&amp;rsquo;t love the Raspberry Pi architecture. Since there were only really
a very few lines of code, and since that code works on my Mac, no time
lost - but time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phase two is a look at RRDtool, a &amp;ldquo;round robin&amp;rdquo; database very often used
for network management efforts. One of the nice things about a round robin
database is that the database itself is at its maximum size when you
create it, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t grow - rather, it cycles out the old data
at whatever time resolution you want to get rid of it. With that in
mind you can have a single database with 10 years worth of daily averages
and a whole year of minute-by-minute data and it hardly takes up any
room at all - perfect for the sort of &amp;ldquo;data logger&amp;rdquo; applications that
I find myself in the middle of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do &lt;code&gt;apt-get install rrdtool&lt;/code&gt; on the Pi you get a working
copy of RRDtool 1.4.7, compiled in 2012. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty long in the
tooth, so I decided to pull down v1.5.4 from the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/pub/?M=D&#34;&gt;RRDtool download area&lt;/a&gt;. The release notes note
dependencies as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install libpango1.0-dev libxml2-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and once you have those pulled down the build is not fast but not
difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pushing data into RRDtool is as simple as a shell script run out of
cron. The first data point I&amp;rsquo;m graphing is &amp;ldquo;total spaces free in the
Ann Arbor DDA parking garages&amp;rdquo;, and I&amp;rsquo;m collecting that on two machines -
my Mac when it&amp;rsquo;s running, and the Pi at all times. A second graph
I want to capture is some really basic weather information, and a
third is inside-the-machine environmental sensing starting with the
system temperature of the Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really useful to make the first round of this be Mongo, because
with Mongo you really don&amp;rsquo;t have to decide anything when you set things up -
just dump in raw JSON documents and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/images/parking.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;RRDtool graph of available parking in downtown Ann Arbor&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>