<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peanut Butter on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/peanut-butter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peanut Butter on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 13:30:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/peanut-butter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recall the days when it was safe to eat peanut butter every day.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-recall-the-days-when-it-was-safe-to-eat-peanut-butter-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 13:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-19-recall-the-days-when-it-was-safe-to-eat-peanut-butter-every-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used to eat a peanut butter and jelly sandwich for lunch every single day in sixth grade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the current 1/19/09 recall information via the Emergency Email Network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table bgcolor=&#34;#ffffff&#34; cellpadding=&#34;12&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emergencyemail.org/newsemergency/anmviewer.asp?a=345&amp;amp;z=1&#34;&gt;FDA Issue definitive statement on Peanut Butter Salmonella - Do not eat guidelines
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr align=&#34;left&#34; valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;table align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; border=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; cellpadding=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; cellspacing=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

 &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; 
  &amp;lt;td class=&amp;quot;images&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
     &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#000000&amp;quot; face=&amp;quot;verdana,Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial;&#34;&gt;January 18, 2009: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;Based on this information, and on the current
state of the investigation, the FDA recommends that consumers avoid
eating products that have been recalled and discard them.&amp;#0160; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34; size=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Because identification of products
subject to recall is continuing, the FDA urges consumers to postpone
eating commercially-prepared or manufactured peanut butter-containing
products and institutionally-served peanut butter until further
information becomes available about which products may be
affected.&amp;#0160;Efforts to specifically identify those products are ongoing. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is conducting a very active and dynamic investigation into the source of the&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt; Typhimurium outbreak.&amp;#0160; At this time, the FDA has traced a source of&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt;
Typhimurium contamination to a plant owned by Peanut Corporation of
America (PCA), which manufactures both peanut butter that is
institutionally served in such settings as long-term care facilities
and cafeterias, and peanut paste?a concentrated product consisting of
ground, roasted peanuts?that is distributed to food manufacturers to be
used as an ingredient in many commercially produced products including
cakes, cookies, crackers, candies, cereal and ice cream.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The FDA has notified PCA that product samples
originating from its Blakely, Ga., processing plant have been tested
and found positive for&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt; by laboratories in the
states of Minnesota and Georgia.&amp;#0160; The state of Minnesota has reported
to FDA that its samples of King Nut peanut butter are a genetic match
to the strain of&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt; that has caused illnesses in that state and around the country.&amp;#0160; King Nut is a distributor of PCA product.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;On January 16, PCA expanded its voluntary recall
to include all peanut butter produced on or after August 8, 2008, and
all peanut paste produced on or after September 26, 2008, in its
Blakely, Ga., plant because of potential&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt;
contamination.&amp;#0160; The product being recalled is sold by PCA in bulk
packaging in containers ranging in size from five to 1700 pounds.&amp;#0160; The
peanut paste is sold in sizes ranging from 35-pound containers to
product sold by the tanker container.&amp;#0160; These products are not sold
directly to consumers.&amp;#0160; PCA has stopped all production at its Blakely,
Ga. plant as the FDA continues its investigation into the source of the&lt;em&gt; Salmonella&lt;/em&gt; contamination.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;At this time, there is no indication that any
national name brand jars of peanut butter sold in retail stores are
linked to the PCA recall.&amp;#0160; As the investigation continues over the
weekend, and into next week, the FDA will be able to update the advice
based on new sampling and distribution information.&amp;#0160;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The FDA is working closely with members of the
food industry to narrow this advice and to publish a detailed list of
implicated products as soon as possible.&amp;#0160; The FDA is encouraging
manufacturers to help inform consumers about whether their
products&amp;#0160;could have contained&amp;#0160;commercially prepared peanut butter or
peanut paste from PCA.&amp;#0160; Also, if manufacturers know their products do
not&amp;#0160;contain ingredients from PCA, they may wish to inform consumers of
that fact.&amp;#0160; Retailers should stop selling products which have been
recalled.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;For information on products containing peanut
butter from companies not reporting recalls, consumers may wish to
consult the company?s website or call the toll-free number listed on
most packaging.&amp;#0160; Information consumers may receive from the companies
has not been verified by the FDA.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&#34;Arial&#34;&gt;The FDA will closely monitor these events by
continuing to work with the firms on the details of their actions,
conduct follow-up audits and inspections, monitor the progress of the
firms? actions, and notify our foreign regulatory counterparts of
products that may have been distributed internationally.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>