<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiny Habits on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/tiny-habits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tiny Habits on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 21:40:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/tiny-habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand resolutions vs tiny habits</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-grand-resolutions-vs-tiny-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 21:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-21-grand-resolutions-vs-tiny-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bjfogg.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;BJ Fogg&lt;/a&gt; is hosting an online program in which he encourages people to produce &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/3tinyhabits&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;three tiny habits&lt;/a&gt; that they can learn to do in the span of a week. One of the ones I&amp;#39;m trying to do, for instance, is to take my medicine after the kitchen is clean. That&amp;#39;s not a huge task - after all, the medicine cabinet is in the kitchen - but it&amp;#39;s one that anchors a little task in a place where I know I can make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know if that&amp;#39;s a perfect example of a tiny habit, since cleaning the kitchen can take a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of tiny habits is radically different from the typical New Year&amp;#39;s Resolution which is grandiose, sweeping, and hard to fulfill. &amp;quot;Be a better person&amp;quot; is really different from &amp;quot;brush your teeth after you floss them&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;go to bed after the computer goes to sleep&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m trying to figure out the tiny habit that will get me writing regularly. Ideally, in some perfect world, I&amp;#39;d write more regularly. I don&amp;#39;t want a &amp;quot;write a page every day&amp;quot; goal, because that&amp;#39;s largely unmanagable - when would I do it? But perhaps I can set myself a tiny goal, that&amp;#39;s more like &amp;quot;when I sit down at the computer after the kitchen is clean, open it up to my blog and start writing until I stop.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, that will ensure that the kitchen will be clean before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>