<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don Norman on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/don-norman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don Norman on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 16:42:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/don-norman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lou Rosenfeld talk at UMSI: Beyond user research, building an organizational brain</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-25-lou-rosenfeld-talk-at-umsi-beyond-user-research-building-an-organizational-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 16:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-25-lou-rosenfeld-talk-at-umsi-beyond-user-research-building-an-organizational-brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m at Lou Rosenfeld&amp;#39;s talk at the Michigan Union, with the title &amp;quot;Beyond user research: Building an organizational brain&amp;quot;. Notes below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;quot;You are not your user.&amp;quot; The importance of talking to your users. The book &amp;quot;Design of Everyday Things&amp;quot;, 1986 as a watershed event. Everyone understands this now, so &amp;quot;we won&amp;quot;. But what does victory look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;Less of an information architect, more of an information therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports from the user research group; information about site search analytics (in another group); logs from the call center (yet another group); reports from web analytics applications (yet another group); also &amp;quot;Voice of the Customer&amp;quot; (survey research); CRM applications like Salesforce; papers from a research center; papers from the net; a &amp;quot;mental model&amp;quot; diagram; brand architecture research; net promoter score (survey research).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem: where&amp;#39;s the insight in a situation that&amp;#39;s completely siloed. Risk to &amp;quot;user research&amp;quot; work is that it&amp;#39;s siloed away. If you collaborate you&amp;#39;re &amp;quot;the brain for the organization&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. What vs. why.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Quantitative vs qualitiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Organizational goals vs user goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Measure what you know vs. explore what you don&amp;#39;t know. (Look for outliers, surprises, patterns.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Statistical data vs. descriptive data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to succeed in getting user research to cooperate? Use data from other siloes. Examples: site search data from search logs; match persona with search log analysis; use analytics tools to frame questions about user behavior; field study + analytics combined.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: query search for &amp;quot;lost&amp;quot; on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to get out of your silo: get out of your (physical) space; eat in the other cafeteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary object: things that are common to a couple of fields. Linkages are connective areas of shared interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The preso will be up in slideshare....these notes are incomplete of course)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build a map - put the various interests on the map to generate the space that you can evaluate the various options.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop using words - &amp;quot;useless, misunderstood terms impede progress&amp;quot;. Meaningless buzzwords, none of which involve solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build a dashboard (a failed metaphor) which incorporates information across a number of separate siloes.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>