<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 Arborwiki on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/a2b3-arborwiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 Arborwiki on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 14:51:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/a2b3-arborwiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;the conversation prism&#34; as seen through the eyes of the a2b3 lunch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-05-27-the-conversation-prism-as-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 14:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-05-27-the-conversation-prism-as-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a Twitter conference, so Twitter is full of good stuff people have been saving up.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s one: a &amp;quot;conversation prism&amp;quot; in bright happy colors showing a set of categories of tools, and how each one of them is occupied by some set of applications.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a mapping of each of them onto the set of tools that I am using to keep a2b3 loosely connected.&amp;#0160;
Sorry no links, didn&amp;#39;t have time to hyperlink everything &lt;a href=&#34;http://theconversationprism.com&#34; title=&#34;The Conversation Prism by Brian Solis and Jesse Thomas&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://theconversationprism.com/convoprismembed.jpg&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px solid #666666;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Conversation Prism by &lt;a href=&#34;http://briansolis.com&#34;&gt;Brian Solis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jess3.com&#34;&gt;Jesse Thomas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Forums: Yahoo Groups&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest single tool I use for group continuity; it perhaps reflects my elderly nature that email is the first system rather than web-based forums or modern social networks.&amp;#0160; All I can say in my defense is that Usenet would have been better but it&amp;#39;s really not available, and that I have 10 years of continuous use into Yahoo Groups and they haven&amp;#39;t ruined it (yet).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social networks: Facebook (intermittently)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook will show up here frequently, if only because it&amp;#39;s ubiquitous and because Ann Arbor is full of people who use it.&amp;#0160; My sense is that its group tools are way weaker than its personal tools and so it&amp;#39;s best used as an adjunct to the main Yahoo group just so you can attach names to faces and so you can promote events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Interest and curated networks&amp;quot; (?): LinkedIn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not sure about the category, but LinkedIn certainly qualifies as one ongoing conversation starting and continuing tool.&amp;#0160; Like Facebook, groups are second class objects in LinkedIn, and thus it&amp;#39;s weak at building cohesion.&amp;#0160; On the plus side you don&amp;#39;t have to pretend to be someone&amp;#39;s pal to look up their resume.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviews and ratings: Yahoo Groups, Arborwiki&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of national scale review sites, but nothing beats asking a good sized group of your peers for recommendations on everything from programming language libraries to pest control.&amp;#0160; To whatever extent possible, Arborwiki becomes the public long term storage for what would otherwise be something ephemeral and hard to retrieve through the Yahoo Groups search interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Location: none; I gave up on Plaxo when it creeped me out&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Location-based mobile services are supposed to be the future of the social mobile web, but I lived through having my location visible on Plaxo and decided against living that way when people who knew where I was without me telling them didn&amp;#39;t have the social clues not to be obvious that they were watching me.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; If I want to tell you where I am I&amp;#39;ll be explicit about it on Twitter, or you can just wonder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Video: whatever people use&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of filmmakers in the group, and I respect their judgement what to use for video.&amp;#0160; None of the video tools have strong group membership characteristics - or even particularly weak ones - so I treat them all pretty much interchangably as dumb hosting.&amp;#0160; (And no, I don&amp;#39;t particular care if any given short video clip goes viral.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customer Service: Get Satisfaction, but it&amp;#39;s not quite right&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a2b3 was a business it might need customer support, but it&amp;#39;s not, and Get Satisfaction is just extra baggage.&amp;#0160; Tried it, it seemed to be functional, but not for the problem at hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documents/Content: SlideShare seems to be a favorite&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those people who are giving presentations seem to have settled on SlideShare as a common denominator for hosting.&amp;#0160; The weekly lunches don&amp;#39;t feature presentations so there&amp;#39;s no natural synchronization around it as a tool, but it works as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Events: upcoming, Facebook events, in-person lunch w/announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Events are perhaps the hardest nut to crack, the thing that would make you spend all week promoting other people&amp;#39;s work and the like.&amp;#0160; I have been telling people who don&amp;#39;t have URLs for events to post them to upcoming; Facebook will tell you about more parties than you can manage to go to; and there&amp;#39;s nothing like someone telling you about something around the table.&amp;#0160; The only way to really lick the events question is to have someone full time collecting them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music: One each of everything; I&amp;#39;m fond of how blip.fm twitters out songs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;blip.fm is the closest thing to Napster that&amp;#39;s out there; do a Twitter search for your favorite artist plus the word &amp;quot;blip&amp;quot; and you may be lucky enough to find a fellow fan and a track you can listen to.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; YouTube is also really good for songs - my 4 y/o calls it &amp;quot;picture music&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wiki: Arborwiki, plus my own private Socialtext space&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arborwiki is the designated spot for dropping in information that deserves to live in a wiki; the &amp;quot;Birthday Deals&amp;quot; page there is the one universal attraction point around which much of the rest lives.&amp;#0160; I keep a Socialtext private wiki for my own personal memory augmentation tool, in part because it works awesomely on my Blackberry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Livecasting video: haven&amp;#39;t done it yet, not appropriate for lunch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to join in to lunch, you don&amp;#39;t want to watch it remotely; the space isn&amp;#39;t set up for that.&amp;#0160; If and when I get to a place where regular live video streaming makes sense I&amp;#39;ll use whatever the cool kids are using then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pictures: Flickr, Facebook photos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time Flickr was a dynamic photo community, with dozens of awesome funny friendly creative people who you really wanted to share pictures with.&amp;#0160; Then everything grew up, people left for greener pastures, Yahoo acted stupid more than once, and my camera died.&amp;#0160; Now if I want to share a photo I&amp;#39;m more likely to put it on Facebook.&amp;#0160; I miss the old Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social bookmarks: Delicious, plus whatever Les is working on&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time Delicious was a dynamic bookmark community, with dozens of awesome funny friendly smart people who you really wanted to share bookmarks with.&amp;#0160; Then everything group up, people left for greener pastures, Yahoo acted stupid more than once, and Twitter came along.&amp;#0160; Now if I want to share a link I think twice and either twitter it out or work it into a longer blog post.&amp;#0160; I just hope my 10,000 bookmarks stick around for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comment and reputation: plenty of that around the lunch table&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s enough people who I care to converse with that I know by face and name that the level of comment-tracking promoted by blog tools seems irrelevant, for the most part, or at least too much work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crowdsourced content: arborwiki, a2geeks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both arborwiki and a2geeks have enough of a wiki platform running for general and for technical info that if you need to crowdsource something there&amp;#39;s a place to point people toward to edit things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collaboration: Google Spreadsheets (for football parking info)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I need to collect a bunch of numbers from a bunch of people, Google Spreadsheets seems to do pretty well.&amp;#0160; I love wiki for private collaboration, but you have to be collaborating with people who love it too.&amp;#0160; Otherwise, printing things out and letting someone else wrestle with tracking changes in Microsoft Word is about as good as I get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blog platforms: Typepad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone else worries about it and I just hit &amp;quot;post&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blogs/conversations: Google Blog Search is the best of a bad lot&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard to track conversations in blogs, in part because the blog vs comment distinction is weird.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s just as easy to do regular Google searches and put in teh word &amp;quot;blog&amp;quot; as an added qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blog communities: mybloglog&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m using this mostly for stats and to detect one-day spikes that mean that some seasonal post is current again or to notice when something is on fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Micromedia: Twitter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;twitter, duh.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter ecosystems: trying out Cotweet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a beta account; it&amp;#39;s working pretty well to do future scheduled postings and to better track responses.&amp;#0160; Not sure yet if and how to open up the @a2b3 account to multiple posters but that&amp;#39;s the next obvious thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SMS/Voice: Google Voice&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It converts voice mail to text so that I don&amp;#39;t have to listen to all of my voice mail.&amp;#0160; Still in closed beta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lifestreams: get a life!&amp;#0160; need some privacy sometime&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of living a life is deciding what to broadcast to the Internet and what to keep quiet.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m just as happy to be offline as online, and the idea that you should soulcast every last mood swing seems to be as unproductive as it gets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;----&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After working my way through this, I realize what it&amp;#39;s missing - all of these apps I write about are apps that work on a big screen.&amp;#0160; The real conversation prism also includes a parallel set of augmented reality supported by mobile devices, and that very well may include entirely new categories than above.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>