<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expertise on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/expertise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expertise on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/expertise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.
One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s no internal inconsistencies.
The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>proximity, distance, and expertise</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</guid>
      <description>The challenge of being an expert is that it is hard to be one in your own home town.
Expertise is valued when it comes from far away. The traveling scholar is special for their pure understanding of a difficult field, and they don&amp;rsquo;t incur the baggage of being a neighbor or even a friend. The distinguished visitor can be an exemplar of their craft, not distracted by any complicated local entanglements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>