<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expertise on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/expertise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expertise on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/expertise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>expertise encapsulated into out of date memory banks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-03-expertise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the case of experts &amp;ldquo;writing down what they know&amp;rdquo;, and
incorporating that data into an expert system or knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges is expecting that the expert can write down
everything that they know, all at once, in such a way that there&amp;rsquo;s
no internal inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world usually works in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s changing fast enough
that an expert with a written memory bank of a certain size is
always holding as &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; in that memory bank something that is
demonstrably false, just because the world shifts out from under
them. Even if you have an iron-clad commitment to keeping the
memory bank narrowly scoped and revisiting every element of it to
refresh it periodically, the nature of written memory is to grow more and more
out of date or to consume more and more resources to keep fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map is not the territory - and even if by some miracle the map
at one time was perfectly matched with the world - the world changes
fast enough that we can&amp;rsquo;t know any more than a small part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the impossible task of keeping a Localwiki fresh in
the face of reflecting changes in a city, by Brian Eno&amp;rsquo;s quote
&amp;ldquo;Forgetting is as important as remembering&amp;rdquo;, and by
Jerry Michalski&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Brain&amp;rdquo; magnum opus. Of course I forget where I
read the Eno quote, and a search for it turns up William James saying
the same thing in 1892, but Eno is easier to remember as a source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>proximity, distance, and expertise</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge of being an expert is that it is hard to be one in
your own home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expertise is valued when it comes from far away. The traveling
scholar is special for their pure understanding of a difficult
field, and they don&amp;rsquo;t incur the baggage of being a neighbor or even
a friend. The distinguished visitor can be an exemplar of their
craft, not distracted by any complicated local entanglements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be recognized as an expert you need to be prepared
to travel beyond where you are well understood out to the parts of
the world where you are known solely for your expertise. Go beyond
your narrow orbit and strike out to a place where your reputation
is solid and where you are an example of the thing you call your
own. Leave your own neighborhood behind, even if only to be seen
elsewhere as an expert on neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expertise is a funny thing. You don&amp;rsquo;t always get a chance to pick
what you are good at, because that can come from the views of others.
The further away those others are, the more likely they have some
essential insight into your character that your close neighbors
will never have. Look at yourself through the eyes of someone far
away and see what special characteristics appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Written mostly on a mobile phone while in a familiar cafe.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; Truism: The further you are away, the more expert you become. Also, never a prophet in your hometown.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Neal Kessler (@NealKessler) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NealKessler/statuses/443936415744024576&#34;&gt;March 13, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>