<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Egg on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/egg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Egg on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:24:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/egg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrambled eggs with slow roasted tomatoes (炒鸡蛋西红柿)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-scrambled-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-scrambled-eggs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did the slow roasting during high tomato season, and there are a few quarts of them in the freezer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wondering which recipes would show up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=recipe+egg+tomato&#34;&gt;a search for &amp;quot;recipe egg tomato&amp;quot; on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, I ended up much to my surprise on a Beijing travel web site, which had a recipe for Fried Egg and Tomato – &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beijingmadeeasy.com/chinese-recipes/egg-and-tomato-chinese-recipe&#34;&gt;Chǎo Jīdàn Xīhóngshì – 炒鸡蛋西红柿.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Egg and tomato might sound like an odd combination, but this is a
really common Chinese dish which can be found on the menu at every
cheap and cheerful Chinese eatery in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes about
five minutes to make and is really straightforward. It’s tasty, but
pretty bland, so it’d probably combine nicely with something spicy, a
vegetable dish and plain rice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further searches for 炒鸡蛋西红柿 turned up&lt;a href=&#34;http://xiaoyao-home.blogspot.com/2008/06/ingredients-onion-eggs-cooking-oil-salt.html&#34;&gt; this bilingual post with several egg+vegetable recipes:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&#34;ZH-CN&#34; style=&#34;font-family: SimSun;&#34;&gt;This
is not the technical difficulty of the two dishes, and international
friends to write down the invitation because they only know that onions
can be together steak and roast, scrambled eggs can not know. (tr. Google)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So then the principles which can be adapted as you might need them based on what is at hand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use roughly equal proportions of eggs and tomatoes.&amp;nbsp; I had roasted tomatoes so they weren&#39;t so watery, but you could use fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chop the onion or garlic and mix with the scrambled eggs.&amp;nbsp; Add to a pan with a generous amount of oil and cook.&amp;nbsp; Think &amp;quot;stir fry&amp;quot;, not &amp;quot;omelet&amp;quot; here.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Remove the eggs from the pan and cook the tomatoes (or peas or green beans or what have you) in the same pan.&amp;nbsp; You might add more of whatever seasoning you are using (garlic e.g.).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When the vegetables are cooked and hot, add the eggs back in, mix, season to taste, and serve.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that as a basic start only your imagination is left to add to the possibilities - this would be good with spring peas, zucchini, red peppers just to think of a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More roasted tomato ideas here from the (long and wonderful) comments on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.101cookbooks.com/archives/roasted-tomato-soup-recipe.html&#34;&gt;Roasted Tomato Soup on 101 Cookbooks.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>