<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 18:15:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>sweet potato cauliflower soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 18:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some sweet potato cauliflower soup recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allyson Kramer likes hers with a bit of garam masala:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Three Peas wants carrots and celery and chicken stock:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food.com and &amp;ldquo;Kelly in TO&amp;rdquo; calls for curry and cinnamon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&#34;&gt;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our meal plan pairs this with biscuits and kale, and it was delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew: six recipes to mix and match from</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haven&#39;t cooked any of these yet, but there&#39;s some recipes to work through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricki Heller: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rickiheller.com/2011/03/anti-candida-sugar-free-gluten-free-vegan-chickpea-tomato-and-potato-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Uses tahini to enrich the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fit Pregnancy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitpregnancy.com/nutrition/recipes/chickpea-potato-tomato-stew-chard&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew with Chard
&lt;/a&gt;. With chard, paprika, parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First Mess: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefirstmess.com/2013/09/26/moroccan-style-vegan-vegetable-chickpea-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;moroccan-style vegetable + chickpea stew
&lt;/a&gt;. Sweet potatoes instead of potatoes, and a cinnamon+coriander+cumin spice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Picky Eater: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pickyeaterblog.com/indian-vegetable-stew-yum/&#34;&gt;Indian Chickpea and Potato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Curry is the flavor here, and cilantro replaces parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and Wine: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodandwine.com/recipes/new-potato-chickpea-and-tomato-stew&#34;&gt;New Potato, Chickpea and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. The surprise ingredient is chorizo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally Ella: &lt;a href=&#34;http://naturallyella.com/2011/12/05/sweet-potato-and-chickpea-stew-with-quinoa/&#34;&gt;Sweet Potato and Chickpea Stew with Quinoa&lt;/a&gt;. Quinoa is the novel grain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>recipe: tortilla casserole</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-15-recipe-tortilla-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 23:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-15-recipe-tortilla-casserole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This comes out kind of like a lasagna and is designed the same way:
lots of layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one package tortillas (whole wheat, corn, or flour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one can tomatoes with chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one can black beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 jar corn relish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one package shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;assemble in layers, roughly as so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tomatoes with chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake in a 350 degree oven; I left it in for about an hour, until the top was nicely browned and not singed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Served 3 (one dinner guest opted out)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nana&#39;s Beer Stew recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-nanas-beer-stew-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-nanas-beer-stew-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beer Stew&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Tish Osborn- Originally from Ada Vielmetti (Nana) &amp;amp; Aunt Florence Burt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To serve @ 6 people, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 lbs. Of good Stew Meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 lb. Onions, thickly sliced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flour to dredge meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil to brown meat, in a large skillet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 cloves of garlic, finely chopped or crushed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3T Dark Brown Sugar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¼ cup red wine vinegar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;½ cup chopped fresh parsley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 small bay leaves, put in whole&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 t. dried thyme leaves.....  Or 2 tsps. of fresh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 T. salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshly ground black pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 bottles of GOOD beer.  I often use English Stout&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 10 ½ oz cans of Beef Broth [not Consume`]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Dumpling mix…. recipe below, put on at end of cooking time.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Cut beef into bite-size pieces.  Dredge in flour and brown in skillet with a little oil, before putting in an ovenproof casserole dish.  [I use a large roaster]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        When all beef has been browned, add a little more oil, and sauté onion and garlic just until soft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add the onion and garlic to the casserole with the meat; except beer and broth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add broth to skillet to de-glaze pan.  Add all other ingredients, and stir to make sure sugar is dissolved. Pour over meat mixture and stir again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add beer.  Stir all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Cover casserole and cook at 325 degrees for @ 2-3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Note:  The stew will appear to be very runny.  The dumplings seem to absorb some of the liquid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Mix dumplings together just before you are ready to serve stew.  Drop spoon dumplings on top of meat, put the lid back on the casserole and bake for 15 minutes without lifting lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Serve, and expect accolades. J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often just mix up Bisquick dumplings....but here’s the original recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Optional Dumpling recipe]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 cups sifted self-rising flour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¾ cup of milk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2T. Melted butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little chopped parsley if you like, for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix together and drop on the stew.  Cook 15 min as directed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Lemon Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of a recipes collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was part of dinner last week - yum! I don&amp;#39;t have the exact proportions in front of me so you&amp;#39;ll want to be prepared to improvise.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potatoes&lt;/strong&gt;, peeled, cut to quarters; to fill lasagna pan; redskins would do well &lt;br /&gt;Juice of 3 &lt;strong&gt;lemons,&amp;#0160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fresh squeezed&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;juice not stuff from bottles if you have it&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;Greek &lt;strong&gt;oregano &lt;/strong&gt;(though Mexican oregano worked OK too) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olive oil&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to a good roasting temperature (450+ degrees).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the potatoes in the lasagna pan. Mix lemon juice, water, oregano, oil together; you are after something like a salad dressing, but since you&amp;#39;re baking it the water will go away, so make sure there&amp;#39;s enough oil. Besides, olive oil is good for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour the dressing over the potatoes, mix until everything is coated. Put in oven. Roast until starting to turn brown, about 40-50 minutes depending on your oven and your potatoes. If you don&amp;#39;t have a lot of oil in the dressing, you may need to turn to keep things from sticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll bet it would be good to put a couple of organic lemon halves in there too to roast along with everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove from oven, test for doneness. Eat. Yum. Also good cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other lemon roasted potato recipes, for comparison: &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/unbound/corby/ct2000-12.htm&#34;&gt;Corby&amp;#39;s Table&lt;/a&gt; from The Atlantic Monthly has a patates riganates recipe from a review of Aglaia Kremezi&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Foods of the Greek Islands&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sandisrecipecorner.com/recipe488H.htm&#34;&gt;Sandi&amp;#39;s Recipe Corner&lt;/a&gt;, adds stock &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dvo.com/recipe_pages/grilln/Greek_Garlic_and_Lemon_Roasted_Potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Cook&amp;#39;n&lt;/a&gt;, adds dill and roasts over wood chips &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autumnjade.com/recipes/133.htm&#34;&gt;Autumn Jade&lt;/a&gt;, basically the same with exact proportions &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalgourmet.com/food/special/2001/greek/potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Global Gourmet&lt;/a&gt; calls these &lt;strong&gt;patates riganates&lt;/strong&gt; and adds garlic &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://creampuffsinvenice.typepad.com/cream_puffs_in_venice/2006/04/some_lemony_spu.html&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Cream Puffs in Venice&amp;quot; has some lemony spuds for you&lt;/a&gt;, adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/work/907079&#34;&gt;Cook This&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Rosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;#39;m sure there are more recipes to be had!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more recipe to go with this if you have any cold leftovers. Put a bed of spring mixed greens on a plate; I like the Asian mix we found at Farmer&amp;#39;s Market. Cut some of these potatoes up and put on top. Add diced cubed cold roasted beets for color and flavor. Dress with some of the lemon-oil mix, with a little red wine vinegar added. Yum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; font-size: 10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/lemon&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;lemon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/potatoes&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;potatoes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/recipe&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rice: prepare 1.5 cups rice according to your taste. Do this first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the broccoli: Preheat oven to 425 degrees F. Cut a few heads of broccoli into bite sized florets. Mix in a bowl with olive oil, then place on a cookie sheet. Sprinkle sea salt on top. Roast 12-15 minutes until the broccoli is every so slightly browned on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the garbanzos: Drain and rinse a can of garbanzos. Put in a small pot and cover with water. Heat until hot, then rinse again under cool water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the red peppers: Cut a red pepper into pieces about the size of a garbanzo bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Make a lemon vinaigrette with a little mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Some sweet chili paste, or gochujang, or your favorite spicy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the feta: crumble some feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve in individual bowls on the table, for people to mix their own salads. If your family is like mine, someone will eat just rice and peppers and beans, someone else will prefer the salad without feta, someone will want a vinaigrette and someone else (me) will douse the whole thing with chili sauce. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven fried potato recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing this down so I remember this one detail: to get fries the right size, cut a medium potato into 16 pieces. (Cut in 4 equal width slices, then cut each slice into 4 parts). It works pretty quickly once you get going, and the resulting fries get crispy much more so than potatoes cut into quarters. A sweet potato yields 32 fries, cut in half and then in fours and then in fours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put the raw potato strips into a big bowl, pour some olive oil on them, and mix until everything is nicely coated, then put them onto cookie sheets and cook for what seems like a long time in a 425 degree F oven. If you want equally crispy on both sides, turn them over part way through. They would be good with a sprinking of sea salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more recipes, not that you need much of a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/recipe/oven-fries/&#34;&gt;All Recipes&lt;/a&gt; uses a little sugar and a little cayenne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eatingwell.com/recipes/oven_fries.html&#34;&gt;Eating Well&lt;/a&gt; cuts into wedges (too big!) and adds dried thyme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Crispy-Oven-Baked-French-Fries/&#34;&gt;Instructables&lt;/a&gt; secret ingredient is cornstarch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, maybe you do need a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoppin&#39; Giovanni (Rapini with white beans)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 16:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This simple dish of beans and greens comes from Mary Ann Esposito&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ciaoitalia.com/seasons/season-2200/episode-2221/broccoli-rabe-with-white-beans&#34;&gt;Ciao Italia&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s similar in many ways to the traditional &#34;Hoppin&#39; John&#34; served for good luck for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hoppin&#39; Giovanni&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash and chop a bunch of rapini (broccoli rabe). If you can&#39;t find rapini, some other mild green like turnip greens (or even kale) would work nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mince a shallot fine and saute in a large pan in olive oil until fragrant. Add a few generous pinches of red pepper flakes. Put the chopped rapini into the pan and cook until the greens are cooked through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drain and rinse a can of white beans (cannellini). When the greens are cooked through, add the beans and stir. You can add a little more olive oil to the pan at this point if you want to. Stir and then bring back up to heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve hot. This would go good with pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lentil, feta, and olive pasta salad</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-29-lentil-feta-and-olive-pasta-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-29-lentil-feta-and-olive-pasta-salad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This delicious lentil, feta, and olive pasta salad is adapted from the cookbook &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.worldcat.org/title/best-125-meatless-pasta-dishes/oclc/24375167&#34;&gt;The Best 125 Meatless Pasta Dishes&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindycooks.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mindy Toomay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/author/geiskopfhadlersusann&#34;&gt;Susann Geiskopf-Hadler&lt;/a&gt;, published by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookbusinessmag.com/article/setting-the-pace-prima-publishing-12266/1&#34;&gt;Prima Publishing&lt;/a&gt; in 1992.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 3 cups of water to 1.5 cups of lentils in a saucepan on the stove. Add 2 bay leaves. Bring to a boil and then cook 25-35 minutes until the lentils are done. Rinse under cold water and drain. Note: you&#39;ll want lentils that hold their shape in cooking; look for French lentils or &lt;a href=&#34;http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/855532&#34;&gt;lentils du Puy&lt;/a&gt; in the bulk section of your favorite grocer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, chop vegetables. Note that all vegetables are to be chopped small, so that they are not that much bigger than the lentils. For the vegetables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one bell pepper, green or red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup sun dried tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup Kalamata olives, pitted of course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, wash a bunch of parsley, and run it through the food processor until it is chopped very fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, make a salad dressing, which is a nice garlicky vinaigrette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup red wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 medium cloves garlic, or more to taste, minced fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the lentil cooking time, put on pasta to cook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before serving, dice or crumble some feta and put it into a separate bowl, in the case that you have dinner guests who don&#39;t care for feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a large bowl, and mix the lentils, vegetables, parsley, and dressing together in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very delicious. Serve at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prep time - 45 to 60 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy sweet potato and black bean salad</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-spicy-sweet-potato-and-black-bean-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-spicy-sweet-potato-and-black-bean-salad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key here is &#34;season to taste&#34;. We had more than 2 tsp of freshly made chipotle powder and I used it all, and it ended up being a bit more spicy than the normal food around our house (but still delicious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe also calls for roasted pasilla peppers, which we didn&#39;t have so we didn&#39;t use them. I&#39;m sure that any other roasted pepper would add to the flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 lbs sweet potatoes, boiled 7 minutes, peeled, cut into 1&#34; chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp chipotle chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cans (15 oz each) of black beans, rinsed well and drained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bunch green onions, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bunch cilantro, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a dressing of the olive oil, lime juice, orange juice, cumin, chipotle powder; mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine the ingredients in a large bowl. I put half the sweet potatoes at the bottom, then one can of beans, then more sweet potatoes, then more beans, with green onions and cilantro at the top. Pour the dressing over and mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works well the next day as leftovers, if you have any!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Cole slaw</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-20-recipe-cole-slaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 22:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-20-recipe-cole-slaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is easy and feeds a lot of people. I don&amp;#39;t tend to measure, so you&amp;#39;ll want to use proportions to your taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One half head of green cabbage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Four carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cider vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mayo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shred the cabbage using the slicing blade of your food processor. Put the cabbage in a large bowl. Shake some salt on top of the cabbage and mix it in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trim the carrots and grate them using the grating blade of your food processor. Add to the cabbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dressing is a mixture of cider vinegar and mayo. Rather than mix them together first and then getting a dish dirty, I simply pour some cider vinegar over the top of the cabbage-carrot mixture, then add some mayo. Mix thoroughly until the cole slaw is lightly coated with the dressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let sit at least an hour before serving. The cabbage and carrots will both lose a little moisture, so you&amp;#39;ll end up with more dressing than you started with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paired with pizza and two-buck chuck wine, this recipe will serve twelve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Asparagus with mushrooms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-recipe-asparagus-with-mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-recipe-asparagus-with-mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This simple asparagus with mushrooms dish is served with pasta. J doesn&amp;#39;t like linguini, so we made it with rotini. This comes together in a hurry - you can cook the whole thing up in the time it takes to boil the pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two or three cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asparagus, about a pound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Button mushrooms, about a pound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basil, dried or fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boil water for pasta. When it&amp;#39;s hot, cook the pasta. There should be time to drain it after you&amp;#39;ve done the cooking of the asparagus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash the asparagus, snap the tough ends, and slice on the bias into 1.5&amp;quot; pieces. Clean the mushrooms and cut each one in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in a large frying pan on high. Fry the garlic until it&amp;#39;s light brown and smells great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the asparagus to the frying pan and cook, stirring frequently, until the asparagus is bright green. Add the mushrooms and keep stirring. When the mushrooms are hot, add the white wine, stir, and cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe called for basil, but I didn&amp;#39;t put it in because I was hurrying to get everything together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wine will deglaze the pan and make a nice sauce. Serve with pasta and white wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;fieldset class=&#34;zemanta-related&#34;&gt;&lt;legend class=&#34;zemanta-related-title&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kokstars.com/2013/05/20/experimental-kitchen-asparagus-with-strawberries/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/170839181_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kokstars.com/2013/05/20/experimental-kitchen-asparagus-with-strawberries/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Experimental Kitchen: Asparagus with Strawberries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://darsword.wordpress.com/2013/05/26/asparagus-pasta-born-and-braised-in-roxbury/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/172379412_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://darsword.wordpress.com/2013/05/26/asparagus-pasta-born-and-braised-in-roxbury/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asparagus Pasta, Born and Braised in Roxbury&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sweetenoughthanks.wordpress.com/2013/05/23/in-less-time-than-it-takes-to-cook-asparagus/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/171592932_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sweetenoughthanks.wordpress.com/2013/05/23/in-less-time-than-it-takes-to-cook-asparagus/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;In less time than it takes to cook asparagus!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; background: none; list-style: none; display: block; float: left; vertical-align: top; text-align: left; width: 84px; font-size: 11px; margin: 2px 10px 10px 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foursweetiepies.com/2013/05/27/quick-and-easy-asparagus-soup/&#34; style=&#34;box-shadow: 0px 0px 4px #999; padding: 2px; display: block; border-radius: 2px; text-decoration: none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://i.zemanta.com/172587159_80_80.jpg&#34; style=&#34;padding: 0; margin: 0; border: 0; display: block; width: 80px; max-width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foursweetiepies.com/2013/05/27/quick-and-easy-asparagus-soup/&#34; style=&#34;display: block; overflow: hidden; text-decoration: none; line-height: 12pt; height: 80px; padding: 5px 2px 0 2px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick and Easy Asparagus Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Kale with corn and green onions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe for kale with corn and green onions works well enough with frozen corn, but I&amp;#39;m sure it would be better with fresh. You cook with the ingredients you have, not the ingredients you want to have. We&amp;#39;re lucky to have fresh kale at the farmers market!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bag kale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;corn - frozen, if you must, but fresh would be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green onions - chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash and spin-dry the kale, being careful to get dirt out of the center rib. We had a very nice bag of small kale from market that didn&amp;#39;t require much more than this, but if you have older, tougher kales, trim them of their tough bits and cut them into pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in a large pot on medium high to high. Chop some garlic into big pieces. Fry the garlic until light brown and it smells good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the kale and cook, stirring frequently, until the kale has cooked down to a fraction of its original size. Add some corn and the chopped green onions; stir. Cook until the corn is warmed through, then add some soy sauce and cover and turn down the heat to low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bag of kale served the family, with one person not eating it; there were a few leftovers. This recipe would multiply quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more kale recipes, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.365daysofkale.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;365 Days of Kale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes, or information for everybody</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-17-recipes-or-information-for-everybody/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-17-recipes-or-information-for-everybody/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weblog has accumulated a number of recipes over time. Here&amp;#39;s an index of sorts that makes it look like I&amp;#39;ve been writing a cookbook. (To be updated over time, as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2009/03/here-is-the-penzeys-apple-pancake-recipea-morph-from-the-dutch-baby----14-cup-butter--34-cup-all-purpose-flour--34-cup.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Apple pancake &amp;quot;Dutch baby&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/11/bi-bim-bap-the-marinade-for-the-vegetables.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Bi bim bap, a marinade for the vegetables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/07/black-bean-tortilla-casserole-recipe.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Black bean tortilla casserole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/07/basil-and-blueberry-recipes-theme-and-variations.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Blueberry and basil recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2009/02/blueberry-muffins-with-cardamom-some-recipes-in-the-hopes-that-summer-will-arrive.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Blueberry muffins with cardamom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/08/burmese_tea_sal.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Burmese tea salad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/every-recipe-for-butternut-squash/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Butternut squash&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(AnnArbor.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/02/coconut-fried-rice-yum.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Coconut fried rice YUM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2009/10/mollys-october-coconut-squash-soup.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Coconut squash soup, Molly&amp;#39;s October&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/eat-garlic-mustard-for-earth-day/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Garlic Mustard for Earth Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(AnnArbor.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/01/greek_lemon_roa.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Greek lemon roasted potatoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/07/green-beans-with-walnuts.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Green beans with walnuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2009/09/karnabeet-recipe.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Karnabeet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(Roasted cauliflower)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/02/middle-eastern-red-lentil-soup.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Middle eastern Red Lentil Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/04/classic_pesto_f.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Pesto, Classic Vegan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polenta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/12/potato-pancakes.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Potato pancakes&lt;/a&gt; (latkes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/10/october-2011-recipes-quince.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Quince&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/01/recipe_roasted_.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Roasted Lima Beans&lt;/a&gt; (Yigantes Plaki) (γίγαντες πλακί)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/05/semolina-pudding.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Semolina Pudding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut fried rice YUM</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-17-coconut-fried-rice-yum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 16:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-17-coconut-fried-rice-yum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This is not a low-fat dish. But it is delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coconut fried rice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leftover rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dessicated (dried) coconut flakes or powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk (I used almond milk to make this vegan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat oil in pan. Add leftover rice and dried coconut flakes. Mix and stir and cook. When the mixture is hot, add some milk. Sprinkle sugar on top to taste. Stir until hot; you&amp;#39;ll know when it&amp;#39;s done when the dried coconut doesn&amp;#39;t taste dry. Serve hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t measure quantities, but I suspect that this recipe is tolerant of a lot of variety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest down side is that the pan ends up sticky. My usual treatment for this in a savory dish is to deglaze the pan with red wine, but that&amp;#39;s obviously a non-starter here. I suspect that a small amount of white wine added to the pan at the end of cooking would be worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>