<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 21:36:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>espresso over ice with a little half and half</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 21:36:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-19-espresso-over-ice-with-a-little-half-and-half/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple recipe that you can order from your favorite barista:
an espresso shot over ice. Leave enough room to add a spot of
half and half. Cold, refreshing, and very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try: a shot of espresso over shaved ice. I think this is
doable at Ann Arbor Farmers Market where you&amp;rsquo;d go to the stall
where a granny is selling shaved ice, and then walk a plain snow cone
over to the Roos Roast stand for your espresso shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a Facebook post from Allen Leibowitz in Texas ordering a snow cone
and the surrounding commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need
to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember
what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing
the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.
The potatoes will be boiled and dressed with a dill vinaigrette.
(I had to look up the word vinaigrette.) The recipes I found add
green beans and boiled eggs to a salad with cold potatoes, using
a mustard vinaigrette with added chopped dill. The cherries will
probably just be eaten out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UP travel discussion included the obligatory discussion of insects,
including ticks (&amp;ldquo;like bedbugs, for the woods&amp;rdquo;) and horrible sand
flies that will swarm you and leave you screaming running from the
beach. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason that the UP has miles of undeveloped beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t mention bugs in the UP without remembering
&lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;The Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI&amp;rdquo;,
by Tim Eisele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still hacking away at generating interesting reports from
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markvanderloo/stringdist&#34;&gt;stringdist&lt;/a&gt;
package from Mark van der Loo. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/31486913/r-producing-a-list-of-near-matches-with-stringdist-and-stringdistmatrix&#34;&gt;R: producing a list of near matches with stringdist and stringdistmatrix&lt;/a&gt; and the answers provided
helped unearth the melt() function from the reshape2 library,
and with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; you take a matrix and turn it into an edge list.
A little bit of filtering, and you get a report of near matches
in a list, enough for me to catch variant spellings of
vinagrette to vinaigrette in a &amp;ldquo;make test&amp;rdquo; step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow was fun for this task, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try it again.
The process of describing your problem in enough detail that someone
who knows the issue can add the one or two lines of code to make
it work is a useful exercise. It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of a search
engine in many ways - of course I could find melt() once I know
its name, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name you can&amp;rsquo;t find anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next bit of interestingness has to do with turning the dist
data structure returned by stringdist into a variety of useful
images. There&amp;rsquo;s a package that dumps out a &amp;ldquo;dendogram&amp;rdquo;, and if I&amp;rsquo;m
careful in formatting the data I think I can coerce R into producing
data that can be imported directly into the tools that
Valdis Krebs
has written for network exploration and visualization. The
promise within R is a &amp;ldquo;distgraph&amp;rdquo; that does the visualization,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet finding the cadre of experts who use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art on the walls is Julie Marron-Parker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sunburst&amp;rdquo;. She writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the sun shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Michigan (160 days of sun per year) I have come to
appreciate when the sun is out. This piece brings the energy of the
sun into the world, regardless of the weather outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Meloche writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
where going through a doorway wipes out your short term memory
to make way for new short term memories. It got me thinking
about the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;memory palace&lt;/span&gt;, and how you might construct
in your mind a series of portals and doorways to walk through so
that you can remember a series of items in such a way that you
take advantage of the doorway effect to pull memories in and out
of your short term thinking. The technology is &amp;ldquo;mnemotechnics&amp;rdquo;,
that&amp;rsquo;s a good keyword to pull lots of interesting thinking
(which sometimes sounds like crazytalk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me - I need to move to another room, so that I can
remember what I need to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the hugo cookbook</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-the-hugo-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:55:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-the-hugo-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every technology for publishing eventually gets used to publish
recipes. This collection of mine here is not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve marked up the recipes with the &amp;ldquo;recipe&amp;rdquo; category, and also
created a &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; taxonomy with ingredients. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of like
a subcategory but not really&amp;hellip;well it is as long as I am careful
about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous attempts to do this include The Usenet Cookbook (from
mod.recipes), alt.gourmand, and most favorite in my book the use
of Gopher as a cookbook. It is said that an old Mac was portable
enough to be set up in the kitchen to look up recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to do is set things up so that if the post is from the
recipes category, then the recipes list will show up in the sidebar
of that post, sorted alphabetically. I think I can make that work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sweet potato cauliflower soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 18:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-14-sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some sweet potato cauliflower soup recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allyson Kramer likes hers with a bit of garam masala:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://www.allysonkramer.com/2011/10/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Three Peas wants carrots and celery and chicken stock:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&#34;&gt;http://ourthreepeas.com/sweet-potato-cauliflower-soup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food.com and &amp;ldquo;Kelly in TO&amp;rdquo; calls for curry and cinnamon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&#34;&gt;http://www.food.com/recipe/cauliflower-sweet-potato-curry-soup-246992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our meal plan pairs this with biscuits and kale, and it was delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac and Goat</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/Mac-and-Goat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/Mac-and-Goat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/strong&gt; calls for goat cheese; we generally use a goat gouda or
a goat cheddar, both of which are usually available at the local
Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s. Feel free to substitute any hard cheese that melts
well in your recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dish also calls for rice pasta, but again feel free to substitute;
you&amp;rsquo;re aiming for something like a rotini which handles the sauce well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Take out a lasagna pan, which is
what you&amp;rsquo;re going to assemble the dish in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-and-goat:b7d41359d960c78f56dcc5a9d35b0ec6&#34;&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb. pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb. goat gouda, goat cheddar, or a nice aged gouda or cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large can crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;romano cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil water for pasta; cook a pound or so of your favorite pasta,
we use a rice rotini pasta in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shred the cheese fine in a food processor or with a hand grater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pasta is done, drain it, and then put about half of it
in the lasagna pan. Cover with about half of the cheese and half of
the tomatoes. Put the rest of the pasta in, then more tomatoes and
more cheese. Top with breadcrumbs and then sprinkle a little romano
cheese on top and a few pinches of nutmeg for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook 20-25 minutes, until the top is lightly browned and the
tomato sauce is bubbling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew: six recipes to mix and match from</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-chickpea-potato-and-tomato-stew-six-recipes-to-mix-and-match-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haven&#39;t cooked any of these yet, but there&#39;s some recipes to work through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricki Heller: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rickiheller.com/2011/03/anti-candida-sugar-free-gluten-free-vegan-chickpea-tomato-and-potato-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Uses tahini to enrich the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fit Pregnancy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitpregnancy.com/nutrition/recipes/chickpea-potato-tomato-stew-chard&#34;&gt;Chickpea, Potato and Tomato Stew with Chard
&lt;/a&gt;. With chard, paprika, parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First Mess: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefirstmess.com/2013/09/26/moroccan-style-vegan-vegetable-chickpea-stew-recipe/&#34;&gt;moroccan-style vegetable + chickpea stew
&lt;/a&gt;. Sweet potatoes instead of potatoes, and a cinnamon+coriander+cumin spice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Picky Eater: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pickyeaterblog.com/indian-vegetable-stew-yum/&#34;&gt;Indian Chickpea and Potato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. Curry is the flavor here, and cilantro replaces parsley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and Wine: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodandwine.com/recipes/new-potato-chickpea-and-tomato-stew&#34;&gt;New Potato, Chickpea and Tomato Stew&lt;/a&gt;. The surprise ingredient is chorizo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally Ella: &lt;a href=&#34;http://naturallyella.com/2011/12/05/sweet-potato-and-chickpea-stew-with-quinoa/&#34;&gt;Sweet Potato and Chickpea Stew with Quinoa&lt;/a&gt;. Quinoa is the novel grain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>recipe: tortilla casserole</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-15-recipe-tortilla-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 23:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-15-recipe-tortilla-casserole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This comes out kind of like a lasagna and is designed the same way:
lots of layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one package tortillas (whole wheat, corn, or flour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one can tomatoes with chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one can black beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 jar corn relish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one package shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;assemble in layers, roughly as so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tomatoes with chiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake in a 350 degree oven; I left it in for about an hour, until the top was nicely browned and not singed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Served 3 (one dinner guest opted out)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nana&#39;s Beer Stew recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-nanas-beer-stew-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-07-nanas-beer-stew-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beer Stew&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Tish Osborn- Originally from Ada Vielmetti (Nana) &amp;amp; Aunt Florence Burt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To serve @ 6 people, use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 lbs. Of good Stew Meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 lb. Onions, thickly sliced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flour to dredge meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil to brown meat, in a large skillet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 cloves of garlic, finely chopped or crushed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3T Dark Brown Sugar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¼ cup red wine vinegar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;½ cup chopped fresh parsley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 small bay leaves, put in whole&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 t. dried thyme leaves.....  Or 2 tsps. of fresh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 T. salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freshly ground black pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 bottles of GOOD beer.  I often use English Stout&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 10 ½ oz cans of Beef Broth [not Consume`]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Dumpling mix…. recipe below, put on at end of cooking time.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Cut beef into bite-size pieces.  Dredge in flour and brown in skillet with a little oil, before putting in an ovenproof casserole dish.  [I use a large roaster]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        When all beef has been browned, add a little more oil, and sauté onion and garlic just until soft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add the onion and garlic to the casserole with the meat; except beer and broth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add broth to skillet to de-glaze pan.  Add all other ingredients, and stir to make sure sugar is dissolved. Pour over meat mixture and stir again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Add beer.  Stir all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Cover casserole and cook at 325 degrees for @ 2-3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Note:  The stew will appear to be very runny.  The dumplings seem to absorb some of the liquid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Mix dumplings together just before you are ready to serve stew.  Drop spoon dumplings on top of meat, put the lid back on the casserole and bake for 15 minutes without lifting lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·        Serve, and expect accolades. J&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often just mix up Bisquick dumplings....but here’s the original recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Optional Dumpling recipe]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 cups sifted self-rising flour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¾ cup of milk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2T. Melted butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little chopped parsley if you like, for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix together and drop on the stew.  Cook 15 min as directed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Lemon Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-greek_lemon_roa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of a recipes collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was part of dinner last week - yum! I don&amp;#39;t have the exact proportions in front of me so you&amp;#39;ll want to be prepared to improvise.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potatoes&lt;/strong&gt;, peeled, cut to quarters; to fill lasagna pan; redskins would do well &lt;br /&gt;Juice of 3 &lt;strong&gt;lemons,&amp;#0160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fresh squeezed&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;juice not stuff from bottles if you have it&amp;#0160;&lt;br /&gt;Greek &lt;strong&gt;oregano &lt;/strong&gt;(though Mexican oregano worked OK too) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olive oil&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to a good roasting temperature (450+ degrees).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the potatoes in the lasagna pan. Mix lemon juice, water, oregano, oil together; you are after something like a salad dressing, but since you&amp;#39;re baking it the water will go away, so make sure there&amp;#39;s enough oil. Besides, olive oil is good for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour the dressing over the potatoes, mix until everything is coated. Put in oven. Roast until starting to turn brown, about 40-50 minutes depending on your oven and your potatoes. If you don&amp;#39;t have a lot of oil in the dressing, you may need to turn to keep things from sticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll bet it would be good to put a couple of organic lemon halves in there too to roast along with everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove from oven, test for doneness. Eat. Yum. Also good cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other lemon roasted potato recipes, for comparison: &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/unbound/corby/ct2000-12.htm&#34;&gt;Corby&amp;#39;s Table&lt;/a&gt; from The Atlantic Monthly has a patates riganates recipe from a review of Aglaia Kremezi&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Foods of the Greek Islands&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sandisrecipecorner.com/recipe488H.htm&#34;&gt;Sandi&amp;#39;s Recipe Corner&lt;/a&gt;, adds stock &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dvo.com/recipe_pages/grilln/Greek_Garlic_and_Lemon_Roasted_Potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Cook&amp;#39;n&lt;/a&gt;, adds dill and roasts over wood chips &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autumnjade.com/recipes/133.htm&#34;&gt;Autumn Jade&lt;/a&gt;, basically the same with exact proportions &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalgourmet.com/food/special/2001/greek/potatoes.html&#34;&gt;Global Gourmet&lt;/a&gt; calls these &lt;strong&gt;patates riganates&lt;/strong&gt; and adds garlic &lt;br /&gt;- &lt;a href=&#34;http://creampuffsinvenice.typepad.com/cream_puffs_in_venice/2006/04/some_lemony_spu.html&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Cream Puffs in Venice&amp;quot; has some lemony spuds for you&lt;/a&gt;, adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/work/907079&#34;&gt;Cook This&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Rosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I&amp;#39;m sure there are more recipes to be had!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more recipe to go with this if you have any cold leftovers. Put a bed of spring mixed greens on a plate; I like the Asian mix we found at Farmer&amp;#39;s Market. Cut some of these potatoes up and put on top. Add diced cubed cold roasted beets for color and flavor. Dress with some of the lemon-oil mix, with a little red wine vinegar added. Yum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right; font-size: 10px;&#34;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/lemon&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;lemon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/potatoes&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;potatoes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/tag/recipe&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rice: prepare 1.5 cups rice according to your taste. Do this first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the broccoli: Preheat oven to 425 degrees F. Cut a few heads of broccoli into bite sized florets. Mix in a bowl with olive oil, then place on a cookie sheet. Sprinkle sea salt on top. Roast 12-15 minutes until the broccoli is every so slightly browned on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the garbanzos: Drain and rinse a can of garbanzos. Put in a small pot and cover with water. Heat until hot, then rinse again under cool water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the red peppers: Cut a red pepper into pieces about the size of a garbanzo bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Make a lemon vinaigrette with a little mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Some sweet chili paste, or gochujang, or your favorite spicy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the feta: crumble some feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve in individual bowls on the table, for people to mix their own salads. If your family is like mine, someone will eat just rice and peppers and beans, someone else will prefer the salad without feta, someone will want a vinaigrette and someone else (me) will douse the whole thing with chili sauce. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven fried potato recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-oven-fried-potato-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing this down so I remember this one detail: to get fries the right size, cut a medium potato into 16 pieces. (Cut in 4 equal width slices, then cut each slice into 4 parts). It works pretty quickly once you get going, and the resulting fries get crispy much more so than potatoes cut into quarters. A sweet potato yields 32 fries, cut in half and then in fours and then in fours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put the raw potato strips into a big bowl, pour some olive oil on them, and mix until everything is nicely coated, then put them onto cookie sheets and cook for what seems like a long time in a 425 degree F oven. If you want equally crispy on both sides, turn them over part way through. They would be good with a sprinking of sea salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more recipes, not that you need much of a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://allrecipes.com/recipe/oven-fries/&#34;&gt;All Recipes&lt;/a&gt; uses a little sugar and a little cayenne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eatingwell.com/recipes/oven_fries.html&#34;&gt;Eating Well&lt;/a&gt; cuts into wedges (too big!) and adds dried thyme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Crispy-Oven-Baked-French-Fries/&#34;&gt;Instructables&lt;/a&gt; secret ingredient is cornstarch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, maybe you do need a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoppin&#39; Giovanni (Rapini with white beans)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 16:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-hoppin-giovanni-rapini-with-white-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This simple dish of beans and greens comes from Mary Ann Esposito&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ciaoitalia.com/seasons/season-2200/episode-2221/broccoli-rabe-with-white-beans&#34;&gt;Ciao Italia&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s similar in many ways to the traditional &#34;Hoppin&#39; John&#34; served for good luck for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hoppin&#39; Giovanni&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wash and chop a bunch of rapini (broccoli rabe). If you can&#39;t find rapini, some other mild green like turnip greens (or even kale) would work nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mince a shallot fine and saute in a large pan in olive oil until fragrant. Add a few generous pinches of red pepper flakes. Put the chopped rapini into the pan and cook until the greens are cooked through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drain and rinse a can of white beans (cannellini). When the greens are cooked through, add the beans and stir. You can add a little more olive oil to the pan at this point if you want to. Stir and then bring back up to heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve hot. This would go good with pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lentil, feta, and olive pasta salad</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-29-lentil-feta-and-olive-pasta-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-29-lentil-feta-and-olive-pasta-salad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This delicious lentil, feta, and olive pasta salad is adapted from the cookbook &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.worldcat.org/title/best-125-meatless-pasta-dishes/oclc/24375167&#34;&gt;The Best 125 Meatless Pasta Dishes&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindycooks.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mindy Toomay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/author/geiskopfhadlersusann&#34;&gt;Susann Geiskopf-Hadler&lt;/a&gt;, published by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookbusinessmag.com/article/setting-the-pace-prima-publishing-12266/1&#34;&gt;Prima Publishing&lt;/a&gt; in 1992.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 3 cups of water to 1.5 cups of lentils in a saucepan on the stove. Add 2 bay leaves. Bring to a boil and then cook 25-35 minutes until the lentils are done. Rinse under cold water and drain. Note: you&#39;ll want lentils that hold their shape in cooking; look for French lentils or &lt;a href=&#34;http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/855532&#34;&gt;lentils du Puy&lt;/a&gt; in the bulk section of your favorite grocer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, chop vegetables. Note that all vegetables are to be chopped small, so that they are not that much bigger than the lentils. For the vegetables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one bell pepper, green or red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup sun dried tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup Kalamata olives, pitted of course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, wash a bunch of parsley, and run it through the food processor until it is chopped very fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lentils are cooking, make a salad dressing, which is a nice garlicky vinaigrette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup red wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 medium cloves garlic, or more to taste, minced fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the lentil cooking time, put on pasta to cook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before serving, dice or crumble some feta and put it into a separate bowl, in the case that you have dinner guests who don&#39;t care for feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a large bowl, and mix the lentils, vegetables, parsley, and dressing together in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very delicious. Serve at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prep time - 45 to 60 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy sweet potato and black bean salad</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-spicy-sweet-potato-and-black-bean-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-26-spicy-sweet-potato-and-black-bean-salad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key here is &#34;season to taste&#34;. We had more than 2 tsp of freshly made chipotle powder and I used it all, and it ended up being a bit more spicy than the normal food around our house (but still delicious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe also calls for roasted pasilla peppers, which we didn&#39;t have so we didn&#39;t use them. I&#39;m sure that any other roasted pepper would add to the flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 lbs sweet potatoes, boiled 7 minutes, peeled, cut into 1&#34; chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 lime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp chipotle chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cans (15 oz each) of black beans, rinsed well and drained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bunch green onions, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bunch cilantro, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a dressing of the olive oil, lime juice, orange juice, cumin, chipotle powder; mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine the ingredients in a large bowl. I put half the sweet potatoes at the bottom, then one can of beans, then more sweet potatoes, then more beans, with green onions and cilantro at the top. Pour the dressing over and mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works well the next day as leftovers, if you have any!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu Plan Monday, December edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-16-menu-plan-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-16-menu-plan-monday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday: Lentil soup with tomatoes, bow tie pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday: Chili, tortillas, greens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday: Tabouli, roasted vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday: Hamburgers, buns, frozen vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday: leftovers (everyone was out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday: Spanish rice, cucumber salad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>