<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/tor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tor on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:12:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/tor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spy vs spy: Tor (US Naval Intelligence designed anonymous network) attacked by NSA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-04-spy-vs-spy-tor-us-naval-intelligence-designed-anonymous-network-attacked-by-nsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-04-spy-vs-spy-tor-us-naval-intelligence-designed-anonymous-network-attacked-by-nsa/</guid>
      <description>The Tor Project runs Tor (&#34;The Onion Router&#34;), a network designed to provide its users with anonymity when using the Internet. Tor was originally developed by US Naval Intelligence, and a large part of support for the network still comes from government interests.
Tor was in the news recently as the high profile Silk Road anonymous marketplace for drugs was shut down. Silk Road had been hosted as a hidden node reachable only through Tor, and it ran openly on that network for years until a dedicated effort unmasked the organizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOR network anonymity compromised by Javascript exploit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-05-tor-network-anonymity-compromised-by-javascript-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 07:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-05-tor-network-anonymity-compromised-by-javascript-exploit/</guid>
      <description>TOR is an anonymous network set up originally by the US Navy in order to support cloaked access by the US Government to the Internet. Users access the network through a computer or browser set up to point traffic towards a network of &amp;quot;onion routers&amp;quot;, which scramble the path that the packet takes to eventually reach the Internet. There are also provisions for &amp;quot;dark&amp;quot; web sites or hidden service operators to exist within the TOR network, which should in theory be reachable anonymously by TOR users but not the great outside Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>