<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openvpn on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/openvpn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openvpn on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 17:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/openvpn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, September 6, 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-daily-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-06-daily-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee and wifi (double espresso over ice) at the &amp;ldquo;dog park Biggby&amp;rdquo;,
Platt Road at Ellsworth. It&amp;rsquo;s not an inconvenient location,
and the very large south-facing windows are good to know about
as the days get shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 90 degrees outside, and I&amp;rsquo;m preparing to make dinner.
The recipe is for &amp;ldquo;broccoli Calabrian style&amp;rdquo; from Martha Rose Shulman.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find that exact recipe online, but this
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.italycookingschools.com/bucatini-con-broccoli-alla-calabresebucatini-broccoli-calabrian-style/&#34;&gt;Bucatini Con Broccoli Alla Calabrese&lt;/a&gt; is close.
Substitute sunflower seeds for pine nuts.
The key to it is that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to cook anything too long,
because it&amp;rsquo;s hot out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First day of the 2016 school year for the boys. S. is at Community High School,
and J. had his first day at Tappan Middle School. I don&amp;rsquo;t write
about them much, but it sounded like today was a good day all in all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two new front tires for the car - one of them was quite flat, and they
were both quite worn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new venue for lunch, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sessionrooma2.com/&#34;&gt;Session Room&lt;/a&gt; on Jackson Road in Scio Township.
They have a very long list of beers which you can conveniently order
in very small glasses (4 oz) to try out and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current challenge is to get an instance of Salt running in a
Docker container, integrated with OpenVPN a la this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://garthwaite.org/virtually-secure-with-openvpn-pillars-and-salt.html&#34;&gt;OpenVPN provisioning with Salt&lt;/a&gt; recipe. We currently think that the
best way to manage this is to connect it to the Docker
container via an &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/amazon-elastic-file-system-shared-file-storage-for-amazon-ec2/&#34;&gt;Elastic File System&lt;/a&gt; mount.
A sub-challenge is finding the right way to run Salt in a container;
tooling for this is awkward because you really to run some commands
within the context of the container. Soon&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thisissoon/Docker-Salt-Master&#34;&gt;Docker Salt Master&lt;/a&gt; looks like a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, Ann Arbor City Council. Follow along on the #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/a2council&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt; hashtag on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>full stack plane spotting and data analysis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-11-full-stack-plane-spotting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The task at hand is simple. Whenever a particular airplane is visible overhead,
send out a tweet with that notice. Don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself with this announcement
more than twice an hour, but try not to have too much lag in reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full stack of hardware and software to do this is not particularly
complicated to use once you get it all running, but there are a series
of issues and observations along the way that add to the complexity. I&amp;rsquo;ll
walk through the whole thing start to finish, and let you know where I
left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic toolkit is dump1090-mutability for plane spotting,
Node-RED for wiring flows for data processing, and
Docker to package up the bits that are stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plane-spotting:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Plane spotting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/&#34;&gt;When last I wrote&lt;/a&gt;,
I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;dump1090&lt;/a&gt;
running on my MacBook. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the same software and gotten
the latest dev release going on a Raspberry Pi 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to a smaller, simpler antenna, and the result was positive: instead of
having a 40 to 50 nautical mile range, now I&amp;rsquo;m in the 60 to 65 nm range (about 110 km).
It might also help that the Pi 2 is not really doing very much else. That
particular Pi 2 setup is using a slightly back-rev version of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com&#34;&gt;Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; software for the Pi, so it has all
of the modern conveniences plus an instance of Docker on board. The
temptation was to Dockerize everything, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone there yet;
the available Docker prebuilt releases don&amp;rsquo;t have the bleeding edge of
the dump1090-mutability code, and I want to see how the whole thing runs
native for a while before containerizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snag that slowed down this deployment a little was Google&amp;rsquo;s decision
to enforce an API key for personal use of Google Maps. In response, the
very latest dump1090-mutability pulled out its Google Maps support, and
went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://openlayers.org/&#34;&gt;OpenLayers&lt;/a&gt;. This new support gives
access to all kinds of base maps, including some aviation-specific
charts. (&amp;ldquo;Not for use in navigation.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another piece of this was bringing up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttpd.net/&#34;&gt;lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;
(&amp;ldquo;lighty&amp;rdquo;), a lightweight HTTP server that replaces the rickety
built-in HTTP server that dump1090 had originally shipped with.
Configuration following the supplied instructions was simple,
and lighttpd looks like a very suitable system to put in place to
serve HTTP on embedded-class system that need flexiblity but not
a big footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other component in the Pi setup is an ADS-B feed to the excellent
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;Planefinder&lt;/a&gt; site. Planefinder provides a Debian
package for setting up the feed, and it runs neatly with only a minimum
of overhead. As a bonus you get free use of their apps, which are
notable for running in much closer to real time than others I have seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi does not yet have a working OpenVPN configuration, so I can&amp;rsquo;t get
to it over the net directly. For that I plan to revisit the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-07-managing-raspberry-pi-openvpn-with-salt/&#34;&gt;SaltStack for Pi&lt;/a&gt;
configuration I wrote up last September. In the interim, salt has
been upgraded, and perhaps it will be a little more stable over bad
connections; we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Data analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090 provides a data feed in a convenient JSON format, available
through a URL on a standard configuruation. The ADS-B messages themselves
are binary encoded, but the system brings them into JSON so that all
of the downstream processing is very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data handling is so straightforward that you can do it all without
needing any special-purpose processing nodes in IBM&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org&#34;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;.
A standard HTTP in node polls the data at the pace that you choose,
and a simple function pulls apart the record of all planes into
individual records for each plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Node-RED running is continuing to get easier over time.
I&amp;rsquo;m doing prototyping work on my Macintosh again, using the
new &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2016/06/docker-mac-windows-public-beta/&#34;&gt;Docker for Mac&lt;/a&gt;
setup to pick up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/cpswan/node-red/&#34;&gt;Node-RED container&lt;/a&gt;
to do the work in. &lt;a href=&#34;https://kitematic.com/&#34;&gt;Kitematic&lt;/a&gt; comes with Docker for Mac,
providing a convenient dashboard and interface to Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Do note, however, that if you got Docker for Mac running a few months
ago, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go through a rebuild process to go to the latest
beta. To &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/troubleshoot/#/recreate-or-update-your-containers-after-beta-18-upgrade&#34;&gt;recreate or update your containers after Beta 18 upgrade&lt;/a&gt;
follow the provided instructions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have both Node-RED and dump1090 running, connecting the
two together is straightforward. I started with this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dceejay/3288996fefdc3aef04846496277b6444&#34;&gt;gist from dceejay&lt;/a&gt; which
provides the basic flow and feeds into a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-web-worldmap&#34;&gt;worldmap node&lt;/a&gt; that
is a general programmable interface for putting things on a map. My
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/vielmetti/6329ea5a49dadd2f106980a20727d16e&#34;&gt;updated dump1090 gist for Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;
adapts the data for a slightly different format between dump1090 forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here in it&amp;rsquo;s relatively clear sailing. Set up a flow downstream
from the plane messages, using a filter node to match the name or
ICAO hex code of the airplane that you want to track. Wire it through
a delay filter to set the frequency of messages you want to
allow through, and a formatting node to pretty up the message in
a form suitable for Twitter output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;incomplete-image-and-next-steps:984b95b4570fb7d5b37f67357af2ada0&#34;&gt;Incomplete image and next steps.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively complex stack, but it all fits neatly on a Raspberry Pi 2,
and with a little bit more elbow grease it should be possible to containerize
everything so that it Just Works and can be made to reliably work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to have OpenVPN running on the Pi 2, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet, pending
rework of Salt to get that to a current version and to port all of the
work I did from an earlier version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m picking up planes from 60+ nm away, but I know that with a better
antenna, bandpass filter, and amplifier that I can do better.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://puck.nether.net/~jared/blog/?p=160&#34;&gt;Jared Mauch&amp;rsquo;s parts list&lt;/a&gt;
would be the place to go for starters with a very modest budget of
a couple of hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reception is best if you have a clear view of the sky, which suggests
an outdoors installation, powering the Pi with power over ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is running on a Pi 2, but reports from Jared and from Phil Karn KA9Q
suggest that if you do upgrade the reception that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to
saturate the Pi 2. Fortunately a Pi 3 does even better at the intended task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out what the very best way to create a Docker image
that handles Node-RED, especially the installation of additional nodes
and the management of flows. You&amp;rsquo;d like to have the whole thing suitably
tidy that it could be all loaded in from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dump1090-mutability is still mutating! It&amp;rsquo;s under active development,
both at the presentation layer and at the decoder layer. So it would
be appropriate to have the attitude for at least one development machine
to be sure that you were ready to rebuild from source whenever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only have half of this stack running (the Node-RED side) but no access
to radios, you can find an existing dump1090 installation and pull the
JSON from there. This is best done only via prior arrangement and only
for testing purposes or for specific tasks. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to crank up Node-RED
to poll a URL every second; don&amp;rsquo;t do that to a poor little Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planes I want to watch don&amp;rsquo;t take off very often - that&amp;rsquo;s the appeal
of watching for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN scaling</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/&#34;&gt;OpenVPN in a container&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-04-split-tunnels-considered-harmful/&#34;&gt;Split tunnels considered harmful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this running in a staging environment and a test
environment; it properly isolates OpenVPN from the underlying
operating system, and seems to do the right thing performing
rather well. However, its biggest limitation is that
it runs on a single host &amp;amp; thus provides neither
high availability in the case of Amazon &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/&#34;&gt;funkiness&lt;/a&gt;
nor scalability to handle lots of clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting this to be more reliable was a matter of tracking
down the right systemd configuration. I&amp;rsquo;ll save systemd
commentary for a separate post, saying only that it&amp;rsquo;s new,
it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily better for managing single machines,
but I can see the advantages for consolidated management of
big collections of machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some OpenVPN config alternatives to pursue that look like they might do
the right thing are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudcoreo.com&#34;&gt;CloudCoreo&lt;/a&gt; has a setup based on the Amazon Elastic Load Balancer.
They say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an OpenVPN config up and running in AWS is difficult. We&amp;rsquo;ve already done it for you in an HA, durable, self-healing way. This blog post details how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog post is in two sections.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cloudcoreo.com/single-points-of-failure-openvpn/&#34;&gt;Part one&lt;/a&gt; details how they
configured autoscaling, elastic load balancing, name service, S3
storage and policies, and security and IAM policies to set things
up the way that you would want them within Amazon&amp;rsquo;s AWS.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cloudcoreo.com/single-points-of-failure-openvpn-part-2-of-2/&#34;&gt;Part two&lt;/a&gt; goes on to describe the particular OpenVPN policy
and routing setup, and there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of policy there particularly
with the use of split tunnels that you want to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their claim that they have
&amp;ldquo;done it all for you&amp;rdquo; reflects a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hub.cloudcoreo.com/stack/servers-vpn_c6a65&#34;&gt;complete configuration&lt;/a&gt; available
through their CloudCoreo system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second approach is detailed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.zalando.com&#34;&gt;Zalando&lt;/a&gt;, a Berlin based retail fashion platform.
Their article &lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.zalando.com/blog/building-an-openvpn-cluster-zalando-style/&#34;&gt;Building an OpenVPN Cluster, Zalando-Style&lt;/a&gt;
uses dynamic routing to distribute routes, and the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nongnu.org/quagga/&#34;&gt;Quagga&lt;/a&gt; system as their software based router. This setup
does not particularly depend on AWS features, and they
claim that
&amp;ldquo;With this set up, we have about 800 users (150 in parallel) and haven’t faced any performance issues at anytime, from anywhere!&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more complex to set up, though the writeup
makes it clear that because of the flexibility that dynamic
routing gives you there&amp;rsquo;s the opportunity to construct
firewall policies that follow the user quite independent
of how they are connecting to the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complex system that works is invariably found to have evolved from a simple system that worked. A complex system designed from scratch never works and cannot be patched up to make it work. You have to start over, beginning with a working simple system. (John Gall, Systemantics)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN in a container</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 16:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-11-20-openvpn-in-a-container/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few notes on setting up OpenVPN in a container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using CoreOS, which gives me Docker 1.7.1 in the &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different Docker configurations are available that take on this task,
with slightly different setups. Kyle Manna&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kylemanna/docker-openvpn&#34;&gt;docker-openvpn&lt;/a&gt;
is what I&amp;rsquo;m working with; it in turn is derived from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jpetazzo/dockvpn&#34;&gt;jpetazzo/dockvpn&lt;/a&gt; which
solves the same problem slightly differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-run-openvpn-in-a-docker-container-on-ubuntu-14-04&#34;&gt;tutorial on Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;
that describes the setup including client-side support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second &lt;a href=&#34;https://stefanscherer.github.io/run-your-own-dockerized-openvpn-server-at-scaleway/&#34;&gt;tutorial by Stefan Scherer&lt;/a&gt;
gives instructions for use in the Scaleway ARM-based server cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m at the stage right now where I downloaded and installed
everything and created an &amp;ldquo;opvn&amp;rdquo; config file that successfully
loads into Tunnelblick, but where it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite yet have
all of the routing set up. The slight complication in the
configuration is that I want to give access to Amazon
VPCs, so I have a few layers of software-defined networking
to knit together (or to unravel depending on your perspective).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;network ho!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>