<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Back To School on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/back-to-school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Back To School on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:18:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/back-to-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Burns Park Elementary - Kindergarten Roundup 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-burns-park-elementary-kindergarten-roundup-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-burns-park-elementary-kindergarten-roundup-2009/</guid>
      <description>from the PTO newsletter
Kindergarten Round-Up - Kindergarten Parent Orientation is Tuesday, February 17th at 7:00 p.m.. &amp;#0160;This is for parents only to talk about our Kindergarten program and answer any questions you may have, visit the classrooms and obtain enrollment forms. &amp;#0160;Free childcare will be provided by the PTO, but you must call the school (734-994-1919) to pre-register. &amp;#0160;The following Thursday, February 19th prospective Kindergartners will be divided into small groups and will then have the opportunity to spend an hour with one of the Kindergarten teachers doing Kindergarten activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to school 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-back-to-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 14:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-back-to-school/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re back from a summer vacation on Cape Cod, and now it&#39;s time for back to school.&amp;nbsp; Ann Arbor makes a very rapid transition from summer town to college town in the span of about 72 hours, and it&#39;s just about time for everything to change.
You know it&#39;s time for school to start when the next projects on your fun list are the new Link Bus schedule, the football parking prices map, the 3d grade start of school picnic and the daycare potluck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop backpacks - summary of recommendations</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-01-laptop-backpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 09:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-01-laptop-backpack/</guid>
      <description>I recently sent out an email query to the a2b3 mailing list about backpacks suitable for laptops.&amp;nbsp; In the interests of not keeping useful information in my inbox, here&#39;s a summary of sorts.
The list, in no particular order, with some amount of incomplete information:
Land&#39;s End: the pack I have has a label, don&#39;t know the name of it in their catalog.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s nice.&amp;nbsp; The Land&#39;s End backpack page has more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figure 8 school bus races in Flat Rock, MI - 2008 season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-09-figure-8-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 09:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-09-figure-8-school/</guid>
      <description>Every year the Flat Rock Speedway does a race series that includes figure eight bus races. This year&#39;s schedule includes:
June 14: Marco&#39;s Pizza School Bus Figure 8, legends cars, factory stock, 4-cylinder.
Sept. 13: Pepsi Cola School Bus Figure 8, street stock.
This year there&#39;s also school bus figure 8s at the Toledo Speedway:
May 23: Night of Destruction, school bus figure 8, figure 8 train, factory stock, 4-cylinder, backup race, rollover contest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible college admissions officer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-07-invisible-colle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 00:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-07-invisible-colle/</guid>
      <description>One of the job titles you expect to see in the future.  Brad DeLong on the invisible college:  Right now I&amp;rsquo;m looking out my office window, perched above the large, grassy, Frisbee-playing, picnicking, and sunbathing area that stretches through Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s campus. I&amp;rsquo;m looking straight out at the Golden Gate Bridge. It&amp;rsquo;s a view that I marvel at every dayI wonder why the chancellor hasn&amp;rsquo;t confiscated such offices and rented them out to hedge funds to improve the university&amp;rsquo;s finances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>