<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority Calendars Community Food And Drink Garlic Mustard Google Ann Arbor Infrastructure Mobile Parking Structures Pedometer Professional Associations on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/a2b3-ann-arbor-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-calendars-community-food-and-drink-garlic-mustard-google-ann-arbor-infrastructure-mobile-parking-structures-pedometer-professional-associations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority Calendars Community Food And Drink Garlic Mustard Google Ann Arbor Infrastructure Mobile Parking Structures Pedometer Professional Associations on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:55:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/a2b3-ann-arbor-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-calendars-community-food-and-drink-garlic-mustard-google-ann-arbor-infrastructure-mobile-parking-structures-pedometer-professional-associations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for Thursday, Feb. 11, 2010</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-02-11-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-feb-11-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-02-11-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-feb-11-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attendance: 19.  I had the udon noodles, which are new on the menu at Eastern Accents and quite good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My list of things to note from the day includes, but is not limited to:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google&#39;s proposed fiber to the home project, and how to get it to Ann Arbor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Susan Crawford is back in Ann Arbor from a stint in DC and teaching cyber law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m not sure that I wouldn&#39;t rather have a Droid phone than a Blackberry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a super-nifty Droid app which is an exercise tracker w/maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searching for low RPM motors that run on 2 AA batteries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next Tues.at Dow Aud. at UMHS a meeting on FDA regs for social media and medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Census is hiring and training workers, $14-18/hr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a2geeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignite 3 is coming up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth Day is Garlic Mustard Day; I need your recipes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next Tuesday is Paczki Day, I need your jelly donuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ann Arbor Government Documents Repository continues to collect local govdocs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gelman Sciences has released some new docs on their pollution plume &amp; cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Buzz is out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the DDA is doing a survey on parking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the hot pepper flakes are called &#34;Ichimi Togarashi&#34;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list deserves hyperlinks; when I get them I&#39;ll go back and edit them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who came, see you next time.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>