<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Huron River on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/huron-river/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Huron River on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:40:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/huron-river/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10,000 gallons of raw sewage dumped into the Huron River on June 27, 2013 after torrential rainstorms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</guid>
      <description>This press release from the City of Ann Arbor was sent to news media on June 28, 2013. As far as I can tell, AnnArbor.com did not run a story. The Ann Arbor Chronicle did publish information about this discharge as part of its meeting reporting for the July 15, 2013 city council meeting.
UPDATE: AnnArbor.com story of July 19, 2013 is up now.
A copy of this news release is available on the Ann Arbor Area Government Document Repository (a2docs), but there&amp;#39;s no copy to be found on the City of Ann Arbor web site as of this writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River Day is Sunday, July 14, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-huron-river-day-is-sunday-july-14-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 09:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-huron-river-day-is-sunday-july-14-2013/</guid>
      <description>Press release cut and paste directly from the City of Ann Arbor web site, with links added that go to Arborwiki.
PRESS RELEASE
For Immediate Release
33RD ANNUAL HURON RIVER DAY CELEBRATION ON SUNDAY, JULY 14 OFFERS FREE RIVER ACTIVITES FOR FAMILIES
ANN ARBOR, Mich., June 7, 2013 — Enjoy the beautiful Huron River and participate in free family river activities during the Huron River Day Celebration at Gallup Park, 3000 Fuller Road in Ann Arbor, on Sunday, July 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erratic water levels on the mighty Huron River, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>This graph measures water levels downstream from Argo Dam. Water levels are not supposed to fluctuate this much - it&amp;#39;s not good for the river.
More data at the USGS.
Update: I checked with USGS to make sure that the gauges were working fine, and got back this result:
We&amp;#39;re pretty certain everything is working just fine there. I believe we have a hydrologic technician there today making a streamflow measurement and he&amp;#39;ll verify the operation of the equipment at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnnArbor.Crowdmap.com - collaborative analysis of storm impact</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-annarborcrowdmapcom-collaborative-analysis-of-storm-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 22:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-annarborcrowdmapcom-collaborative-analysis-of-storm-impact/</guid>
      <description>AnnArbor.Crowdmap.com&amp;#0160;is an online system which has been collecting storm reports from the May 2011 flooding in Ann Arbor, as well as having in it previous information from past flood events and other incidents in Ann Arbor where there was widespread problems.
 Crowdmap&amp;#0160;is a tool that allows you to crowdsource information and visualize it on a map and timeline.
 I&amp;#39;ve typed in a bunch of these, but if you notice a news report of flooding, sewer spills, landslides, closed roads or fish flopping around on the road please add in a dot on the map with a link.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>