<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/huron-river/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/huron-river/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10,000 gallons of raw sewage dumped into the Huron River on June 27, 2013 after torrential rainstorms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-10000-gallons-of-raw-sewage-dumped-into-the-huron-river-on-june-27-2013-after-torrential-rainstorms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This press release from the City of Ann Arbor was sent to news media on June 28, 2013. As far as I can tell, AnnArbor.com did not run a story. The Ann Arbor Chronicle did publish information about this discharge as part of its meeting reporting for the July 15, 2013 city council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/news/ann-arbor-wastewater-treatment-staff-evaluating-operations-after-10k-gallon-raw-sewage-spill/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AnnArbor.com story of July 19, 2013&lt;/a&gt; is up now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2docs.org/doc/316/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;copy of this news release&lt;/a&gt; is available on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2docs.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Area Government Document Repository&lt;/a&gt; (a2docs), but there&amp;#39;s no copy to be found on the City of Ann Arbor web site as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;----&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR, Mich., June 28, 2013 — On Thursday, June 27, 2013, the Ann Arbor area was deluged with intense rainfall that caused flooding conditions and significantly increased the flow of wastewater to the City of Ann Arbor Wastewater Treatment Plant (WWTP) over a short period of time.&amp;#0160; Plant flows more than tripled within a half hour.&amp;#0160; As a result of this unprecedented increase in plant flow, approximately 10,000 gallons of untreated wastewater was discharged to the Huron River from&amp;#0160;5:20 to 5:30 p.m.&amp;#0160; By comparison, the WWTP fully treated approximately 350,000 gallons of wastewater during the 10-minute period over which this incident occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, due to a number of factors, the impact of this incident on human health and the environment is minimal.&amp;#0160; The flow within the Huron River for the 10 minutes over which the discharge occurred was approximately 11,000,000 gallons, consequently the estimated 10,000 gallons of untreated wastewater was diluted by a factor of 1,000.&amp;#0160; Further, mesh filters were already in place over the storm sewer inlets as part of the ongoing major construction project at the plant, which prevented solid material from entering the Huron River.&amp;#0160; There are no communities downstream of the plant that withdraw water from the Huron River for drinking purposes.&amp;#0160; In addition, the fact that the discharges occurred during extreme rain conditions makes it very unlikely that direct human contact would have occurred, particularly with the significant and immediate dilution of the discharge by the relatively high river flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;In accordance with regulatory protocols, the City of Ann Arbor WWTP contacted the Michigan Department of Environmental Quality and the Washtenaw County Health Department to inform them of this unfortunate incident.&amp;#0160; Plant staff is commended for demonstrating clear thinking and fast action under extreme conditions, which prevented this situation from being much worse.&amp;#0160; Additionally, actions to avoid similar circumstances are being evaluated by plant staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# # # # #&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River Day is Sunday, July 14, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-huron-river-day-is-sunday-july-14-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 09:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-08-huron-river-day-is-sunday-july-14-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Press release cut and paste directly from the City of Ann Arbor web site, with links added that go to Arborwiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESS RELEASE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;For Immediate Release&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33RD ANNUAL HURON RIVER DAY CELEBRATION ON SUNDAY, JULY 14 OFFERS FREE RIVER ACTIVITES FOR FAMILIES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR, Mich., June 7, 2013 — Enjoy the beautiful &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Huron_River&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Huron River&lt;/a&gt; and participate in free family river activities during the Huron River Day Celebration at &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Gallup_Park&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Gallup Park&lt;/a&gt;, 3000 Fuller Road in Ann Arbor, on Sunday, July 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 33rd annual event will be kicked off in the morning with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Ann_Arbor_Track_Club&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Track Club&lt;/a&gt; Gallup Gallop 5K Run/Fitness Walk at Gallup Park at 8:30 a.m. For online registration, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aatrackclub.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;www.aatrackclub.org&lt;/a&gt;. Also in the morning at Gallup Park is a naturalist-guided paddling trip from 11 a.m. to noon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main Huron River Day activities will be held on Sunday, July 14 at Gallup Park from noon to 4 p.m. Have fun discovering and learning about the Huron River. Paddle a boat with $5/boat canoe and kayak rentals, visit the exhibit tents to learn about the river and enjoy live music all on the banks of the beautiful Huron River. Among the many activities offered will be a children’s tent with art and science activities and the enviro-challenge game; have your picture taken in a canoe photo booth; catch a fish; see a live animal program with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Leslie_Science_and_Nature_Center&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Leslie Science &amp;amp; Nature Center&lt;/a&gt;; step into a Butterfly House; and try out stand-up paddleboarding (SUP) on the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the history of the river with the Classic Small Boat Show. Musical entertainment will be provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Joe_Reilly&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Joe Reilly&lt;/a&gt; from noon to 1 p.m., &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Gemini&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; from 1:30 to 2:30 p.m. and &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Wire_in_the_Wood&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Wire in the Wood&lt;/a&gt; from 2:45 to 3:45 p.m. Throughout the afternoon, there will be performances by &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/AuxWerks_Dance&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AuxWerks Dance&lt;/a&gt; celebrating the river through dance. Food available will include a hot dog stand, &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Pilar&amp;#39;s_Tamales&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Pilars&lt;/a&gt; tamales, Italian Ice, &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Zingermans&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Zingerman’s&lt;/a&gt; baked goods and more.&amp;#0160; Ride your bike to the event, and your boat rental will be free. Bicycle valet parking will be provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Washtenaw_Bicycling_and_Walking_Coalition&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Washtenaw Bicycling and Walking Coalition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on Sunday, July 14, the Washtenaw County Parker Mill County Park will offer tours of the Pioneer Grist Mill from noon to 4 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Huron River Day Celebration is sponsored by DTE Energy Foundation. Additional support provided by Toyota, Washtenaw County Water Resources Commissioner, Washtenaw County Parks and Recreation and the City of Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huron River Day History&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;More than 30 years ago, the Huron River Day celebration began as a way to encourage partnerships among government, private and non-profit organizations and to educate citizens about the importance of water quality and Huron River preservation. Each year, this event draws approximately 2,500 people from the Ann Arbor community to celebrate the Huron River.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Huron River Day, call&amp;#0160;(734) 794-6240&amp;#0160;or visit&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/HRD&#34;&gt;www.a2gov.org/HRD&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erratic water levels on the mighty Huron River, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-09-05-erratic-water-levels-on-the-mighty-huron-river-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This graph measures water levels downstream from Argo Dam. Water levels are not supposed to fluctuate this much - it&amp;#39;s not good for the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis/uv/?site_no=04174500&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;More data at the USGS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;USGS.04174500.01.00060..20120829.20120905.log.0.p50&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448a29b2970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0177448a29b2970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;USGS.04174500.01.00060..20120829.20120905.log.0.p50&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: I checked with USGS to make sure that the gauges were working fine, and got back this result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;We&amp;#39;re pretty certain everything is working just fine there. I believe we have a hydrologic technician there today making a streamflow measurement and he&amp;#39;ll verify the operation of the equipment at the same time. Tom&amp;#0160;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnnArbor.Crowdmap.com - collaborative analysis of storm impact</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-annarborcrowdmapcom-collaborative-analysis-of-storm-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 22:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-annarborcrowdmapcom-collaborative-analysis-of-storm-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.crowdmap.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;AnnArbor.Crowdmap.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is an online system which has been collecting storm reports from the May 2011 flooding in Ann Arbor, as well as having in it previous information from past flood events and other incidents in Ann Arbor where there was widespread problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crowdmap.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Crowdmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;is a tool that allows you to crowdsource information and visualize it on a map and timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve typed in a bunch of these, but if you notice a news report of flooding, sewer spills, landslides, closed roads or fish flopping around on the road please add in a dot on the map with a link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88b33c4f970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 20&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88b33c4f970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88b33c4f970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 20&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image shows storm-to-date stormwater related incidents in Ann Arbor and the surrounding area - I will leave it to the world to decide how far away &amp;quot;surrounding&amp;quot; is, but certainly the Huron River watershed is in scope, and I suspect that the area to watch is roughly the size of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt; catchment basin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about Crowdmap at &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcocktail.com/crowdmap-2011-03&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Tech Cocktail&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/omidyar-network-invests-14-million-into-ushahidis-crowd-source-alert-platform-2009-12&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;2009 Business Insider story&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;covers eBay founder&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre Omidyar&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s investment in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ushahidi.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ushahidi&lt;/a&gt;, the system that Crowdmap was built out of.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>