<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colorado on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/colorado/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colorado on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 21:58:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/colorado/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental contamination from Colorado floods? Too soon to know the full extent</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-environmental-contamination-from-colorado-floods-too-soon-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 21:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-18-environmental-contamination-from-colorado-floods-too-soon-to-know/</guid>
      <description>From a transcript of an 18 September 2013 interview on Democracy Now about the aftermath of the 2013 Colorado floods. Jim Pullen is a reporter at Colorado radio station KGNU, an independent community station in Boulder and Denver. Hyperlinks are my own.
 NERMEEN SHAIKH: And when do you expect to learn, Jim Pullen, of the extent of the environmental contamination as a result of these floods?
JIM PULLEN: That, I think that is going to take some weeks, very unfortunately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boulder Colorado Flood of September 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-12-boulder-colorado-flood-of-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 10:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-12-boulder-colorado-flood-of-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>The city of Boulder, Colorado is flooded after several days of torrential rains. Here&#39;s some useful links if you want to get up to speed on what&#39;s going on.
Turn around, don&#39;t drown. If you&#39;re in the affected area, get authoritative news from local sources (and not this blog).
Scanner For raw unfiltered news of what is happening, listen to the emergency services scanner for the Boulder area. The Boulder County Sheriff and Fire feed has over 800 listeners as of this writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denver International Airport hit by June 18, 2013 EF-1 tornado, no one hurt</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-denver-international-airport-hit-by-june-18-2013-ef-1-tornado-no-one-hurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 20:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-denver-international-airport-hit-by-june-18-2013-ef-1-tornado-no-one-hurt/</guid>
      <description>Dr Jeff Masters has remarkable radar imagery from Weather Underground, since the storm went directly over the NWS Denver station.
 
More news coverage:
The Washington Post collected photos and video from Twitter.
Denver Post:&amp;#0160;Tornado at Denver International Airport forces diversions, evacuations</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>