<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 13:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10/1 Ann Arbor DDA public hearing on proposed parking rate increases</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-20-101-ann-arbor-dda-public-hearing-on-proposed-parking-rate-increases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 13:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-20-101-ann-arbor-dda-public-hearing-on-proposed-parking-rate-increases/</guid>
      <description>A public hearing on a proposed parking rate change for municipal Ann Arbor garages will be included as part of the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority&#39;s October 1, 2014 board meeting at the very beginning (12:00 noon) of the agenda. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text of comments to Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority, September 3, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-03-text-of-comments-to-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-september-3-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 14:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-03-text-of-comments-to-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-september-3-2014/</guid>
      <description>This is a partial text of the public comments I gave at the September 3, 2014 meeting, for the record. Please incorporate these comments into the public record of the meeting. I have provided a copy of these comments to Susan Pollay in advance of my presentation.
Thank you for your time.
I wish to address two issues: copyrights on DDA maps and public notice of the Bill&#39;s Beer Garden meeting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor DDA has a new web site, and real time parking information is available again</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-ann-arbor-dda-has-a-new-web-site-and-real-time-parking-information-is-available-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-16-ann-arbor-dda-has-a-new-web-site-and-real-time-parking-information-is-available-again/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor DDA has launched a new web site, and one of the features of it is a map with information available in real time about parking availability at various structures.
 
The structures are in a shade of pale blue, and the lots are in pale green; my current location is marked with a bubble. If you&amp;#39;re looking for just space available information, there&amp;#39;s a JSON file with that data; you&amp;#39;ll have to unpack it to map structures to their ID numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public hearing December 7, 2011 to discuss increase of hourly parking rates in Ann Arbor</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-a2dda-parking-increase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-a2dda-parking-increase/</guid>
      <description>Notice of Public Hearing
Under Paragraph 8 of the City/DDA Parking Agreement, the public must be provided with an opportunity to speak at a public hearing before changes are made to hourly parking meter rates. A public hearing has been scheduled to elicit feedback on a proposed change to increase the hourly parking meter rate $0.10/hour, from $1.40/hour to $1.50/hour in September 2012.
Wednesday, December 7, 2011 at 12 noon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On knowing about more public meetings than you possibly could attend</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-public-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-public-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s an overly simplified description of the process by which you can learn about, and participate in, more public meetings on more topics of public interest than you could possibly attend in person - without ever relying on someone else&amp;#39;s account of what transpired at that meeting.
&amp;#0160;
Identify the public body which has oversight or jurisdiction over the issue in question. There may be multiples of these, at the local, county, state and federal levels, plus occasionally a treaty organization or two that gets involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor DDA revised committee meeting schedule, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-a2dda-committee-revised/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 19:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-a2dda-committee-revised/</guid>
      <description>Details? See http://a2dda.org&amp;#0160;or call 734-994-6697.&amp;#0160;
 Edward Vielmetti seeks out public meetings which also serve a light snack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on the media and government - watching the DDA, day 3</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-01-on-the-media-and-government-watching-the-dda-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 23:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-01-on-the-media-and-government-watching-the-dda-day-3/</guid>
      <description>day 3 notes
I ducked out at the end of the second day of MT training and headed off to the DDA meeting downtown.&amp;#0160; The meeting had started on time, but I didn&amp;#39;t get there on time, so I missed some of the initial public commentary.
In addition to the usual crowd of developers, city staff, and other interested parties, there were three reporters in attendance: Dave Askins from the Ann Arbor Chronicle; Andrew Cluley, a news reporter at 89.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDA meeting, downtown, today; I have 4 minutes on the agenda; here&#39;s what I said</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-dda-meeting-downtown-today-i-have-4-minutes-on-the-agenda-heres-what-i-said/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 12:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-dda-meeting-downtown-today-i-have-4-minutes-on-the-agenda-heres-what-i-said/</guid>
      <description>Thanks all for your suggestions; I gave them my 4 minutes. Here&amp;#39;s what I said.
 1. &amp;#0160;Not going to talk about the Link Bus and how bad the signage is; I did my own pocket schedule and now I&amp;#39;m OK.&amp;#0160; This is not the right board to give that feedback to.
 2. &amp;#0160;Not going to talk about how the AATA Ridetrak is down and how it&amp;#39;s been down for a month; that&amp;#39;s a message to the AATA board, not this board.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>