<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 13:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10/1 Ann Arbor DDA public hearing on proposed parking rate increases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-20-101-ann-arbor-dda-public-hearing-on-proposed-parking-rate-increases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 13:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-20-101-ann-arbor-dda-public-hearing-on-proposed-parking-rate-increases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A public hearing on a proposed parking rate change for municipal Ann Arbor garages will be included as part of the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority&#39;s October 1, 2014 board meeting at the very beginning (12:00 noon) of the agenda. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text of comments to Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority, September 3, 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-03-text-of-comments-to-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-september-3-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 14:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-03-text-of-comments-to-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-september-3-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a partial text of the public comments I gave at the September 3, 2014 meeting, for the record. Please incorporate these comments into the public record of the meeting. I have provided a copy of these comments to Susan Pollay in advance of my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish to address two issues: copyrights on DDA maps and public notice of the Bill&#39;s Beer Garden meeting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Downtown Development Authority maintains a map, created by the City of Ann Arbor, showing the official DDA boundaries. It is an essential document to define the DDA and should be readily available to anyone. However, the map contains this copyright notice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#34;No part of this product shall be reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, for any purpose, without prior written permission from the City of Ann Arbor. This map complies with National Map Accuracy Standards for mapping at 1 Inch = 100 Feet. The City of Ann Arbor and its mapping contractors assume no legal representation for the content and/or inappropriate use of information on this map.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an unreasonable copyright notice, and should be replaced promptly and at the very minimum with a copyright notice explicitly allowing reuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Bill&#39;s Beer Garden meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A notice I received during this meeting from the Twitter account of Bill&#39;s Beer Garden noted that the venue is not open until 5:30 p.m., though the published meeting time is 5:00 p.m. In the interest of following both the letter and the spirit of the Michigan Open Meetings Act, which states in part&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#34;All meetings of a public body shall be open to the public and shall be held in a place available to the general public. &#34;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signage at Bill&#39;s Beer Garden must make it clear to the public that a public meeting is being held and that the general public is able to attend. In particular, there is a concern that since this venue serves alcohol, that there may be restrictions on individuals to attend who are under the legal drinking age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank your for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noted later:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/A2DDA&#34;&gt;@A2DDA&lt;/a&gt; Guests under 21 are welcome with a parent/guardian&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bill&amp;#39;s Beer Garden (@BillsBeerGarden) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BillsBeerGarden/status/507229621428183040&#34;&gt;September 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BillsBeerGarden&#34;&gt;@BillsBeerGarden&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/A2DDA&#34;&gt;@A2DDA&lt;/a&gt; unaccompanied adults between the ages 18-21, not just minors.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ryan Burns (@ryanburns) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ryanburns/status/507245510349299712&#34;&gt;September 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>