<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Transportation Authority on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-transportation-authority/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Transportation Authority on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 16:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-transportation-authority/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A test of Ridescout for Ann Arbor multi-modal transit use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 16:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-10-10-a-test-of-ridescout-for-ann-arbor-multi-modal-transit-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RideScout is an app that provides info about a whole range of
transit options, including taxi, car share, bus, parking, and
more. They have support for Ann Arbor as a city, so I tried it
while riding AAATA (The Ride).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ridescoutapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.ridescoutapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the first independent app that I&#39;ve seen that shows where
every AAATA stop is, in a nice little app that works on your phone
with a zippy little map that scrolls nicely. That&#39;s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RideScout has bus arrival and departure information for schedules,
but it doesn&#39;t have real-time bus location info. So it thought that
I had made it to N Campus when really I was still waiting on the bus at
BTC. It could also have real-time parking info in Ann Arbor from
the Ann Arbor DDA, but it also doesn&#39;t. I didn&#39;t see the Arborbike
system in there either though that&#39;s pretty new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company behind RideScout has been bought by Car2Go, a car-sharing
service. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xconomy.com/texas/2014/09/03/austins-ridescout-bought-by-daimler-car-rental-service-car2go/&#34;&gt;Xconomy&lt;/a&gt; has the story. Since Car2Go doesn&#39;t
have operations in Ann Arbor, I don&#39;t know what to expect of their
continued development here, but I like the idea!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>