<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetup on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for August 6, 2015 at Mi Compadre</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-06-a2b3-mi-compadre-non-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;a2b3&lt;/span&gt; lunch this week was at
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Mi Compadre&lt;/span&gt;, a Mexican place on Packard.
We had a good turnout. I recommend the lengua tacos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was inspired this week for the lunch question by
going to the &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Workantile&lt;/span&gt; lunch on Wednesday,
which followed the same general pattern - sit down, introduce
yourself around the table, and answer some simple question.
At Workantile the prompt was simply &amp;ldquo;share something nice that happened to you this week&amp;rdquo;,
and that was enough of a prompt for everyone to be brief and cheery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When lunches are well attended, it seems to be that it happens
because the news gets out in plenty of time and plenty of detail
on Facebook. Not everyone in my world does Facebook, but there&amp;rsquo;s
more people there than on Twitter or Meetup, and it appears that
Facebook might now have the tools for lunch organizing that it didn&amp;rsquo;t
have a year ago when I started using Meetup for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the help of &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Tom Meloche&lt;/span&gt; it looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going
to move the primary ritual of notifying people where the next meeting is
through a Facebook event, and move away from Meetup as the primary organizing
tool. That&amp;rsquo;s going to take a few months to pull off but it looks like
the right organizing tool for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss the olden days when &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;eGroups&lt;/span&gt; was so novel that
you could build an instant community around an easy to run mailing
list. Yahoo so completely missed the boat when they turned that
into Yahoo Groups over a decade ago. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 Yahoo group&lt;/a&gt; around indefinitely -
it&amp;rsquo;s free after all, and it&amp;rsquo;s old - but it&amp;rsquo;s not growing and
working on a system that doesn&amp;rsquo;t support growth is a recipe for
stagnatation. Where I used to count on a new person every week from
Yahoo Groups I now only get 10-15 new subscribers a year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>