<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/christopher-olston/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/christopher-olston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>quantitative measures of usability (or, measuring measurability)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-quantitative-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 11:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2007/2007-12-04-quantitative-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I did the Google search for &#34;quantitative measures of usability&#34;, to see if that line of thinking would get me something useful.  Here&#39;s some explorations around those search results, and some reflections on that line of reasoning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;CHI: single usability metric&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There is a site &#34;measuring usability&#34; which unsurprisingly ranked high on the list.  It introduces the novel concept of a &#34;single measure of usability&#34;, which looks like the sum of a bunch of individual metrics all mushed together into a single number.  (Sauro and Kindlund, CHI 2005).  It measures task completion times, task time, satisfaction and error counts, and is a formalized version of what looks like an original Excel spreadsheet.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From an electronic commerce point of view this is a promising number, but an expensive one to compute - from web server logs you can impute task completion and task times, and maybe get some sense for errors, but satisfaction is hard to grind out of a server log.   It comes from the CHI tradition of simple models of user behavior assessed from small data sets.  But it&#39;s a start.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Patents: quantitative measures of qualitative usability&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There&#39;s a patent filing (Ed Chi, Christopher Olston) with this initial claim:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
A system for determining a quantitative measure of qualitative usability of related Web pages, comprising: stored Web pages that each include at least one hyperlink referencing and proximal cues relating to distal content included in another Web page; a stored information goal identifying a target Web page; an activation network, comprising a directed graph comprising nodes corresponding to the Web pages and arcs corresponding to the hyperlinks, wherein a weight is assigned to each arc to represent a probability of traversal of the corresponding hyperlink based on a relatedness of keywords in the information goal to the proximal cues included in the referenced Web page; and a simulator to evaluate a traversal through the activation network to the node corresponding to the target Web page as a quantitative measure of usability.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There&#39;s more (of course, it&#39;s a patent, there&#39;s a lot more).  It appears to be a simulator-driven version of the same PageRank algorithms that Google started out with, except that rather than assuming a random walk through page space it takes into account what Google would call quality scores and what they call &#34;information scent&#34;.  Chi works at PARC, and this looks like an elaboration of their &lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=937550&#34;&gt;ScentTrails&lt;/a&gt; paper (TOCHI 2003).  Note that it&#39;s not about task completion as above but more about findability within a search space, and as thus it describes a different problem than above.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;More work
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;I&#39;m sure there&#39;s more relevant work in this field, but given that the first words I used to look both unearthed CHI related papers, I&#39;m not sure I have the right language to express the thing I&#39;m really after.  so I&#39;ll stop...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>