<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soundcloud on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/soundcloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soundcloud on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/soundcloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Soundcloud, now and in the future</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-soundcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-soundcloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have exactly one copy of something and it&amp;rsquo;s only on Soundcloud,
this would be an opportune time to make a backup. That&amp;rsquo;s always a good
idea anyway not to rely on single web servers for anything, but it&amp;rsquo;s
especially notable in the light of these articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the upbeat &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2015-07-10/can-soundcloud-be-the-facebook-of-music-&#34;&gt;Bloomberg Business&lt;/a&gt; article of July 10, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; SoundCloud’s potential is fascinating, and perhaps unique.
The founders have ambitious goals that respond to changes in the
way music and sound are created and consumed. It’s a beautiful
dream. So long as all the crucial participants—labels, publishers,
artists, SoundCloud itself—can agree on how to share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, the downbeat &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techtimes.com/articles/72325/20150729/soundcloud-losing-money-fast-as-record-labels-apply-licensing-pressure.htm&#34;&gt;Tech Times&lt;/a&gt; on July 29, 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently reported on rumors that popular music streaming service
SoundCloud is planning on adding a subscription-based tier to its
currently all-free streaming service, and that rumor was just
confirmed by company co-founder Eric Wahlforss in a conversation
with the Wall Street Journal. Now, it appears that the impetus
behind the development of the subscription tier is clear: the company
is in dire need of cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dire need of cash&amp;rdquo; because record labels are not thrilled with
the beautiful dream of listening to the world&amp;rsquo;s music for free.
Remember how Napster turned out? It was a beautiful dream, too,
but labels and publishers just saw it as piracy. This from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmtunes.com/2015/06/editorial-believe-it-or-not-soundcloud-is-fighting-the-good-fight/&#34;&gt;EDM Tunes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2015 SoundCloud controversy is Napster all over again. We
aren’t sharing files anymore, we’re sharing sound. 15 years ago
record labels objected to us downloading their music, now they
object to us streaming it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Napster, SoundCloud is a goldfish that’s been unwillingly
thrust into battle with three super-wale companies. Just for a
matter of reference, consider that SoundCloud has about 200 employees,
while the Sony, Universal, and Warner corporate networks employ
more than 200,000. At this point, SoundCloud is fighting to survive,
and unfortunately has received a lot of critical media attention.
Since its 2007 inception, SoundCloud has served as a haven for
electronic music producers and fans; allowing sound to be seamlessly
shared from artist to listener. This luxury is being threatened,
and we’re all pissed about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enjoy Soundcloud while you can, and when you are producing things
for it make sure you keep a backup on your own machines!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>