<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Typepad on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/typepad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typepad on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:33:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/typepad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>converting typepad to hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-07-14-converting-typepad-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 13:33:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-07-14-converting-typepad-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task of the night was getting a few years worth of Typepad posts
into Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first step was to convert to Jekyll format, which I did using this
typepad_to_jekyll Ruby gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/koozie/typepad_to_jekyll&#34;&gt;https://github.com/koozie/typepad_to_jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then need to do a few things to get the Jekyll files exactly right
for Hugo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the date format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite the Categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and relink all of the images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the format for &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; was a one-liner in perl with the -i (&amp;ldquo;edit in
place&amp;rdquo;) flag.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the category rewrite or the image rescue yet.
The approach I took was to simply hack on the output files, rather than
change the source code to the typepad_to_jekyll program, but if you were
serious about it you&amp;rsquo;d do the latter and fork it until it did the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relinking all of the images requires opening a support ticket because Typepad
does not have an easy image export. Actually image hosting is a real
challenge and I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly the right way to do it inside Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll need to adjust the theme or pick a new theme so that it only shows
the first n posts on a page and then paginates, and I also need to adjust
it so that it shows categories. The show everything approach is unreasonable
when you have 1000s of pages to show off. On the other hand, the most
reasonable themes that I can find that look nice don&amp;rsquo;t have pagination
turned on by default. There&amp;rsquo;s some learning curve to roll my own, maybe
one that has some kind of reasonable sidebar structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>