<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gastonia North Carolina on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/gastonia-north-carolina/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gastonia North Carolina on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:50:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/gastonia-north-carolina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Affinia Group to move headquarters from Ann Arbor, MI to Gastonia, NC; 50 jobs at stake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-from-ann-arbor-mi-to-gastonia-nc-50-jobs-at-stake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.charlotteobserver.com/2013/10/15/4390165/ann-arbor-mich-company-to-relocate.html&#34;&gt;Charlotte Observer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Affinia Group Inc., a firm that designs, manufactures, distributes and markets industrial grade products and services, will relocate its Ann Arbor, Mich., headquarters to Gastonia, home of its Global Filtration group.
  The transition to the new corporate headquarters will occur in phases during 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia gives a little background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Affinia Group, a motor industry company, was formed in 2004 and specializes in the design, manufacture and replacement of parts for and on and off-road vehicles. Specifically filtration and chassis components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gastongazette.com/spotlight/affinia-group-moving-headquarters-to-gastonia-1.218940&#34;&gt;Gaston Gazette&lt;/a&gt; has additional details -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Affinia has approximately 50 jobs at its current headquarters, but that doesn’t mean all those jobs will relocate here. “We’re still putting together the transition plan,” said Keith Wilson, president of WIX Global Filtration. “It’s more of a consolidation than it is a big addition of people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bizjournals.com/charlotte/blog/outside_the_loop/2013/10/affinia-group-to-move-headquarters-to.html&#34;&gt;Charlotte Business Journal&lt;/a&gt; points to a new CFO at Affinia as an impetus for the move:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It all started in December, when Affinia spun off its brakes unit that makes Raybestos brand of automobile brakes. That unit, called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/brake-parts-inc-is-back-199857601.html&#34;&gt;Brake Parts Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, was sold to members of Affinia’s brakes unit management team. The price of the deal for Brake Parts, which contributed one-third of Affinia’s sales in 2011, wasn’t disclosed. Then on Monday, Affinia announced it had hired a Charlotte executive, Steve Klueg, as its new chief financial officer. Klueg, CFO at ReCommunity Recycling in Charlotte, will stay in the Charlotte area after he replaces Thomas Madden at Affinia, Howat says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Madden, the former Affinia CFO, is retiring, notes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aftermarketnews.com/Item/119412/affinia_group_cfo_tom_madden_announces_retirement.aspx&#34;&gt;Aftermarket News&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&#34;Tom Madden has almost 40 years of financial leadership to our company, and his guidance has been an immeasurable ingredient in helping us achieve our status as a worldwide leader,&#34; said Terry McCormack, president and CEO of Affinia Group. &#34;In a continuing demonstration of the commitment he has shown throughout his career, Tom will work side by side with our incoming CFO Steve Klueg to seamlessly transfer financial leadership over the coming months.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affinia&#39;s Ann Arbor headquarters is located at 1101 Technology Drive, Ann Arbor, MI 48108.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>