<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Obituaries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/obituaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Obituaries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 14:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/obituaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Prince</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-04-22-prince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s radio was full of the Prince music catalog. The artist
passed away in his Minnesota home at the age of 57. In response
any radio station that had anything other that pre-programmed music
responded by playing his hits - &amp;ldquo;Little Red Corvette&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Raspberry Beret&amp;rdquo;,
&amp;ldquo;Purple Rain&amp;rdquo; - and the radio stations that had artistic control
also played B sides, live shows, bootlegs and whatever they could find.
Ann Arbor&amp;rsquo;s own WCBN was exemplary in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radio that I remember is from the 80s when Prince&amp;rsquo;s music was
in regular play on the Electrifyin&amp;rsquo; Mojo&amp;rsquo;s show on Detroit&amp;rsquo;s WJLB.
Prince did a very rare live radio interview with Mojo, and you can
hear it in two parts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJZCoxZ5COY&#34;&gt;part one&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ftKtWgXzMS8&#34;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt; - on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I haven&amp;rsquo;t found yet is the computer font with a perfect Prince
symbol in it. You can get close by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://parkerhiggins.net/2013/01/writing-the-prince-symbol-in-unicode/&#34;&gt;writing the prince symbol in unicode&lt;/a&gt;,
or this ASCII representation may suffice: O(+&amp;gt; . But the
real deal came on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://nymag.com/following/2016/04/princes-legendary-floppy-disk-symbol-font.html&#34;&gt;3.5&amp;rdquo; floppy disc&lt;/a&gt; from Warner Bros.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Faye Amo (1954-2011), high school French teacher</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MARQUETTE – Faye M. Amo, age 57, of 425 West Ridge Street, Marquette,
entered eternal life Wednesday evening, July 13, 2011, at her home
in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula
Home Health and Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born March 23, 1954 in Lima, Ohio, a daughter of Stephen J. and
Ethel (Salidas) Catel, Faye was raised in Ishpeming and graduated
from the Ishpeming High School as salutatorian of her class. From
her days in grade school, Faye held the desire to become a teacher.
She enrolled at Northern Michigan University, where she received
her baccalaureate degree summa cum laude (with highest honor) with
a double major in French and English. She continued at Northern,
obtaining a double masters degree in English and French in 1977 and
later studied at the University of the Sorbonne in Paris where she
earned highest honors in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye’s
lifelong dream of becoming a teacher began with her first teaching
assignment at the Ishpeming High School in 1977. In 1979, she started
teaching French at the Marquette Senior High School, a career that
would span 31 years. Teaching French was her passion in life and
she loved all her students and they loved her. Affectionately known
as Madame Amo, she was the consummate professional teacher, one who
truly cared about her students and was dedicated to their education
and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not enough that the
students learned the French language, she felt they needed to
experience what “French” meant. Heading the French Club at Marquette
Senior High School, Faye planned numerous trips for club members
to big city museums to view French art exhibits, eat at French
eateries, and learn about French culture. Over the years, several
trips were taken to Chicago and to France in her mission to educate.
These memorable events were always anticipated by Faye and greeted
with enthusiasm by her students. For a number of years, she served
as class advisor, particularly enjoying building and decorating
floats for homecoming and decorating the gym for junior prom
activities. Throughout her life, Faye maintained an untiring interest
in the students at MSHS, often asking parents about their children,
even through the children may never have been her students and she
kept in regular contact with students who were now living adult
lives, with families of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition
to her affiliations at MSHS as foreign language department head for
several years, class advisor for the MSHS graduating class of 2008,
and serving on numerous parent-teacher committees, Faye was also a
member of the Greek Orthodox Church of the Assumption and the Ladies
Philoptochos Society, and active in civic committees such as the
American Association of University Women and the Marquette
Beautification Committee. In her leisure, Faye loved walking her
dog, Mario, for the 13 years of his life, bicycling, running – even
participating in marathons in Detroit and France, and riding in her
boat on beautiful Lake Superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye is
survived by her husband, John; her cherished son, Bret; two sisters,
Stephanie (Bob) Trumm and Jayme (Rick) Iknoiah both of California;
her mother-in-law, Leone Amo of Ironwood; brothers-in-law, Tom Amo
of Philadelphia, PA, Jim (Brooke) Amo of Livonia, and Ken Amo of
Ft Worth, TX; and several nieces and nephews. Faye was preceded in
death by her father, the honorable judge, Stephen J. Catel, her
mother, Ethel Catel; brother-in-law, Andrew Walton; and father-in-law,
John M. Amo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family will receive friends
at the Swanson-Lundquist Funeral Home on Sunday from 4:00 pm until
7:00 pm. Trisagion will be held at 6:00 pm. The Funeral Liturgy
will be held on Monday, July 18, at 11:00 am at the Greek Orthodox
Church of the Assumption with Rev. Tom Michalos officiating. Burial
will be made in the Park Cemetery. Pallbearers will be Jimmy Pedakis,
Lou Roumanis, Paul Andronis, Paul Wainio, Gary Shaffer, and Craig
Cox. Memorials may be directed to the Greek Orthodox Church of the
Assumption, 235 W. Ridge Street, Marquette, MI 49855 or to the Faye
Amo Scholarship Fund, Wells Fargo Bank, 101 W. Washington Street,
Marquette, MI 49855. Condolences may be expressed online at
www.swansonlundquistfuneralhome.com Adieu Madame Amo. Repose en
paix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy Yuill (1932-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 12:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-joy-yuill-1932/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/508946.html?nav=5007&#34;&gt;as printed in the Marquette Mining Journal, April 22 2008&lt;/a&gt;.  Joy and Baldy were neighbors of ours in Marquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REPUBLIC — Joy Elizabeth Yuill, 75, of 11676 River Road, Republic, and former Marquette resident, entered eternal life Tuesday afternoon, April 15, 2008, at her home in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula Home Health &amp; Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Born September 11, 1932, in Gaylord, the daughter of Stanley and Dorothy (Siegel) Yuill, Joy was raised in Vanderbilt and graduated from the Gaylord High School in 1949. She attended Hillsdale College for a year before transferring to Grinnell College in Grinnell, Iowa, where she received a bachelor of science degree in education in 1953. Joy taught in Detroit, while also taking classes at Wayne State University, which led to her receiving her master’s degree in special education in 1956, with special emphasis on blind and partially sighted clients. In 1957, Joy moved to Marquette, traveling extensively throughout the Upper Peninsula to serve sight-impaired students. In 1971, Joy received a nursing degree from Northern Michigan University, working at Marquette General Hospital mostly on weekends. She retired from her nursing career in 2000. For over 17 years, Joy worked summers at Bay Cliff Health Camp in Big Bay as a special education teacher and swimming instructor. She retired from this position in 2005 and then assisted with adult campers for one week each year. 1972 was to produce yet another degree for Joy, this time a master’s degree in music from Wayne State. Joy continued teaching full time until 2002 and thereafter taught on a part-time basis for the next two years. When not in the classroom, Joy was the piano accompanist for the Marquette Male Chorus for many years. She also assisted many students with their solo and ensemble pieces at the Negaunee and Westwood high schools for over 20 years. Known locally for her beautiful renditions on the harp, Joy was a participant in many concerts and musical programs over the years. She was a member of the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming. In June 1963, Joy married Vincent “Baldy” Bur, and he preceded her in death in 1999. Joy and Baldy were great animal lovers and took in all sorts of stray and unwanted animals over the years. In her leisure, she enjoyed baking bread, knitting, sewing, gardening, and being involved in anything musical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Joy is survived by her brother, Robert “Beezle” Yuill of Harvey; a brother-in-law, Leonard Bur of Marquette; sister-in-law, Amelia Kent of North Little Rock, Ark.; her niece, Martha Yuill of St. Paul, Minn.; and a nephew, Stephen Yuill of Ishpeming. In addition to her parents and husband, Joy was preceded in death by sisters-in-law, Christine Yuill and Verna Bur; and a nephew, Michael Bur. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The family will receive relatives and friends at the United Presbyterian Church in Ishpeming on Saturday, May 10, beginning at 1 p.m. A memorial service will follow at 2 p.m. Saturday with the Rev. James Robb officiating. Memorials may be directed to the Marquette County Humane Society, 84 Snowfield Road, Negaunee, MI 49866; or to the United Presbyterian Church, 112 E. Euclid St., Ishpeming, MI 49849.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Fassbender Funeral Home is serving the family, where condolences may be expressed online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&#34;&gt;www.fassbenderfuneralhome.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>