<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categorization on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/categorization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categorization on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/categorization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custom views of taxonomies</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 18:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-custom-views-of-taxonomies/</guid>
      <description>One of the motivation ideas behind going to the work to move a big weblog to a new platform is to get better control over categories. With Typepad, every category looks about the same; the idea now is with Hugo I can have separate categories that look different. For instance:
There are a number of recipes in the collection, which should be sorted alphabetically or by key ingredient, not chronologically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories and their utter impossibility of reflecting the current real world</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-categories-and-their-utter-impossibility-of-reflecting-the-current-real-world-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-categories-and-their-utter-impossibility-of-reflecting-the-current-real-world-/</guid>
      <description>Open up a &amp;quot;New Post&amp;quot; window, start typing.
Look at the categories on the right side of the screen - my screen, not yours. There&amp;#39;s an infinite scrolling list of them, from &amp;quot;Americana&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;zzz Draft Postings&amp;quot;. Somehow, categories became the wrong way to describe what is in this blog; aside from &amp;quot;Ann Arbor&amp;quot;, there&amp;#39;s few of them that have routine postings. But with almost 3000 articles written, it&amp;#39;s had to imagine any coherent way to recategorize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorization and its discontents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-30-categorization-and-its-discontents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 01:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-30-categorization-and-its-discontents/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia is going through one of its periodic existential crises, this time over the use of categories. A diligent editor created a category of &amp;quot;American women novelists&amp;quot; and began adding female novelists to it, and then removing them from the category &amp;quot;American novelists&amp;quot;. A predictable hue and cry ensued. James Gleick tells the story in some detail in the NY Review of Books, under the title &amp;quot;Wikipedia&amp;#39;s Women Problem&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the categorical imperative</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-24-losing-the-categorical-imperative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-24-losing-the-categorical-imperative/</guid>
      <description>For a long time - over 2000 posts - I have been putting blog entries into categories. The categories used to live in a long list on the right sidebar. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken them out of the sidebar, and now they&amp;rsquo;re much less visible in the user interface to the point of being invisible unless you happen to search for them.
I have touched enough categories to not be authoritative on any of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-13-system-mapping/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#39;s always good to collect a lot of examples as you look to map out a system. For that you want to have generative tools that suggest the kinds of examples that you want to look for.
The power outage maps I have been collecting started with the generative system of making a blank entry for each of 50 states, and looking to collect one in each state. I&amp;#39;ve done similar exercises where the generator is the first letter of the alphabet collecting examples A-Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holdridge vegetation classification system</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-11-holdridge-vegetation-classification-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-11-holdridge-vegetation-classification-system/</guid>
      <description>Another triangle, this one found in a University of Michigan Global Change lecture on the Tropical Rain Forest, by George Kling.&amp;#0160;
The triangle is the &amp;quot;Holdridge triangle&amp;quot;, dating to 1947.&amp;#0160;
 Holdridge, L.R. (1947) Determination of world plant formations from simple climatic data.&amp;#0160;Science, 105, 367--368.  
All materials © the Regents of the University of Michigan unless noted otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finding buckets to refill regularly</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-finding-buckets-to-refill-regularly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-14-finding-buckets-to-refill-regularly/</guid>
      <description>Much of the writing I do these days has tags but not much in the way of categories. There are a few very broad categories that things can go into, but not much in the way of narrow ones, and the world of tags means that you can always think up one more new tag to apply rather than revisiting an old one.
In some ways I miss the regular reinforcement obtained by the reminders that I&amp;#39;ve written on items in a category previously in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>working on metadata - stopped in your tracks and watched until you get it right</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-29-stopped-watched-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 22:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-29-stopped-watched-metadata/</guid>
      <description>Michael Sippey writes about Ben Hammersley writing about metadata.The quote he pulls is
So why do everything you can to keep metadata intact? Because it’s from this information that new products can be automatically created, at a scale and rapidity that would be impossible otherwise. With every piece of metadata that you don’t throw away, you gain a factor more potential ways of slicing through your content and delivering it as a separate product, simply as a result of a database lookup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radial categorization and the trouble with tags</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-24-radial-categorization-and-the-trouble-with-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-24-radial-categorization-and-the-trouble-with-tags/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m writing this post, and I don&amp;#39;t have a good category to put it in, so I have to create a category for it; but the process of creating the category describes some other set of things that could belong to it, and then by the time I am done with figuring out where it belongs inside my word-hoard posted to this blog I can go back and retroactively cross-post a half dozen other prototypical posts to that category so it looks like I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about it all along.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>