<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/coffee/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Caribou Coffee, hello Peet&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-14-goodbye-caribou-coffee-hello-peets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-14-goodbye-caribou-coffee-hello-peets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our local Caribou Coffee closed its doors for the last time on Sunday. A trailer appeared in the front of it Monday sporting a Peet&#39;s logo. The effort to rebuild the corner coffee shop under a new name is expected to take a couple of weeks, with a planned opening date in mid-November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change is hard, and change in a coffee routine is doubly hard. The corner Caribou had been a study spot, a meeting place, a second office and a place to see Mike the Mailman. Can we count on Peet&#39;s to fill the same neighborhood niche? Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir Vitae Coffee and Tea, E Liberty St, Ann Arbor next to Liberty St Robot Supply</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-18-elixir-vitae-coffee-and-tea-e-liberty-st-ann-arbor-next-to-liberty-st-robot-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 15:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-18-elixir-vitae-coffee-and-tea-e-liberty-st-ann-arbor-next-to-liberty-st-robot-supply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had my first chance to sit at the new Elixir Vitae cafe on East Liberty today. The store is one of two with that name, after the Cafe Ambrosia store on Maynard Street changed its name. (Same ownership, just a new name, because of conflicts with too many other coffee businesses called Ambrosia).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some impressions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot more sunshine in the new cafe than there ever was in the old one. Maynard is shaded by the parking structure and by Tower Plaza, but East Liberty has a nice south-facing window and light coming in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general ambiance is about the same, but not as many people have discovered the new cafe just yet. I&amp;#39;m expecting it to eventually get something between a Main Street and a State Street sense to it, but for now, I was mostly alone in using the place for an extended typing session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local events bulletin board has a good selection to look at - it&amp;#39;s not quite as big as the Maynard location, which has in my opinion one of the finest bulletin boards in town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a solid showing and a good new place to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>supermemo and morning coffee ritual memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An important piece of having coffee in the morning is making it part of a routine.  If you&#39;re predictable in your habits, you start to see the same people in the same space at the same time, and you get to be something of a regular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re careful, and switch your morning allegiances from time to time but still visit the old haunts often enough, you can be what passes for a regular long after you stopped coming every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often, then, do you need to show up for people to remember you?  For that I turn to structured repetition, and the power of priming memory periodically to strengthen it.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.supermemo.com&#34;&gt;Supermemo&lt;/a&gt;, a software package for memory improvement, has a nice paper on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.supermemo.com/articles/paper.htm&#34;&gt;using Supermemo without a computer&lt;/a&gt;, which specifies a pattern of repetitions and intervals to get details into memory.  The table of intervals specified says that you review materials at this pace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 days, 7 days, 12 days, 20 days, 1 month, 2 months, 3 months, 5 months, 9 months, 16 months, 2 years, 4 years, 6 years, 11 years, 18 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which suggests that a well-timed practice of showing up at a cafe, introducing yourself to everyone, learning their names, and them coming back at precisely timed intervals to repeat the process would be enough to make you a regular in no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>