<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two
people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away.
I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about
quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch
a postcard from the command line of my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;s got to be easier (so I don&amp;rsquo;t
have to look up command line options) but the basic structure works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postcards are archaic, perhaps, and also perhaps more expensive per each than
reaching someone through Facebook advertising. I do have to say though that I
love sending them, and love receiving them in return. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do the experiment
of $20 spent on Facebook vs $20 spent on postcards, and wonder what the return
would be; or better yet, $20 spent on each and identify particular synergies between
super-high-tech and old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card I got in the mail today was from Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain,
two of my faithful correspondents. They sent a photo of the Pickle Barrel House Museum
in Grand Marais, Michigan. The historic marker there reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer Cooperage Company of Chicago designed this small
vacation cottage, which stood on the shores of nearby Sable Lake
from 1926 until about 1937. It was built for William Donahey, creator
of the Chicago Tribune cartoon story The Teenie Weenies. The house
was constructed as a typical barrel would have been, only on a much
larger scale. The main barrel contained a living area on the first
floor and a bedroom on the second. A pantry connected this barrel
to a smaller single-story one, which housed a kitchen. Donahey spent
ten summers at the cottage with his wife, Mary, herself a noted
author of children&amp;rsquo;s books. The structure was then moved to its
current site and used as a tourist information center. The Pickle
Barrel House is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a destination for next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight of us met for lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aysesturkishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; today. It was a normal
Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for
the lunch group these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time
to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning
or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a
remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make
sure that the things that needed to get done got done. Among the
tasks that took up lots more time than they deserved included
dealing with the health insurance marketplace and with other
healthcare providers for dealing with billing and accounting problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the people at lunch were new to the table, but since Ann
Arbor is bascially a small town, it was not a surprise to me that
I had easily identifiable mutual friends with two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was delicious, well prepared and well presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll be back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Madras_Masala&#34;&gt;Madras Masala&lt;/a&gt;, as art fair will have
ended and town will be more back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big event coming up is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makerfairedetroit.com/&#34;&gt;Maker Faire Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, to be held at The
Henry Ford in Dearborn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://argusfarmstop.com&#34;&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/a&gt;. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Harnois_Farm&#34;&gt;Harnois Farm&lt;/a&gt;, and we had 9 at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>from a2b3 this week at Ayse&#39;s Courtyard Cafe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 20:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;he’s ed &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt;. he organizes lunch. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/wUAWmeGgcX&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/wUAWmeGgcX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; peter honeyman (@peterhoneyman) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/peterhoneyman/status/525316870463684608&#34;&gt;October 23, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 years of professionals eating lunch together on a regular basis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 07:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote up a piece about how you might rewrite your resume to provide a &#34;retcon&#34; (&#34;retroactive continuity&#34;) treatment, which emphasizes reinterpreting past events in such a way that they look like part of a story with a narrative arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me to thinking about lunch, of course, and the little hoary old story I tell about when the a2b3 group started &#34;8 years ago&#34;. And I realize now that I can trace back continuity way longer than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, when Sun 3/50s roamed the earth, I worked at OTA Limited Partnership as a systems guy. The company traded options, and I was a junior part of the ops team that kept the trading systems running. I wrote some code, I did some sysadmin work, I debugged flaky Proteon routers, I made sure we had a Usenet newsfeed. Life was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market was open every hour that lunch was served, so it didn&#39;t really ever make sense to leave the building during trading hours. That mean that lunch was brought in for everyone every single day. We had an elaborate scoring system where instead of you always buying lunch for yourself, you&#39;d buy lunch for the team, and you&#39;d get tally marks on the board to make sure that you properly were credited plus or minus depending on the number of lunches you bought. The bookshelves had a big thick binder full of menus, and we had some favorites. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my first real experience with professionals eating lunch together on a routine basis, and I&#39;m still friends with the OTA crew, long after the last tally mark was erased. That dates to 1989 or so, which means I&#39;ve been eating lunch as a grownup for about 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize now that if I were ever to get a real job again, one of my interview questions would have to be &#34;what do you do for lunch around here&#34;. If the answer is wrong, I can&#39;t take the job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to David Bloom for prodding me to tell more of a back story, and to my former daily lunch companions at OTA (including specifically John Hritz who is an a2b3 regular) for initiation into a professional lunch ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re invited for lunch at Bell&#39;s Diner on Thursday 9/11. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch&#34;&gt;a2b3 weekly lunch meetup group&lt;/a&gt; will let you say yes or no; if you&#39;re not coming, I&#39;ll still see your smiling face in the app, and it would be good to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thanks again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2014 Conversation Prism seen through the eyes of the a2b3 lunch</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-30-the-2014-conversation-prism-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 14:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-30-the-2014-conversation-prism-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5119281c0970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5119281c0970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;JESS3_BrianSolis_ConversationPrism4_WEB_2880x1800&#34; title=&#34;JESS3_BrianSolis_ConversationPrism4_WEB_2880x1800&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a5119281c0970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed in 2008 by Brian Solis, The [Conversation Prism] is a visual map of the social media landscape. It’s an ongoing study in digital ethnography that tracks dominant and promising social networks and organizes them by how they’re used in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2009/05/the-conversation-prism-as-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch.html&#34;&gt;In 2009&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote up how the a2b3 lunch organizes itself through the eye of the this system. I ran across it again, and decided to do a repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Conversation Prism]; https://conversationprism.com
* Social networks: Facebook, Yahoo Groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll see Yahoo Groups show up in lots of the entries, because the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 mailing list&lt;/a&gt; is the heart and soul of the whole effort. Facebook plays second fiddle, with a lot less people watching the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/2207503206/&#34;&gt;a2b3 group on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and a lot less traffic to that group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog: Typepad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the a2b3 &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/a2b3&#34;&gt;category on my Typepad blog&lt;/a&gt; . Mostly the specific thing that gets blogged about is the a2b3 lunch non-summaries, which I like going back to but which also take enough time to do that I don&#39;t always do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crowd Wisdom: Yahoo Groups, lunch conversation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions and answers: Yahoo Groups, lunch conversation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crowd is good about answering almost any reasonable question you throw at it, either at lunchtime or on the mailing list, and coming up with an answer. We don&#39;t need Quora or their ilk to get a good answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments: Disqus, Yahoo Groups, lunch conversation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I converted over this Typepad install to &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2014/03/the-next-major-change-for-this-weblog-is-converting-over-comments-to-disqus.html&#34;&gt;Disqus comments&lt;/a&gt;, but really, the comments are in the discussions on the mailing list and over lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social commerce: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social marketplace: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one yet has found a reason or a compelling method to sell things to each other, which is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social streams: Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2b3&#34;&gt;@a2b3 twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; that I very occasionally post to which has 500+ followers and only 150+ tweets. There&#39;s an opportunity to improve on that effort. If I could, I would automatically tweet out the stream from Meetup, but I haven&#39;t figured out yet how IFTTT plays with Meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Meetup, Foursquare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch/&#34;&gt;a2b3 Meetup&lt;/a&gt; answers the question of &#34;where is lunch going to be&#34;, and provides nice maps. It&#39;s the one piece of the 2009 landscape that was missing, and I&#39;m happy with the results. Foursquare answers the question of &#34;where do you eat lunch&#34;. I put together a [map of recent a2b3 lunch spots on Foursquare] without too much work. Perhaps I&#39;ll start checking in on Foursquare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicheworking: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is this I don&#39;t even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enterprise: Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enterprisiest tool I have for lunch is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2014/02/slack-first-impressions.html&#34;&gt;a2b3 Slack instance&lt;/a&gt;, a closed system (you&#39;re invited, just ask) which does chat (a la IRC) and newsfeed syndication. It&#39;s great as a tool, but it&#39;s not just the right fit for this particular group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki: Arborwiki (Localwiki)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localwiki.org&#34;&gt;Localwiki&lt;/a&gt; is a perfect fit for a local lunch group, because you can stash away answers to questions about the area as they come up and then refer back to them later as needed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt; has been running for 8+ years and has been a tremendous asset to a2b3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion and forums: Yahoo Groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 Yahoo Group&lt;/a&gt; is the key to the whole system. Without it, I guess I&#39;d reconstruct a mailing list with Google Groups. Please don&#39;t ever ruin it, Yahoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business: LinkedIn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn groups can be tedious to manage, and their discussion forums never took off. However, it&#39;s an easy way to read people&#39;s resumes, so there&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/groups?featured=&amp;amp;gid=36174&#34;&gt;a LinkedIn group for a2b3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service networking: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure what this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews and ratings: Yahoo Groups, Arborwiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t need a separate review system when &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt; is there to either catch reviews or at least to point to same on Yelp. For real-time reviews in response to queries, there&#39;s the Yahoo group. Who&#39;s Angie?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social curation: Pinterest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinterest.com/vielmetti/a2b3/&#34;&gt;add a map to a Pinterest board&lt;/a&gt;, you can pin Foursquare locations and their photos. So I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video: Youtube, I guess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a &#34;how to organize lunch&#34; video from Ignite Ann Arbor 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/a5BS9_-UAYo?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content / documents: a2docs (Scribd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2docs.org&#34;&gt;a2docs&lt;/a&gt; is a place to stash government records for the Ann Arbor area. It&#39;s powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/A2Docs/documents&#34;&gt;Scribd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events: Meetup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetup is new to the group since 2013. Over the span of 6 months I&#39;ve used it to organize two dozen events. Meetup is a little bit pricy for what you get, but they have timing for meetup updates down pat and a very low-impact way of keeping people informed. Join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch/&#34;&gt;a2b3 Meetup&lt;/a&gt; to get weekly announcements of lunch locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music: Soundcloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official a2b3 chime (played at 12:30pm on Thursdays) is hosted on Soundcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/97501588&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;visual=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Livecasting: Ustream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t livecast meetings as a rule, but if we did, it would probably be through Ustream which I&#39;ve used for other events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social bookmarks: pinboard.in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in/t:a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3 tag on pinboard&lt;/a&gt; captures bookmarks. Bookmarking is not from this decade, and thus it&#39;s not religiously kept up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Influence: Klout, I guess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only say this because former a2b3 regular Joe Cothrel works at Lithium, which just acquired Klout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantified self: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all about keeping track of what you do (e.g. tracking exercise with a pedometer or a phone) and sharing that with yourself or the world. Several people in the group do this but we haven&#39;t all coalesced on any single platform to share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for March 20, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 16:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The weekly a2b3 lunch met at Madras Masala on this the third Thursday of March. It&#39;s been our habit to meet at Madras on the 1st and 3rd Thursdays. The dining room is large and could seat a large party, but our typical lunch has rarely less than 6 and rarely more than 8 people there, which is just about perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&#39;s tally was 6, which is just barely big enough to justify a formal round of introductions, but we did it anyway. The discussion, minus the introductions, ranged widely from the workings of lathes to the scene at Community High School to the everyday objects that we carry with us each day. I won&#39;t even try to summarize, there was just so much to say that we talked non-stop for 90 minutes and were still chatting at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always the food at Madras was good, and just spicy enough that some people who had been regulars aren&#39;t likely to come because the diet does not agree with them. To this end we are planning a west side visit to Chela&#39;s on March 27, 2014. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch/events/168490202/&#34;&gt;See the details on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;, and hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where should a2b3 eat lunch? Take our poll</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-where-should-a2b3-eat-lunch-take-our-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 14:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-where-should-a2b3-eat-lunch-take-our-poll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take our lunch poll!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#39;http://widget.allourideas.org/a2b3-lunch&#39; width=&#39;550&#39; height=&#39;650&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Meetup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-24-notes-on-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 22:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-24-notes-on-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019aff96dcaa970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019aff96dcaa970b&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34; title=&#34;Logo&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019aff96dcaa970b-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I&#39;ve started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com&#34;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; to organize several groups. Here&#39;s some notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the longest time I&#39;ve used a Yahoo Groups list to organize the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3&lt;/a&gt; group, and that long-lived mailing list continues. It&#39;s great to have a mailing list, but it&#39;s kind of chatty as a lunch-planning-only effort. So the first of my Meetup groups is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/a2b3-lunch&#34;&gt;a2b3 meetup&lt;/a&gt; which is solely devoted to the tasks of providing an events listing and (most importantly) to plan lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brand new Meetup is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/a2civictech&#34;&gt;a2civictech&lt;/a&gt; Ann Arbor Civic Technology meetup, which had its first meeting the other night. This is a more classic meetup, one that tries to meet monthly rather than weekly, one that&#39;s similar to other groups around the country, and one where I&#39;m starting out from the perspective that I mostly don&#39;t know everyone who&#39;s going to be interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetup is a form of civic technology (for the purpose of organizing meetings). For a2civictech, I&#39;ve been able to use the function of annotating the photos from the meeting to remember who was there, and the little discussion forum around the event is just enough to prepare for meetings and remember what happened there. Meetup also allows you to track the input and output of money to the group, so it&#39;s reasonable to track expenses and reimbursement for even little bits of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meetup system isn&#39;t free; a semi-annual fee of $72 applies. So by not being free it gives me the opportunity to have other folks help share in the cost of running things. a2civictech is sponsored in part by &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2geeks.org&#34;&gt;a2geeks&lt;/a&gt; and that&#39;s been a great plus in getting it going. You can also share in the roles of actually organizing things by giving co-conspirators some additional rights to manage things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What strikes me the most is that Meetup is actually designed pretty well to help you successfully organize a meeting. I&#39;m so used to group-forming tools like Yahoo Groups and Google Groups where the goal is to have a discussion online and where the in-person efforts are a very late afterthought. The system comes with a checklist of all of the useful things you can do, and the automated emails for the event planner gently prompt you to do the right thing at the right time. There&#39;s obviously a lot of thought and evolution in this system which is a welcome change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The verdict so far: worthwhile to continue for 6 months, and probably worth renewing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 September 12 2013 meetup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-a2b3-september-12-2013-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 15:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-a2b3-september-12-2013-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-weekly-Thursday-lunch-group/events/138747032/&#34; data-event=&#34;138747032&#34; class=&#34;mu-rsvp-btn&#34;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; now through Meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch at Madras Masala (Maynard St) for a2b3 this week, Thursday from about 11:45 a.m. to about 1:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script&gt;!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s); js.id=id;js.async=true;js.src=&#34;https://secure.meetup.com/3245529744623182445/script/api/mu.btns.js?id=igjj6e5ek67086svhlh1bblo1o&#34;;fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,&#34;script&#34;,&#34;mu-bootjs&#34;);&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual routine is to show up, fill up a plate with yummy food from the buffet, and sit down for discussion. At 12:30pm someone will note the time and then I&#39;ll make a round of introductions and ask a question to prompt conversation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve had as many as 8 people for lunch and as few as 4 at Madras Masala, but the restaurant is flexible and if we were to get a huge crowd there&#39;s space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 chime</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-a2b3-chime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-a2b3-chime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chime from the a2b3 weekly lunch meetings, as captured by Roger Rayle at Eastern Accents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F97501588&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Slow-moving-version-of-twitter&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c-600wi&#34; alt=&#34;Slow-moving-version-of-twitter&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bright idea? Write it down, photograph it, transcribe it, then (and only then) post to the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s OK to wait quite a long time between initial idea and eventual posting. This also works for blog postings, or at least it should. Twitter happens to make it easy to do in one step for short posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will lunch work on Thursday at a new place? (A2B3 lost its regular restaurant, Eastern Accents, and we&#39;re meeting at Conor O&#39;Neill&#39;s instead.) Caroline is manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you want to have stored up so that you can respond quickly to something new after having already thought through it at leisure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is the drawing? (Very.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you focus on something long enough to make it worthwhile to construct a lengthy effort to assemble media to support it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marginalia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Grant&#39;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.giveandtake.com/Home/AdamGrant&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Give and Take&lt;/a&gt;. Jerry Davis is interviewed. Look in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/magazine/is-giving-the-secret-to-getting-ahead.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;March 31 NY Times Magazine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest it at the Ann Arbor District Library once I get online. It&#39;s too hard to fill out the suggestion form from my teeny tiny phone screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry Michalski suggesting a similar piece on &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2012/10/plodding-and-bursting/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;bursting vs plodding&lt;/a&gt;&#34; and the benefits of each, written by Steve Pavlina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m listening to electronica by Valdis Krebs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F85186702&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterword&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I think Buddha is one line of work.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastern Accents is closing for good on March 16, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 13:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR (Monday, February 18, 2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mj9WSvmepDjNQxMvcNfznJjRBjFzlCS9J8jTHQrDi60/edit&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;news release&lt;/a&gt; from Carol Sun of Eastern Accents.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.43474730011075735&#34;&gt;Eastern Accents will be closing its doors for good at 7:00 p.m. on Saturday, March 16, 2013 (end of the day). &amp;#0160;A long-simmering dispute with our landlord has finally come to a head, and we’ve decided that it is time for change.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feel free to help spread the word. &amp;#0160;We want to get the word out--especially to anyone who might have gift card values to redeem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;for the years of support (if you recall, you were in the picture that appeared in the first article on Eastern Accents!) and the networking that you do that benefits Eastern Accents.&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2B3 will continue on Thursdays until the March 14, 2013 lunch, and then we&amp;#39;ll go into exile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 meeting non-summary for Thursday, January 24, 2013 at Eastern Accents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 09:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bunch of folks met for lunch on Thursday. Here&amp;#39;s some notes from that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked people how they stayed warm. They dress in layers, use solar thermal heating, wear sweaters, wear hats, huddle under electric blankets, and all manner of good adaptive Michigan behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some events coming up, each of which features some a2b3 group member. Some details elided in the interests of brevity, click to links for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already happened: Linda Diane Feldt spoke at Crazy Wisdom about the liver. &amp;quot;The liver is the largest and most critical organ for detoxifying the blood, moving lymph, and processing food and storing nutrients. I&amp;#39;m in awe of how well it functions, and how much it does.&amp;quot; About 18 people were at the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night 1/24/13 is David Bloom and Friends playing lounge-jazz standards at Chelsea&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Back to the Roots&amp;quot; cafe, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/188090337997019/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;details on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday 1/31/13 2-8p at Burton Manor in Livonia is ACE &amp;#39;13, the Annual Collaboration for Entrepreneurs. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ace-event.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Details on their web site&lt;/a&gt;; volunteer opportunities are available which I&amp;#39;m happy to help you track down if you&amp;#39;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 2/16/13 10a-noon at Eastern Accents is the 4th Death Cafe, led by Merilynne Rush. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deathcafe.com/2013/01/3rd-ann-arbor-death-cafe.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Notes on the 3d meeting are here&lt;/a&gt; with contact info and more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday 2/27/13 from 7pm to 8:30pm in the Multi-Purpose Room is Dan Romanchik about how to self-publish e-books, based on his experience with writing books on amateur radio. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=17403&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Event details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for coming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for January 10, 2013; Michigan Terminal System, miniaturized</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-10-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-january-10-2013-michigan-terminal-system-miniaturized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 16:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-10-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-january-10-2013-michigan-terminal-system-miniaturized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I organize lunch every week on Thursdays at Eastern Accents in downtown Ann Arbor. About 400 people get some kind of invitation, and attendance varies from 6 to 25+. (One week we filled the restaurant, which was just a little bit scary.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;#39;s crowd was good - I counted 18 seats - and the question of the week was asking people to talk about the job they had in college. The answers ranged from selling pots and pans door to door to selling ice cream in Manhattan to running a student bus company to programming PDP-8 computers. One person was there who was in college now and he talked about his startup that connects bands with bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology of the week was the notice that &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/michiganterminalsystem/discussions/mts-today/6mtsrunningonaraspberrypi&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;the Michigan Terminal System has been made to work on the ultra-small Raspberry Pi system&lt;/a&gt;. A photo shows the setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee732726c970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;MTS_screen&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee732726c970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee732726c970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;MTS_screen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c358f1743970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;RaspberryPi&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c358f1743970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017c358f1743970b-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;RaspberryPi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing an event that happens every week is easy, especially when the venue is open. All you have to do is show up every single week, invite anyone you can find, and make sure that if someone arrives twice that you remember their name. It helps if you happen to be part of a community where people have learned to communicate online for a long time, and where the online community and the in-person community dovetail nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>