<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary at Blue Nile for 30 July 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-30-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary/</guid>
      <description>Nice lunch today at the Blue Nile. We had 10 people for lunch, including two people (Azita Azadi and Tom Meloche) who had moved back to town from far away. I had the vegetarian plate which was delicious (love me some injera).
The question of the day was regarding postcards, something I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about quite a bit. With a modest (but still too big) amount of effort I can launch a postcard from the command line of my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>Eight of us met for lunch at Ayse&amp;rsquo;s today. It was a normal Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for the lunch group these days.
We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make sure that the things that needed to get done got done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>A nice lunch at Argus Farm Stop. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from Harnois Farm, and we had 9 at the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>from a2b3 this week at Ayse&#39;s Courtyard Cafe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 20:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</guid>
      <description>he’s ed @vielmetti. he organizes lunch. pic.twitter.com/wUAWmeGgcX
&amp;mdash; peter honeyman (@peterhoneyman) October 23, 2014</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 years of professionals eating lunch together on a regular basis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 07:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up a piece about how you might rewrite your resume to provide a &#34;retcon&#34; (&#34;retroactive continuity&#34;) treatment, which emphasizes reinterpreting past events in such a way that they look like part of a story with a narrative arc.
That got me to thinking about lunch, of course, and the little hoary old story I tell about when the a2b3 group started &#34;8 years ago&#34;. And I realize now that I can trace back continuity way longer than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2014 Conversation Prism seen through the eyes of the a2b3 lunch</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-30-the-2014-conversation-prism-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 14:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-30-the-2014-conversation-prism-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</guid>
      <description>Developed in 2008 by Brian Solis, The [Conversation Prism] is a visual map of the social media landscape. It’s an ongoing study in digital ethnography that tracks dominant and promising social networks and organizes them by how they’re used in everyday life.
In 2009, I wrote up how the a2b3 lunch organizes itself through the eye of the this system. I ran across it again, and decided to do a repeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for March 20, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 16:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</guid>
      <description>The weekly a2b3 lunch met at Madras Masala on this the third Thursday of March. It&#39;s been our habit to meet at Madras on the 1st and 3rd Thursdays. The dining room is large and could seat a large party, but our typical lunch has rarely less than 6 and rarely more than 8 people there, which is just about perfect.
This week&#39;s tally was 6, which is just barely big enough to justify a formal round of introductions, but we did it anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where should a2b3 eat lunch? Take our poll</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-where-should-a2b3-eat-lunch-take-our-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 14:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-03-where-should-a2b3-eat-lunch-take-our-poll/</guid>
      <description>Take our lunch poll!
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Meetup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-24-notes-on-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 22:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-24-notes-on-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve started using Meetup.com to organize several groups. Here&#39;s some notes.
For the longest time I&#39;ve used a Yahoo Groups list to organize the a2b3 group, and that long-lived mailing list continues. It&#39;s great to have a mailing list, but it&#39;s kind of chatty as a lunch-planning-only effort. So the first of my Meetup groups is the a2b3 meetup which is solely devoted to the tasks of providing an events listing and (most importantly) to plan lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 September 12 2013 meetup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-a2b3-september-12-2013-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 15:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-11-a2b3-september-12-2013-meetup/</guid>
      <description>RSVP now through Meetup.
Lunch at Madras Masala (Maynard St) for a2b3 this week, Thursday from about 11:45 a.m. to about 1:00 p.m.
!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s); js.id=id;js.async=true;js.src=&#34;https://secure.meetup.com/3245529744623182445/script/api/mu.btns.js?id=igjj6e5ek67086svhlh1bblo1o&#34;;fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,&#34;script&#34;,&#34;mu-bootjs&#34;); The usual routine is to show up, fill up a plate with yummy food from the buffet, and sit down for discussion. At 12:30pm someone will note the time and then I&#39;ll make a round of introductions and ask a question to prompt conversation. We&#39;ve had as many as 8 people for lunch and as few as 4 at Madras Masala, but the restaurant is flexible and if we were to get a huge crowd there&#39;s space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 chime</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-a2b3-chime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-a2b3-chime/</guid>
      <description>The chime from the a2b3 weekly lunch meetings, as captured by Roger Rayle at Eastern Accents.
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</guid>
      <description>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.

Bright idea? Write it down, photograph it, transcribe it, then (and only then) post to the network.
It&#39;s OK to wait quite a long time between initial idea and eventual posting. This also works for blog postings, or at least it should. Twitter happens to make it easy to do in one step for short posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastern Accents is closing for good on March 16, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 13:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-02-18-eastern-accents-is-closing-for-good-on-march-16-2013/</guid>
      <description>ANN ARBOR (Monday, February 18, 2013)
From a news release from Carol Sun of Eastern Accents.&amp;#0160;
Eastern Accents will be closing its doors for good at 7:00 p.m. on Saturday, March 16, 2013 (end of the day). &amp;#0160;A long-simmering dispute with our landlord has finally come to a head, and we’ve decided that it is time for change.
Carol writes:
Feel free to help spread the word. &amp;#0160;We want to get the word out--especially to anyone who might have gift card values to redeem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 meeting non-summary for Thursday, January 24, 2013 at Eastern Accents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 09:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</guid>
      <description>A bunch of folks met for lunch on Thursday. Here&amp;#39;s some notes from that meeting.
I asked people how they stayed warm. They dress in layers, use solar thermal heating, wear sweaters, wear hats, huddle under electric blankets, and all manner of good adaptive Michigan behavior.
Some events coming up, each of which features some a2b3 group member. Some details elided in the interests of brevity, click to links for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for November 29, 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-30-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-29-2012-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-30-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-29-2012-/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Patricia F. Anderson for this non-summary of the November 29, 2012 A2B3 lunch at Eastern Accents.&amp;#0160;
Hi, folk!
Yesterday saw a decent sized group for lunch, roughly a dozen.&amp;#0160;Conversation was, as usual, fascinating and diverse.
General conversation included the search for a proper formalmythological &amp;quot;Muse&amp;quot; or Goddess as a kind of patron saint of geeks and&amp;#0160;code monkeys. A suggestion was Seshat, the Egyptian goddess of
measurement, mathematics, and librarianship, known for her&amp;#0160;seven-pointed headdress and leopardskin dress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th week of March 2012</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-week-of-march-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 06:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-03-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-week-of-march-2012/</guid>
      <description>Name check!
Thanks to +Gyll Stanford, +Steven W. Cornell,&amp;#0160;+Joel Vergun&amp;#0160;,&amp;#0160;+Patrick Haggood&amp;#0160;,&amp;#0160;+Dan Romanchik&amp;#0160;, +Linda Diane Feldt, +John Hritz,&amp;#0160;+Roger Rayle&amp;#0160;, +Dan Friedus, and +Brian Rice who made for good conversation at lunch last Thursday.
In no particular order, we talked about the +a2b3 Amateur Radio Club (with Dan Romanchik as the likely point of contact), since we had a couple of people who were online listening to +Skywarn for the last tornado. There was also good discussion of fruit trees and the impact of unseasonable weather on the fruit crops, and at my end of the table some neat talk about underground clay irrigation systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 meeting non-summary, June 2, 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-02-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-june-2-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 16:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-02-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-june-2-2011/</guid>
      <description>The a2b3 group met at Eastern Accents this Thursday, June 2, 2011. Here&amp;#39;s a summary of sorts.
I took notes in a quadrille notebook   for the meeting, as an exercise in trying to keep better track of what was happening. The book is similar to what became popular on the University of Michigan campus during the 1980s, when university president and nuclear engineer James Duderstadt would bring quad notebooks to meetings, and everyone else followed suit quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you measure success?  Assessing 5 years of a2b3 lunch</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-15-how-do-you-measure-successthats-a-question-i-often-pose-at-the-beginning-of-projects-and-one-that-i-struggle-with-often-whe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-15-how-do-you-measure-successthats-a-question-i-often-pose-at-the-beginning-of-projects-and-one-that-i-struggle-with-often-whe/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;#39;s a question I often pose at the beginning of projects, and one that I struggle with often when there is no simple answer.&amp;#0160; Some reflection has me thinking it might be too simple a question to pose when goals are complex and long term and emergent.
I&amp;#39;ll illustrate with a project that by some multiple measures has been successful so far, my weekly lunch meeting called a2b3.&amp;#0160; Every week we gather for lunch, people eat, they talk, they leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 logo</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-a2b3-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 21:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-05-a2b3-logo/</guid>
      <description>for reference:
The A2B3 logo design is by Laura Fisher of Mitten Artworks.
The font is P22&amp;#39;s London Underground. &amp;#0160;Accept no substitutes.
The stickers I printed were printed at VG Kids&amp;#0160;in Ypsilanti. &amp;#0160;We used a&amp;#0160;2.75&amp;quot; x 4.25&amp;quot; oval, and one of their standard templates.
The hoodie with the top secret illuminati lining is still under construction.
Update 6/13/10: Typekit has the P22 London Underground font, for $25/yr. &amp;#0160;Hmm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for Thursday, Feb. 11, 2010</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-11-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-feb-11-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-11-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-feb-11-2010/</guid>
      <description>Attendance: 19. I had the udon noodles, which are new on the menu at Eastern Accents and quite good.
My list of things to note from the day includes, but is not limited to:  Google&#39;s proposed fiber to the home project, and how to get it to Ann Arbor Susan Crawford is back in Ann Arbor from a stint in DC and teaching cyber law I&#39;m not sure that I wouldn&#39;t rather have a Droid phone than a Blackberry There is a super-nifty Droid app which is an exercise tracker w/maps Searching for low RPM motors that run on 2 AA batteries Next Tues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 Thursday lunch meeting ritual introduction as Ignite talk</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-10-a2b3-thursday-lunch-meeting-ritual-introduction-as-ignite-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 22:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-10-a2b3-thursday-lunch-meeting-ritual-introduction-as-ignite-talk/</guid>
      <description>I put in an application for Ignite 3 Ann Arbor. 5 minutes, 20 slides. The working structure for the talk is the 5 minute or so talk I give at the beginning of every a2b3 meeting, with the little ritual introduction of the group and the origin story and the monologue. I think it will work out; heaven knows that I&#39;ve had some practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for Thursday, July 16, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-16-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-july-16-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 23:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-16-a2b3-nonsummary-for-thursday-july-16-2009/</guid>
      <description>Every Thursday I organize lunch, come hell, high water, or Art Fair. &amp;#0160;This time it was Art Fair.
 Eastern Accents takes a vacation in the summer time so I was on my own to organize something somewhere else; and all of Ann Arbor is full of Art Fair food vendors, serving a wide range of cuisine ranging from elephant ears and funnel cakes to key lime limeade and coffee. &amp;#0160;(Water, $1 almost everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary, day 8</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 14:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-09-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-day-8/</guid>
      <description>day 8 of notes on my new job at annarbor.com
Almost every week for the last 4 years I&amp;#39;ve been organizing a Thursday lunch.&amp;#0160; It started with 4 people, and the mailing list now has almost 400; our record attendance at lunch was 41 but the typical table size is much like today, with 22 people sitting around a long table plus one person who came late sitting by themselves.&amp;#0160; As with any mostly-open lunch series, you get to know people bit by bit over time, and some people take a few weeks to gain the confidence to describe who they are to a group of strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@a2b3 non-summary for July 2, 2009: how to introduce lots of people; day 4</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-a2b3-nonsummary-for-july-2-2009-how-to-introduce-lots-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-03-a2b3-nonsummary-for-july-2-2009-how-to-introduce-lots-of-people/</guid>
      <description>Not a summary of what was said, but more of some observations on process.
Lunch was incredibly full today - we had upwards of 30, filled one entire side of the restaurant plus a second table of four.&amp;#0160; And becuase I asked a question that allowed a long answer, it took a full hour to get through everyone, and some people left early.
In some sense that&amp;#39;s OK, if you believe in the open space &amp;quot;law of two feet&amp;quot;, and if you think that whoever shows up are the right people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;the conversation prism&#34; as seen through the eyes of the a2b3 lunch</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-27-the-conversation-prism-as-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 14:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-27-the-conversation-prism-as-seen-through-the-eyes-of-the-a2b3-lunch/</guid>
      <description>Today is a Twitter conference, so Twitter is full of good stuff people have been saving up.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s one: a &amp;quot;conversation prism&amp;quot; in bright happy colors showing a set of categories of tools, and how each one of them is occupied by some set of applications.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s a mapping of each of them onto the set of tools that I am using to keep a2b3 loosely connected.&amp;#0160; Sorry no links, didn&amp;#39;t have time to hyperlink everything</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for 22 May 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-22-a2b3-nonsummary-for-22-may-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-22-a2b3-nonsummary-for-22-may-2009/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday May 22 I had lunch with the a2b3 group for the 183d time.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m writing that down as though it was a perfectly accurate number, just so that next week I can look it up and say that it will be the 184th time.
Every week I host lunch on Thursdays at Eastern Accents in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; People start showing up at 11:30 or so, most everyone has ordered and sat down and pulled up however many tables we need by noon, and at 12:30 someone bangs on a glass and I stand up and give roughly this presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizations that don&#39;t exist yet, but should</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-13-organizations-that-dont-exist-yet-but-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 00:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-13-organizations-that-dont-exist-yet-but-should/</guid>
      <description>National Association of Professional Lunch Organizers.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; For people who organize civic, professional, and industry meetings at lunchtime.&amp;#0160; Publishes a national directory of meeting times and locations organized by day of the week, and a guide to the tax laws on entertainment expenses with a handy records filing system for the lunch professional.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; Their for-profit software development spinoff, NAPLOsoft, produces mobile phone applications with customized daily alerts for travelers for professional lunch opportunities wherever they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>community organizer&#39;s checklist: weekly lunch meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 11:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</guid>
      <description>A checklist of things to do for the weekly lunch.
1.&amp;#0160; Day of the week: Mo - Tu - We - Th - Fri
2.&amp;#0160; Frequency: Every - First - Second - Third - Fourth - Last - Even - Odd
3.&amp;#0160; Location: Fixed (Eastern Accents) - Floating - Alternate (Ypsilanti TBD)
4.&amp;#0160; Holiday schedule: Skip - Alternate Day (Weds or Fri) - Alternate Week 5.&amp;#0160; Summer schedule: Skip - Alternate Time - Alternate Location (Ypsilanti TBD)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 anticipatory non-summary for November 13, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-11-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-13-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-11-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-13-2008/</guid>
      <description>(graphic float left) a2b3 is a [noun phrase] organization that meets [frequency] for [meal] at [location] in [city]. &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; It started in [year] and is modelled on [well known organization], which first started in [previous century] to provide [noble goal] for its [notable participants].&amp;#0160; This week&amp;#39;s a2b3 meeting [future perfect tense] held&amp;#0160; on Thursday, [date], [number] days [relative time] to [notable event].&amp;#0160; I had [meal description], which was delicious.&amp;#0160; The soup of the day was [soup name] (link to soup recipe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for November 6, 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-06-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-6-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-06-a2b3-non-summary-for-november-6-2008/</guid>
      <description>The weekly a2b3 meeting was held at Eastern Accents on Thursday, November 6, 2008, two days after the election of Barack Obama as the new President of the United States.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; I had ... and ..., which was delicious.&amp;#0160; The soup of the day was ...
There were ... people in attendance, a turnout (helped, hurted) in part by a (rare) promotion of the event on Facebook.&amp;#0160; Facebook doesn&amp;#39;t have a repeating event structure, so to do this regularly I&amp;#39;d have to type it in every week; perhaps it&amp;#39;s worth that, perhaps not, I don&amp;#39;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is a2b3?  genotypes, unicode characters, and lunch meetings</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-23-what-is-a2b3-ge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 12:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-23-what-is-a2b3-ge/</guid>
      <description>every once in a while you have to look at the net to see what other people say that you are. so here&#39;s that search for a2b3.
First, all the things that don&#39;t relate to the lunch meeting:
A2B3 is a rare genotype resulting from the inheritance of both A and B genes on one chromosome.
The p16INK4a tumour suppressor protein inhibits a2b3 integrin-mediated cell spreading on vitronectin by blocking PKC-dependent localization of a2b3 to focal contacts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 non-summary for 17 April 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-17-a2b3-non-summar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 14:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-17-a2b3-non-summar/</guid>
      <description>26 people for lunch today, plus 3 who weren&#39;t at the introductions. Thanks to everyone for coming.
I&#39;m resuming a previous effort to do post-event &#34;non-summaries&#34;, just a few words about what everyone was up to. Even a non-summary with links takes a little time.
Helene Gidley is organizing an Agile Groupies meeting Apr 30 5-7pm at Spark. (UPDATED)
Phil Barr has a new job at Thomson Healthcare.
Spencer Thomas has photos up at Sweetwaters from Festifools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>