<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2b3 on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2b3 on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/a2b3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch at Ayse&#39;s, Art Fair 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 11:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-16-a2b3-lunch-at-ayses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight of us met for lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://aysesturkishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Ayse&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; today. It was a normal
Thursday in that regard, as that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty typical size for
the lunch group these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked at question time about how we get big chunks of time
to work on projects. One answer was to work early in the morning
or late at night when there were fewer distractions. Gyll, a
remodeling contractor, mentioned the use of checklists to make
sure that the things that needed to get done got done. Among the
tasks that took up lots more time than they deserved included
dealing with the health insurance marketplace and with other
healthcare providers for dealing with billing and accounting problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the people at lunch were new to the table, but since Ann
Arbor is bascially a small town, it was not a surprise to me that
I had easily identifiable mutual friends with two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was delicious, well prepared and well presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll be back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Madras_Masala&#34;&gt;Madras Masala&lt;/a&gt;, as art fair will have
ended and town will be more back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big event coming up is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makerfairedetroit.com/&#34;&gt;Maker Faire Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, to be held at The
Henry Ford in Dearborn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for 4th Thursday of April at Argus Farm Stop</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 03:59:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-25-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-4th-thursday-of-april-at-argus-farm-stop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice lunch at &lt;a href=&#34;http://argusfarmstop.com&#34;&gt;Argus Farm Stop&lt;/a&gt;. I bought bread for the table, John Harnois supplied hard-boiled duck eggs from &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/ann-arbor/Harnois_Farm&#34;&gt;Harnois Farm&lt;/a&gt;, and we had 9 at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>from a2b3 this week at Ayse&#39;s Courtyard Cafe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 20:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-24-from-a2b3-this-week-at-ayses-courtyard-cafe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;he’s ed &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt;. he organizes lunch. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/wUAWmeGgcX&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/wUAWmeGgcX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; peter honeyman (@peterhoneyman) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/peterhoneyman/status/525316870463684608&#34;&gt;October 23, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 years of professionals eating lunch together on a regular basis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 07:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-25-years-of-professionals-eating-lunch-together-on-a-regular-basis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote up a piece about how you might rewrite your resume to provide a &#34;retcon&#34; (&#34;retroactive continuity&#34;) treatment, which emphasizes reinterpreting past events in such a way that they look like part of a story with a narrative arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me to thinking about lunch, of course, and the little hoary old story I tell about when the a2b3 group started &#34;8 years ago&#34;. And I realize now that I can trace back continuity way longer than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, when Sun 3/50s roamed the earth, I worked at OTA Limited Partnership as a systems guy. The company traded options, and I was a junior part of the ops team that kept the trading systems running. I wrote some code, I did some sysadmin work, I debugged flaky Proteon routers, I made sure we had a Usenet newsfeed. Life was pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market was open every hour that lunch was served, so it didn&#39;t really ever make sense to leave the building during trading hours. That mean that lunch was brought in for everyone every single day. We had an elaborate scoring system where instead of you always buying lunch for yourself, you&#39;d buy lunch for the team, and you&#39;d get tally marks on the board to make sure that you properly were credited plus or minus depending on the number of lunches you bought. The bookshelves had a big thick binder full of menus, and we had some favorites. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my first real experience with professionals eating lunch together on a routine basis, and I&#39;m still friends with the OTA crew, long after the last tally mark was erased. That dates to 1989 or so, which means I&#39;ve been eating lunch as a grownup for about 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize now that if I were ever to get a real job again, one of my interview questions would have to be &#34;what do you do for lunch around here&#34;. If the answer is wrong, I can&#39;t take the job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to David Bloom for prodding me to tell more of a back story, and to my former daily lunch companions at OTA (including specifically John Hritz who is an a2b3 regular) for initiation into a professional lunch ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re invited for lunch at Bell&#39;s Diner on Thursday 9/11. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch&#34;&gt;a2b3 weekly lunch meetup group&lt;/a&gt; will let you say yes or no; if you&#39;re not coming, I&#39;ll still see your smiling face in the app, and it would be good to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thanks again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for March 20, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 16:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-a2b3-lunch-non-summary-for-march-20-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The weekly a2b3 lunch met at Madras Masala on this the third Thursday of March. It&#39;s been our habit to meet at Madras on the 1st and 3rd Thursdays. The dining room is large and could seat a large party, but our typical lunch has rarely less than 6 and rarely more than 8 people there, which is just about perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&#39;s tally was 6, which is just barely big enough to justify a formal round of introductions, but we did it anyway. The discussion, minus the introductions, ranged widely from the workings of lathes to the scene at Community High School to the everyday objects that we carry with us each day. I won&#39;t even try to summarize, there was just so much to say that we talked non-stop for 90 minutes and were still chatting at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always the food at Madras was good, and just spicy enough that some people who had been regulars aren&#39;t likely to come because the diet does not agree with them. To this end we are planning a west side visit to Chela&#39;s on March 27, 2014. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/a2b3-lunch/events/168490202/&#34;&gt;See the details on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;, and hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 meeting non-summary for Thursday, January 24, 2013 at Eastern Accents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 09:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-25-a2b3-meeting-non-summary-for-thursday-january-24-2013-at-eastern-accents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bunch of folks met for lunch on Thursday. Here&amp;#39;s some notes from that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked people how they stayed warm. They dress in layers, use solar thermal heating, wear sweaters, wear hats, huddle under electric blankets, and all manner of good adaptive Michigan behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some events coming up, each of which features some a2b3 group member. Some details elided in the interests of brevity, click to links for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already happened: Linda Diane Feldt spoke at Crazy Wisdom about the liver. &amp;quot;The liver is the largest and most critical organ for detoxifying the blood, moving lymph, and processing food and storing nutrients. I&amp;#39;m in awe of how well it functions, and how much it does.&amp;quot; About 18 people were at the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night 1/24/13 is David Bloom and Friends playing lounge-jazz standards at Chelsea&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Back to the Roots&amp;quot; cafe, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/188090337997019/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;details on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday 1/31/13 2-8p at Burton Manor in Livonia is ACE &amp;#39;13, the Annual Collaboration for Entrepreneurs. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ace-event.org/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Details on their web site&lt;/a&gt;; volunteer opportunities are available which I&amp;#39;m happy to help you track down if you&amp;#39;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 2/16/13 10a-noon at Eastern Accents is the 4th Death Cafe, led by Merilynne Rush. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deathcafe.com/2013/01/3rd-ann-arbor-death-cafe.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Notes on the 3d meeting are here&lt;/a&gt; with contact info and more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday 2/27/13 from 7pm to 8:30pm in the Multi-Purpose Room is Dan Romanchik about how to self-publish e-books, based on his experience with writing books on amateur radio. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/events/list?id=17403&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Event details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for coming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>