<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeroen Janssens on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jeroen-janssens/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeroen Janssens on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 16:19:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jeroen-janssens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R, me hearties</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-28-r-me-hearties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 16:19:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-02-28-r-me-hearties/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been fond of maps and graphs for a long time, but haven&#39;t had a good set of tools to play with that easily generate decent versions of same from various data sets I&#39;ve found or accumulated.
The small hope is that a little bit of hacking on the right tools will fix this.
One of the tools of choice is R, a language for statistics and data analysis. It&#39;s tremendously powerful and a bit complicated, but I&#39;m not trying to learn the whole thing; rather, I&#39;m after just the barest minimum so that I can competently generate a scatterplot of data and place it onto a map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using &#34;jq&#34; for command line web applications for civic data</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-using-jq-for-command-line-web-applications-for-civic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 09:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-05-using-jq-for-command-line-web-applications-for-civic-data/</guid>
      <description>One of the tools that I rediscovered and have been really happy for having done so is &amp;ldquo;jq&amp;rdquo;, a command line tool that bills itself as &amp;ldquo;awk for json&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing awk code since 1985, and some limited subset of it is something that I know really, really well. awk, however, is from the punchcard era, and as such it likes to deal with records that are all on one line each.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>