<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Building Board Of Appeals on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/building-board-of-appeals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Building Board Of Appeals on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 09:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/building-board-of-appeals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2016 Ann Arbor Building Board of Appeals lacks a quorum</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-building-board-of-appeals-lacks-quorum-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-building-board-of-appeals-lacks-quorum-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor Building Board of Appeals will not meet today, January
13, 2016, for lack of a quorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to know the following to help understand more about this group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is on the board, and how long have they been on it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have there been any recent changes to board membership?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is eligible to be appointed to the board, and what does that process entail?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to decisions that the board needs to make if a quorum cannot be met?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the status of the search for a full-time building official?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When does the board next anticipate meeting with a quorum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who has been nominated to serve on this board?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why did the board not make quorum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com/MeetingDetail.aspx?ID=452565&amp;amp;GUID=F55A2A53-26AB-404B-9A59-8A9FCD92EE39&amp;amp;Options=info&amp;amp;Search=&#34;&gt;agenda for the meeting&lt;/a&gt; has been
posted, which gives you an idea of what is not being done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 325 W Liberty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 215 N Maple&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Variance Application for 121 W Kingsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Show Cause Hearing for 2001 Commerce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBA Show Cause Hearing for 111 S Main St&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last of these, 111 S Main St, is a building on the city&amp;rsquo;s
Dangerous Buildings list right on Main Street. The building
has a tree growing out of the roof, spongy floors due to water
infiltration, and mold everywhere according to the building
inspector&amp;rsquo;s report. The unavailability of the Building Board
means that the owner of 111 S Main doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to face a
public hearing for another month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>