<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rice on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/rice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rice on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/rice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta For the rice: prepare 1.5 cups rice according to your taste. Do this first.
For the broccoli: Preheat oven to 425 degrees F. Cut a few heads of broccoli into bite sized florets. Mix in a bowl with olive oil, then place on a cookie sheet. Sprinkle sea salt on top. Roast 12-15 minutes until the broccoli is every so slightly browned on top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kedgeree, or something quite similar to it</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-20-kedgeree-or-something-quite-similar-to-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 14:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-20-kedgeree-or-something-quite-similar-to-it/</guid>
      <description>I cooked this recipe - inspired by the recipes I found for Kedgeree - last night. I don&amp;#39;t know what all of the boundaries are for an authentic recipe for this dish, which appears to have enough variety in the various descriptions of it that nearly anything with fish flaked into rice and spiced with Indian spices could be close.
 2 cups rice cooked in 4 cups water safflower oil; some recipes call for ghee 1 onion, chopped small; garlic if you like it spices: curry powder, mustard seed, and similar vegetables: chopped tomatoes, peas, etc 2 tablespoons lemon juice salt, pepper fish: cooked or canned fish, fresh or smoked; we used canned boneless salmon greens: minced parsley or cilantro; dried OK in a pinch hard boiled eggs for garnish  The method runs roughly as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed peppers with leftover grains recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-28-stuffed-peppers-with-leftover-grains-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 23:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-28-stuffed-peppers-with-leftover-grains-recipe/</guid>
      <description>The basic idea is from Martha Rose &amp;quot;Fast Vegetarian Feasts&amp;quot; 1986, p. 103.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s very simple, as befits her normal cooking.&amp;#0160; Cut the tops from peppers, clean them out, fill with a mix of leftover rice and beans and top with cheese.&amp;#0160; Bake 30 to 40 minutes, as long as it takes for things to get as soft as you want.
I&amp;#39;m guessing I&amp;#39;ll end up using black beans; there&amp;#39;s rice from yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>