<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rice on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/rice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rice on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/rice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kedgeree, or something quite similar to it</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-20-kedgeree-or-something-quite-similar-to-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 14:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-20-kedgeree-or-something-quite-similar-to-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I cooked this recipe - inspired by the recipes I found for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kedgeree&#34; rel=&#34;wikipedia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Kedgeree&#34;&gt;Kedgeree&lt;/a&gt; - last night. I don&amp;#39;t know what all of the boundaries are for an authentic recipe for this dish, which appears to have enough variety in the various descriptions of it that nearly anything with fish flaked into rice and spiced with Indian spices could be close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups rice cooked in 4 cups water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;safflower oil; some recipes call for ghee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped small; garlic if you like it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spices: curry powder, mustard seed, and similar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vegetables: chopped tomatoes, peas, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt, pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fish: cooked or canned fish, fresh or smoked; we used canned boneless salmon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greens: minced parsley or cilantro; dried OK in a pinch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard boiled eggs for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method runs roughly as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cook the rice first; if you happen to have enough leftover rice, you can use that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat the oil in a large pan, and saute the onion (and possibly garlic) for 3-5 minutes until soft. Add the spices which will give the onions a wonderful color and smell when thoroughly mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix in the vegetables so that they are heated through or cooked; again, suitably prepared leftovers would work here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the rice to the onion mixture, stirring well. Add lemon juice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flake the fish and mix in with the rice. Mix in chopped parsley or cilantro. Stir well, and transfer to a serving dish. Garnish with hard boiled eggs if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- end -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some deviations from this basic approach are useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jamieoliver.com/recipes/fish-recipes/kedgeree&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jamie Oliver&amp;#39;s kedgeree recipe&lt;/a&gt; is what I started from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://becksposhnosh.blogspot.com/2004/10/kedgeree.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Becks and Posh kedgeree recipe&lt;/a&gt; has cardamom and saffron as spices, and lemon wedges and toasted almonds as garnish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greatbritishkitchen.co.uk/recipebook/index.php?option=com_rapidrecipe&amp;amp;page=viewrecipe&amp;amp;recipe_id=592&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Great British Food Trust kedgeree recipe&lt;/a&gt; is very simple, but it notes that cumin seeds and lentils are optional extras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-13-recipe-roasted-broccoli-salad-with-rice-and-feta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Roasted broccoli salad with rice and feta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rice: prepare 1.5 cups rice according to your taste. Do this first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the broccoli: Preheat oven to 425 degrees F. Cut a few heads of broccoli into bite sized florets. Mix in a bowl with olive oil, then place on a cookie sheet. Sprinkle sea salt on top. Roast 12-15 minutes until the broccoli is every so slightly browned on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the garbanzos: Drain and rinse a can of garbanzos. Put in a small pot and cover with water. Heat until hot, then rinse again under cool water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the red peppers: Cut a red pepper into pieces about the size of a garbanzo bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Make a lemon vinaigrette with a little mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dressing: Some sweet chili paste, or gochujang, or your favorite spicy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the feta: crumble some feta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve in individual bowls on the table, for people to mix their own salads. If your family is like mine, someone will eat just rice and peppers and beans, someone else will prefer the salad without feta, someone will want a vinaigrette and someone else (me) will douse the whole thing with chili sauce. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed peppers with leftover grains recipe</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-28-stuffed-peppers-with-leftover-grains-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 23:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-28-stuffed-peppers-with-leftover-grains-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is from Martha Rose &amp;quot;Fast Vegetarian Feasts&amp;quot; 1986, p. 103.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s very simple, as befits her normal cooking.&amp;#0160; Cut the tops from peppers, clean them out, fill with a mix of leftover rice and beans and top with cheese.&amp;#0160; Bake 30 to 40 minutes, as long as it takes for things to get as soft as you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m guessing I&amp;#39;ll end up using black beans; there&amp;#39;s rice from yesterday.&amp;#0160; We have an abundance of tomatoes from market, since it&amp;#39;s the season when you order a half a peck they are SO HAPPY that someone wants their roma tomatoes in quantity that you end up with an extra pint of cherry tomatoes just to taste.&amp;#0160; The 4 y/o will want the beans plain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cook all the peppers in the fridge, there will be more on Saturday. The freeze watch line is as far south as Gaylord, so we should be good for a few more weeks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;asset asset-image&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a5a6dc58970b-pi&#34; style=&#34;display: inline;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Frz_plt-Sep-28&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a5a6dc58970b image-full &#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0120a5a6dc58970b-800wi&#34; title=&#34;Frz_plt-Sep-28&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>