<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elections on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/elections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elections on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 14:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/maps/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 election prediction maps</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-03-2012-election-prediction-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 14:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-03-2012-election-prediction-maps/</guid>
      <description>From Nate Silver&amp;#39;s NY Times weblog FiveThirtyEight, captured Saturday, November 3, 2012:
 
The Los Angeles Times electoral map, again a prediction from Saturday. Note that this analysis doesn&amp;#39;t give exact numerical predictions. The Chicago Tribune links to the same map.
 
&amp;#0160;
The Detroit Free Press runs with&amp;#0160;a map from Real Clear Politics:
The Australian Broadcasting Company (ABC) interactive map, showing toss-up states in orange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Election Maps: Wayne Baker on metaphors of color in Mark Newman&#39;s cartograms</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-2008-election-maps-wayne-baker-on-metaphors-of-color-in-mark-newmans-cartograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-15-2008-election-maps-wayne-baker-on-metaphors-of-color-in-mark-newmans-cartograms/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;ve seen lots of electoral maps, with the US colored various shades of red, blue, or purple. The simplest ones just colorize the map; the most complex distort the map and refine the color space to show various aspects of the population, its voting patterns and changes over time. Jason Kottke has a good collection of 2008 election maps from all over the world, showing mostly the state of real time map software by newspapers, web sites, and television updated during the vote count.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>