<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom Of Information Act Geology on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/freedom-of-information-act-geology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom Of Information Act Geology on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 14:22:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/freedom-of-information-act-geology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association a public body under Michigan FOIA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-03-is-the-northern-michigan-geologic-repository-association-a-public-body-under-michigan-foia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miningjournal.net/page/content.detail/id/589393/FOIA-at-core-of-court-case.html?nav=5006&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;a story in the Marquette Mining Journal&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MARQUETTE - Marquette County Circuit Court Judge Thomas Solka heard oral arguments Thursday on a case involving whether the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association is a public body subject to producing financial information under the Freedom of Information Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association is important to plaintiffs in the case because it was created under state law requirements by the Michigan Department of Environmental Quality, which makes it a public body by extension, the plaintiffs contend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association in question is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.michigan.gov/deq/0,4561,7-135-3311_4111_18442-168830--,00.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Assocation&lt;/a&gt;, described on a Michigan DEQ site as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Geological Core and Sample Repository holds a &lt;br /&gt;collection of drill core and cuttings from 67 counties &lt;br /&gt;in Michigan, including all 15 counties from the Upper &lt;br /&gt;Peninsula. The purpose of the collection is to act as &lt;br /&gt;a &amp;quot;rock library&amp;quot; and make the collected material &lt;br /&gt;available to individual researchers and industry for &lt;br /&gt;geologic study. It is hoped that the collection will &lt;br /&gt;lead to increased mineral and fuel exploration and &lt;br /&gt;development in various parts of Michigan. Both the &lt;br /&gt;local and state economies may benefit by more jobs &lt;br /&gt;being created.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plaintiffs contend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The murky facts surrounding the Northern Michigan Geologic Repository Association exemplify the need for the Freedom of Information Act and the purpose for which it was enacted: to shine a light on the actions of government officials which directly impact the citizens whom they purport to represent,&amp;quot; said Jana Mathieu, the plaintiff&amp;#39;s attorney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details from &lt;a href=&#34;http://savethewildup.org/2013/06/citizens-demand-federal-investigation-of-collusion-between-state-regulators-and-mining-industry/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Save the Wild UP&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Near the Upper Peninsula District Office of the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) in Gwinn, this map taped to the wall of a large warehouse labels the facility a “State Warehouse.” Core samples are stored within, but the DEQ claims no further association with NMGRA, the non-profit that has leased the warehouse and is attempting to raise money to make it a state geologic repository.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>