<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/quince/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/quince/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I wish I had already written, October 2010 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-october-2010-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-31-things-i-wish-i-had-written-october-2010-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A monthly recounting of stories not told, or code not written, or things otherwise that should have been done by me or at least discovered by me, but not done; this, the October 2010 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detailed breakdown of AATA route productivity by hour and by route, showing which of the routes are the busiest at which times of day. &amp;#0160;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/foia-friday-tracking-on-time-performance-of-the-bus-system/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;A start at bus tracking&lt;/a&gt;; the easy to grab data is late times.)&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of recipes for quince, with notes on what I actually made and where to pick quince off the tree in parks in Ann Arbor based on the city tree list. (An account of making &lt;a href=&#34;http://charchechaukeke.wordpress.com/2007/12/20/quince-jams-spicy-nuance/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;quince jam&lt;/a&gt;, using a quince purchased from ZZ&amp;#39;s; doesn&amp;#39;t look any harder than making applesauce.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The automated script to pull a council agenda and hyperlink or wikify it to match Capitalized Phrases to wiki pages inside Arborwiki. (Alas, The Council Agenda Is All Capitalized Phrases; This Will Take Some Effort.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to hyperlink directly to Ann Arbor City Code (by short URL) and also to Ann Arbor City Council agenda items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to get a personal protection order if someone harasses you online and in person, and how to get a trespass order written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A walking tour of the October vegetation at Olson Park, complete with a bunch of photos and Latin names for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to get to Chelsea on the bus, based on a ride that I made myself, with a full day commute complete with kid dropoff, morning deadline, lunch, afternoon moderation and kid pickup here. (Start with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twp-scio.ewashtenaw.org/pdfs/schedulewave/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Washtenaw Wave&lt;/a&gt; schedule.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to quickly go from wiki markup to publication-ready HTML markup using tools, and how to edit those tools to reflect your peculiar world. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://goessner.net/articles/wiky/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;wiky&lt;/a&gt; is the closest, but it&amp;#39;s in Javascript which isn&amp;#39;t one of my native languages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A review of the new Mighty Good Coffee on North Main, and how the Workantile vibe has changed now that it no longer has a cafe for a front. &amp;#0160;(Done, partially, here:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/north-main-links-the-view-out-the-window-from-mighty-good-coffee/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt; The view out the window from Mighty Good Coffee&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A review of the Embassy Hotel, based on a overnight stay.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>