<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/blueberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:50:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/blueberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>making fruit liqueurs, (or) how to prepare for the holidays well in advance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s fruit season (or nearly so) and so it&#39;s time to start thinking about what we&#39;re going to do for making holiday gifts. One staple in our house is a simple fruit liqueur of some sort, which turns sugar + fruit + vodka + time into something yummy.
We are not generally a cocktails household, so part of the corresponding challenge is giving people some sense of what do to with the jar to help them enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Michigan blueberry picking information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-09-2008-michigan-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-09-2008-michigan-b/</guid>
      <description>Photo credit: annethelibrarian; taken July 1, 2008 in Westland, MI. Used with permission, some rights reserved
It&#39;s just about blueberry picking season here near Ann Arbor and all over the state of Michigan.
There are two farms that I know about in easy driving distance of Ann Arbor. The Dexter Blueberry Farm is in Dexter on Beach Road north of Dexter-Chelsea Road; when I called yesterday they said about a week, so call ahead to (734)426-2900 to confirm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mechanical blueberry harvesters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-mechanical-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-mechanical-blue/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re serious about harvesting blueberries (as opposed to just picking them), you mechanize the operation. Here&#39;s an example of a blueberry harvester from Nova Scotia
 Doug Bragg Enterprises Ltd. Mechanical Blueberry Harvester consists of a reel-type picking head. The head is side mounted to a tractor in such a manner as to allow the picking head to follow contours of the ground. The reel rotates within the head in the same direction as the tractor wheels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Michigan fruit crop estimates, early reports</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 17:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</guid>
      <description>A place to collect fruit crop damage reports for 2008. Today is the 53rd Annual Fruit Crop Guesstimate, sponsored by the Michigan Frozen Food Packers Association, will be June 18, at 2 p.m. at the Amway Grand Hotel, in Grand Rapids; when those reports come in for real I&#39;ll post them.
UPDATE: Guesstimate results are in - details here, too long to post, at Fruit Growers News:
 Poor Weather Has Cut Size of Most U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Muffins (Ann Arbor Cookbook, 1904)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-19-blueberry-muffi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-19-blueberry-muffi/</guid>
      <description>Blueberry Muffins (Ann Arbor Cookbook, 1904)
Compiled by the Ladies’ Aid Society of the Congregational Church
Ann Arbor, Michigan: George Wahr, 1904
Cream one level tablespoon of butter and 1/3 cup of sugar together, add 1 egg, a scant 1/2 cup of milk, 1 cup of flour and two tablespoons more measured level, a pinch of salt and 2 level teaspoons of baking powder. Mix well and then stir in carefully 1 cup of blueberries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>