<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/blueberries/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/blueberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>making fruit liqueurs, (or) how to prepare for the holidays well in advance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 23:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-making-fruit-li/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s fruit season (or nearly so) and so it&#39;s time to start thinking about what we&#39;re going to do for making holiday gifts.  One staple in our house is a simple fruit liqueur of some sort, which turns sugar + fruit + vodka + time into something yummy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not generally a cocktails household, so part of the corresponding challenge is giving people some sense of what do to with the jar to help them enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some minimal collection of things to help for this year, one fruit at a time; not exhaustive, but maybe it will help jump start next year.  Ordered in rough order of appearance of the fruit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strawberry liqueur.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cottagesmallholder.com/?p=750&#34;&gt;Irene&#39;s Strawberry liqueur&lt;/a&gt; from The Cottage Smallholder; noting that &#34;There’s nothing like the distraction of homemade grog when times are getting tough.&#34;
&lt;li&gt;Juneberry liqueur.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.farm-garden.com/viewtopic.php?id=1056&#34;&gt;Saskatoons go with gin&lt;/a&gt;, says contributor &#34;prairiemaid&#34; from Manitoba.
&lt;li&gt;Gooseberry liqueur.  In the 1930s, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bedfordshire.gov.uk/CommunityAndLiving/ArchivesAndRecordOffice/GuidesToCollections/MeltisofBedford.aspx&#34;&gt;Meltis of Bedford&lt;/a&gt; introduced a gooseberry liqueur sweet to the UK market which was a big success, so they say.    Read Anton Chekov&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eldritchpress.org/ac/gooseb.html&#34;&gt;Gooseberries&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&#39;t have a recipe.
&lt;li&gt;Currants.  Make cassis; here&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.ibiblio.org/pipermail/labruscagrape/2005-June/000296.html&#34;&gt;cassis recipe&lt;/a&gt;, from &#34; The Cook and the Gardener&#34; by Amanda Hesser, A Year of Recipes and Writings from the French Countryside.
&lt;li&gt;Blueberries.  Freeze the berries first, then make &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guntheranderson.com/liqueurs/blueber0.htm&#34;&gt;blueberry liqueur.&lt;/a&gt;.  Ex-Michigander &lt;a href=&#34;http://culinariaeugenius.wordpress.com/2008/02/28/my-staples-summer-blueberry-liqueur/&#34;&gt;Culinaria Eugenius&lt;/a&gt; has a photo of the red-purple liquid that results.  
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Michigan blueberry picking information</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-09-2008-michigan-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-09-2008-michigan-b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/annethelibrarian/2628924075/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3140/2628924075_afb3e6bcc0_d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Photo credit: annethelibrarian; taken July 1, 2008 in Westland, MI.  Used with permission, &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/deed.en&#34;&gt;some rights reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s just about blueberry picking season here near Ann Arbor and all over the state of Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two farms that I know about in easy driving distance of Ann Arbor.  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Dexter_Blueberry_Farm&#34;&gt;Dexter Blueberry Farm&lt;/a&gt; is in Dexter on Beach Road north of Dexter-Chelsea Road; when I called yesterday they said about a week, so call ahead to (734)426-2900 to confirm.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/07/dexter-blueberr.html&#34;&gt;Last year they charged $1.35 per pound for U-Pick&lt;/a&gt;, and it was easy to fill a five pound bucket in a single session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the Main Street Bridge through Dexter is closed to eastbound traffic, so if you are heading back to Ann Arbor you&#39;ll go around downtown Dexter.  See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.villageofdexter.org/&#34;&gt;Village of Dexter web site&lt;/a&gt; for details and a construction webcam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slightly farther away is &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/The_Blueberry_Patch&#34;&gt;The Blueberry Patch&lt;/a&gt; in Grass Lake, just east of Jackson.  The berries are organic, and they use nets to keep away the birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other part of the state where I know a bit of detail is in the southwestern corner (known as Michiana) near New Buffalo, MI, Michigan City IN and the surrounding area.  I scanned in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/edward-vielmetti/1225078024/&#34;&gt;list of Michiana blueberry picking farms&lt;/a&gt; when we were there last year, and that info should still be good.  It&#39;s the closest Michigan berrypicking you&#39;ll get if you&#39;re coming from Chicagoland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leduc Blueberries near Kalamazoo has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leducblueberries.com/extra.iml&#34;&gt;a collection of eight years worth of annual blueberry recipes&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), which include the usual bakes, crumbles, pies and the like plus a series of dinner salads like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabulousfoods.com/index.php?option=com_resource&amp;controller=article&amp;category_id=157&amp;article=18460&#34;&gt;blueberry lemon chicken salad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other blueberry crop news:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report from Hammonton, New Jersey predicts an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thehammontonnews.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080625/LIFESTYLE/806250307/1024/NEWS17&#34;&gt;average New Jersey blueberry crop for 2008&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#34;The hot weather that we&#39;ve been having has had some effects on the ripening and harvesting of our products, though the cooler-than-normal ground temperatures and, until recently, cool overnight temperatures have helped to somewhat mitigate the day heat,&#34; said William Walker of the New Jersey Department Agriculture&#39;s Jersey Fresh program. &#34;The season was slow to begin, but we&#39;re now on a normal production schedule.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeGrandchamp Farms predicts a good 2008 season:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As I write this article, the 2008 blueberry crop looks like it has the potential to be an excellent one. I believe a lot has to do with the excellent growing season last summer which produced good growth and bud set. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wholesale prices for the fresh market were strong last year and should continue for the 2008 season. Demand for blueberries is strong for the processing market as more manufacturers are using blueberries in their product lines. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://usda.mannlib.cornell.edu/usda/current/CropValuSu/CropValuSu-02-14-2008.txt&#34;&gt;USDA crop price report&lt;/a&gt; for the last three years for blueberries:&lt;br/&gt;
2005: $1.44/lb&lt;br /&gt;
2006: $1.76/lb        &lt;br /&gt;
2007: $1.83/lb &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.absolutemichigan.com/dig/michigan/ready-to-pick-michigan-blueberries/&#34;&gt;Absolute Michigan has a Ready To Pick feature on blueberries&lt;/a&gt; with recipes and crop and grower info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;m looking for in comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you gone blueberry picking recently, and how was it?&lt;br /&gt;
Where do you go wild (not cultivated) berry picking - if not precisely where, then at least the township?&lt;br /&gt;
What do you know about mechanical blueberry harvesters?&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever used a blueberry rake, and is it easy to make one out of ordinary materials by hand?&lt;br /&gt;
What are your favorite blueberry recipes?&lt;br /&gt;
How do you preserve blueberries for February in Michigan when it&#39;s gray all the time?&lt;br /&gt;
What varieties of blueberry are good for growing in your yard, and what soil do you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thanks&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mechanical blueberry harvesters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-mechanical-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-24-mechanical-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re serious about harvesting blueberries (as opposed to just picking them), you mechanize the operation.  Here&#39;s an example of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dbe.ca/blueberryharvester.htm&#34;&gt;blueberry harvester from Nova Scotia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Doug Bragg Enterprises Ltd. Mechanical Blueberry Harvester consists of a reel-type picking head. The head is side mounted to a tractor in such a manner as to allow the picking head to follow contours of the ground. The reel rotates within the head in the same direction as the tractor wheels. This rotation is at a speed in ratio to the forward motion of the tractor. As the comb type-picking bars rake the blueberries from the plants they are carried around the reel and deposited in a conveyor. This conveyor delivers them to another longer conveyor, which carries them to the rear three-point-hitch mounted loading platform. As the berries fall from the conveyor a blower cleans them.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The harvester was invented by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsac.ns.ca/halloffame/citations/bragg_douglas.htm&#34;&gt;R. Douglas Bragg&lt;/a&gt; (1930-1996):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Doug Bragg always maintained a strong interest in the blueberry industry. Not only was he a manufacturer of the patented wild blueberry harvester and a blueberry producer himself, but he was an active member of the Wild Blueberry Producers Association of Nova Scotia. From 1979 to 1981 he served as a Director and was an active member of the Research Committee from the time of its inception until the fall of 1996. He was a Founding Director of the Nova Scotia Blueberry Institute and was instrumental in the early days of its development and building of the research field station at Debert. In 1995 Doug received the Wild Blueberry Producers Association of Nova Scotia Award of Recognition.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a set of patents on blueberry harvesters.  Here&#39;s what US Patent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patentstorm.us/patents/5375403/description.html&#34;&gt;5365403, Lowbush berry harvester&lt;/a&gt; has to say about the Bragg patented harvester:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
A later development is reported in Canadian Pat. No. 1,249,727 of Bragg Lumber Company. According to the patent, this harvester mounts a picking head, almost identical to the Chisholm-Ryder head, on the side of a farm tractor, but in such a manner that the picking head is &#34;towed &#34; by the tractor. The arrangement ostensibly accommodates variations in the ground by allowing for pitch and roll of the head during operation. As with the Chisholm-Ryder head, the tines of the Bragg harvester are controlled by a cam and cam follower arrangement. In the Bragg harvester, as the tines approach top dead centre of the reel they are caused to flap rapidly to dislodge the berries carried thereby for easy deposit on the internal conveyor.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my favorite blueberry-picking grounds, there&#39;s way too many ferns, jack pines, jack pine cones, bits of lichen and moss to ever make it suited for mechanical harvesting; just as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(pictures needed)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Michigan fruit crop estimates, early reports</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 17:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-2008-michigan-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A place to collect fruit crop damage reports for 2008.  Today is the 53rd Annual Fruit Crop Guesstimate, sponsored by the Michigan Frozen Food Packers Association, will be June 18, at 2 p.m. at the Amway Grand Hotel, in Grand Rapids; when those reports come in for real I&#39;ll post them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Guesstimate results are in - details here, too long to post, at &lt;a href=&#34;http://fruitgrowersnews.com/pages/news.php?ns=1614&#34;&gt;Fruit Growers News&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Poor Weather Has Cut Size of Most U.S. Fruit Crops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 19, 2008 - By Dick Lehnert &lt;br /&gt;
Managing Editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crummy spring weather coast to coast has reduced the production for most fruit crops. The word “record” was used only once – for blueberries – during the 53rd annual Fruit Crop Guesstimate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Guesstimate, sponsored by the Michigan Frozen Food Packers Association and attended by more than 150 people from across North America, was held June 18 in Grand Rapids, Mich. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the presenters adjusted their PowerPoint presentations as they were making them, reflecting continuing poor weather. New York has hit by a hail storm of “epic proportions” on June 16, and the June drop, delayed and prolonged by cool weather that slowed crop development, was still taking apples and peaches from trees across the northern states. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 18: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.record-eagle.com/local/local_story_170094110.html&#34;&gt;Traverse City cherry crop damage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just completely trashed,&amp;rdquo; Williams said of the small tract of cherry trees along Bright Road south of Maple City. &amp;ldquo;You can see how it took the leaves down and everything &amp;hellip; it stripped (the cherries) right off the trees.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hail that pelted Williams&#39; fruit trees marked the latest episode in a series of nature-related setbacks blamed for damaging the region&#39;s cherry crop. This year&#39;s harvest is shaping up as the worst since the nearly cherry-less summer of 2002, experts said.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 10: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leelanaunews.com/blog/2008/06/10/southern-leelanau-hardest-hit-by-frost/&#34;&gt;Southern Leelenau apple crop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Orchards were damaged last week when temperatures dropped as low as the mid-20s, but farms in the northern half of the county – above the 45th Parallel – weren’t hit quite so hard, said Nikki Rothwell, director of the Northwest Michigan Horticultural Resource Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think there is significant damage out there. We can’t put a number on it but we’ve got poor pollination on top of a freeze event,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apples were hit hardest by early morning cold May 28, followed by sweet cherries and then tarts and other crops growing in moderate to poor sites, or in a valley or pocket more susceptible to cold weather, she said.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Muffins (Ann Arbor Cookbook, 1904)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-19-blueberry-muffi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-19-blueberry-muffi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/cooks/6745&#34;&gt;Blueberry Muffins (Ann Arbor Cookbook, 1904)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Compiled by the Ladies’ Aid Society of the Congregational Church&lt;br /&gt;
Ann Arbor, Michigan: &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/index.php/George_Wahr&#34;&gt;George Wahr&lt;/a&gt;, 1904&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Cream one level tablespoon of butter and 1/3 cup of sugar together, add 1 egg, a scant 1/2 cup of milk, 1 cup of flour and two tablespoons more measured level, a pinch of salt and 2 level teaspoons of baking powder. Mix well and then stir in carefully 1 cup of blueberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/cooks/&#34;&gt;&#34;Ann Arbor Cooks&#34; collection at the Ann Arbor District Library.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>