<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yooper on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/yooper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yooper on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 21:12:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/yooper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The searchers all say they&#39;d&#39;ve made Whitefish Bay if they&#39;d put fifteen more miles behind her.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-10-the-searchers-all-say-theydve-made-whitefish-bay-if-theyd-put-fifteen-more-miles-behind-her-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 21:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-10-the-searchers-all-say-theydve-made-whitefish-bay-if-theyd-put-fifteen-more-miles-behind-her-/</guid>
      <description>Whitefish Bay is a bay at the eastern end of Lake Superior.
On Weather Underground, the local weather for Whitefish Bay is LS 321.
Map from NOAA, showing how 15 miles could mean the different between heavy winds and relative calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miner&#39;s Revenge - bicycle race in Greenland, MI in an underground copper mine</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-03-miners-revenge-bicycle-race-in-greenland-mi-in-an-underground-copper-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 01:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-03-miners-revenge-bicycle-race-in-greenland-mi-in-an-underground-copper-mine/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a novel reuse of an old copper mine - the Miner&amp;rsquo;s Revenge bicycle race is using a 1&amp;frasl;3 mile long section of the mine no longer in active use as a part of the race course.&amp;nbsp; Bring your own lights - it&amp;rsquo;s dark in there.
 The race is July 11-12, 2009, with free on-site camping for racers and a bonfire the night before. Greenland is near Ontonagon; the mine is owned by the Adventure Mining Company which also does walking tours as well as other more extreme mining adventures that involve rappelling down a mine shaft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trenary Outhouse Races 2009 - &#34;Haul Your Arse to the Sweetest 16th Ever&#34; - Feb 28, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-trenary-outhouse-races-2009-haul-your-arse-to-the-sweetest-16th-ever-feb-28-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 23:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-trenary-outhouse-races-2009-haul-your-arse-to-the-sweetest-16th-ever-feb-28-2009/</guid>
      <description>In Trenary, MI each year, when it&amp;#39;s cold and snowy, they hold a race to see who can push an outhouse on skis (suitably decorated) the fastest down Main Street.
The official web site has many more details.
Past year&amp;#39;s coverage:
2008:&amp;#0160;Trenary Outhouse Classic - Races show Yooper spirit&amp;#0160;from the Mining Journal&amp;#39;s Winter Visitor&amp;#39;s Guide has an interview with athlete Tom Felty
Tom said he built the outhouse in his yard back home and described it as a “conversation piece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rio Tinto &#34;Eagle&#34; sulfide mine project delayed due to market conditions (Forbes via AP)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-rio-tinto-eagle-sulfide-mine-project-delayed-due-to-market-conditions-forbes-via-ap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-rio-tinto-eagle-sulfide-mine-project-delayed-due-to-market-conditions-forbes-via-ap/</guid>
      <description>as seen in Forbes
Poor markets delay construction of Michigan mine By JOHN FLESHER , 02.12.09, 05:25 PM EST        Construction of a proposed nickel and copper mine in Michigan&amp;#39;s Upper Peninsula is being delayed because of poor market conditions, its parent company said Thursday.
But project manager Jon Cherry said the announcement by London-based Rio Tinto Group  (nyse: RTP - news  - people ) does not mean the Kennecott Eagle mine is off the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan DEQ public meeting in Humboldt, MI on Kennecott plans to open old Humboldt Mill to process sulfide ores from Eagle Project sulfide mine</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-michigan-deq-public-meeting-in-humboldt-mi-on-kennecott-plans-to-open-old-humboldt-mill-to-process-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 09:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-09-michigan-deq-public-meeting-in-humboldt-mi-on-kennecott-plans-to-open-old-humboldt-mill-to-process-s/</guid>
      <description>via Save the Wild UP:
Concerned citizens will get a chance on February 18 to voice their opinions on Kennecott&amp;rsquo;s plans to re-open the old Humboldt Mill at a public meeting hosted by Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Department of Environmental Quality
Kennecott Minerals bought the property last September with plans to process ore from its proposed Eagle Project. Without legal permits to develop Eagle, the company continues to push permits for this processing facility, which was not part of the original mine plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4000 days of pasties</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-03-4000-days-of-pasties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 16:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-03-4000-days-of-pasties/</guid>
      <description>lifted straight from Matt Roush&amp;#39;s Great Lakes IT Report
Pasty Cam marks 4,000th straight daily item on the Web
Next Tuesday, Feb. 10, the Upper Peninsula&amp;#39;s Pasty Cam will publish its 4,000th consecutive daily picture and discussion. That&amp;#39;s nearly 11 years without missing a single day. Personally, I don&amp;#39;t know of any other daily feature Web site that has been around that long -- especially without missing a day. The daily cam is the brain child of Charlie Hopper, who fell in love with the Keweenaw as a kid at summer camp, and moved there for keeps in 1988 with his wife Edie and two kids after selling a software company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket docks of the Great Lakes, Patrick Cooleybeck, paper at the Society for Industrial Archaeology, Duluth MN 2003</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-14-pocket-docks-of-the-great-lakes-patrick-cooleybeck-paper-at-the-society-for-industrial-archaeology-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 12:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-14-pocket-docks-of-the-great-lakes-patrick-cooleybeck-paper-at-the-society-for-industrial-archaeology-d/</guid>
      <description>a question about this paper came up in email; posting here to collect more.
Cooleybeck, Patrick—
Moshe Safdie &amp;amp; Associates, Somerville, MA
 &amp;quot;Iron ore docks of the Great Lakes&amp;quot;
 Pocket ore docks are monumental structures used to transfer iron ore from railway cars traveling from nearby mines to ships that carry the ore to steelmaking centers or transfer points on the Lower Great Lakes. These structures were constructed from wood, steel, or reinforced concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell phone winter gloves</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-cell-phone-winter-gloves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-30-cell-phone-winter-gloves/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s winter, your hands see cold so you are wearing gloves, but you need at least a few fingers free for your mobile phone. What designs work?
The gloves I am wearing now have a flap to expose a sort of fingerless Mitten, and if I fold things right I can expose just two index fingers. I could imagine thumbs free gloves too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 summer bug camp in the UP</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-29-2008-summer-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 17:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-29-2008-summer-bug/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve typed some things about bug camp, but haven&#39;t blogged about it.
The name of the place is not really bug camp; it&#39;s the Page Center in Little Lake, MI:

Our peaceful, natural setting on Little Lake is the perfect place for your next retreat, reunion, wedding, reception or workshop. Located 3 miles East of M-35/553, approximately 24 miles south of Marquette.

It&#39;s a nice spot, a former church camp, with a lovely main house, a dining hall and kitchen, and eight bunk cabins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pop vs. soda: Michigan soft drink name map, with special attention to Upper Peninsula / Wisconsin border issues</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-pop-vs-soda-mic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 12:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-18-pop-vs-soda-mic/</guid>
      <description>Two versions of this map, one showing survey details, the other aggregating by county.




The great pop vs. soda controversy is a project that Alan McConchie did to survey regional use of generic names for soft drinks. You&#39;ll see here clearly that Michigan is a &#34;pop&#34; state; the sharp Wisconsin vs. Upper Peninsula divide of soda vs. pop is notable. You have to do pretty far south into Indiana to see &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trenary Outhouse Classic - 15th Annual - Feb 23 2008 - Trenary, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-trenary-outhous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 22:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-10-trenary-outhous/</guid>
      <description>For the past 15 years, intrepid outdoorspeople in Trenary, MI have been pushing outhouses down a racetrack in February. Here&amp;rsquo;s some details and coverage of this year&amp;rsquo;s event, and reports from previous years. Phone for more detail (906) 228-7749 or the Marquette County Convention and Visitors Bureau.  Autoweek Magazine on the 2007 Trenary Outhouse Classic:  From the towering dunes of Dakar to the thrill rides beside Suzuka to most of the highlights in between, we have witnessed no racing sillier than the Trenary Outhouse Classic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>