<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ifttt on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/ifttt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ifttt on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:44:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/ifttt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A design for an an Ann Arbor events channel, @a2events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 21:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-13-a-design-for-an-an-ann-arbor-events-channel-a2events-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a design for a low overhead way to post about events coming up in Ann Arbor. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2events&#34;&gt;@a2events on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you want to play along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule of business is that every event has to have a URL, and the more simple and direct the URL is the more likely it is that it&#39;s authoritative for the event. If an event doesn&#39;t have a URL yet, I&#39;ll blog about it here if I need to post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second rule of business is that I&#39;m not keeping a calendar, just a feed, and the feed is not going to be a 100% comprehensive feed; you have to be prepared to get events info from multiple sources and I&#39;m just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third rule of business of course is that if you want to pay for this service we&#39;ll find a way to let you pay, though the specifics are TBD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic idea for technology is to use a tag on my Pinboard account to feed a specific tag, and to use that tag to feed IFTTT to feed Twitter so that events get pushed out. I&#39;ll probably also use a Node-RED page to help construct something that does the right thing, and there will be a Slack channel on the a2b3 slack to do - something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Brian Kerr for having the foresight to reserve the name a2events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>