<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:49:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>running mjpg-streamer on a Raspberry Pi 2 with an old Logitech webcam</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-27-running-mjpg-streamer-on-a-raspberry-pi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:49:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-27-running-mjpg-streamer-on-a-raspberry-pi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I followed the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxmediaserver.net/linux-basics/streaming-webcam-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;this post on LinuxMediaServer.net&lt;/a&gt; to get an old Logitech web camera running on a Raspberry Pi 2. Here are some of the changes I did from the original to support my hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lsusb returns this device:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bus 001 Device 004: ID 046d:08ae Logitech, Inc. QuickCam for Notebooks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to add a driver for the camera:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo modprobe gspca_zc3xx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera I have shows up as /dev/video0 and has a resolution of 320x240:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;sudo ./mjpg_streamer -i &#34;./input_uvc.so -r 320x240 -d /dev/video0&#34; -o &#34;./output_http.so -w www&#34; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existence proof, showing that it works. You should be able to recognize the Festifools t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c7a58928970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c7a58928970b img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-27 at 12.35.07 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-06-27 at 12.35.07 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b7c7a58928970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not an awesome camera, but the resolution is perfectly adequate to a small task. A next challenge, should I choose to take it on, is to wrap up all of the dependencies into a Dockerfile and do a Docker build. I&#39;m going to wait on that until Docker 1.7.1 drops since 1.7.0 is not stable on ARM platforms. I haven&#39;t yet successfully managed to get Docker on the Pi to read from USB devices (but how hard, indeed, could it be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: looks like @chuckleb built a Dockerfile for this for Ubuntu at &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/u/chuckleb/mjpg-streamer/&#34;&gt;chuckleb/mjpg-streamer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2: If you&#39;re using the Raspberry Pi camera, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.miguelgrinberg.com/post/how-to-build-and-run-mjpg-streamer-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;Miguel Grinberg has these build instructions for that device&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Node-RED on a Raspberry Pi with Docker and Hypriot</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 02:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal for the week was to empty out my inbox sufficiently that I would be able to make progress on some programming tasks that are hard to do when there&#39;s distractions. The inbox got all the way down to zero, and that meant that there was a chunk of evening time suitable for hacking. Happy to report that the result of this is Node-RED running on a Raspberry Pi under Docker on top of Hypriot. A word of explanation of how this all works in detail is too much, but here&#39;s where I got the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device/&#34;&gt;Hypriot&#39;s gettting started guide&lt;/a&gt; brings you up to speed on getting Docker running on your ARM device (e.g. your Raspberry Pi). They have bootable images that you can download and burn to SD card, and from there you load up applications from Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypriot has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/hypriot/talk&#34;&gt;chat window&lt;/a&gt; on Gitter, so you can pop in and there will be occasionally people to assist. Best to do things European time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/&#34;&gt;DockerHub&lt;/a&gt; is a one stop shop for packaged applications. When you&#39;re running on the Pi, you&#39;ll want to seek out versions with &#39;rpi&#39; or &#39;arm&#39; in their names as they have likely been adapted for that system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up pulling Niel Eyde&#39;s Raspberry Pi versions of Node-RED from DockerHub as &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/u/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/&#34;&gt;nieleyde/rpi-nodered&lt;/a&gt;. It has all sorts of interesting modules that I had not previously built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is at 0.10.6 at this writing. Its &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org/docs/hardware/raspberrypi.html&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi support&lt;/a&gt; includes hardware support using &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiringpi.com/&#34;&gt;WiringPi&lt;/a&gt; to access the GPIO pins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED currently supports Node.JS 0.10. Node.JS and IO.JS have &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdtimes.com/node-js-and-io-js-to-merge-under-node-js-foundation/&#34;&gt;merged forces&lt;/a&gt; after a fork, which means hopefully development will start to be sane again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all said I am not sure I have everything I need yet but as a leap forward it&#39;s pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>