<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gooseberry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/gooseberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gooseberry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 12:33:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/recipes/gooseberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From Chekov&#39;s &#34;Gooseberries&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-07-13-from-chekovs-gooseberries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 12:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-07-13-from-chekovs-gooseberries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eldritchpress.org/ac/gooseb.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Full text of Anton Chekov&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Gooseberries&amp;quot; is available at Eldritch Press.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;An excerpt from this short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But my point does not concern him so much as myself. I want to tell you what a change took place in me in those few hours while I was in his house. In the evening, while we were having tea, the cook laid a plateful of gooseberries on the table. They had not been bought, but were his own gooseberries, plucked for the first time since the bushes were planted. Nicholai Ivanich laughed with joy and for a minute or two he looked in silence at the gooseberries with tears in his eyes. He could not speak for excitement, then put one into his mouth, glanced at me in triumph, like a child at last being given its favourite toy, and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;How good they are!&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He went on eating greedily, and saying all the while:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;How good they are! Do try one!&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It was hard and sour, but, as Poushkin said, the illusion which exalts us is dearer to us than ten thousand truths. I saw a happy man, one whose dearest dream had come true, who had attained his goal in life, who had got what he wanted, and was pleased with his destiny and with himself....&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>