<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/cleary-university/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/cleary-university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council highlights for 5 January 2015, a preview</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:33:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-01-05-ann-arbor-city-council-highlights-for-5-january-2015-a-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor City Council is meeting tonight, 5 January 2015, at 7:00 p.m. the Washtenaw County Administration Building. Here are some highlights from the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three public hearings are on the docket. The public will get a chance to weigh in on a proposed amendment to the chicken-keeping ordinance and two hearings on downtown zoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chicken-keeping ordinance (Section 107) would be amended to allow people to keep 6 chickens instead of the current 4, and to allow people to keep chickens without getting the mandatory consent of the neighbors. Expect the neighborliness issue to be a substantial point of discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downtown zoning plans revolve around the changes proposed to what&#39;s now a parking lot next to the DTE building on S Main St. The parcel abuts a residential neighborhood and the neighbors don&#39;t particularly want a giant building to the west looming over their back yards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the consent agenda is approval of an emergency repair to the city&#39;s tower truck in the sum of $64,464.93 which is to repair damage from an accident on October 31, 2014. The fire department has brought its 18 year old previous tower unit back into service in reserve, according to the city administrator&#39;s notes accompanying the purchase order approval request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Council will take up the issue of rezoning of a parcel at 3601 Plymouth Road to allow the construction of a Plum Market on the land most recently occupied by Cleary University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be an early night at council.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>