<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 20:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My somewhat internet-free vacation to the Upper Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-23-my-somewhat-internet-free-vacation-to-the-upper-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-23-my-somewhat-internet-free-vacation-to-the-upper-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>It wasn&#39;t completely internet-free, because there was wifi at my Mom&#39;s place and wifi at McDonald&#39;s for the occasional stops and wifi at the very nice Dead River Cafe in Marquette. But for the most part the net was kept at bay, since T-Mobile data service ended at Pinconning and I was with a phone that didn&#39;t have internet-everywhere coverage for the better part of a week.
There are a couple of places I would have liked to have captured in the moment while I was there with a camera and with Twitter to share them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United Airlines grounded by computer systems crash, 17 June 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-united-airlines-grounded-by-computer-systems-crash-17-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-united-airlines-grounded-by-computer-systems-crash-17-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>United Airlines is down because of a computer systems crash. Details are minimal as to what has actually happened. Here&amp;rsquo;s some sources.
Chicago: Chicago Breaking News puts the start of the problems at 7:15 p.m. Central (8:15 p.m. Eastern) and reports major problems at O&amp;rsquo;Hare. A later update attributes the first official announcement of the problem as coming from the FAA, not from United.
Flyertalk forums: Major Systems Outage Impacting United&amp;rsquo;s Airport and Online Operations details problems into the night affecting United locations nationwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interurban newsletters</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-27-interurban-newsletters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 11:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-27-interurban-newsletters/</guid>
      <description>Some titles available in Google Books; there&amp;#39;s certain to be more.
Electric Railway Journal. &amp;#0160;v.33, 1906. v.42, 1913. v.45, 1915.
Street Railway Journal. v.21, 1903.
Electric Railway Service (Detroit United Lines). 1917. This last one is remarkable as an in-house PR newsletter, full of editorials railing against the Detroit Evening News, and with notably precise accounting for the delays (and causes thereof) on streetcar lines. &amp;quot;The Lying Evening News Still Continues to Lie&amp;quot; was a headline from 1914.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subaru Forester 2006 diagnostic code P0851</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-04-11-subaru-forester-2006-diagnostic-code-p0851/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 22:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-04-11-subaru-forester-2006-diagnostic-code-p0851/</guid>
      <description>Check engine light goes on, and the cruise control light blinks. &amp;#0160;The vehicle&amp;#39;s owner is concerned.
Drive the car to an auto parts store (O&amp;#39;Reilly, formerly Murray&amp;#39;s), borrow their diagnostic tool, read out the code. &amp;#0160;The tool itself doesn&amp;#39;t say too much about what it is, but it was free to use, and it was easy to use. &amp;#0160;Note to self: next time the check engine light goes on on any vehicle, take it there first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I-75 at 9 Mile Road in Hazel Park, north of Detroit MI: tanker explosion (w/video)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-i75-at-9-mile-road-in-hazel-park-north-of-detroit-mi-tanker-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 21:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-15-i75-at-9-mile-road-in-hazel-park-north-of-detroit-mi-tanker-explosion/</guid>
      <description>A gasoline tanker exploded at I-75 and 9 Mile Road. &amp;nbsp;Here&#39;s what I was able to find out. &amp;nbsp;No photos posted here, a few videos embedded, you will find plenty by clicking through.

Detroit Free Press: Tanker Fire in Hazel Park closes I-75Fire crews are on the scene of the crash 10 miles north of downtown Detroit. Police are ordering onlookers gathered along the top of the embankments along the crash site to move back to avoid exposure to toxic smoke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;After the car&#34;, John Urry and Kingsley Dennis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 23:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</guid>
      <description>Kingsley Dennis and John Urry have a new book out, &amp;ldquo;After The Car&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; I have a review copy on the way from the publisher; until it arrives, you can see the intro and the index from the Amazon link below.&amp;nbsp; This is an oddly appropriate text to anticipate the week GM went bankrupt.
Allow me for a brief moment to indulge. I would like to inform you that my co-authored book titled &amp;lsquo;After the Car&amp;rsquo; has now been published (finally!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the bus game: why it&#39;s important to get the AATA&#39;s mobile ridetrak back online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-23-the-bus-game-why-its-important-to-get-the-aatas-mobile-ridetrak-back-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 16:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-23-the-bus-game-why-its-important-to-get-the-aatas-mobile-ridetrak-back-online/</guid>
      <description>While waiting for the AATA&amp;#39;s mobile ridetrak system to go back online (it&amp;#39;s been down for two weeks now due to a series of unfortunate events), I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about how to model the network of bus and pedestrian routes so that you could say some useful things about the goodness of a given route network for a particular task at a particular time of day.&amp;#0160; What I&amp;#39;m after is understanding just how far I can reasonably go from where I am to somewhere else useful based on bus routes, my willingness or ability to walk, and the minute by minute information about how late the bus is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;After the car&#34;, John Urry and Kingsley Dennis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-15-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 13:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-15-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</guid>
      <description>thanks to Paul Hartzog for the connection.
A new book on its way on the post-automotive era; quoting their release page in its entirety.
After the Car By: John Urry (Lancaster University) and Kingsley DENNIS.    Description It is difficult to imagine a world without the car, and yet that is exactly what Dennis and Urry set out to do in this provocative new book. They argue that the days of the car are numbered: powerful forces around the world are undermining the car system and will usher in a new transport system sometime in the next few decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Bus 2008 map (plus a sticker project)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-link-bus-2008-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 14:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-18-link-bus-2008-m/</guid>
      <description>The Ann Arbor Link Bus starts service again next week.&amp;nbsp; Every year I get tired of not being able to figure out when the bus is going to show up, and this year I tried to build a new map to help out.&amp;nbsp; This is a work in progress.
The key idea here (so far poorly executed, but I&#39;ll get it right) is to replace the stop letters with stop numbers, and to number the stops by the number of minutes after the quarter hour that the bus is expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized transit planning for the AATA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-personalized-tr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-06-personalized-tr/</guid>
      <description>Some notes on something that doesn&#39;t exist yet, but should.
Imagine a service that has URLs like
http://wheresmybus.org/route/5/inbound/packard+granger/3
http://wheresmybus.org/route/any/inbound/packard+state/0
http://wheresmybus.org/route/any/any/stone-school+eisenhower/4
and which has a very simple output of the times you need to leave to catch the next bus
8:04
8:22
based on the following:
real time bus location information (via mobile ridetrak), for buses already en route, and then estimated times for scheduled buses not yet visible. This is scrapable from existing services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>