<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expert on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/expert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expert on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/expert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>proximity, distance, and expertise</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge of being an expert is that it is hard to be one in
your own home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expertise is valued when it comes from far away. The traveling
scholar is special for their pure understanding of a difficult
field, and they don&amp;rsquo;t incur the baggage of being a neighbor or even
a friend. The distinguished visitor can be an exemplar of their
craft, not distracted by any complicated local entanglements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be recognized as an expert you need to be prepared
to travel beyond where you are well understood out to the parts of
the world where you are known solely for your expertise. Go beyond
your narrow orbit and strike out to a place where your reputation
is solid and where you are an example of the thing you call your
own. Leave your own neighborhood behind, even if only to be seen
elsewhere as an expert on neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expertise is a funny thing. You don&amp;rsquo;t always get a chance to pick
what you are good at, because that can come from the views of others.
The further away those others are, the more likely they have some
essential insight into your character that your close neighbors
will never have. Look at yourself through the eyes of someone far
away and see what special characteristics appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Written mostly on a mobile phone while in a familiar cafe.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; Truism: The further you are away, the more expert you become. Also, never a prophet in your hometown.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Neal Kessler (@NealKessler) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NealKessler/statuses/443936415744024576&#34;&gt;March 13, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become an expert by collecting other experts in your field or other fields</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 23:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you become an expert in a field?  By writing about that
field, repeatedly, until you have mastered it to the level which
people find you easily and draw on your expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of being able to write about something twice a day is
to have a ready collection of other people to call on for ideas or
to ask for details or referrals.   By being ready to tap into other
people&amp;rsquo;s expertise, you figure out what you need to know fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/12/bird_by_bird_an.html&#34;&gt;Anne Lamott&amp;rsquo;s Bird by Bird&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are an enormous number of people out there with invaluable
information to share with you, and all you have to do is pick up
the phone.  They love it when you do, just as you love it when
people ask if they can pick your brain about something you happen
to know a great deal about &amp;ndash; or, as in my case, have a number of
impassioned opinions on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/expert/&#34;&gt;blogger&amp;rsquo;s secret&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: how to be an expert about anything</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can be an expert with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.micropersuasion.com/2008/05/become-an-exper.html#comment-113533638&#34;&gt;blogger&#39;s secret&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Pick a topic.&lt;br /&gt;
2. Write about it twice a day.&lt;br /&gt;
3. At the end of six months, you will be an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note well: choose carefully what you want to be an expert about!  It&#39;s mighty hard to be an expert about more than one thing this way, just because it consumes so much time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>