<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expert on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/expert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expert on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/expert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>proximity, distance, and expertise</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 21:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-12-proximity-and-distance/</guid>
      <description>The challenge of being an expert is that it is hard to be one in your own home town.
Expertise is valued when it comes from far away. The traveling scholar is special for their pure understanding of a difficult field, and they don&amp;rsquo;t incur the baggage of being a neighbor or even a friend. The distinguished visitor can be an exemplar of their craft, not distracted by any complicated local entanglements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become an expert by collecting other experts in your field or other fields</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 23:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-08-become-an-exper/</guid>
      <description>How do you become an expert in a field? By writing about that field, repeatedly, until you have mastered it to the level which people find you easily and draw on your expertise.
A big part of being able to write about something twice a day is to have a ready collection of other people to call on for ideas or to ask for details or referrals. By being ready to tap into other people&amp;rsquo;s expertise, you figure out what you need to know fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: how to be an expert about anything</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-07-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>You can be an expert with the blogger&#39;s secret:
1. Pick a topic.
2. Write about it twice a day.
3. At the end of six months, you will be an expert.
Note well: choose carefully what you want to be an expert about! It&#39;s mighty hard to be an expert about more than one thing this way, just because it consumes so much time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>