<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Lakes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/great-lakes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Lakes on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 14:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/great-lakes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Ships of the Great Lakes at Lake Erie Metropark, Nov. 22, 2pm, Brownstown MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-09-great-ships-of-the-great-lakes-at-lake-erie-metropark-nov-22-2pm-brownstown-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 14:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-09-great-ships-of-the-great-lakes-at-lake-erie-metropark-nov-22-2pm-brownstown-mi/</guid>
      <description>Cut and paste of a press release, with a few hyperlinks tossed in.

Great Ships of the Great Lakes at Lake Erie Metropark
&amp;#0160;
Join nationally recognized lecturer, model maker and marine historian Keith Steffke for a fascinating look at some of the great ships that have plied and died on the Great Lakes at our special presentation “Great Ships of the Great Lakes,” on Sunday, November 22 at 2 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edmund Fitzgerald - memorial at the Great Lakes Shipwreck Museum, Whitefish Point, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-edmund-fitzgerald---memorial-at-the-great-lakes-shipwreck-museum-whitefish-point-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-11-08-edmund-fitzgerald---memorial-at-the-great-lakes-shipwreck-museum-whitefish-point-mi/</guid>
      <description>(write about the display in Paradise)
from the Sault Star:
The Great Lakes Shipwreck Museum is getting to once again ring the bell 29 times, during the 14th annual Edmund Fizgerald Memorial Service. The Edmund Fitzgerald, a 729-foot ore carrier, and her entire crew of 29 men were lost on Lake Superior 34 years ago in one of the worst storms in three decades. The freighter lies north-northwest of Whitefish Point in 160 metres of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bumboat Marine Trader in Duluth, MN, and other parts of Great Lakes marine life</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-12-the-bumboat-marine-trader-in-duluth-mn-and-other-parts-of-great-lakes-marine-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 15:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-12-the-bumboat-marine-trader-in-duluth-mn-and-other-parts-of-great-lakes-marine-life/</guid>
      <description>Bumboats are small boats used as floating shops that market to sailors in harbor.&amp;nbsp; There&amp;rsquo;s a tradition of them on the Great Lakes; here&amp;rsquo;s what I could find with a bit of searching.
In Duluth, Minnesota, the Marine Trader went back to the lakes in 1998:&amp;nbsp; (via a story in Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s World Port w/photos)
On May 24, 1998, an old boat and an even older maritime practice both came back to life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>