<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calendars Discardia on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars-discardia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calendars Discardia on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 01:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/calendars-discardia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2008 Discardia, 22-29 September 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-fall-2008-disca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 01:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-fall-2008-disca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/&#34;&gt;Dinah&lt;/a&gt; made up a holiday called 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;Discardia&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/metagrrrl/2002/12/a_new_holiday_d.html&#34;&gt;She wrote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve decided to invent a new holiday called Discardia. It takes place
in the time between the Solstices &amp;amp; Equinoxes and their following
new moons. Discardia is celebrated by getting rid of stuff and ideas
and habits you no longer need. On the Discardian new moon you don&#39;t
buy anything or bring anything into your home and enjoy the fact that
you have enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend&#39;s project is emptying out bits of the garage that have accumulated reusable leftovers from the summer&#39;s kitchen project.&amp;nbsp; We took a couple of windows to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Reuse_Center&#34;&gt;Reuse Center on S. Industrial&lt;/a&gt; which gladly took them, and there&#39;s more in the garage that looks like it should go before the first frost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In thinking about how to identify the things that need to go, I&#39;m back to notes I wrote about seiri.&amp;nbsp; The approach here is to use red tags to identify things that don&#39;t belong, and then to systematically remove the things that don&#39;t belong so that no red tags are left and no new red tags appear.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/edward-vielmetti/48871860/&#34;&gt;The most interesting thing I&#39;ve written about seiri &lt;/a&gt;was written on paper, so you can see the scan.&amp;nbsp; I want to go back and do the red tag thing online in some clever way.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>