<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thorstein Veblen on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/thorstein-veblen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thorstein Veblen on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 01:36:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/thorstein-veblen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin, conspicuous consumption, and conspicuous waste</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-bitcoin-conspicuous-consumption-and-conspicuous-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 01:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-21-bitcoin-conspicuous-consumption-and-conspicuous-waste/</guid>
      <description>From the Bitcointalk forums, 2011: &amp;quot;Bitcoins are peacock tails&amp;quot;
A series of studies, &amp;quot;Peacocks, Porsches and Thorstein Veblen: Conspicuous Consumption as a Sexual Signaling System,&amp;quot; was published recently in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology.&amp;#0160;A peacock&amp;#39;s tail is beautiful: magnificent plumage, iridescent colors. Alas, it is also wasteful. It takes a tremendous amount of energy to develop. Sound like bitcoins?
Let&amp;#39;s look at the Bitcoin as a signal of conspicuous consumption and conspicuous waste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thorstein Veblen, cranky economist, on handmade goods</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-18-thorstein-veblen-cranky-economist-on-handmade-goods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 01:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-18-thorstein-veblen-cranky-economist-on-handmade-goods/</guid>
      <description>For future reference, since I end up immediately thinking of Veblen when I read about artisanal tofu. This from Theory of the Leisure Class is on hand-made goods (emphasis added).
 The position here taken is enforced in a felicitous manner by the place assigned in the economy of consumption to machine products. The point of material difference between machine-made goods and the hand-wrought goods which serve the same purposes is, ordinarily, that the former serve their primary purpose more adequately.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>