<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imagemagick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/imagemagick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Imagemagick on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/imagemagick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Library notes from Malletts Creek</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-library-notes/</guid>
      <description>Out for a bike ride to Malletts Creek Branch Library after a delicious lunch of BBQ at Ricewood.
 One of the challenges of low overhead custom postcard making is getting an image manipulation pipeline that kicks out photos that a appropriately cropped and sized. The latest challenge is identifying the single command line that will turn a photo from my phone&amp;rsquo;s camera into an appropriately sized image for the card with a minimum of cropping, distortion, and manual file transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink. Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong iced latte, just add a little half and half.
The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence of mind seven years ago to write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick for image manipulation and that helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>image processing on the mac with sips, ImageMagick - watching DTE restore power, slowly</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-29-image-processing-on-the-mac-with-sips-imagemagick-watching-dte-restore-power-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 15:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-29-image-processing-on-the-mac-with-sips-imagemagick-watching-dte-restore-power-slowly/</guid>
      <description>As part of watching DTE slowly restore power to the area, I&amp;#39;ve been pulling down copies of their outage maps.&amp;#0160; These are big PDF files, suitable for framing, that encode a bunch of data in them about where the power is out.&amp;#0160; Here&amp;#39;s some tools I used to get details out of PDF into image formats, (hopefully) to get them back down to a spreadsheet full of numbers.
1.&amp;#0160; Fetch the outage report automatically with curl:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>