<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/foia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foia on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 12:03:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/foia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA: inspection reports for downtown Ann Arbor street lights</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 12:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-23-foia-inspection-reports-for-downtown-ann-arbor-street-lights/</guid>
      <description>As sent to the Ann Arbor City Clerk, 23 October 2013:
To the clerk:
The City Council meeting of this week Tuesday (ed.: actually late Monday) had an extended discussion of street lighting in the downtown area, and council weighed the problems with rust on street lamps and decided not to spend money to replace them.
To follow up on this discussion, and motivated by the uncertainty at council about the state of the lighting, I&#39;d like to make this request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving FOIA logs, a study in contrasts</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-19-retrieving-foia-logs-a-study-in-contrasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-19-retrieving-foia-logs-a-study-in-contrasts/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve had the occasion to send out requests for FOIA logs to several local units of government. Here&#39;s my varied experience with these requests. I&#39;m not certain that I have perfected the standard query, and so you shouldn&#39;t necessarily show the non-responsiveness of any given agency as a ding on them - it might be me.
The FOIA log is a set of records associated with FOIA requests. Typically I&#39;ve been asking for copies of FOIA request letters, the cover letters of responses that are sent back, but not the full details of the relevant documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOIA jobs: looking for all of your ideas on #FOIAchat</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-18-foia-jobs-looking-for-all-of-your-ideas-on-foiachat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 11:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-18-foia-jobs-looking-for-all-of-your-ideas-on-foiachat/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a weekly FOIA Friday column for AnnArbor.com for about a year. The position that I had was eliminated in layoffs in March 2011, as the Ann Arbor Chronicle&#39;s story History Repeats at AnnArbor.com describes. Ironically, I was laid off the week before the newspaper industry promotes Sunshine Week, though I am certain that was just coincidence.
What do you do with all of this experience in dealing with the Freedom of Information Act?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>records request: ann arbor downtown development authority parking data</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-14-records-request-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-parking-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 02:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-14-records-request-ann-arbor-downtown-development-authority-parking-data/</guid>
      <description>update: broken links fixed to interview, thanks John Balogh for the heads up as sent by postal mail and email
March 14, 2009
&amp;#0160;
Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority 150 South Fifth Avenue Suite 301 Ann Arbor, MI 48104
&amp;#0160;
&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;RECORDS REQUEST
&amp;#0160;
Dear Records Request Officer:
&amp;#0160;
Pursuant to the state open records act, I request access to and copies of the continuously updated information about the current availability of parking structure occupancy and free spaces, as currently provided to the general public on the web page</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>