<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/chicago/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicago on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 13:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/chicago/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>People I saw or met in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 13:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-12-people-i-saw-or-met-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Just a list, so I can&#39;t forget who I saw on a very good trip to Chicago last week.
 Megabus. Cheap and cheerful transportation, very convenient to where I was going, good drivers both ways. The return trip bus was kind of old (e.g. the power outlets didn&#39;t work) but the driver was fantastic. HI-Chicago a hostel in the loop. Cheap and cheerful lodging, very convenient. Eric Sinclair and Anne Zender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working on traffic safety in Chicago</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-on-traffic-safety-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 23:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-working-on-traffic-safety-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>noting along the way the Chicago Crash Browser, ChicagoCrashes.org.

The Michigan Traffic Crash Facts site is very competent as well, perhaps better than this Chicago site in some ways. This image shows bicycle crashes in Washtenaw County, 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying at Hosteling International Chicago (HI-Chicago)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-staying-at-hosteling-international-chicago-hi-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 07:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-07-staying-at-hosteling-international-chicago-hi-chicago/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m completely happy with my choice of HI-Chicago as a place to stay. It&#39;s inexpensive, clean, well run, the staff is friendly, and there&#39;s lots of community space in the building to get things done in outside of your room.
I stayed here for the eChicago conference in an 8-person room; this time I upgraded to the 4-person room. Two nights stay is less than $100, which is hard to beat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago postcards at the Chicago Architecture Foundation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 21:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-06-chicago-postcards-at-the-chicago-architecture-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Some very nice postcards indeed from their postcard rack, at about $1 a piece. I&#39;m going to study them closely and them mail them off!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m heading to Chicago. I&#39;ll be near the Loop. Where should I buy postcards?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 10:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-im-heading-to-chicago-ill-be-near-the-loop-where-should-i-buy-postcards/</guid>
      <description>I found the Chicago Postcard Museum which is all online; pity that it&#39;s not in a real place or I&#39;d visit.
Where would you go in the Loop to get good and interesting cards? I&#39;m not interested in spending lots of money per card, but I would like to have a nice variety to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>