<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gopher on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/gopher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gopher on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:43:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/gopher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;brew install lynx&#34;, and then Gopher lives on</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-08-brew-install-lynx-and-then-gopher-lives-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-08-brew-install-lynx-and-then-gopher-lives-on/</guid>
      <description>Since we&#39;re reinventing the Olde Web with systems like tilde.club, here&#39;s a screen shot of the current state of Gopher.
&#34;brew install lynx&#34; gets a Lynx client on my Mac, and then you point lynx at gopher://gopher.floodgap.com and you&#39;re good to go.
&#34;ssh new@sdf.org&#34; and you can set yourself up a shell account with a gopher client installed and gopher server space available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>node-gopher, the White Mesa gopher server for node.js</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-04-node-gopher-the-white-mesa-gopher-server-for-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 23:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-04-node-gopher-the-white-mesa-gopher-server-for-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>node-gopher is a little Gopher protocol server written in node.js by Robert Cunnings, NW8L. It supports an RFC 1436 Gopher server (no Gopher+) and has CGI-like support for running scripts that return Gopher pages.
Thanks to Cameron Kaiser for running the Floodgap gopher gateway that provides web access to venerable (and new) Gopherspace resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinboard now supports gopher:// URLs</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-15-pinboard-now-supports-gopher-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-15-pinboard-now-supports-gopher-urls/</guid>
      <description>from @pinboard
    @Pinboard:&amp;#0160;@vielmetti&amp;#0160;@doctorlinguist&amp;#0160;alright, extremely proud to announce Pinboard now supports the gopher:// scheme   To test, go to&amp;#0160;https://pinboard.in/u:vielmetti/b:7fb419764b79&amp;#0160;and examine what you get, following the link to its logical conclusions. To really test, get a Gopher client; I am using Overbite Chrome from Floodgap Systems.   Thanks to Cameron Kaiser for noticing, and to&amp;#0160;Maciej Ceglowski for making it happen.   For more coverage of Gopherspace, I occasionally write something at http://vielmetti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How twitter and gopher were born, (or) why you should make it work on the worst system first</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-01-how-twitter-and-gopher-were-born-or-why-you-should-make-it-work-on-the-worst-system-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 15:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-01-how-twitter-and-gopher-were-born-or-why-you-should-make-it-work-on-the-worst-system-first/</guid>
      <description>this post on &amp;quot;how twitter was born&amp;quot; is making the rounds; thanks to Prentiss Riddle for alerting me to it.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; The best quote from it is the use case that involves the worst possible internet device in the world: text messages from a mobile phone.
I remember that @Jack’s first use case was city-related: telling people that the club he’s at is happening. “I want to have a dispatch service that connects us on our phones using text.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>