<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lewis Peters on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/lewis-peters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lewis Peters on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/lewis-peters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Two repaired shortwave receivers in one day !</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the fix-it-yourself department, two successful radio repairs in one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my dad&#39;s old Kenwood R-2000, a replaced 100ma 5x20mm fuse brought it back to life. The antenna fuse search took a rather long time to get started, but the help of the UMARC club and Dean KD8VXR was enough to unearth the right part. For reference the Mouser part number is 693-0034.3107 for a Schurter fuse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my old Sony ICF-2010, a fresh set of AA batteries for the computer was enough to get it going again. I&#39;m especially happy about the Sony because I had feared that it was a complicated repair. There&#39;s some corrosion on the battery terminals and I might be forewarned that would be the first thing to look at again. A discussion of another repair is written up by &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlenot.com/?p=1481&#34;&gt;KE1RI&lt;/a&gt; to replace an audio capacitor, fortunately I haven&#39;t had to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both stations are tuned to R Havana Cuba&#39;s Sunday night programming on 6000 KHz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Doc&#34; title=&#34;Doc&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961. During his tenure, Lew served as department head from 1971 to 1975, taught Anatomy, Physiology and Parasitology, and in 1980 received a contract from the National Park Service to study parasites at Isle Royale. He retired in 1996 after 35 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew was a member of St. Michael Catholic Church and Marquette Rotary Club. He is survived by his wife, Kathy Peters of Marquette; children, Raymond (Velquis) Peters of Indianapolis, IN, Matthew (Elizabeth) Peters of Austin, TX, Dan (Jennifer) Peters of Tallahassee, FL, Edward (Deborah Fisch) Vielmetti of Ann Arbor, MI, Stephen (Paula) Vielmetti of Milwaukee, WI and Anne (Douglas) Moody of Vancouver, WA; grandchildren, Nicolette &amp;amp; Elizabeth Peters, Zack and Ava Peters, Garrett, Bryson &amp;amp; Reese Peters, Saul and Jonathan Vielmetti, Marshall, Nathan, Sophia and Zevon Vielmetti, Graham and Spencer Moody; sister, Robyn (David) Messner of Jensen Beach, FL; numerous nieces &amp;amp; nephews; and special family friend&#39;s, Tim Glover and his family. He was preceded in death by his parents, first wife, Oneita &#34;Beth&#34; Peters and a brother, Edward Peters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew&#39;s family would like to thank the staff of Brookridge Heights and Lake Superior Hospice for the wonderful care they provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A memorial service will be held on Monday, March 9, 2015 at 3:00 p.m. at the Canale-Tonella Funeral Home with Deacon David Adler officiating. Visitation will be held from 1:00 p.m. until the time of the service in the funeral home. Inurnment will take place at Park Cemetery. In lieu of flowers, memorials can be directed to the Biology Department at NMU in care of the NMU Foundation or the Lake Superior Land Conservancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canale-Tonella Funeral Home is assisting the family where memories may be shared at canalefuneral.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>