<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lewis Peters on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/lewis-peters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lewis Peters on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/lewis-peters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two repaired shortwave receivers in one day !</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 22:04:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-17-two-repaired-shortwave-receivers-in-one-day-/</guid>
      <description>From the fix-it-yourself department, two successful radio repairs in one day.
For my dad&#39;s old Kenwood R-2000, a replaced 100ma 5x20mm fuse brought it back to life. The antenna fuse search took a rather long time to get started, but the help of the UMARC club and Dean KD8VXR was enough to unearth the right part. For reference the Mouser part number is 693-0034.3107 for a Schurter fuse. For my old Sony ICF-2010, a fresh set of AA batteries for the computer was enough to get it going again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.
He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>