<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kale on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/kale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kale on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/kale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and onion curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-02-14-chicken-and-onion-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 21:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-02-14-chicken-and-onion-curry/</guid>
      <description>Saveur Magazine has a recipe for a chicken and onion curry from January 27, 2010. It took a little more than an hour to cook, but the results were very much worth it - delicious, and worth repeating.
We had the meal with rice, kale, and a daikon raita from food.com that I kind of liked but which was not a big hit with the rest of the table.
The current meal planning regime here uses a Google calendar and a question at the end of every meal: do you want this again, and how many weeks before we have it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I turned 99 cents worth of kale into half a gallon of delicious ice cream</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-22-kale-into-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-22-kale-into-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Learn this one weird trick&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Grocery stores hate him&amp;rdquo;
Really though it&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple. Lucky&amp;rsquo;s had a sale on kale for 99 cents, so I bought one bunch. The clerk rang it up at $2.49, and when I asked, they said it was organic. I figured I had pulled it from the wrong bin, whatever.
Get home, cook the kale (it&amp;rsquo;s delicious; recipe below). Check the twist tie to check my mistake, and find out that the kale wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually organic, and that I was overcharged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer dinner</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-summer-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 11:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-summer-dinner/</guid>
      <description>Dinner: roasted red peppers, roasted green beans, boiled potatoes, cool and crunchy red pepper and yellow tomato salad with balsamic, kale, and either eggs or bratwurst depending on your preferences. I really prefer cooking in the summertime!
Discussion on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2015 Farmers Market report</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-august-farmers-market-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 16:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-august-farmers-market-report/</guid>
      <description>At Ann Arbor Farmers Market:
Red Haven peaches 🍑, potatoes 🍠, kale, green onions, tomatoes, red peppers, and a cherry snow cone for my shopping companion.
(Testing to see how the emoji comes out; I didn&amp;rsquo;t see a kale emoji.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Kale with corn and green onions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-28-kale-with-corn-and-green-onions/</guid>
      <description>This recipe for kale with corn and green onions works well enough with frozen corn, but I&amp;#39;m sure it would be better with fresh. You cook with the ingredients you have, not the ingredients you want to have. We&amp;#39;re lucky to have fresh kale at the farmers market!
Ingredients:
 oil for frying garlic 1 bag kale corn - frozen, if you must, but fresh would be better green onions - chopped soy sauce  Method:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report for June 27, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 12:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</guid>
      <description>mostly pulled from twitter, but also from some field reporting from your fearless market reporter.
The Farmer&amp;#39;s Marketer (Kim Bayer) notes
&amp;quot;Committee forming to determine if year round indoor farmers market viable in downtown Ann Arbor.&amp;quot; Open House 7.8.09. 3:30-7pm. Eaton Bldg.
I don&amp;#39;t have a URL to point to for this one for more details but you could ask Kim.
Jeff McCabe is on a misson to create &amp;quot;as many hoop houses in our area as these efforts can muster&amp;quot;; he has resources to support two of them to be built this fall, contact him for the application due July 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.
March 21, 2009!&amp;#0160;
  Apples  Baked goods  Beef  Beet greens  Beets  Bison  Biscotti  Cider  Cupcakes  Delicious chocolate cookies  Cultivated mushrooms  Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)  Dulce du leche  Eggs  Honey  Jams &amp;amp; jellies  Kale  Lamb  Maple Syrup  Onions  Popcorn  Potatoes  Delicate salad greens  Radishes  Spinach  Tamales  Winter squash   +&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>