<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Urry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-urry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in John Urry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 23:05:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/john-urry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;After the car&#34;, John Urry and Kingsley Dennis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 23:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-after-the-car-john-urry-and-kingsley-dennis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kingsley Dennis and John Urry have a new book out, &amp;ldquo;After The Car&amp;rdquo;.&amp;nbsp; I have a review copy on the way from the publisher; until it arrives, you can see the intro and the index from the Amazon link below.&amp;nbsp; This is an oddly appropriate text to anticipate the week GM went bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Allow me for a brief moment to indulge. I would
like to inform you that my co-authored book titled &amp;lsquo;After the Car&amp;rsquo; has
now been published (finally!), and is currently sitting idly in Amazon.
See - &lt;br&gt;
&lt;iframe marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=superpatron-20&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;asins=0745644228&amp;amp;md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&amp;amp;fc1=000000&amp;amp;IS2=1&amp;amp;lt1=_blank&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;amp;bc1=000000&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Generally
the book is &amp;lsquo;academic-ish&amp;rsquo; and I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting any of you to buy!
Although concerned with the car the book is also about the &amp;lsquo;future&amp;rsquo; and
addresses issues of a post peak-oil society. If you should feel so
inclined, or know of anyone who might be mildly interested, I would be
happy that you pass on the news. Below is the blurb:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; It is difficult to imagine a world
without the car, and yet that is exactly what Dennis and Urry set out
to do in this provocative new book. They argue that the days of the car
are numbered: powerful forces around the world are undermining the car
system and will usher in a new transport system sometime in the next
few decades. Specifically, the book examines how several major
processes are shaping the future of how we travel, including:&lt;br&gt;• Global warming and its many global consequences&lt;br&gt;• Peaking of oil supplies&lt;br&gt;• Increased digitisation of many aspects of economic and social life&lt;br&gt;• Massive global population increases&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The
authors look at changes in technology, policy, economy and society, and
make a convincing argument for a future where, by necessity, the
present car system will be re–designed and re–engineered. Yet the
book also suggests that there are some hugely bleak dilemmas facing the
twenty first century. The authors lay out what they consider to be
possible ‘post–car’ future scenarios. These they describe as ‘local
sustainability’, ‘regional warlordism’ and ‘digital networks of
control’. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;After The Car&lt;/em&gt; will be of great interest to
planners, policy makers, social scientists, futurologists, those
working in industry, as well as general readers.&lt;br&gt;Some have
described the 20th Century as the century of the car. Now that century
has come to a close – and things are about to change. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>