<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 11:08:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>another day, another network, another cup of coffee</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 11:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</guid>
      <description>Some notes from the table at the People&#39;s Food Co-op.
My Saturday routine is to go to the farmer&#39;s market and to the food co-op. I have been doing this for a long time, more than a decade at least. When the boys were smaller they always came along, but now I head out solo.
There is a small cadre of folks who I know from town and from Twitter who also have the same habit, and we compare notes on line as to what is at market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2011 U-Pick strawberry season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-michigan-2011-u-pick-strawberry-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 13:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-michigan-2011-u-pick-strawberry-season/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s collected reports from the places that I&amp;#39;m on mailing lists for U-Pick strawberry season for 2011 near Ann Arbor. Comments welcomed. &amp;#0160;The June 2011 &amp;quot;strawberry moon&amp;quot; (full moon) is June 15.
Whitaker&amp;#39;s Berry Farm in Ida, MI (about 30 miles S of Ann Arbor.)&amp;#0160;opens Thursday, June 9, 2011 at 8:00 a.m. U-Pick $1.30/#, $3.25/qt prepicked. &amp;#0160;&amp;quot;Those wanting real large amounts for canning and freezing, may wish to wait until closer to June 15th, which is when peak season should begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report, third Saturday in May 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-third-saturday-in-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 18:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-third-saturday-in-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s what some people have written about recently in their writings about the Ann Arbor Farmers Market, especially looking at produce that&amp;#39;s at market, new vendors and old, how people are doing and checking the weather.
The one constant is that everyone seems to have gotten a lot of rain. Here&amp;#39;s a map of the last 7 days of precipitation.
Some notes:
Eggs: Grandma from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen brought 137 dozen eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report, third Saturday in March 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-farmers-market-march-third-saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 17:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-farmers-market-march-third-saturday/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s the market report for the third Saturday in March, 3/19/2011, at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market.
Eggs were plentiful, $3/doz and up.&amp;#0160;Donna&amp;#0160;Puehler&amp;#0160;from Delta, Ohio who owns Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen said her chickens were enjoying the out of doors.
The most lovely ornamental I saw were the pussy willows from Jan Upston at Wasem Fruit Farm&amp;#0160;in Augusta Township. &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;
Molly Notarianni, the market manager, talked to me about plans for a new Wednesday evening market, which will only feature prepared foods and fresh produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Westside Farmers Market on hold due to zoning restrictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>If you can figure out the City of Ann Arbor zoning, you&amp;#39;re better than me.
The Westside Farmers Market, which has been holding court in the parking lot of Zingerman&amp;#39;s Roadhouse, has put off its 2009 season until zoning issues get resolved.&amp;#0160; Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Westside Farmers&amp;#39; Market is currently &amp;quot;on hold&amp;quot; due to zoning restrictions from the city of Ann Arbor.
The Ann Arbor News story by Judy McGovern reads</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday: menu plan, Used Cars, 1880s ann arbor panorama</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</guid>
      <description>The menu plan for tonight for the late supper for the resident scholar: spring salad w/asparagus, oyster mushrooms from Alpena, eggs from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen, spinach from Brines Farm, savory tofu from the coop, and a curry dressing. The boys will probably get something a lot simpler.
I wish I had rhubarb to have made stewed rhubarb but I got there to market too late.&amp;#0160; A stewed rhubarb is a compote, which is not to say a compost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.
March 21, 2009!&amp;#0160;
  Apples  Baked goods  Beef  Beet greens  Beets  Bison  Biscotti  Cider  Cupcakes  Delicious chocolate cookies  Cultivated mushrooms  Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)  Dulce du leche  Eggs  Honey  Jams &amp;amp; jellies  Kale  Lamb  Maple Syrup  Onions  Popcorn  Potatoes  Delicate salad greens  Radishes  Spinach  Tamales  Winter squash   +&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>