<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>another day, another network, another cup of coffee</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 11:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes from the table at the People&#39;s Food Co-op.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Saturday routine is to go to the farmer&#39;s market and to the food co-op. I have been doing this for a long time, more than a decade at least. When the boys were smaller they always came along, but now I head out solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a small cadre of folks who I know from town and from Twitter who also have the same habit, and we compare notes on line as to what is at market. If you track the @a2market account you will see notes on fruits in season, what is missing from market (no peaches this year, alas), and anything else notable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time a new bit of social network software appears, and the usual crowd of early adopters descends in a nova mob to try it out. This week&#39;s novelty is &#34;ello&#34;, which is basically a variant on Twitter. There are a small number of structural changes - replies are threaded - and a large number of missing features. Mostly it&#39;s new and another chance to reinvent yourself and claim a network identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Saturday morning market Twitter routine does not have much to fear from &#34;ello&#34;. It takes a long time to accumulate enough people who share geography, a common interest, and a particular technological proficiency. &#34;ello&#34; does not have that, and it really isn&#39;t ever likely to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Saturday routine includes a lot of people who I don&#39;t know from online. Making the rounds at market and saying hi and making small talk does not depend on getting people to sign up for your net or upgrade their phone. In cases where the online ritual is also tied to space and time, you use whatever system worked last time, not something new!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2011 U-Pick strawberry season</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-michigan-2011-u-pick-strawberry-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 13:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-07-michigan-2011-u-pick-strawberry-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88f8148a970d-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Strawberry-culturist&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88f8148a970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88f8148a970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Strawberry-culturist&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Here&amp;#39;s collected reports from the places that I&amp;#39;m on mailing lists for U-Pick strawberry season for 2011 near Ann Arbor. Comments welcomed. &amp;#0160;The June 2011 &amp;quot;strawberry moon&amp;quot; (full moon) is June 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whittakersberryfarm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Whitaker&amp;#39;s Berry Farm&lt;/a&gt; in Ida, MI (about 30 miles S of Ann Arbor.)&amp;#0160;opens Thursday, June 9, 2011 at 8:00 a.m. U-Pick $1.30/#, $3.25/qt prepicked. &amp;#0160;&amp;quot;Those wanting real large amounts for canning and freezing, may wish to wait until closer to June 15th, which is when peak season should begin.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rowesproducefarm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Rowe&amp;#39;s Produce Farm&lt;/a&gt; in Rawsonville, MI (about 10 miles E of Ann Arbor) is opening on Thursday, June 9, 2011 at 7:00 a.m. U-Pick $1.57/#. Call for picking conditions 734-482-8538 as they may have to close Friday for more ripening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.degrootsstrawberries.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;DeGroot&amp;#39;s Strawberries&lt;/a&gt; in Gregory, MI (about 45 miles NW of Ann Arbor) said &amp;quot;mid June&amp;quot; on its Facebook page about 3 weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gibb&amp;#39;s Berry Farm in Eaton Rapids (about 60 miles WNW of Ann Arbor) is bringing strawberries to the Ann Arbor Farmers Market. Price was $4.25 /quart on the first week of June, often prices change during the season and dip during peak times when produce is more plentiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m looking forward to a Father&amp;#39;s Day berrypicking trip, which should be about right. My notes from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/06/2008-strawberry.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;2008 strawberry season&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;reminded me to bring more water while picking; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/06/strawberry-and-.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;2007 strawberry season&lt;/a&gt; notes an early use of Twitter to coordinate berrypicking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is from &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=6CpCAAAAYAAJ&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Illustrated Strawberry Culturist&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(Fuller, 1887).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report, third Saturday in May 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-third-saturday-in-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 18:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-21-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-third-saturday-in-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s what some people have written about recently in their writings about the Ann Arbor Farmers Market, especially looking at produce that&amp;#39;s at market, new vendors and old, how people are doing and checking the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one constant is that everyone seems to have gotten a lot of rain. Here&amp;#39;s a map of the last 7 days of precipitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0154326f295c970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 13&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0154326f295c970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0154326f295c970c-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 13&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eggs: Grandma from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen brought 137 dozen eggs. Her tractor is still in the mud up to its axles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhubarb: $3.50 for about 1.5 # from Wasem&amp;#39;s Fruit Farm. Cynthia from Mother&amp;#39;s Kitchen has this recipe for&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://motherskitchen.blogspot.com/2011/05/stewed-rhubarb.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Stewed Rhubarb&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;ll need any miracles today.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; And if you are new to canning, you won&amp;#39;t need any miracles either&amp;#0160;if give rhubarb a try.&amp;#0160; Canning stewed rhubarb is ridiculously simple - all you need is rhubarb and sugar.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greens: It was the week for a bag of braising greens, knowing full well that greens needed to stay in the fridge a day or two before being eaten and thus the spinach was a bad choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolate: Paul from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Mindo_Chocolates&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Mindo Chocolates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;was there sampling some amazing freshly roasted chocolate. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report, third Saturday in March 2011</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-farmers-market-march-third-saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 17:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-farmers-market-march-third-saturday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the market report for the third Saturday in March, 3/19/2011, at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eggs were plentiful, $3/doz and up.&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;Donna&amp;#0160;Puehler&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;from Delta, Ohio who owns Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen said her chickens were enjoying the out of doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most lovely ornamental I saw were the pussy willows from &lt;strong&gt;Jan Upston &lt;/strong&gt;at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wasemfruitfarm.com/market.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Wasem Fruit Farm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;in Augusta Township. &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molly Notarianni&lt;/strong&gt;, the market manager, talked to me about plans for a new Wednesday evening market, which will only feature prepared foods and fresh produce. Molly noted that the expanding local food cart market means that a whole set of new vendors will be at the new market this summer. The market would be a pilot project, running for this summer only to gauge vendor and public interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Goetz_Greenhouse&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Goetz Greenhouse&lt;/a&gt; brought this lovely chard; photo courtesy &lt;strong&gt;Karl Rosaen&lt;/strong&gt;, Real Time Farms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3558b63970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Goetz-chard-real-time-farms-march-2011&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3558b63970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3558b63970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Goetz-chard-real-time-farms-march-2011&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realtimefarms.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Real Time Farms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is as always a good source of market data and details; see the&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realtimefarms.com/market/ann-arbor-farmers-market/2011/3/19&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt; Ann Arbor Farmers Market page for 3/19/2011&lt;/a&gt; for more photos and vendor information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor District Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/farmersmarket&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;oral history of the Farmers Market&lt;/a&gt;, with interviews with a number of vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti shops at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market with his son Saul Vielmetti. Reach him at edward.vielmetti@gmail.com or 734-330-2465.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Westside Farmers Market on hold due to zoning restrictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 14:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-18-ann-arbor-westside-farmers-market-on-hold-due-to-zoning-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you can figure out the City of Ann Arbor zoning, you&amp;#39;re better than me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.westsidefarmersmarket.com/&#34;&gt;Westside Farmers Market&lt;/a&gt;, which has been holding court in the parking lot of Zingerman&amp;#39;s Roadhouse, has put off its 2009 season until zoning issues get resolved.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ann Arbor&amp;#39;s Westside Farmers&amp;#39; Market is currently &amp;quot;on hold&amp;quot; due to zoning restrictions from the city of Ann Arbor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2009/05/zoning_violation_shuts_down_an.html&#34;&gt;The Ann Arbor News story by Judy McGovern reads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The property&amp;#39;s C3 zoning is the most relaxed of the three commercial categories, but it doesn&amp;#39;t allow the kind of &amp;quot;special use&amp;quot; permits that can be issued to properties in the more restrictive C1 and C2 categories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That appears to be an oversight in the regulations, and city officials are working to change the code, said City Council Member Carsten Hohnke, whose 5th Ward includes the property.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/City_Clerk/Ordinances/Pages/Online%20City%20Code.aspx&#34;&gt;city code&lt;/a&gt;; it appears that C3 zoning (5:10.23) for the properly in question is preferential to properties where automotive access is the characteristic function:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;Normal-Level&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote l0&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;(1)&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal; font-style: italic; text-decoration: none; display: inline;&#34;&gt;Intent.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;
            &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal; font-style: normal; text-decoration: none; display: inline;&#34;&gt;The
design and regulations of this district are set up to provide for
certain types of commercial activities which have characteristics in
common. In this district, the customer usually comes directly to the
particular establishment by automobile, making a separate stop for each
errand. Comparison shopping activity is less than in the central
business district. Since there is little essential interdependence of
activities, establishments can be dispersed over considerable areas
with each establishment having its own automobile parking. Good
automobile accessibility is essential to these districts. The uses
permitted, because of their lack of intense pedestrian activity and
their required contact with auto access, would be incompatible in the
central business district.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#0160;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The get-out-of-jail-free card is this language on special use permits, as described in the C-1 Local Business District language (5.10.15):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;Normal-Level&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;l1 blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;(h)&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;The City Council may, by resolution, designate
certain dates and locations as special events temporary outdoor sales
areas. Said resolution shall include conditions and standards of
conduct to be in force for outdoor sales and displays on private
property. A property owner who wishes to conduct outdoor sales and
displays on his or her private property, as provided for in the council
resolution, shall first apply for and receive a Zoning Compliance
Permit by the date designated in the resolution. The conditions and
standards contained in the resolution shall be conditions of the Zoning
Compliance Permit issued to a property owner. Failure to comply with
the conditions set in the resolution shall be a violation of this
ordinance section and shall be grounds to revoke all permits granted to
the property owner for the duration of the special event identified in
the resolution.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The question, is appears, is whether the C-1 &amp;quot;special events&amp;quot; language applies to C-3 zoning, or whether there is no permit possible for someone in the automotive, big box, strip mall and huge parking lot district to ever do a temporary outdoor sales area.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given that Zingerman&amp;#39;s had a previous permit for this use I suspect there&amp;#39;s some other story not yet being told.&amp;#0160; Your guess is as good as mine what prompted this whole snafu.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/index.ssf/2009/04/development_dirt_dda_drug_stor.html&#34;&gt;Zingerman&amp;#39;s has had disputes with the city about their 322 E Kingsley property&amp;#39;s zoning&lt;/a&gt; , which have come to council recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>saturday: menu plan, Used Cars, 1880s ann arbor panorama</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-saturday-menu-plan-used-cars-1880s-ann-arbor-panorama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The menu plan for tonight for the late supper for the resident scholar: spring salad w/asparagus, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.williamsfamilyfungi.com/&#34;&gt;oyster mushrooms from Alpena&lt;/a&gt;, eggs from Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen, spinach from Brines Farm, savory tofu from the coop, and a curry dressing. The boys will probably get something a lot simpler.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I had rhubarb to have made &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tonytantillo.com/vegetables/rhubarb.html&#34;&gt;stewed rhubarb&lt;/a&gt; but I got there to market too late.&amp;#0160; A stewed rhubarb is a compote, which is not to say a compost.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rhubarbinfo.com/rhubarb-poison.html&#34;&gt;Don&amp;#39;t eat the leaves&lt;/a&gt;, they have oxalic acid which is toxic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/teacherpatti&#34;&gt;teacherpatti&lt;/a&gt; for the Farmers Market heads-up, to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/suchpretty&#34;&gt;suchpretty&lt;/a&gt; for the pretty things to look at at market, and to @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/roosroast&#34;&gt;roosroast&lt;/a&gt; and crew resplendent in ties selling coffee with a movie recommendation (here&amp;#39;s a scene from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQiTRQTiMGY&#34;&gt;Used Cars&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;You ought to buy it right now.&lt;br /&gt;This Buick is you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing that came up along the way was a mention of the Arborwiki stickers; here&amp;#39;s the art that I have&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/ArborWiki_Stickers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/images/2/2f/ArborWiki-3x4.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current market location is just to the north of the old location, which was the grounds of the county courthouse visible upper right in this 1880s panorama view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ms-rteCustom-ArticleByline&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 21, 2009!&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Apples&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Baked goods&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beef&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beet greens&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Biscotti&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cider&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cupcakes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delicious chocolate cookies&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cultivated mushrooms&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dulce du leche&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Eggs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Honey&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jams &amp;amp; jellies&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kale&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lamb&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Maple Syrup&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Onions&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Popcorn&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Potatoes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delicate salad greens&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Radishes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Spinach&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tamales&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Winter squash &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ms-rteCustom-ArticleHeadLine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;+&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>