<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Farmers Market on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 11:08:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>another day, another network, another cup of coffee</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 11:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-another-day-another-network-another-cup-of-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes from the table at the People&#39;s Food Co-op.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Saturday routine is to go to the farmer&#39;s market and to the food co-op. I have been doing this for a long time, more than a decade at least. When the boys were smaller they always came along, but now I head out solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a small cadre of folks who I know from town and from Twitter who also have the same habit, and we compare notes on line as to what is at market. If you track the @a2market account you will see notes on fruits in season, what is missing from market (no peaches this year, alas), and anything else notable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time a new bit of social network software appears, and the usual crowd of early adopters descends in a nova mob to try it out. This week&#39;s novelty is &#34;ello&#34;, which is basically a variant on Twitter. There are a small number of structural changes - replies are threaded - and a large number of missing features. Mostly it&#39;s new and another chance to reinvent yourself and claim a network identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Saturday morning market Twitter routine does not have much to fear from &#34;ello&#34;. It takes a long time to accumulate enough people who share geography, a common interest, and a particular technological proficiency. &#34;ello&#34; does not have that, and it really isn&#39;t ever likely to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Saturday routine includes a lot of people who I don&#39;t know from online. Making the rounds at market and saying hi and making small talk does not depend on getting people to sign up for your net or upgrade their phone. In cases where the online ritual is also tied to space and time, you use whatever system worked last time, not something new!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>