<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bloggers Secret on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bloggers-secret/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bloggers Secret on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 01:32:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bloggers-secret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging is easy.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 01:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</guid>
      <description>Blogging is easy. All you have to do is write twice a day without any direction and stay on target until you find out what the target was.
Everyone who writes a blog struggles with the tension between staying on focus and writing whatever you damn well please. Without an editor to nix your worst impulses, you can easily go far, far astray from whatever initial impulse brought you to writing and whatever attractive topic led you to have readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Amazing Posts EVERY TIME (and why you shouldn&#39;t)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 19:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>Mack Collier has an amazing post about how to write amazing posts. (Here, go read it.) I&#39;m here to tell you why to listen to his advice but not to write like he does.
Collier calls for an amped-up style of blog writing, one that is full of lists and awesome photographs and cheerleading enthusiasm. That&#39;s a good style to recognize, and you&#39;ll see it in some of the most popular parts of the web - the Buzzfeed or Upworthy style, with headlines like &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish quickly, edit at leisure, make the first version coherent.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 22:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</guid>
      <description>Publish quickly. The network rewards the first person to show up on the scene to describe what is going on, and it&amp;#39;s important to get a version of that story underway promptly.&amp;#0160;
Edit at leisure.&amp;#0160;The editing process takes time, and it shouldn&amp;#39;t be unduly rushed. If necessary, work at it one paragraph at a time, and publish each paragraph after it is finished. Every single piece of work can be improved at any time by an edit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On emptying your inbox into your blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-on-emptying-your-inbox-into-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 22:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-on-emptying-your-inbox-into-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>This seems to be a plausible strategy - people send you interesting things that you want to remember, so you post them to your blog so that when you search for them you find them.
If the blog seems overful of cut and paste of events sometimes, it&amp;#39;s not that I&amp;#39;m necessarily going to be going to all of them - who can do that with two kids at home! - but that it seemed like the best way to deal with an influx of details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000&#43; posts and ten years later, what have I learned from blogging?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-2000-posts-and-ten-years-later-what-have-i-learned-from-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 19:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-2000-posts-and-ten-years-later-what-have-i-learned-from-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Typepad says that I have 2,000 posts in this weblog. &amp;#0160;Some of them, to be sure, are drafts that were abandoned, and some are scheduled in the future, but that&amp;#39;s as good a round number as I need to reflect on blogging (the practice and the habit).
I&amp;#39;ve been blogging since April 1999; here&amp;#39;s the first month or so of posts. &amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;They were edited oh so patiently with vi, and at the time the genre was new enough that I could say with confidence &amp;quot;Huh, this daily weblog stuff is too hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogger&#39;s secret: don&#39;t feed the trolls</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-09-bloggers-secr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 12:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-09-bloggers-secr-1/</guid>
      <description>This advice goes back as far as Usenet, and really is about managing the comments in your weblog.&amp;nbsp; And it&#39;s simple advice: don&#39;t post any comments to your blog that you find inappropriate.
This means filtering out spam, either by hand or (better) with the help of spam fighting tools; it means taking fake comments from people who are paid to post them and neutering them of their commercial value; and it means taking your angry, abusive critics off your page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: familiar searches in unfamiliar databases</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-1/</guid>
      <description>One in an occasional series on secrets to blogging.
If your site is like mine, it gets a sizable fraction of its readership from people who type things into the main Google search index and click through. More than half the traffic comes from that, and on a typical day 80%+ of the visitors are new.
Search traffic coming from other search engines are relatively small, almost to the level of being noise - even though, for some search terms, the arguably &#39;best answer&#39; for those searches is not anything I wrote but some targeted, focused search in some other database other than GOOG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: cumulative advantage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 15:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>One in an occasional series on the secrets of blogging.
The longer that you have been blogging, the more materials you have accumulated, and the more things you have written that may possibly attract search traffic.
By tuning into this effect you can get distant early warning of when people are interested in topics that are seasonal, and start work on them before they hit mainstream news and media.&amp;nbsp; Your cumulative advantage is not just that you&#39;ve done your homework last year, but that you know when people are starting to be interested in seasonal things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the blogger&#39;s secret: how to write a great weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Write well, write often, and write with passion.&amp;quot; (Jack Shedd)
Jack has more in a rant that&amp;#39;s making the rounds; the opposite of the great weblog is the &amp;quot;cheese food manufacturing&amp;quot; that Merlin Mann observes as dominating the world of &amp;quot;pro bloggers&amp;quot;.
In some sense, this triple of {well, often, with passion} echoes the computer systems lament of {better, faster, cheaper} - &amp;quot;pick any two&amp;quot; is the easiest answer. It&amp;#39;s possible to write often and well, but what you get is a wire service, with a style guide that homogenizes the passion right out of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>