<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bloggers-secret/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/bloggers-secret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging is easy.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 01:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-23-blogging-is-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging is easy. All you have to do is write twice a day without any direction and stay on target until you find out what the target was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who writes a blog struggles with the tension between staying on focus and writing whatever you damn well please. Without an editor to nix your worst impulses, you can easily go far, far astray from whatever initial impulse brought you to writing and whatever attractive topic led you to have readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A useful mechanism of self-guidance for me is to ensure that every post fits into at least one existing category. It doesn&#39;t help that I have to date created &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/archives.html&#34;&gt;two hundred and thirty eight categories&lt;/a&gt; into which something might fit. That at least is honest; this weblog doesn&#39;t have one narrow focus, and it&#39;s been running for ten years, so some divergence of interests is not just anticipated but expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an illustration of the simplicity of this approach, see Dan Cooney&#39;s painting &#34;The Simplicity of the Semantic Web&#34;. (All rights reserved, used with permission.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b037f3a8f970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b037f3a8f970c&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Dan-cooney-simplicity-of-the-semantic-web&#34; title=&#34;Dan-cooney-simplicity-of-the-semantic-web&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b037f3a8f970c-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Amazing Posts EVERY TIME (and why you shouldn&#39;t)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 19:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-how-to-write-amazing-posts-every-time-and-why-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mackcollier.com/&#34;&gt;Mack Collier&lt;/a&gt; has an amazing post about how to write amazing posts. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mackcollier.com/how-to-write-awesome-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;Here, go read it.&lt;/a&gt;) I&#39;m here to tell you why to listen to his advice but not to write like he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collier calls for an amped-up style of blog writing, one that is full of lists and awesome photographs and cheerleading enthusiasm. That&#39;s a good style to recognize, and you&#39;ll see it in some of the most popular parts of the web - the Buzzfeed or Upworthy style, with headlines like &#34;New Dads Learned One Weird Tip To Make Their Blogs POP!&#34;  These are interesting and amazing the way a slow-motion televised car chase is amazing. They are not, however, how I write my weblog - and not a style for you, unless you are in a weird job where counting pageviews drives your wages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The net has enough of the hyperkinetic blog fodder to go around. What it doesn&#39;t have, and needs, is bloggers who take an old-school approach to blog writing and who are careful and respectful of their audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is about writing to pick up an audience, one that would read everything you had to say and comment on it. That means not only writing about what people might click on because their eye got caught by a headline, but also writing the day-in, day-out thematic and topical materials that someone who cares more than a little bit will follow along for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is figuring out what sorts of regular obscure parts of the world that you cover and being a go-to resource for that issue when it comes up in the world. To illustrate, I bring you Dave Petley&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.agu.org/landslideblog/&#34;&gt;Landslide Blog&lt;/a&gt;. You won&#39;t find awesome stock photography, but you will find a whole series of carefully selected photos that illustrate the stories he writes about landslides and their origin and effect. Or see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://somethingscrawlinginmyhair.com/&#34;&gt;Backyard Arthropod Project&lt;/a&gt;, which is a lovingly illustrated guide to the bugs of Atlantic Mine, MI with great macrophotography of bugs, beetles, insects, spiders, slugs, and more. There are dozens more like this, people who toil away in relative obscurity writing carefully about their craft, and I love them. It&#39;s a style that lends itself to slowly but surely being a recognized expert in your field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love weblogs that take a narrow view on some interesting part of the world and are thorough in how they document it. They don&#39;t need weird tricks or compelling lists or catchy copy to make their mark on the world. Rather, they illustrate and tell a whole series of stories that might never have been told before, told by someone who is expert in their corner of the world. Even though they might only get a few followers compared to Buzzfeed, they add a lot more to our understanding of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is the topic of the 8 December 2013 #&lt;a href=&#34;http://tchat.io/rooms/blogchat&#34;&gt;blogchat&lt;/a&gt; chat, at 9pm Eastern time).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish quickly, edit at leisure, make the first version coherent.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 22:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-19-first-version-coherent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Publish &lt;strong&gt;quickly&lt;/strong&gt;. The network rewards the first person to show up on the scene to describe what is going on, and it&amp;#39;s important to get a version of that story underway promptly.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;strong&gt;at leisure.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;The editing process takes time, and it shouldn&amp;#39;t be unduly rushed. If necessary, work at it one paragraph at a time, and publish each paragraph after it is finished. Every single piece of work can be improved at any time by an edit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the first version &lt;strong&gt;coherent&lt;/strong&gt;. A first version that stands alone and accurate to itself might just be a concise headline and a lead paragraph. Each subsequent edit can grow the whole thing, but the first thing that hits the wire should be so fully composed that there would be no more reason to keep working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/bitSecure/status/49248378525192192&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Shh, trade secrets are secret.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; - Mark D. Adams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On emptying your inbox into your blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-on-emptying-your-inbox-into-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 22:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-02-on-emptying-your-inbox-into-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a plausible strategy - people send you interesting things that you want to remember, so you post them to your blog so that when you search for them you find them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the blog seems overful of cut and paste of events sometimes, it&amp;#39;s not that I&amp;#39;m necessarily going to be going to all of them - who can do that with two kids at home! - but that it seemed like the best way to deal with an influx of details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000&#43; posts and ten years later, what have I learned from blogging?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-2000-posts-and-ten-years-later-what-have-i-learned-from-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 19:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-24-2000-posts-and-ten-years-later-what-have-i-learned-from-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typepad says that I have 2,000 posts in this weblog. &amp;#0160;Some of them, to be sure, are drafts that were abandoned, and some are scheduled in the future, but that&amp;#39;s as good a round number as I need to reflect on blogging (the practice and the habit).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~emv/project/vacuum/weblog-0001.html&#34;&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been blogging since April 1999; here&amp;#39;s the first month or so of posts. &amp;#0160;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;They were edited oh so patiently with vi, and at the time the genre was new enough that I could say with confidence &amp;quot;Huh, this daily weblog stuff is too hard. &amp;quot; and have that be a novel observation. &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;Jorn Barger at the time noted in his Robot Wisdom blog&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Times; line-height: normal; &#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Times; line-height: normal; &#34;&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160; &amp;#0160;&amp;quot;New weblog from Ed Vielmetti, who&amp;#39;s been on the Net forever.&amp;quot; &amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Times; line-height: normal;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ten years later I&amp;#39;m still at it. &amp;#0160;I suppose that I might have just enough experience in blogging that even I would think of myself as an expert at it, for what that&amp;#39;s worth. &amp;#0160;(As Forbes once said about my bright ideas, &amp;quot;Too bad everyone else had the same idea.&amp;quot;) And like any good blogger, I have a nice pat seven item list to share with you - because people who read blogs love pointless numbered lists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;1. &amp;#0160;Repetition is the soul of the net. &amp;#0160;If I&amp;#39;ve told you this once, I&amp;#39;ve said it a thousand times. &amp;#0160;Every year, regular as clockwork, there is an audience for people reading about where to pick blueberries, how to get election returns, who makes the best paczki, what to do on your birthday or your kids birthday. &amp;#0160;You get a free pass to repeat your good content over and over again annually, do it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;2. &amp;#0160;Don&amp;#39;t think too much. &amp;#0160;Think more, perhaps, than you would in writing a 140 character twitter message; think twice before saying something that you&amp;#39;d regret before a judge or in print. &amp;#0160;But don&amp;#39;t think more than twice, and be prepared to post something before it&amp;#39;s absolutely polished and done. &amp;#0160;Sometimes the people who read what you are writing will fill in the blanks for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;3. &amp;#0160;Omit needless words. &amp;#0160;Your screen is small, and the day is short. &amp;#0160;Don&amp;#39;t ramble on and on - fill the text input box until it&amp;#39;s full, and hit post.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;4. &amp;#0160;Leave comments. &amp;#0160;Comments on other people&amp;#39;s blogs will remind them of stuff that you have collected that&amp;#39;s relevant; comments on your own blog will let you update things that are changing without going back and re-editing. &amp;#0160;Every once in a while, you&amp;#39;ll unearth someone who is a bona fide expert who reads the news clippings you pasted together and gets an insight.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;5. &amp;#0160;Don&amp;#39;t feed the trolls. &amp;#0160;(And there are so many of them.) &amp;#0160;Squash idiot comments, commercial spam comments, irritating comments, stray trackbacks, and any other crud out of your blog as soon as you see it. &amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;6. &amp;#0160;Did I mention pointless numbered lists? &amp;#0160;Use them. &amp;#0160;Everyone&amp;#39;s attention span is short, and lists let people know just how far along they are before they can be done. &amp;#0160;They let you jump from idea to idea without pesky transitions, and make it easy for someone else to cut and paste that one good idea hiding in your pile of dreck and take it for their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;7. &amp;#0160;Quote liberally (and credit liberally). &amp;#0160;Half the battle in blogging is figuring out who knows more than you do about something; the other half the battle is figuring out who is uselessly ignorant but still writes a lot. &amp;#0160;If you are good and thorough and relentless in clipping out good paragraphs from other people&amp;#39;s work, and you are good and thorough and relentless in doing the searches that end up in results that aren&amp;#39;t on everyone else&amp;#39;s front page of Google, you can learn a lot and share a lot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been averaging a post a day for a long time. &amp;#0160;Some days more, some days less, and some blogs are mercifully left for dead from ideas that didn&amp;#39;t pan out. &amp;#0160;I wish I knew what it all meant. &amp;#0160;In some ways it reminds me a lot of my short lived but illustrious high school forensics career of impromptu speaking - all it really shows is that you can be coherent on short notice about pretty much anything, and that you have enough diligence to keep being coherent for a long time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;If someone can tell me what career that qualifies me for, please let me know - I&amp;#39;m looking.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogger&#39;s secret: don&#39;t feed the trolls</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-09-bloggers-secr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 12:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-09-bloggers-secr-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This advice goes back as far as Usenet, and really is about managing the comments in your weblog.&amp;nbsp; And it&#39;s simple advice: don&#39;t post any comments to your blog that you find inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means filtering out spam, either by hand or (better) with the help of spam fighting tools; it means taking fake comments from people who are paid to post them and neutering them of their commercial value; and it means taking your angry, abusive critics off your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the spam fighting front, your choice of platform matters a lot.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve been happy with Typepad&#39;s service, though it lets a few things go by the admin tools make it possible to unpublish something fairly quickly.&amp;nbsp; People using Wordpress use its default Akismet tool with good success.&amp;nbsp; If your comment tool doesn&#39;t aggressively screen for spam, you need a better system.&amp;nbsp; In many cases, Trackback is a source of spam as well; I ended up completely blocking that just to save the hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a huge and messy market in fake comments, helped by systems like Amazon&#39;s Mechanical Turk that anonymize the payments for them.&amp;nbsp; Every so often the fake commenter actually has something marginally interesting to say, so I tend to let those through but rewrite the target URL of their post to remove the commercial value from it.&amp;nbsp; Life is too short to live with commenter bots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When on the odd chance that you have an angry, abusive critic aimed at you - the sort of person who would scribble profanities or spew personal attacks - the only reasonable remedy is to remove the text.&amp;nbsp; Ideally, you do that without acknowledging it, or if it&#39;s important for context to keep some fragment of it around, a traditional method is to edit the text to make it semi-legible e.g. by removing the vwls or st*rr*ng th* ess*nt**l p*rts **t.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Let the critics and nastygrams find their own site, and force their authors out into the open.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that blogs emerged from the Internet primordial soup in the late 1990s was that Usenet had degenerated into spam, fake posts, and abuse; by holding the discussion on a web page you control, you could start to control it.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;That makes the world a little bit harder to follow when discussions fly around, but in exchange you get to be not just author but (critically) also editor of your own publication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: familiar searches in unfamiliar databases</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One in an occasional series on secrets to blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your site is like mine, it gets a sizable fraction of its readership from people who type things into the main Google search index and click through. More than half the traffic comes from that, and on a typical day 80%+ of the visitors are new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search traffic coming from other search engines are relatively small, almost to the level of being noise - even though, for some search terms, the arguably &#39;best answer&#39; for those searches is not anything I wrote but some targeted, focused search in some other database other than GOOG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re doing your homework, you should be able to do homework for your readers. Find a popular search term that&#39;s driving traffic to an existing page, identify an alternate database with better resources than what a simple Google search will unearth, and add to your existing copy. I find Google Books to be a good source, especially for pre-1922 materials which give some historical perspective on the matter. Amazon and your favorite library are good book reference sources. Thousands of other databases have awful user interfaces and hidden away content which can be selectively referenced for good effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is neatly summarized by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Fuller_(social_epistemologist)&#34;&gt;Steve Fuller&lt;/a&gt; in his 2001 book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Knowledge-Management-Foundations-KMCI-Press/dp/0750673656&#34;&gt;Knowledge management foundations&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public ignorance thus ascends to the meta-level of not knowing the expert system in which the relevant expertise is contained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;and thus as a blogger you have an opportunity to pull from one unfamiliar expert system into a familiar non-expert system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogger&#39;s secret: cumulative advantage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 15:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-05-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One in an occasional series on the secrets of blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer that you have been blogging, the more materials you have accumulated, and the more things you have written that may possibly attract search traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By tuning into this effect you can get distant early warning of when people are interested in topics that are seasonal, and start work on them before they hit mainstream news and media.&amp;nbsp; Your cumulative advantage is not just that you&#39;ve done your homework last year, but that you know when people are starting to be interested in seasonal things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, this afternoon&#39;s traffic included this query:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:04
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=prices of pumpkins&#34; target=&#34;_new&#34; href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=prices%20of%20pumpkins&#34;&gt;Google Search:&amp;nbsp; prices of pumpkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which reminds me that Halloween is right around the corner, and that it&#39;s time to check out the pumpkin crop and locate a source for this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone says to you that they won&#39;t write about or invest in topics that have limited &amp;quot;shelf life&amp;quot; - the annual outhouse races, the chicken broil, the first tomato, football parking, the opening day of deer season - smile and know that those one time events happen every year and if you ever write something reasonable about it you&#39;ll start getting repeat visits next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the blogger&#39;s secret: how to write a great weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-22-the-bloggers-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Write well, write often, and write with passion.&amp;quot;  (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigcontrarian.com/2008/07/21/tacky/&#34;&gt;Jack Shedd&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack has more in a rant that&amp;#39;s making the rounds; the opposite of the great weblog is the &amp;quot;cheese food manufacturing&amp;quot; that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.43folders.com/2008/07/21/blog-pimping&#34;&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt; observes as dominating the world of &amp;quot;pro bloggers&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some sense, this triple of {well, often, with passion} echoes the computer systems lament of {better, faster, cheaper} - &amp;quot;pick any two&amp;quot; is the easiest answer.  It&amp;#39;s possible to write often and well, but what you get is a wire service, with a style guide that homogenizes the passion right out of the system.&amp;#0160;Writing well and with passion and not often gives you an occasional lovely essay but not enough page views to get ads worth anything.  And writing often and with passion generally is all about passion for attention and for the ad-fueled money that goes with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>