<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback Loop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/feedback-loop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feedback Loop on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 17:33:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/feedback-loop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No comments, thanks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-no-comments-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-no-comments-thanks/</guid>
      <description>For the most part, I don&amp;#39;t comment on newspaper web sites any more; it&amp;#39;s generally more effective to engage by writing the same message directly to the reporter or to the editor.
In some cases, good results can also be had by sending messages directly to the parties involved in the story, and cc&amp;#39;ing (or bcc&amp;#39;ing) the reporter in question.
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spectral overseers as guides to good online behavior</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</guid>
      <description>James Poulos in a comment on Ricochet on the role of editors:
Writers now have competing pressures -- to be witty, quick, ironic, noticeable, flip, to dispatch every clay pigeon tossed up by a culture pandemic with pigeons; but also to self-edit, to self-moderate, to be reticent at the right time, to pussyfoot expertly, to pick battles, to avoid perils, to besmirch rarely, to duck blame, to satisfy spectral overseers. This is a serious pickle, is it not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you measure and value attention?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-26-how-do-you-measure-and-value-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-26-how-do-you-measure-and-value-attention/</guid>
      <description>We measure things that are easy to measure about media, like
 time on page, time on site  click through rate  conversion rate to some desired action  frequency of interaction  responsiveness of interaction  hot spots that are getting lots of attention  &amp;quot;lag&amp;quot;, whatever that is, but everyone knows what it is   In general, media that have small amounts of lag are good for gaming, because you can play many small bets and iteratively define a better result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 31, 2008: ICOS: Wendy Espeland, Northwestern University, &#34;How to Study Numbers, or: A Different Kind of Quantitative Sociology&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-october-31-2008-icos-wendy-espeland-northwestern-university-how-to-study-numbers-or-a-different-kind-of-quantitative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 11:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-october-31-2008-icos-wendy-espeland-northwestern-university-how-to-study-numbers-or-a-different-kind-of-quantitative/</guid>
      <description>(from the ICOS mailing list)
Join ICOS this Friday to hear from Wendy Espeland of Northwestern’s Sociology Department. &amp;#0160;Espeland has developed the concept of commensuration in markets—efforts to value diverse things in a common
metric, from finance and human organs to environmental degradation. &amp;#0160;Her talk this week examines the effect of widely-publicized US News &amp;amp; World Report rankings on law schools and their conception of legal education.
The Discipline of Rankings: Public Measures, Decoupling, and Organizational Change (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>