<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/feedback-loop/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/feedback-loop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No comments, thanks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-no-comments-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-08-23-no-comments-thanks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the most part, I don&amp;#39;t comment on newspaper web sites any more; it&amp;#39;s generally more effective to engage by writing the same message directly to the reporter or to the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, good results can also be had by sending messages directly to the parties involved in the story, and cc&amp;#39;ing (or bcc&amp;#39;ing) the reporter in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spectral overseers as guides to good online behavior</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-spectral-overseers-as-guides-to-good-online-behavior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;James Poulos in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ricochet.com/conversations/Where-Are-All-the-Editors/(comment)/8368&#34;&gt;comment on Ricochet&lt;/a&gt; on the role of editors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Writers now have competing pressures -- to be witty, quick, ironic, noticeable, flip, to dispatch every clay pigeon tossed up by a culture pandemic with pigeons; but also to self-edit, to self-moderate, to be reticent at the right time, to pussyfoot expertly, to pick battles, to avoid perils, to besmirch rarely, to duck blame, to satisfy spectral overseers. This is a serious pickle, is it not? And yet it now appears to be the cost of doing business. Possibly, this is the internet imitating life.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved the &amp;quot;satisfy spectral overseers&amp;quot; bit. Where did that come from? Who gets that description?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knute Rockne, in a H.W. Wilson Company 1942 biography:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;blockquote&gt;No one will ever tackle the job of football coach at the University of Notre Dame without a sense of solemn obligation, for the spirit of Knute Rockne still hovers above the campus like a spectral overseer. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walt Disney, as referenced in two 1990s management texts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Eisner came aboard and cleared the deck, bringing in new managers, most of whom had never met Disney. The new crew, freed of the spectral overseer, began to create a culture that was more sophisticated than stodgy, more adventurous than cautious, more ambitious than content.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Edward McCullough, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaltheatre.org/location/ghost.htm&#34;&gt;National Theatre&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The shade of Actor John Edward McCullough, a popular American thespian of the 1800&amp;#39;s, is said to roam the premises of the theatre in the dark of night. No longer thirsting for an audience&amp;#39;s applause, the once famed star performer has taken on the lonely role of ghostly custodian and spectral overseer, checking to be sure that all is in readiness for the next performance.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one welcome the editorial guidance of our spectral overseers. But whose guidance should we channel for this task? &amp;#0160;That&amp;#39;s some other post about people (not necessarily &amp;quot;writers&amp;quot;) who have mastered the online form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you measure and value attention?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-26-how-do-you-measure-and-value-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-26-how-do-you-measure-and-value-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We measure things that are easy to measure about media, like&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time on page, time on site
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click through rate
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conversion rate to some desired action
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frequency of interaction
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;responsiveness of interaction
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hot spots that are getting lots of attention
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;lag&amp;quot;, whatever that is, but everyone knows what it is
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

In general, media that have small amounts of lag are good for gaming, because you can play many small bets and iteratively define a better result. As the amount of lag increases, the attention games change, and you start to get out of the realm of reality-based feedback and into the realm of ROI fictions, and systems that have enormous expensive command and
control infrastructures.&amp;#0160;
&lt;p&gt;It’s one thing to hack people’s attention about tomorrow if you start working on it today, and something very different to plan a campaign that results in their attention (or the fulfillment of their desire) 6 or 12 or 18 or 120 months hence.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally written for &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/kevindoylejones&#34;&gt;Kevin Doyle Jones&lt;/a&gt;, and published obscurely in 2007; rescued and republished with only minor edits 3 years hence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 31, 2008: ICOS: Wendy Espeland, Northwestern University, &#34;How to Study Numbers, or: A Different Kind of Quantitative Sociology&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-october-31-2008-icos-wendy-espeland-northwestern-university-how-to-study-numbers-or-a-different-kind-of-quantitative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 11:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-29-october-31-2008-icos-wendy-espeland-northwestern-university-how-to-study-numbers-or-a-different-kind-of-quantitative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(from the ICOS mailing list)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join ICOS this Friday to hear from Wendy Espeland of Northwestern’s Sociology Department. &amp;#0160;Espeland has developed the concept of commensuration in markets—efforts to value diverse things in a common&lt;br /&gt;
metric, from finance and human organs to environmental degradation. &amp;#0160;Her talk this week examines the effect of widely-publicized US News &amp;amp; World Report rankings on law schools and their conception of legal education.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://icos.cms.si.umich.edu/sites/icos.cms.si.umich.edu/files/Espeland.pdf&#34;&gt;The Discipline of Rankings: 
Public Measures, Decoupling, and Organizational Change (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Sauder 
University of Iowa 
 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sociology.northwestern.edu/faculty/espeland/home.html&#34;&gt;Wendy Espeland 
Northwestern University &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article demonstrates the value of Foucault‟s conception of discipline for understanding organizational responses to rankings. Using a case study of law schools, we explain why rankings have permeated law schools so extensively and why these organizations have been unable to buffer these institutional pressures. Foucault‟s 
depiction of two important processes, surveillance and normalization, show how rankings 
change perceptions of legal education through both coercive and seductive means. This 
approach advances organizational theory by highlighting conditions that affect the 
prevalence and effectiveness of buffering. Decoupling is not determined solely by the 
external enforcement of institutional pressures or the capacity of organizational actors to 
buffer or hide some activities. Members‟ tendency to internalize these pressures, to 
become self-disciplining, is also salient. Internalization is fostered by the anxiety that 
rankings produce, by their allure for the administrators who try to manipulate them, and 
by the resistance they provoke. Rankings are just one example of the public measures of 
performance that are becoming increasingly influential in many institutional 
environments, and understanding how organizations respond to these measures is a 
crucial task for scholars. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>