<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fukushima Japan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/fukushima-japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fukushima Japan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 14:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/fukushima-japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fukushima fallout plume animation</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-18-fukushima-fallout-plume-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-18-fukushima-fallout-plume-animation/</guid>
      <description>Click to animate this plume of fallout from the Fukushima nuclear disaster in Japan, as produced by ZAMG&amp;#0160;(Zentralanstalt für Meteorologie und Geodynamik,&amp;#0160;Viennese Central Institute for Meteorology and Geodynamics, Vienna Austria). Via the Harvard Japan Sendai Earthquake Data Portal.
Note that this is not the hoax map &amp;quot;Nuclear fallout&amp;quot; described by Snopes.
Of the map, the authors write (in German)
 Zur Farbskalierung ist zu sagen, dass die rote Skala Gebiete kennzeichnet, die seit Beginn des Unfalles mit einer Effektivdosis von&amp;#0160;maximal&amp;#0160;100 Milli-Sievert pro Stunde belastet waren (laut Informationen der IAEO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fukushima maps</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-13-fukushima-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-13-fukushima-maps/</guid>
      <description>Radiation is escaping from the Fukushima nuclear power plant after multiple explosions at the site.
A widely distributed graphic, attributed to&amp;#0160;Australian Radiation Services and purporting to show fallout patterns, is confirmed to be a hoax. A map from ZAMG in Vienna models the plume.
This post has been updated Friday, March 18 2011 at 3:00 pm to add the ZAMG info, which is on its own page.
News sources
Wikipedia: Fukushima I Nuclear Power Plant; Fukushima I nuclear accidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tsunami maps for March 2011 Honshu earthquake</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-11-tsunami-maps-for-march-2011-honshu-earthquake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 06:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-11-tsunami-maps-for-march-2011-honshu-earthquake/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#39;s a view from Ann Arbor of the Japanese earthquake. A magnitude 8.9 earthquake struck off the coast of Honshu, Japan at 5:46 UTC, 2:46 pm Japan time, and 12:46 a.m. Eastern Time, about 6200 miles from Ann Arbor. Damage is extensive, with the city of Sendai hit hard, and concern for the&amp;#0160;Fukushima Nuclear Plant. The effects of the tsunami stretched across the Pacific.
This post was last updated Friday, March 11 2011 at 11:50 a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>