<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jim Benson on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jim-benson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jim Benson on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 23:55:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jim-benson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Github Issues and Waffle.io as a personal kanban board</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-github-waffle-kanban-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 23:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-github-waffle-kanban-board/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Github issues to track my personal todo list for quite some time now, and since November I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Waffle.io to help that process.
Waffle in this use is a view of a series of queues in my todo list. Most everything that I&amp;rsquo;m not doing now lives in the &amp;ldquo;backlog&amp;rdquo; queue, which I try to keep to less than 100 just to keep myself sane. (At more than 100 there&amp;rsquo;s usually a lot of duplicates; at less than 100 I&amp;rsquo;m probably not acknowledging that there&amp;rsquo;s something to be done).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Kanban from Jim Benson and Modus Cooperandi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-personal-kanban-from-jim-benson-and-modus-cooperandi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-personal-kanban-from-jim-benson-and-modus-cooperandi/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m reading PersonalKanban.com. &amp;nbsp;There are at the simplest only two rules:
 1. Visualize your work 2. Limit your work-in-progress  to which is added a third, &amp;ldquo;prioritize&amp;rdquo;. The rest is commentary.
Jim is good at commentary, so the blog and the rest of the effort is well worth reading. Here&amp;rsquo;s Personal Kanban 101 to start.
  Personal Kanban 101  from Jim Benson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban; or, management by post-it note</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 21:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-28-kanban-or-manag/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a few years back about a mini-kanban that John Hritz had put together to remember to refill washer fluid. There are a lot of colorful sticky notes around my workplace these days, so I thought I&#39;d read up on how kanban-inspired systems are being used for process management in the software development and other non-manufacturing worlds.  Some inspiring examples (with post-its to illustrate):  Corey Ladas on Kanban systems for software engineering:  A perfect state of flow may be very difficult, or at least uneconomical, to achieve in a robust product development process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>