<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Snow Computing on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-snow-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Snow Computing on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 22:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-snow-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Snow Removal Ordinance</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-02-06-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-removal-ordinance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 22:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-02-06-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-removal-ordinance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because it&#39;s that time of year when sidewalks are full of snow and ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4:60. Snow and ice.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All snow and ice which has accumulated prior to 6:00 a.m. on a public sidewalk adjacent to property not zoned residentially shall be removed by the owner or occupant by noon. Immediately after the accumulation of ice on such sidewalk it shall be treated with sand, salt or other substance to prevent it from being slippery and the ice shall be removed within the time limits of this paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for sidewalks defined by section 4:51(1)(b) and (c), within 24 hours after the end of each accumulation of snow greater than 1 inch, the owner or occupant of every residentially zoned property shall remove the accumulation from the adjacent public sidewalk and walks and ramps leading to a crosswalk. The accumulation may be from any source including precipitation and drifting. Immediately after the accumulation of ice on such sidewalk, it shall be treated with sand, salt or other substance to prevent it from being slippery and the ice shall be removed within 24 hours after accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All property zoned PL (public land) shall have snow and ice removed as if it held the same zoning classification as the adjacent property. The removal of snow and ice shall mean free of snow and ice for the entire constructed width and length of the sidewalk, including walks and ramps leading to a crosswalk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Ord. No. 5-86, 2-20-86; Ord. No. 77-92, § 1, 12-21-92; Ord. No. 49-01, § 3, 10-15-01; Ord. No. 13-15, § 1, 10-21-13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4:61. Removal by city.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If snow or ice is not removed or treated as required section 4:60, the city may notify the owner or occupant of the violation of section 4:60. This notification may be made in person, by telephone, by mail or by written notice left at the property. If the owner or occupant fails to remove snow or ice within 24 hours of the notification of violation of section 4:60, the city may cause such snow or ice to be removed. The owner (as indicated by the records of the assessor) of the adjacent property shall then be charged the actual cost of the sidewalk clearance, plus an administrative fee of $50.00. If that charge is not paid within 45 days, it may be assessed against the parcel under section 1:292 of this Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Ord. No. 83-70, 10-13-70; Ord. No. 46-77, 1-23-78; Ord. No. 81-81, 12-7-81; Ord. No. 5-86, 2-20-86; Ord. No. 77-92, § 2, 12-21-92)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4:62. Financial hardship.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon proof of financial hardship the Administrator may authorize charges under section 4:61 to be paid in installments, to be reduced, or to be cancelled and will be subject to Council approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Ord. No. 11-75, 2-10-75; Ord. No. 5-86, 2-20-86)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4:63. Penalty.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner (as shown on the assessor&#39;s records) of the property with adjacent sidewalks which do not comply with section 4:60, who fails to comply with the notice given in section 4:61, shall be responsible for a civil infraction, which shall be punishable by a civil fine of not less than $100.00 for the first offense, not less than $250.00 and up to $500.00 for the second offense, and not less than $500.00 and up to $1,000.00 for each additional or subsequent offense within a 2-year time period, plus costs and all other remedies available by statute.. The maximum fine for any offense shall not exceed $1,000.00. If the penalty is not paid within 45 days, it may be assessed against the parcel under section 1:292 of this Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Ord. No. 5-86, 2-20-86; Ord. No. 77-92, § 3, 12-21-92; Ord. No. 25-04, § 4, 8-2-04)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan 5, 2014: Snow condition yellow: alert from Washtenaw County Snow Emergency Council</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-05-jan-5-2014-snow-condition-yellow-alert-from-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 21:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-05-jan-5-2014-snow-condition-yellow-alert-from-washtenaw-county-snow-emergency-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SNOW CONDITION YELLOW &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WASHTENAW COUNTY EMERGENCY OPERATIONS CENTER &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SUN JAN 5 2014 8:50 PM EST &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DUE TO SIGNIFICANT SNOWFALL ACCUMULATION, NUMEROUS MOTOR VEHICLE ACCIDENTS AND DETERIORATING TRAVEL CONDITIONS THIS EVENING, THE WASHTENAW COUNTY SNOW EMERGENCY COUNCIL HAS ISSUED A SNOW CONDITION YELLOW FOR WASHTENAW COUNTY UNTIL 12:00 NOON ON MONDAY. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A SNOW CONDITION YELLOW MEANS VERY HAZARDOUS DRIVING CONDITIONS EXIST WITH HEAVY SNOW OR ICE, DRIFTING, OR LIMITED VISIBILITY. TRAFFIC IS MOVING AT REDUCED SPEEDS WITH MAJOR HIGHWAYS BEING MAINTAINED IN FAIR CONDITION, BUT LOCAL ROADS MAY BE IMPASSABLE. MOTORISTS ARE URGED THAT IF THEY MUST DRIVE, USE EXTREME CARE AND ALLOW FOR A SIGNIFICANT DRIVE TIME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://local.nixle.com/alert/5119106/&#34;&gt;Nixle&lt;/a&gt; from the Washtenaw County Sheriff&#39;s Office. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on snow emergencies, from this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/38908575/Snow-Emergency-Plan-2009-2010&#34;&gt;2009-2010 snow emergency plan&lt;/a&gt;. Some details may have changed in the 5 years since this plan was published, but it should still be relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-apocalyptic snow shopping, Meijer edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-04-pre-apocalyptic-snow-shopping-meijer-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-04-pre-apocalyptic-snow-shopping-meijer-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The day&#39;s news brings stories of shoppers trying to get their grocery shopping
in before the storm of January 5, 2014 hits. Trader Joe&#39;s and Kroger were packed, and it looks like at least a few Ann Arbor area Meijer stores had shelves stripped bare. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnarbor.com&#34;&gt;Damn Arbor&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the Carpenter Road &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/meijer&#34;&gt;@meijer&lt;/a&gt; has been picked clean. Should I be worried? &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/sQgGoaK7PR&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/sQgGoaK7PR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Damn Arbor (@damnarbor) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/damnarbor/statuses/419659369098145794&#34;&gt;January 5, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chronicles of the Belleville Meijer in preparation for the end times: Decimated green rack &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/Gkd8y5kN0Y&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Gkd8y5kN0Y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ben Franklin (@BFSEsq) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BFSEsq/statuses/419649682281734144&#34;&gt;January 5, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City of Ann Arbor Snow Emergency Ordinance, 10:143</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 16:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-04-city-of-ann-arbor-snow-emergency-ordinance-10143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is current as of January 4, 2014. Check on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://library.municode.com/HTML/11782/level3/TITXTR_CH126TR_ARTXIAC.html#TITXTR_CH126TR_ARTXIAC_10_143SNEM&#34;&gt;Municode&lt;/a&gt; web site for the absolute latest information, though it&#39;s unlikely that the ordinance will change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that as of 9:30pm January 5, 2014, there is no snow emergency declared for the City of Ann Arbor, but Washtenaw County has declared a &#34;Snow Condition Yellow&#34;. From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/TheCityOfAnnArbor&#34;&gt;City of Ann Arbor Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor is not declaring a snow emergency at this point, but we are recommending residents move their cars off the streets, if possible, to make it easier for city trucks to plow the full width of streets. Moving your car will also keep it from being plowed in with snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A snow emergency declared on Dec. 25-26, 2002, but City Council voted in Jan. 6, 2003 to waive or reduce fines from tickets issued during that event; this &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2011/03/02/monthly-milestone-institutional-memory/&#34;&gt;according to the Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:143. Snow emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1)
Prohibited parking for snow removal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a)
Whenever the City Administrator finds, on the basis of snow, sleet, freezing rain, or on the basis of a weather forecast, that weather conditions make it necessary to restrict parking to allow removal of existing or forecasted snow, the Administrator may declare a snow emergency and put in effect an odd/even parking prohibition on some or all city streets by providing notice of the prohibition in the manner prescribed by this section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b)
When an odd/even parking prohibition is in effect, no person shall park a vehicle or permit a vehicle owned by him or her to remain parked on the following described portions of any street; provided, however, that the parking prohibition of this subsection does not apply during the hours of 8:00 p.m. to 12:00 midnight, so that vehicles can be positioned to comply with the next day&#39;s prohibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(i)
On days having uneven dates, vehicles are prohibited from parking on the side of the street having even street addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(ii)
On days having even dates, vehicles are prohibited from parking on the side of the street having uneven street addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2)
Notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a)
The prohibitions provided in this section shall take effect when the Administrator causes notice of such prohibitions to be publicly announced by radio stations, Community Television Network and any other suitable media outlet with normal operating ranges covering the city. The prohibitions shall then take effect at the time provided in the announcement. The Administrator may also cause notice of the parking prohibition to be published in newspapers of general circulation when feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b)
The parking prohibitions provided by this section shall remain in effect until the Administrator makes a public announcement of the termination of the prohibitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3)
Nothing contained in this section permits parking at times or places where it is otherwise prohibited by this Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Ord. No. 48-01, § 3, 11-19-01; Ord. No. 38-02, § 1, 10-21-02; Ord. No. 2-03, § 1, 2-18-03)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>