<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 23:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Plane finding with dump1090</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-07-02-plane-finding-with-dump1090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2015 I wrote briefly about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/&#34;&gt;plane spotting with dump1090&lt;/a&gt;.
In short, many airplanes have ADS-B transponders which squawk out
their location, airspeed, and current conditions, and you can pick
up those transmissions using an inexpensive RTL-SDR tuner stick and
a simple antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into this again to see if I can get a better
understanding of how it works as well as to take advantage of a year plus
of software development. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the state of the art
circa July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware: I&amp;rsquo;m using a Nooelec NESDR Mini 2 tuner stick plugged into a MacBook Air
as a portable plane-finding system. I have a Raspberry Pi 2 which looks
like it could be a permanent installation for this, though the recommendation
for busy skies is a Pi 3 which is enough faster to make a difference if you
have a good antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antenna: The Mini 2 comes with a small whip antenna with a magnetic base, and I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing
a larger antenna. There are scads of antenna designs out there for inexpensive
small antennas tuned to 1090 Mhz, but I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet. There are also
filters and amplifiers that can improve plane-finding capabilities; also not
there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software: Here&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;ve made progress. The dump1090 software has been
forked several times, each time with just a little bit more sophistication
on the visual display as well as refinements of the decoding system. The
one I&amp;rsquo;m using right now is a fork by &amp;ldquo;mutability&amp;rdquo;, available at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mutability/dump1090&lt;/a&gt; . It&amp;rsquo;s notable for being
designed to run on a Raspberry Pi, as well as a bunch of small changes
in the display that make it more pleasant to use than the older software
I had been using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Range: Just like I reported back in 2015, the typical results from my
house are a range of 40-50 nautical miles in every direction. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
yet taken the rig to my favorite plane-spotting cafe &amp;ndash; the Biggby at
Platt and Ellsworth &amp;ndash; which has a clear view of the southern sky at
a good elevation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweaking the setup: Aside from changing out the hardware and relocating
the antenna, the tweakable changes seem to be adjusting the gain control
on the SDR. Initial experiments don&amp;rsquo;t give me strong conclusions as to
what&amp;rsquo;s best. The reviews of a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/ADS-B-1090MHz-Band-pass-SMA-Filter/dp/B010GBQXK8&#34;&gt;$20 band pass filter&lt;/a&gt; are
promising for increasing the range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeding the data elsewhere: One of the collective efforts around looking for
airplanes is the ability to share the data with commerical and non-commericial
systems that aggregate data from around the world. I&amp;rsquo;m digging
&lt;a href=&#34;http://planefinder.net&#34;&gt;http://planefinder.net&lt;/a&gt; which has a nifty near-real-time feed of ADS-B
and FAA and other international data for tracking flights. Planefinder is
fast enough that I can hear an airplane overheard, check the display,
and figure out which flight is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellite plane finding: The &lt;a href=&#34;https://directory.eoportal.org/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/gomx-3&#34;&gt;GOMX-3 satellite&lt;/a&gt;
has an SDR with ADS-B reception and has successfully
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airtrafficmanagement.net/2016/07/fr24-completes-satbased-adsb-tracking/&#34;&gt;fed data to Flightradar24&lt;/a&gt;,
another commericial plane tracking system. ADS-B receivers are expected
to be installed on the Iridium system over the next couple of years,
which should over time provide improved global coverage and visibility
into the current status of aircraft over oceans and the poles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it looks like: I don&amp;rsquo;t have a permanent installation running,
but if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the airspace above San Diego, you can
see Phil Karn KA9Q&amp;rsquo;s system at &lt;a href=&#34;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&#34;&gt;http://maggie.ka9q.net:8080/dump1090/gmap.html&lt;/a&gt;
noting that he&amp;rsquo;s in easy range of picking traffic into LAX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area APRS network status, January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APRS is the &amp;ldquo;Automatic Position Reporting Service&amp;rdquo;, a
system for sharing information about the position of
participating amateur radio stations. Clients transmit
position reports on 144.39 Mhz; digipeaters repeat
these reports to other monitoring stations; and various
IGate sites monitor transmissions and send their findings
to &lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi&#34;&gt;aprs.fi&lt;/a&gt; which collects worldwide data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent memory there has been an APRS digipeater in
Chelsea, Michigan with wide area coverage, good enough
to pick up travellers on I-94 west of Ann Arbor.
The Chelsea digirepeater is currently off the air,
which leaves a coverage gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one station within the city of Ann Arbor.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/KD8TDF&#34;&gt;KD8TDF&lt;/a&gt; is in southeast
Ann Arbor (EN82dg). Its coverage is enough to pick up
part of I-94 right adjacent to town. A second station,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://aprs.fi/info/a/AB3DC-1&#34;&gt;AB3DC-1&lt;/a&gt; is the
Ann Arbor/Ypsi Rx-iGate, w8pgw.org, right near St.
Joe&amp;rsquo;s Hospital (EN82eg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussion at last night&amp;rsquo;s ARROW meeting included a
desire to experiment on 2 meters with digital modes.
Dave New &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qrz.com/DB/N8SBE&#34;&gt;N8SBE&lt;/a&gt; talked
about software defined radio and GNU Radio, and demonstrated
monitoring car key-fobs on UHF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APRS is a very old and useful digital mode, and I
am hopeful that local network conditions will improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave New N8SBE to speak at ARROW on Software Defined Radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dave New N8SBE will be speaking at the January 2016 meeting of
the ARROW radio club on the topic of Software Defined Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will present an introduction to GNU Radio and the GNU Radio
Companion visual programming environment, and the HackRF One Software
Defined Transceiver from Great Scott Gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demo will include a disucssion of receiver and transmitter flow
graphs, as well as resources to learn more about
digital signal processing using the HackRF One and GNU Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARROW meets Wednesday, January 13, 2016, from 7:00 p.m. to 9:00 p.m. at
Washtenaw Community College, room BE-172 or nearby room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details contact ARROW at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w8pgw.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.w8pgw.org/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>