<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/the-broken-egg/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/the-broken-egg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a2b3 lunch non-summary for the Broken Egg</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-13-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-broken-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-13-a2b3-lunch-nonsummary-broken-egg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lunch at The Broken Egg with the a2b3 crew. We had 17 people show up,
which is about 2x what had been the normal attendance. The restaurant
was very accomodating, and everyone was well fed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizing lunch is the highlight of my week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of things were discussed, here&amp;rsquo;s a few of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Perseid meteor shower peaked last night, notes Linda Diane Feldt,
who saw a few shooting stars from her cabin in Lyndon Township. I listened
to meteor scatter radio transmissions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livemeteors.com&#34;&gt;http://www.livemeteors.com&lt;/a&gt; which
listens for reflections of Toronto TV signals using a directional antenna
from Washington DC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vintage baseball is happening in Chelsea and Dexter reports Patti Smith,
and she loves the uniforms. The next game is
Vintage Base Ball: Chelsea Monitors vs. Dexter Union
August 29 @ 2:30 pm - 4:30 pm in Chelsea at Veterans Park.
The teams are the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ChelseaMonitors&#34;&gt;Chelsea Monitors&lt;/a&gt; (facebook) and
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unionbbc.com/&#34;&gt;Dexter Union&lt;/a&gt;. Dexter has a game vs Port Huron
at St. Joseph Catholic Church (Mast and N. Territorial)
on Saturday, August 15th at 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s partners meeting is an open meeting, and Tom Meloche
was there. He reported that it&amp;rsquo;s a 2.5 hour event that&amp;rsquo;s carefully
time-boxed, so that they cover everything without going over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a2b3 regular and jazz singer David Bloom is performing tonight,
Thursday August 13, 2015, at the Chelsea Clock Tower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stickers! My print run of stickers from VGKids in Ypsilanti is in, and I brought
stickers to lunch. Thanks to everyone who chipped in to help with
printing costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>