<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prentiss Riddle on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/prentiss-riddle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prentiss Riddle on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 11:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/prentiss-riddle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Oblique strategies as a service</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-w12-4-oblique-strategy-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2017/2017-w12-4-oblique-strategy-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>In 1975, Brian Eno and Peter Schmidt collaborated on a card deck of strategies for overcoming creative blocks. This was produced in limited and somewhat varying editions, and when it escaped into the computing world at slightly later date, various electronic versions were produced (including one in FORTRAN). Prentiss Riddle noted some of this history in 2004.
The &amp;lsquo;oblique&amp;rsquo; code is simple; a file with strategies, one per line, and a function to return a random line from that file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, ERC South Main</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-21-daily-coffee-wifi-erc-south-main/</guid>
      <description>Espresso over ice at ERC South Main. This is now my favorite summer drink. Served in a cup with enough ice and you get the makings of a very strong iced latte, just add a little half and half.
The work of the morning is finishing up yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on sending postcards with Lob.com. Key to this effort is resizing your favorite images so that they meet the template. Fortunately I had the presence of mind seven years ago to write up my notes on using sips and Imagemagick for image manipulation and that helped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write for multiple social media channels at once</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-how-to-write-for-multiple-social-media-channels-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-12-how-to-write-for-multiple-social-media-channels-at-once/</guid>
      <description>I connected my Twitter feed to my Facebook feed; now I need to learn to write for both at once. Hard to do. Is there a way to be selective?
One suggestion, from long-time blogger Prentiss Riddle, is to write things first in your weblog and then syndicate them out to wherever you want them to go. This is said to behave well with systems like Facebook that reward outbound clicks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathan Schneider defends the memory theater</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-12-nathan-schneider-defends-the-memory-theater/</guid>
      <description>An essay published in Open Letters Monthly.
What concerns me about the literary apocalypse that everybody now expects—the at least partial elimination of paper books in favor of digital alternatives—is not chiefly the books themselves, but the bookshelf. My fear is for the eclectic, personal collections that we bookish people assemble over the course of our lives, as well as for their grander, public step-siblings. I fear for our memory theaters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How twitter and gopher were born, (or) why you should make it work on the worst system first</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-01-how-twitter-and-gopher-were-born-or-why-you-should-make-it-work-on-the-worst-system-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 15:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-01-how-twitter-and-gopher-were-born-or-why-you-should-make-it-work-on-the-worst-system-first/</guid>
      <description>this post on &amp;quot;how twitter was born&amp;quot; is making the rounds; thanks to Prentiss Riddle for alerting me to it.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; The best quote from it is the use case that involves the worst possible internet device in the world: text messages from a mobile phone.
I remember that @Jack’s first use case was city-related: telling people that the club he’s at is happening. “I want to have a dispatch service that connects us on our phones using text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Brown Jug, and other Michigan - Minnesota connections</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 14:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-08-the-little-brown-jug-and-other-michigan---minnesota-connections/</guid>
      <description>Since it&amp;#39;s game day (Michigan at Minnesota) I thought I&amp;#39;d link to at least a few connections between Michigan and Minnesota.
1.&amp;#0160; The Little Brown Jug is the trophy that goes back and forth between the two schools depending on which one wins the game.&amp;#0160; It was originally purchased as a water jug for the Michigan team on an away game to Minnesota in 1903, it was left behind after the game (a 6-6 tie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Tigre - &#34;Get off the Internet&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-28-le-tigre---get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 11:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-28-le-tigre---get/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Prentiss Riddle for this gem from Le Tigre.

(Get off the Internet!)
I&#39;ll meet you in the street
get the whole scoop at last.fm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>