<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ralph Welton on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/ralph-welton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ralph Welton on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 21:44:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/ralph-welton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>When is Ann Arbor going to have a full time building official?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 21:44:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-14-when-is-ann-arbor-going-to-have-a-full-time-building-official/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor does not have a full time building official, and the routine operations of the building department are suffering as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at a Building Board of Appeals meeting today, 14 May 2015. The group just barely met quorum and had just three members seated, with one member absent and one vacant position. The regular staff member who handles the meetings is on medical leave, and the building official who had been present at previous meetings (Ralph Welton) has left the city&#39;s employment under circumstances which have not been fully and adequately explained. The city has hired a contractor to handle the building official&#39;s role, but that contractor is not working on the day of this meeting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group&#39;s meetings are in Legistar, which I looked at at 8:30 a.m. today before a 1:30 p.m. meeting. Legistar should have details and staff reports for all of the items on the agenda, but as of 8:30 a.m. there was only the barest detail listed, with five parcels under review but no detail for any of those parcels and no information about old business to be reviewed. Several members of the board noted that they did not get any email from the building department reminding them that there was going to be a meeting, let alone informing them of the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to the meeting at 1:30 p.m. I find that one of the items was removed from the agenda (that&#39;s pretty typical) and there was a bare minimum of documentation for the other four items. Bare minimum in this case included photos but no writeup of the staff recommendation and no detail at all. There were also two surprise agenda items under old business, neither of which had any written supporting documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the meeting itself there was a fair amount of confusion. One unfortunate petitioner who was asking for a variance for basement apartment filled out his form asking for this as a Housing Board of Appeals request, but then someone (the petitioner or the city, not sure who) whited out the word &#34;Housing&#34; and replaced it with &#34;Building&#34;. Some substantial amount of time was spent sorting out which appeals board actually would address the appeal, and the petitioner felt that it should be the Housing Board of Appeals that would address a variance for occupancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course that discovers another problem. The Housing Board of Appeals, as currently constituted, has three members; but seven are specified by charter, and thus it does not have a quorum and cannot meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of Kafkaesque city do we live in where matters are best referred to a body that cannot meet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke up at public commentary at the end of the meeting, there being no opportunity to speak at the beginning, pointing out some of this sad state of affairs and especially encouraging the board to prepare more carefully for meetings in such a way that members of the public would be able to avail themselves of information about the matters coming before the board. Certainly there is public interest in some of the long-term dilapidated buildings that have come before the board - in particular 410 Miller, which has been a mess as long as I can recall - but there being no adequate agenda publicized there is no way for the public to be even aware that a discussion is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When is Ann Arbor going to have a full time building official? Without someone in an official position to make the department work, the city&#39;s systems for handling exceptional cases appears to be entirely and completely broken. I can only imagine that routine issues are under a similar sort of chaotic pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>