<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiki on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiki on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 16:33:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For machines, by machines: Wikipedia is for bots</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-for-machines-by-machines-wikipedia-is-for-bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 16:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-26-for-machines-by-machines-wikipedia-is-for-bots/</guid>
      <description>What is Wikipedia for? It&#39;s for bots.
This machine kills trolls: How Wikipedia’s robots and cyborgs snuff out vandalism writes up the work of the Wikipedia contributors who have written robots (bots) that automatically extirpate contributions to the encyclopedia that are unwanted.
Alas, the result of all of this highly efficient robot-driven editing is that many new editors first interaction with the system is not with a human being, but with a faceless robot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Marquette Localwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 21:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-28-building-a-marquette-localwiki/</guid>
      <description>I visit Marquette Michigan every summer to see family and catch up with friends and visit the place I went to high school. Every so often there&#39;s a reunion, but often it&#39;s just a matter of going back to the home town and figuring out what&#39;s up and what&#39;s what.
Since I&#39;ve been working on Arborwiki for the better part of eight years, I thought last year that I&#39;d give a try to make a Localwiki for Marquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of Ferguson, Missouri via the St Louis Localwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-21-making-sense-of-ferguson-missouri-via-the-st-louis-localwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 20:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-21-making-sense-of-ferguson-missouri-via-the-st-louis-localwiki/</guid>
      <description>The St Louis, Missouri Localwiki - http://localwiki.net/st-louis - was mostly empty when the events in Ferguson, MO started on August 9, 2014 with the death of 18 year old student Michael Brown. As with any event where there&#39;s a lot that&#39;s going on in an unfamiliar area, I was drawn to making some sense of what was happening. This has been especially true when the coverage on the #ferguson hashtag overwhelmed my Twitter feed, which had been usually quiet at night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jay Gatsby - the Wikipedia page from 2009, as edited by Dan Murphy, before the wikivandals took over</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-24-jay-gatsby-the-wikipedia-page-from-2009-as-edited-by-dan-murphy-before-the-wikivandals-took-over/</guid>
      <description>Dan Murphy wrote this biography of the fictional character Jay Gatsby for Wikipedia in 2009. Since then, the anonymous hordes of Wikipedia editors have not improved upon the page. Here is the 23 October 2009 version of &amp;quot;Jay Gatsby&amp;quot;, which is much better written than the current edition.
&amp;#0160;
Jay Gatsby&amp;#0160;is the&amp;#0160;titular character&amp;#0160;of&amp;#0160;F. Scott Fitzgerald&amp;#39;s 1925 novel&amp;#0160;The Great Gatsby. The character has become an archetype of self-made American men seeking to join&amp;#0160;High society&amp;#0160;and the name has become synonymous with successful businessmen with shady pasts in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Wikipedia is the great postmodern novel&#34; - Qworty and wikipedia as unreliable text</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-21-wikipedia-is-the-great-postmodern-novel-qworty-and-wikipedia-as-unreliable-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-21-wikipedia-is-the-great-postmodern-novel-qworty-and-wikipedia-as-unreliable-text/</guid>
      <description>Credit to Salon&amp;#39;s Andrew Leonard for the article &amp;quot;Revenge, ego, and the corruption of Wikipedia&amp;quot;, which unmasks wiki-troll Qworty and his pattern of anonymous mean-spirited edits to settle old grudges. Qworty - his real name is not important to my discussion of him - was a prolific Wikipedian. He routinely sabotaged the biographies of rival writers by doing things like removing lists of literary prizes they had won after they had died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorization and its discontents</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-30-categorization-and-its-discontents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 01:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-30-categorization-and-its-discontents/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia is going through one of its periodic existential crises, this time over the use of categories. A diligent editor created a category of &amp;quot;American women novelists&amp;quot; and began adding female novelists to it, and then removing them from the category &amp;quot;American novelists&amp;quot;. A predictable hue and cry ensued. James Gleick tells the story in some detail in the NY Review of Books, under the title &amp;quot;Wikipedia&amp;#39;s Women Problem&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from my talk on Arborwiki and Localwiki at eChicago, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 00:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-29-notes-from-my-talk-on-arborwiki-and-localwiki-at-echicago-2013/</guid>
      <description>I had the good fortune to talk about Arborwiki and Localwiki at eChicago in April 2013. Here are the notes that I took in preparation for the talk; the actual text of the talk varied from this, since I was speaking impromptu.
About Arborwiki
Who: More than a dozen core contributors over the lifespan of the project, plus many more who have made small edits to pages.
Where: Greater Ann Arbor - including Washtenaw County and the farmers who come to the Farmers Market from surrounding counties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locality vs notability</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-23-locality-vs-notability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-23-locality-vs-notability/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#0160;
 Localwiki  In Wikipedia, every article is measured against a broad global sense of &amp;quot;notability&amp;quot;. An individual or a topic has to be notable and newsworthy enough to be included, and though the standards vary there is some global consensus to what it means. If an article doesn&amp;#39;t meet the grade, it&amp;#39;s subject to deletion. &amp;#0160;
On a Localwiki, every article is measured against an individual sense of &amp;quot;locality&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ToledoWiki is up and running</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-03-toledowiki-is-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-03-toledowiki-is-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>See toledowiki.net&amp;#0160;for a city wiki for Toledo, Ohio. As of this writing it has 113 users, who have created 362 pages about the city.
It&amp;#39;s always interesting to see a city wiki start up, and by stumbling around the first few pages you get a sense for the places that are at the interesting core of a city. The first few coffee shops that are mapped tell you where people care enough to share their places to work, and the flyers collection lets you see what&amp;#39;s on the bulletin boards around town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal, public, and team wikis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-09-personal-public-and-team-wikis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 22:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-09-personal-public-and-team-wikis/</guid>
      <description>Personal wikis are a source for endless fascination, and they would lend themselves towards machine learning to the extent that you can imagine personal information management as a machine-assisted process. These are as individualized as snowflakes and about as durable.
Public utility wikis come in a variety of flavors, and don&#39;t always share an equivalent management structure or function. Sometimes there is a very small team of creators and a large periphery of consumers, and it&#39;s possible for a suitably designed personal effort to extend to public use if approached with care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera-wiki.org is a successful, non-commercial fork of Camerapedia</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-camera-wikiorg-is-a-successful-non-commercial-fork-of-camerapedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 22:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-camera-wikiorg-is-a-successful-non-commercial-fork-of-camerapedia/</guid>
      <description>Camera-wiki.org is a successful, non-commercial fork of Camerapedia. It was built over the span of about a month, with a small team of volunteers reconstructing the wiki and its image database in response to a sale of Camerapedia to Wikia. Steevithiak tells the tale from the inside, of late-night perl scripts crawling through the databases reconstructing the site and of coordinated action to rebuild the photo pool.
The challenge of running a wiki is not only that you have to maintain a large collection of encyclopedic content, but also that you have to keep a pile of funky software running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wiki wednesday: using google analytics to find places to add to your content</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-23-wiki-wednesday-using-google-analytics-to-find-places-to-add-to-your-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 13:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-23-wiki-wednesday-using-google-analytics-to-find-places-to-add-to-your-content/</guid>
      <description>Of course it isn&amp;#39;t Wednesday yet, but I&amp;#39;ll be a day early.
One of the things I&amp;#39;ve been tracking over at Arborwiki with our analytics install is the fraction of pages that people hit that don&amp;#39;t exist yet.&amp;#0160; These are marked on screen so that if you know what you are looking for you&amp;#39;ll recognize it, but often people don&amp;#39;t, so they click through and get a blank edit screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On wandering into someone else&#39;s wiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-25-on-wandering-into-someone-elses-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 12:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-25-on-wandering-into-someone-elses-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while you find a smallish wiki that looks like it&amp;#39;s healthy and has interesting material. &amp;#0160;These wikis are bigger than the single person brain-dump, and smaller than Wikipedia, and less abandoned than most temporary bouts of enthusiasm that bring people into wiki-land.
Inevitably when I find one of these I have the urge to edit and organize just long enough to figure out what kind of stuff is in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s National Farm and Garden Association / ArborWiki Wiki Wednesday</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-womens-national-farm-and-garden-association-arborwiki-wiki-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 15:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-07-womens-national-farm-and-garden-association-arborwiki-wiki-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>For Wiki Wednesday, I&amp;#39;m starting a new series where I pull a random (or at least semi-random) page from Arborwiki and look for ways to improve it.
Women&amp;#39;s National Farm and Garden Association  From ArborWiki  The Ann Arbor Branch, Woman’s National Farm &amp;amp; Garden Association, is dedicated to ensuring opportunities for women in horticulture and providing children an environment that is green and safe to learn from and to steward; our fundraising supports educational scholarships in horticulture and related areas and grants for community gardens that further our mission and goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki analytics: using the new Google Analytics tools to measure and improve a civic wiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-19-wiki-analytics-using-the-new-google-analytics-tools-to-measure-and-improve-a-civic-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-19-wiki-analytics-using-the-new-google-analytics-tools-to-measure-and-improve-a-civic-wiki/</guid>
      <description>This is part of the Wiki Wednesday and coincidentally also part of the Web Analytics Wednesday series.
UPDATE: changed throughout, some spots still not filled in, I am promising some graphs; want to work in the RichmondWiki blog notes as well.
UPDATE2: analytics for wiki edit failure
Google Analytics has a bunch of new features.&amp;#0160; Mediawiki, the code that runs Arborwiki, has Google Analytics installed and is tracking user behavior to help improve the quality and relevance of the content that&amp;#39;s there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing wiki to the expert user of Microsoft Word</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-12-describing-wiki-to-the-expert-user-of-microsoft-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-12-describing-wiki-to-the-expert-user-of-microsoft-word/</guid>
      <description>Part of a Wiki Wednesday series; this post is NOT FINISHED but I needed to post it anyway.
Using a wiki to help develop and edit text for your project is appealing because when it all works you can, when everything works right, get a lot more done with less document management overhead. &amp;#0160; However, there is a large group of professionals who regularly work with complex documents who are intimately familiar with Microsoft Word, are experts in understanding how it can be used to build complex and attractive deliverables, and for whom a wiki environment is novel - not just because the mechanics of editing, change tracking, and formatting for presentation are different, but because the model for how people work together in this world is not the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>notes on wiki use in organizations</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-notes-on-wiki-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 16:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-02-notes-on-wiki-u/</guid>
      <description>Stewart Mader and I had a good conversation, and from it came references to these posts; I&#39;m noting them now here so that I can find them again (!) and so that I can remember the context of the conversation.&amp;nbsp; Five effective wiki uses - a piece in Website Magazine.&amp;nbsp; In short: project management, customer/client collaboration, documentation, online community, FAQs and policies.
Onboarding: getting your new employees cleared for takeoff - some wiki patterns associated with using wiki to answer new hire questions and otherwise get new people to be part of an organization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google AdSense in professional association wikis</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-26-google-adsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 10:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-26-google-adsense/</guid>
      <description>Google&#39;s AdSense program is designed to provide relevant targeted advertising content to web pages.&amp;nbsp; It works, sometimes intermittently, on weblogs - but there&#39;s often enough other non-relevant things on the design of those pages to work only indifferently.&amp;nbsp; What you do find however is that the appropriately targeted wiki design - especially one where the subject matter expertise of a professional association is involved, and where the words in use a specific to a field of specialty - yields extremely targeted results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thank you for supporting arborwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 00:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-23-thank-you-for-s/</guid>
      <description>From time to time people ask questions about Ann Arbor, and from time to time there are what appear to be encyclopedic responses to them. Part of the reason for this is Arborwiki, a wiki that covers information about Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, Washtenaw County and the rest of the area.
Matt Hampel runs this with an ad hoc collective doing editorial direction and the Ann Arbor District Library providing hosting. It&#39;s not advertising driven, and while is has a lot of information about businesses any obviously marketing copy gets edited out pretty quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>