<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House And Home on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/house-and-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in House And Home on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/house-and-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing machine has a hose leak? How to repair it.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of good sites for information about do-it-yourself washing machine repair. Ours had a leak, which I think I traced to a tiny hole in the low-pressure drain hose that was fixable with a pipe tape that the good folks at Stadium Hardware helped me find. Let&amp;#39;s hope the repair holds!
I used the Family Handyman&amp;#39;s How To Repair a Leaking Washing Machine&amp;#0160;as my guide. The pinhole sized leak was in the middle of the low-pressure drain hose, where a rusty piece of bracket had wedged itself against the hose and slowly caused it to get a pinhole sized hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting laundry done, notes on the topic</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-laundry-is-a-chore-im-only-slowly-getting-better-at-it-after-most-of--a-year-of-having-increasing-responsibilities--mama-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-laundry-is-a-chore-im-only-slowly-getting-better-at-it-after-most-of--a-year-of-having-increasing-responsibilities--mama-ma/</guid>
      <description>Laundry is a chore. I&amp;#39;m only slowly getting better at it after most of a year of having increasing responsibilities. Mama mama make me clean. Every day the same routine.&amp;#0160; (Jean Marzollo)

The most important part of doing laundry once you start it is to figure out what the cycle time is that you need to keep up to make continuous progress, and then work with that timing in mind as you plan your effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to insulate your windows with bubble wrap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-insulate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 15:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-insulate/</guid>
      <description>Bubble wrap!&amp;nbsp; Who knew.
Build It Solar has the super-easy instructions, which involve cutting the wrap to the size of the window, spraying a thin film of water on the window, and letting the bubble wrap stick.&amp;nbsp; Add a little glycerin perhaps if you have trouble removing it in the spring.
It&#39;s apparently a common practice in the greenhouse industry.
And it&#39;s more transparent and high tech than duct taping some foam insulation to the window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>