<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House And Home on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/house-and-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in House And Home on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/house-and-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing machine has a hose leak? How to repair it.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of good sites for information about do-it-yourself washing machine repair. Ours had a leak, which I think I traced to a tiny hole in the low-pressure drain hose that was fixable with a pipe tape that the good folks at Stadium Hardware helped me find. Let&amp;#39;s hope the repair holds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.familyhandyman.com/DIY-Projects/Home-Repair/Appliance-Repair/how-to-repair-a-leaking-washing-machine/View-All&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Family Handyman&amp;#39;s How To Repair a Leaking Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;as my guide. The pinhole sized leak was in the middle of the low-pressure drain hose, where a rusty piece of bracket had wedged itself against the hose and slowly caused it to get a pinhole sized hole. The repair was made with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.duckbrand.com/Products/diy-products/diy-specialties/self-fusing-repair-tape.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Duck Brand Wrap-Fix Tape&lt;/a&gt;, a self-fusing silicone tape that says it&amp;#39;s good to 100 PSI.&amp;#0160;And &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Stadium_Hardware&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Stadium Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(Arborwiki link) is a marvelous store, with helpful folks and a seemingly infinite supply of parts for every hardware need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#39;s just hope the repair holds! The next step, if it doesn&amp;#39;t, is to replace that hose entirely. Repair Clinic has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.repairclinic.com/GE-Washing-Machine-Hose-Tube-Or-Fittings-Parts?z=100&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;about 70 different GE washing machine hose parts available&lt;/a&gt;; I haven&amp;#39;t yet identified the exact part.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the repair for the high-pressure supply hose would be very different, as noted in the comment below. The Family Handyman guide referenced above suggests getting a metallic no-burst supply hose &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluidmaster.com/washing-machine-connectors.html/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;similar to this one from Fluidmaster&lt;/a&gt; to replace any worn, corroded, or leaky supply hoses. Supply lines run at much higher pressure than drain lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting laundry done, notes on the topic</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-laundry-is-a-chore-im-only-slowly-getting-better-at-it-after-most-of--a-year-of-having-increasing-responsibilities--mama-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-laundry-is-a-chore-im-only-slowly-getting-better-at-it-after-most-of--a-year-of-having-increasing-responsibilities--mama-ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laundry is a chore. I&amp;#39;m only slowly getting better at it after most of
a year of having increasing responsibilities.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Mama mama make me clean. Every day the same routine.&amp;#0160;
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=SWX2jBT6Cm0C&#34;&gt;Jean Marzollo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The most important part of doing laundry once you start it is to figure
out what the cycle time is that you need to keep up to make continuous
progress, and then work with that timing in mind as you plan your
effort. If your washing machine takes 45 minutes to run, then going
downstairs 30 minutes later is a wasted trip, and going down an hour
later slows down system throughput considerably.&amp;#0160; No one yet that I know is using any web based time to change the laundry app that monitors your appliance directly, but simple timers or even just knowing that the top of the hour is when you go down to work on it should be enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laundry works best when clothes and wash are sorted before they get
dumped into the washer. This suggests that every time you put in a load
you should immediately sort the next load, so that there&amp;#39;s no need to
wait any more time that you need to the next time the cycle runs.
Sorting is made a lot easier by having big clearly labeled baskets. (I
never have figured out the symbols.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One school of laundry thought says to do a load every day; the other
says to do all the wash you have to do once a week in a continuous
stream. What is best for you depends on how many kids there are getting
clothes dirty, how many days or weeks of little boy clothing you have
in your stockpile so that there&amp;#39;s always a dry pair of clean pants
during mud puddle season, and what kind of mindless work you can do
while folding. In any case, there&amp;#39;s little to be gained from making
laundry a random process - routines repeated every week make it all
easier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 2:00pm; I promised myself that I&amp;#39;d go to the basement every hour
on the hour and move the process forwards. If I work at this properly
it will take less than 15 minutes to get the next load in and then I&amp;#39;ll
be able to have another 45 minutes of writing time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More reading, should you need to, falls in two rather distinct camps: the domestic diva enthusiasm as seen on &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=#flylady&#34;&gt;#flylady&lt;/a&gt; , or the art and science of keeping home exemplified by &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search?q=cheryl+mendelson+home+comforts&#34;&gt;Cheryl Mendelson&amp;#39;s Home Comforts&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; Either way there&amp;#39;s method in the madness, and I haven&amp;#39;t even touched on the strategies of sending all of your wash out to be done, or taking it all to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Category:Laundromats&#34;&gt;laundromat&lt;/a&gt; weekly for one big megawash. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to insulate your windows with bubble wrap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-insulate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 15:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-insulate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bubble wrap!&amp;nbsp; Who knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditsolar.com/Projects/Conservation/bubblewrap.htm&#34;&gt;Build It Solar has the super-easy instructions&lt;/a&gt;, which involve cutting the wrap to the size of the window, spraying a thin film of water on the window, and letting the bubble wrap stick.&amp;nbsp; Add a little glycerin perhaps if you have trouble removing it in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s apparently &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums2.gardenweb.com/forums/load/strucs/msg042302161244.html&#34;&gt;a common practice in the greenhouse industry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&#39;s more transparent and high tech than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hammerzone.com/archives/letters/windows/insulate.htm&#34;&gt;duct taping some foam insulation to the window.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>