<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skywarn on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/skywarn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skywarn on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/skywarn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.
I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you tune into during severe weather?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 22:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>I get all the news I need from the weather report. Here&amp;#39;s where I get the weather report from.
Twitter, to chat with people who are also in their basements. The local hash tag is #miwx for severe weather. I have a list @vielmetti/weather that I follow for the news.
Weather Underground for radar and forecasts and what not. I like the classic version of the user interface, which is busy and deep and which I know well enough to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>