<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/skywarn/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/skywarn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Skywarn training</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 22:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-11-2015-skywarn-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After three or four years of planning to get Skywarn training, this year I finally did it. The good folks at Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Center and at the National Weather Service in White Lake, MI did a training session at Pioneer High School. The class was concurrent with a Michigan ballroom dancing competition so there was music and festivities and accomplished looking dancers to enjoy before the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there with John Hritz KD8MKE and Ann Hanson. Ann captured the opening slide. There was a nifty online multiplayer game (can&#39;t recall the site it was built on) which had 95 people playing along from their smart phones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skywarn Spotter Training in A2 now! Hanging w/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vielmetti&#34;&gt;@vielmetti&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jhritz&#34;&gt;@jhritz&lt;/a&gt; Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NWSDetroit&#34;&gt;@NWSDetroit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/0X078Jl5Dg&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/0X078Jl5Dg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; annyhanny (@annyhanny) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/annyhanny/status/586890972371386368&#34;&gt;April 11, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My spotter ID good for 2 years is 242.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought my radio to the event and made a contact from the car with Marty KD8RGL from Canton MI. We were both using 5 watt radios contacting the W8UM repeater in Ann Arbor - I&#39;m always surprised how well things work when they do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered that it works a lot better to identify myself as &#34;Eddie&#34; when on the air. This because &#34;Ed&#34; gets misinterpreted as &#34;Andy&#34; all too often, and &#34;Edward&#34; seems awfully formal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you tune into during severe weather?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 22:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-29-severe-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get all the news I need from the weather report. Here&amp;#39;s where I get the weather report from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;, to chat with people who are also in their basements. The local hash tag is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23miwx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;#miwx&lt;/a&gt; for severe weather. I have a list &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/vielmetti/weather&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;@vielmetti/weather&lt;/a&gt; that I follow for the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wunderground.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Weather Underground&lt;/a&gt; for radar and forecasts and what not. I like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://classic.wunderground.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;classic version of the user interface&lt;/a&gt;, which is busy and deep and which I know well enough to navigate. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.wund.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;minimalist mobile version of the site&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is starkly unbusy and works fine even on a relatively dumb smart phone. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKYWARN&lt;/strong&gt;, the local ham radio emergency weather channel. The local repeater is&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/N8DUY&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;N8DUY&lt;/a&gt;, located near I-94 and M-14 in Scio Township, available at&amp;#0160;145.150&amp;#0160;Mhz or via the&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radioreference.com/apps/audio/?action=wp&amp;amp;feedId=5230&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Radio Reference relay online&lt;/a&gt;. This is the single best source of real time news during events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dteenergy.com/map/outage.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;DTE Energy outage map&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;is good for tracking storm damage starting about 30 minutes after the storm has gone through - you start to pick up which power outages will take a long time to fix. Note in this map below from Sunday, May 29, 2011, that the storm damage near Lansing ends at the DTE boundary; that doesn&amp;#39;t mean there isn&amp;#39;t more storm damage, only that I don&amp;#39;t have a map of the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88c2d284970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 22&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88c2d284970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e88c2d284970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 22&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Television&lt;/strong&gt;, which we don&amp;#39;t have for over the air reception. WDIV Channel 4 &amp;quot;Click On Detroit&amp;quot; has useful email weather alerts and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://detroit.justweather.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Detroit JustWeather&lt;/a&gt; page, and WXYZ Channel 7&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23backchannel&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;#backchannel&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter always has good chatter from the news desk there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AM/FM radio&lt;/strong&gt;. Locally the best bet is &lt;a href=&#34;http://weather.detroit.cbslocal.com/auto/wwjtvV4/MI/Detroit.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;WWJ &amp;quot;News radio 950&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, with traffic and weather together on the 8&amp;#39;s; it&amp;#39;s intended to be listened to while you are driving, and they do talk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather band radio, &lt;/strong&gt;which speaks in a synthesized scary voice. There are receivers that only turn on when there is an alert in your area, but I don&amp;#39;t have one. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crh.noaa.gov/dtx/wxradio.php&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Details from National Weather Service Detroit&lt;/a&gt; about the network of weather radios in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather facsimile&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, never have managed to do this, but if you have the right radio you can decode faxes with weather maps on the that are broadcast over the air. Also known as WEFAX, the technology dates from the 1920s. Details if you are good at such things from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nws.noaa.gov/om/marine/radiofax.htm&#34;&gt;National Weather Service marine forecast services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to get real time notifications of severe weather even if you have no power, no cell tower, and no Internet; that&amp;#39;s why you have batteries for your radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;405&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/K0oMPfigUWY&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>