<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory Palace on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/memory-palace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory Palace on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/memory-palace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily coffee and wifi, September 7, 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-07-daily-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-09-07-daily-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coffee and wifi (double espresso over ice) at the Peoples Food Coop,
on North Fourth Ave. The lunch hot bar here is very good
and the place is busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night was Ann Arbor City Council, a marathon session that
resulted in grudging approval of site plans for hundreds of new homes
and apartments over the opposition of neighbors in adjacent
neighborhoods. Woodbury Club Apartments will be on the northeast
side of town near Nixon Road and M-14, and South Pond Village
will be tucked away off Chalmers behind Arborland but not connected
to it. In both cases the votes reflected the split between the
Council Party who saw the &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; vote as obligatory to avoid a
lawsuit, and the Anti Party who had few enough votes to be
able to vote &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; as a protest vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple keynote is today, awaiting news about new shiny toys
to see how much less the old shiny toys are worth.
Apparently the new Apple watch will have Pokemon Go on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I took notes at the coop was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/&#34;&gt;July 18, 2015&lt;/a&gt;, when
I took note of Tom Meloche&amp;rsquo;s post on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tommeloche.com/the-doorway-effect/&#34;&gt;the doorway effect&lt;/a&gt;,
and how our short term memory gets dumped when we cross
a threshold. &lt;a href=&#34;https://al.nd.edu/news/latest-news/27483-walking-through-doorways-causes-forgetting-new-research-shows/&#34;&gt;Gabriel Radvansky&lt;/a&gt;
from Notre Dame is the scientist that Tom remembers.
The effect apparently is that going through a door
starts a new memory event, and to prepare for that
new event and give us a fresh landscape for thinking
the short term memory we had been holding gets emptied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an active imagination you can think of yourself
moving through doors without ever really changing your
place of sitting. My guess is that not only do you have
your current thinking flushed when you leave a room, but
the new room (if it&amp;rsquo;s familiar) pre-loads some thoughts.
Construct your mental landscape appropriately and you
end up with the memory palace which you can walk through
effortlessly in your mind, remembering its details everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>