<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Menu Plan Monday on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/menu-plan-monday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Menu Plan Monday on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/menu-plan-monday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu Plan Monday, December edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-16-menu-plan-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-16-menu-plan-monday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday: Lentil soup with tomatoes, bow tie pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday: Chili, tortillas, greens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday: Tabouli, roasted vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday: Hamburgers, buns, frozen vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday: leftovers (everyone was out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday: Spanish rice, cucumber salad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday: ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Coconut-potato curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is good for those days when you have dinner that might be postponed for a long time. The curry can be served quickly, but if you leave it on the stove longer the potatoes turn into a kind of delicious curry gravy for the garbanzos. We served it with greens, and it would have been good with a side of cauliflower as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coconut-potato curry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 lbs potatoes, boiled, with 1 cup cooking water reserved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curry powder, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cans garbanzo beans, cooked and drained and rinsed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare potatoes by boiling them until done. Reserve some cooking water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the potatoes are boiling, fry a chopped onion in some oil on low heat. When the onion smells nice but is not brown, add the curry powder and cook, stirring, until fragrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the coconut milk to the curry mixture and stir until well mixed. Then add the garbanzoes, and cook covered on low heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the potatoes are ready, add them to the garbanzo curry. Cut the potatoes into smaller pieces if they are too large. Keep covered, and add up to 1 cup potato water if the mixture gets too dry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>menu plan monday: first week of April</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-06-menu-plan-monday-first-week-of-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-06-menu-plan-monday-first-week-of-april/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some notes, more for myself than for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Horseradish&#34;&gt;Horseradish&lt;/a&gt; is now available at market; $4 for a jar from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Grandma%27s_Kitchen&#34;&gt;Grandma&amp;#39;s Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; Grandma says hers is pure, not mixed with turnip as some would do.&amp;#0160; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farmers Market had a lot of produce - field greens and flowers were the big new crops.&amp;#0160; We had some tat soi from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Shannon_Brines&#34;&gt;Shannon Brines&lt;/a&gt; that was very good in a stir fry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The phone on the farm in Homer, MI is answered only at 8am, if I read the handout right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No zucchini yet (and not expected for a long while), but Grandma says that if you mix the zucchini with a small amount of pineapple essential oil and let it sit overnight you&amp;#39;ll swear that it was really fresh pineapples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People&amp;#39;s Food Coop had sunflower sprouts (or sunsprouts) from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Gardenworks&#34;&gt;Gardenworks&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; Delicious and green with the taste of the sunflower.&amp;#0160; It would be a nice add-in to a mixed stirfry greens or as a few on top of a rice and beans salad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I start the lentil soup from Martha Rose at 9am (p84-85) I can not hurry in the evening on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a little water and cook off the crusty rice at the bottom of the rice pan, stirring until you have a kind of a rice slurry.&amp;#0160; Then add salt, pepper, and butter to taste.&amp;#0160; Mmmm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mexican style kosher for Passover foods recipes from &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jewishchronicle.org/article.php?article_id=11366&#34;&gt; Julian Medina, chef and owner of Toloache&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#0160; To read more than to cook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pixietangerine.com/&#34;&gt;Ojai Pixie Tangerines&lt;/a&gt; at Trader Joes in Ann Arbor.&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt;The Pixie is a result of open 
             pollination of Kincy mandarins (Kincys are a hybrid 
             between a King Mandarin and a Dancy Tangerine).&amp;#0160; Small and delicious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People&amp;#39;s Food Coop does a much better job than Whole Foods at merchandising their &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Ann_Arbor_Tortilla_Factory&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Tortilla Factory&lt;/a&gt; tortillas; they are much fresher, and you don&amp;#39;t have to dig into the cooler to see them.&amp;#0160; Both places have troubles keeping them in stock daily.&amp;#0160; Produce Station is another good source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Avalon Bread bakery is very close to Wayne State University, but I don&amp;#39;t have any sense for that walk.&amp;#0160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?q=422+w+willis,+detroit+mi+48201&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;split=0&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;ei=r2XZSfXfMYy0NerLnAY&amp;amp;ll=42.35171,-83.064065&amp;amp;spn=0.007469,0.017638&amp;amp;z=16&amp;amp;iwloc=addr&#34;&gt;422 W. Willis, Detroit MI 48201&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The week:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday: quesadillas, rice, beans, veg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monday: Lentil soup, w/pasta, radish salad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tues: Tofu, veg, rice&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weds: Seder&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thurs: Seder&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friday: Mac and cheese, frozen veg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sat: Turkey dogs, soycutash&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu plan Monday: second week of January</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-12-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-01-12-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-january/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A second try at menu plan Monday, written Sunday night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farmer&amp;#39;s market on Saturday was eggs, apples, some good conversation and not much more food.&amp;#0160; We didn&amp;#39;t get there early enough for fresh greens from Brines Farm, and by the time we were there Wasem&amp;#39;s was out of donuts.&amp;#0160; Still a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food coop was pleasant, but I didn&amp;#39;t do most of my shopping there.&amp;#0160; Next week I&amp;#39;ll do shopping for spices there, since their selection is best and they are never out of stock of anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trader Joes was picked over on Sunday night - I am usually out on Sunday a.m. so it was hard to believe how much of the store had empty shelves because I know they were full in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whole Foods had blueberries (Chile, commercial) for something like $2.99 for 6 ounces.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t buy them!&amp;#0160; especially noting the Frog Blog report that blueberries were incredibly cheap wholesale.&amp;#0160; As always, I had to dig way way way back in the cooler for the Ann Arbor Tortilla Factory tortillas - it&amp;#39;s as though whoever stocks the competing tortilla product (which costs 2x as much) pushes them to the back.&amp;#0160; Out of stock: red lentils, basil (how, I ask you, can you be out of stock of basil?&amp;#0160; worldwide basil shortage?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that here&amp;#39;s the menu plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monday: rice and bean salad with olives; some kind of dressing; I&amp;#39;m looking for a vegetarian Green Goddess style dressing recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuesday: potato gratin; frozen mixed veg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday: Mediterranean lentil soup (recipe from freddyknits), frozen broc, bulgar.&amp;#0160; The lentil soup uses the red lentils that were out, so I need to figure out how to get some.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thursday (easy): tortillas and beans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friday: pasta with leeks and pecans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday: soupe de samedi (Samstagsuppe) + bunny biscuits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday: chili and corn muffins&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu plan Monday: second week of December</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-08-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-08-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Menu for the week.&amp;#0160; The motto: &amp;quot;ogni pasto rappresentato&amp;quot; (every meal accounted for).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m joining the menu plan Monday group with this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>