<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/menu-plan-monday/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/menu-plan-monday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Coconut-potato curry</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-31-recipe-coconut-potato-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is good for those days when you have dinner that might be postponed for a long time. The curry can be served quickly, but if you leave it on the stove longer the potatoes turn into a kind of delicious curry gravy for the garbanzos. We served it with greens, and it would have been good with a side of cauliflower as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coconut-potato curry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 lbs potatoes, boiled, with 1 cup cooking water reserved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oil for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curry powder, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cans garbanzo beans, cooked and drained and rinsed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare potatoes by boiling them until done. Reserve some cooking water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the potatoes are boiling, fry a chopped onion in some oil on low heat. When the onion smells nice but is not brown, add the curry powder and cook, stirring, until fragrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the coconut milk to the curry mixture and stir until well mixed. Then add the garbanzoes, and cook covered on low heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the potatoes are ready, add them to the garbanzo curry. Cut the potatoes into smaller pieces if they are too large. Keep covered, and add up to 1 cup potato water if the mixture gets too dry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu plan Monday: second week of December</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-08-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-08-menu-plan-monday-second-week-of-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Menu for the week.&amp;#0160; The motto: &amp;quot;ogni pasto rappresentato&amp;quot; (every meal accounted for).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m joining the menu plan Monday group with this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>