<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spectrum Auction on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/spectrum-auction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spectrum Auction on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 17:29:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/spectrum-auction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Michigan University spokesman responds to Morning Sun editorial regarding WCMU-TV spectrum auction</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 17:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-08-central-michigan-responds-to-morning-sun-wcmu-editorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 8, 2016, 5:30 pm (Ann Arbor time): Central Michigan University
spokesman Steve Smith answered questions today by telephone regarding
a Morning Sun editorial, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themorningsun.com/opinion/20160108/editorial-status-quo-cmu-mum-on-talk-of-shutting-tv-station&#34;&gt;Status quo: CMU mum on talk of shutting TV station&lt;/a&gt;, published in this Digital First Media newspaper
from Mt. Pleasant, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the lede, the newspaper writes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Central Michigan University considers whether or not to shut
down its Public Broadcasting television network, the silence is
deafening.  CMU trustees almost a month ago voted to consider
shutting WCMU-TV and its three sister stations in exchange for up
to $726 million from the Federal Communications Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith poined out that the University had only approved to &amp;ldquo;apply
for eligibility&amp;rdquo;, which is not binding on CMU to proceed, and that
all options were open. In addition, he noted a Federal anti-collusion
rule that restricts the rights of potential auction participants
to speak freely about their intent leading up to the auction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central Michigan University invites public comment on its decisions
to sell part or all of its broadcast spectrum back to the FCC, in an
auction that is scheduled to begin on March 29, 2016. Address your
comments in email to trustees@cmich.edu or by postal mail to
106 Warriner Hall, Central Michigan University, Mt. Pleasant, MI 48859.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmich.edu/bot/Pages/default.aspx&#34;&gt;The next public meeting of the Trustees is on February 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;,
and with prior arrangement there is time for the public to provide
comment on agenda items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for the Federal Communications Commission, which
manages this auction, was not available for comment at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference see the following FCC documents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://transition.fcc.gov/Daily_Releases/Daily_Business/2015/db0806/DOC-334756A1.pdf&#34;&gt;FCC ESTABLISHES BIDDING PROCEDURES FOR
2016 INCENTIVE AUCTION
Auction Scheduled to Begin March 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;, August 6, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.fcc.gov/edocs_public/attachmatch/DA-15-1129A1.pdf&#34;&gt;GUIDANCE REGARDING THE PROHIBITION OF CERTAIN COMMUNICATIONS DURING
THE INCENTIVE AUCTION, AUCTION 1000&lt;/a&gt;, FCC Public Notice DA 15-1129.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WKAR-TV television spectrum may be up for sale, and the station is at risk</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-wkar-television-spectrum-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-06-wkar-television-spectrum-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan State University is considering placing the spectrum
that it uses for WKAR-TV into an auction that the FCC is running,
in which case it might receive upwards of $200 million in exchange
for ceasing all of its terrestrial broadcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strikes me as a penny wise, pound foolish approach. Once
the spectrum is gone you can&amp;rsquo;t get it back, and as a land grant
institution should know it&amp;rsquo;s important to be a good steward of
the resources you have been handed not just for the short term
but for the long term. Selling off a 50+ year tradition of
public broadcasting for a quick buck seems like a bad approach,
no matter how appealing a big check would be, especially
considering the community&amp;rsquo;s investment in the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have a TV receiver for over the air broadcasts,
but my neighbor down the street who does make the trek from Ann
Arbor to Lansing to give her thoughts. Her family grew up on WKAR-TV
and have been supporters for years, and they rely on over the
air television to bring in the signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More as I have it; I&amp;rsquo;m collecting links and news articles at
the Lansing Localwiki, at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://localwiki.org/lansing/WKAR-TV&#34;&gt;WKAR-TV&lt;/a&gt;
page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>