<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/obituaries/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/obituaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Doc&#34; title=&#34;Doc&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961. During his tenure, Lew served as department head from 1971 to 1975, taught Anatomy, Physiology and Parasitology, and in 1980 received a contract from the National Park Service to study parasites at Isle Royale. He retired in 1996 after 35 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew was a member of St. Michael Catholic Church and Marquette Rotary Club. He is survived by his wife, Kathy Peters of Marquette; children, Raymond (Velquis) Peters of Indianapolis, IN, Matthew (Elizabeth) Peters of Austin, TX, Dan (Jennifer) Peters of Tallahassee, FL, Edward (Deborah Fisch) Vielmetti of Ann Arbor, MI, Stephen (Paula) Vielmetti of Milwaukee, WI and Anne (Douglas) Moody of Vancouver, WA; grandchildren, Nicolette &amp;amp; Elizabeth Peters, Zack and Ava Peters, Garrett, Bryson &amp;amp; Reese Peters, Saul and Jonathan Vielmetti, Marshall, Nathan, Sophia and Zevon Vielmetti, Graham and Spencer Moody; sister, Robyn (David) Messner of Jensen Beach, FL; numerous nieces &amp;amp; nephews; and special family friend&#39;s, Tim Glover and his family. He was preceded in death by his parents, first wife, Oneita &#34;Beth&#34; Peters and a brother, Edward Peters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew&#39;s family would like to thank the staff of Brookridge Heights and Lake Superior Hospice for the wonderful care they provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A memorial service will be held on Monday, March 9, 2015 at 3:00 p.m. at the Canale-Tonella Funeral Home with Deacon David Adler officiating. Visitation will be held from 1:00 p.m. until the time of the service in the funeral home. Inurnment will take place at Park Cemetery. In lieu of flowers, memorials can be directed to the Biology Department at NMU in care of the NMU Foundation or the Lake Superior Land Conservancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canale-Tonella Funeral Home is assisting the family where memories may be shared at canalefuneral.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: John Gall, 1925-2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gall, John C. 9/18/1925 - 12/15/2014 Walker, MN John C. Gall, Jr.,
beloved husband, father, pediatrician, scholar and author, passed
away with his wife by his side Dec. 15, 2014, in Walker, MN, from
natural causes. He was 89. John was born on September 18, 1925 in
Washington, D.C. and grew up near Upperville, VA. In 1945 he was
drafted into the Army Air Corps and sent to Germany, where he served
as a medic in the Allied army of occupation. During his tour of
duty he attended the Nuremberg trials, which kindled in him a
lifelong passion to heal the afflicted and promote justice. Upon
returning home he furthered his education, graduating from Yale and
George Washington University Medical School. He was a postdoctorate
fellow at the Mayo Clinic, where he was dubbed &amp;ldquo;the best pediatric
diagnostician [they had] ever seen!&amp;rdquo; In addition he earned a
certification in Human Genetics and completed 7 years of therapy
training. Dr. Gall began his medical career as a researcher at the
University of Virginia, followed by a 3-year stint at the Geisinger
Clinic in Danville, PA. He next went into private practice in Miles
City, MT, but was soon invited to teach at the University of Michigan
Medical School in Ann Arbor, MI. There he also served as head of
the Plymouth State Home, where he did research partially funded by
the Kennedy family foundation, and named and described several
syndromes of the developmentally disabled . In addition he established
a long-running private pediatric practice of 38 years. During this
period he developed a special appreciation for, and an enduring
interest in, the importance of nonverbal communication between very
young children and their parents. This led him to expand his practice
to include support and education classes, in which he was aided by
his late wife, Beth, and then by his wife Carol. Their observations
and anecdotes are included in Elegant Parenting, written with wife,
Beth; in Dancing with Elves written by John, and with wife Carol
he wrote Hit by a Low-Flying Goose. John&amp;rsquo;s best known book is System
Antics, later published under the title The Systems Bible, a humorous
but insightful study of the problems and pitfalls that afflict every
type of system that human beings create-whether mechanical, economic,
corporate, aeronautical, legal, linguistic, religious, medical or
electronic. It was first published in 1976 by the New York
Times/Quadrangle Press and has been translated (officially or
unofficially) into at least 14 languages. He lectured widely
throughout the United States and was interviewed by the Voice of
America on nuclear proliferation issues after its publication. John
and Carol were both invited to speak in London in 2012 to a group
of CEOs and other executives from around the world and John was
introduced as &amp;ldquo;The Grandfather of Systems Theory.&amp;rdquo; He retired to
Walker, MN, in 2001 in search of privacy and uninterrupted time,
which he used to write seven other books, including a novel, First
Queen, plus books and video books on parenting and the art of
pediatric practice. He was very proud that the great Swiss psychiatrist,
Alice Miller, who introduced the world to the subject of child
sexual abuse, endorsed his work before she died. His work has also
been endorsed by others too numerous to name, but including such
luminaries as the head of the Dept. of Psychology at Cambridge,
University, who forwarded his material to several British social
service agencies. In the late 1990s John helped to write the National
Pediatric Nurse Practitioner Exam in Washington D.C several years
running. More recently he was invited to Washington D.C. by a
government psychiatrist and consulted with this man on the development
of psychological profiles of moles (double agents). He also spoke
at a symposium at Princeton University entitled &amp;ldquo;Children under the
Shadow of War.&amp;rdquo; The group included scholars from around the world,
and filmmakers who had photographed kidnapped children who had been
conscripted into war and forced to commit atrocities. It was John&amp;rsquo;s
job to deliver the final speech, summarizing and tying together all
of the presentations. This was the only lecture open to the public.
John gave a moving presentation that left not a dry eye in the
audience. In the final months of his life, John continued to think
and write actively on a wide range of subjects. Most recently he
completed a 4th edition of Systemantics and contributed, with other
international scholars, to a book on Panarchy, due to be published
in 2015. John was preceded in death by his first wife, Beth, and
three step-grandsons, Michael Nelson, and Franklin and Alexander
Sawvel. His is survived by his wife, Carol, brothers Dr. Joseph
Gall (Diane Dwyer) and Howard, sons Duane (Valerie) and David
(Suzette), step-sons Steven (Sarah) and Terrell (Eleanor) Nelson,
and grandchildren Izzie, Nathan, Sebastian, and Simone, plus
step-grandchildren Anthony, Cody, Alaya, Nicole, and Branden Nelson.
A private family ceremony will be held in the Episcopal Church in
Upperville, VA, in the late spring.  -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more at:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=173778701#sthash.HpdH8buv.dpuf&#34;&gt;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=173778701#sthash.HpdH8buv.dpuf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Tom Fourner, WWII veteran, June 27, 1925 - November 7, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 11:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fournier, Thomas James 6/27/1925 - 11/7/2014 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Tom_Fournier&#34;&gt;Tom Fournier&lt;/a&gt; died peacefully with family by his side on November 7, 2014. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom was born on June 27, 1925 in Detroit, MI, to Christopher and Alice Fournier. He joined the Navy to fight in World War II and fought in the D-Day landing on Omaha Beach. After the war, Tom returned home to marry the love of his life, Joan, on June 1, 1946. Tom was proud of his wartime service and of the many accomplishments in his life including pursuing his doctoral degree in counseling. He loved to write stories about the many people he met; he loved to go camping; he loved to cook especially desserts. Tom was outgoing and made many friends in and around Ann Arbor, his beloved home town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom is survived by his eight children Julie Bloomfield, MaryAlice Galloway (Dennis), Tom Fournier, Jr. (Betty), Tim Fournier (Chris), Gay Marie Fournier (Rod Kroes), Amy Fournier, Joe Fournier (Molly), and Steve Fournier. His family legacy includes 14 grandchildren and 5 delightful great-grandchildren. A funeral liturgy honoring Tom&#39;s life will be held at St. Thomas the Apostle Church (530 Elizabeth St, Ann Arbor 48014) on Thursday, November 13, at 10:00 a.m. with family visitation at 9:00 a.m. In lieu of flowers, donations may be made to the Humane Society of Huron Valley or the VA Ann Arbor Healthcare System. Please visit www.muehligannarbor.com to leave the family your condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the daily birth and death</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the bitterest criticisms I have heard of late of what is left of our local media&#39;s coverage of town is their inability to function as a simple daily log of births and deaths. When a prominent local citizen dies, you expect a proper story told of their life. This is a service to friends and neighbors to get them to the b funeral on time, and it&#39;s an opportunity to reflect on a life well lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries have traditionally clipped obits in the service of local historians and genealogists to help the info seeker. From time to time I have posted or reprinted obits here, and Arborwiki collects them as well, unevenly but diligently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would you have if your collection had every obituary printed for a city, carefully indexed and cross referenced? The big challenge I can imagine is disambiguation, making sure that you can tell the many people apart who share a name and a home town. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Alfio Vielmetti (1911-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This eulogy was read for my great-uncle Alfio (Auch) by his nephew Zorba. Alfio Vielmetti died in 2008 at the age of 96. I think of him when I am out on my walks, and I miss him when I wish I had someone like him to talk to about city council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUCH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My uncle Alfio lived a life centered on family and community, with lessons learned hard in early years, and applied for a very long lifetime. Many of these lessons came from his father, Max, and Max didn&#39;t discuss, he announced the lessons - and in some cased, how they were going to be learned. One of the earliest and strongest was sharing, and with seven siblings, there was plenty of constant reinforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brothers worked to help one another –to be there when needed- after all, Auch had an older brother named Rock. They all worked as kids, then as students at Ann Arbor- always working. Always remembering the hard times- that when they were kids, their shoes were stored once the weather turned warm- and they stayed there until the fall. Working for the iceman- that was tough work for a kid, but it helped make for a pretty tough kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auch had a real love of working with his hands- building things, fixing things- his own, but also for others. He’d show up with the right tools to get a project going – or finished. He was generous with his time and talents- right down to answering a lot of questions from hyper-inquisitive nephews who wanted to build things too. He built a cottage at Spread Eagle pretty much from the dirt up, and helped Howard and Mitch keep their places going across the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was always providing for the family- building things, fixing things, making things better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was great pain in his earlier years, with the death of his wife Marge during the birth of his son David, but he found a new partner in Lois and with her support rebuilt the Vielmetti family home over 7 years down to the smallest detail –building the &#39;&#39;&#39;components&#39;&#39;&#39; of the smallest details., while building a business and partnering with his brother on various ventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auch was a lifelong supporter of this church, not just going to mass every day and helping out financially, but working with Father Mark on the history of the parish and helping to identify folks in pictures and stories. He had a prodigious memory in regard to the people and history of Norway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Auch’s fathers great commitments in life was to education- and as usual, Max walked the walk, sending every one of his children to the university of Michigan. Auch took it to heart as well, checking in on the next generation- verifying mid-story to see if they indeed knew the meaning of some of his terms and references, as well as founding standing scholarships at the Norway-Vulcan High School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was at the hospital visiting Auch while he was recovering from cancer surgery, and before he unloaded on the doctors and staff about what they did right- the surgery; and what they did wrong, everything else; and how he was going home that day, regardless of what they thought, that he had his nephew and Jack Osborne there to spring him- well before all that, we talked about charity. No- that’s not quite right- I mostly listened. I listened as he told me of the importance of having charity in your life- in a very broad sense –in that we are all in this together, and that you owed something as your share- your contribution to your family, your friends, your town, and your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pitched in on every level- from installing a new pump at our cottage, to establishing scholarships at the high school, to spending years following Patton across Europe during the war. He spoke of the easier kinds of charity- where you could send a check to folks doing good deeds here and there in the community- the world, and the closer in version- the one where you showed up, spent some time and effort to help out. The one where you had to get up, and get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his later years Auch did a lot of walking. I mean a LOT of walking, some of it right below us when the weather was bad, and I am convinced that his amblings had a lot to do with the length of his stay with us. He walked every day to the library to read the WSJ, he walked to the stores and the bowling alley, and also, You see, on a lot of his walks, he went to sundry houses and visited the sick and the infirm- just a stop in to see how they were doing- and to cheer them up he said. Now if he was on tear about the city council, I’m not certain how cheery it was, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walking tours made for better health through exercise - as well as better health through helping others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auch was a good man who has left a rich legacy by example, and a lot of us are going to miss him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: James Doyle, Lower Burns Park resident whose home was rehabbed by community groups in 2006</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jim Doyle, a long time Lower Burns Park resident, passed away late last month at the Grand Rapids VA.  Mr. Doyle had lived at 1023 Granger Ave. for over 50 years. He served in the Philippines on General MacArthur&#39;s staff during the war.  After the war, Mr. Doyle returned to Ann Arbor where after the passing of his parents, he spent the majority of his adult life taking care of his younger brother who was severely disabled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may remember Mr. Doyle from the efforts to &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20060727194215/http://www.ewashtenaw.org/news/2006/doyle_home.html/Assets/aa_news_james_doyle.pdf&#34;&gt;refurbish his house&lt;/a&gt; by Veteran groups back in 2006.  Mr. Doyle was a friendly man who always had a smile on his face and a penchant for whole milk and chocolate candy bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Graydon Krapohl for the information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and obituaries, part 2</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-18-facebook-and-obituaries-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-18-facebook-and-obituaries-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook seems to be the place where I find out about deaths in people&#39;s families. It&#39;s a little jarring sometimes to have a newsfeed of cat video, advertisement, funny meme, obituary, cat video etc. It certainly makes me want to read down far enough in my feed that I haven&#39;t missed anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all that Facebook is good at capturing people&#39;s thoughtfulness in the moment, it&#39;s a lousy place to publish anything enduring. That&#39;s why when a proper obituary is written I like to cut and paste it out of wherever it has been and post it here. It seems that unless you do that the words so carefully and lovingly written disappear, either into the unsearchable maw of Facebook or into the tattered yellow clippings of a typical newspaper obituary site. You&#39;ll see a few of them in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/obituaries&#34;&gt;obituaries&lt;/a&gt; category here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve written previously about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/07/facebook-and-obituaries.html&#34;&gt;Facebook and obituaries&lt;/a&gt;, so this is more a reminder and a capture of a few thoughts than something earth-shakingly new. I have to wonder how the net will evolve over time and whether some hip new service of the moment will transform into something that people use to share their time of grief.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/blogofneworleans/archives/2013/08/02/suspect-device-cartoonist-greg-peters-dies&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;obituary for Greg Peters&lt;/a&gt; is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01901e97a6b3970b-600wi&#34; alt=&#34;Greg-peters-high-school-bowl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obit as published in NOLA.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cartoonist and writer Greg Peters died Friday morning, Aug. 2, after emergency surgery at Ochsner Medical Center. Mr. Peters, who had suffered from a congenital heart condition throughout his life, was 50 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in Marquette, Mich., Peters arrived in Louisiana in 1990 to pursue a doctorate in English literature at the University of Louisiana at Lafayette. He became best known as the creator of “Suspect Device,” a starkly crafted, blackly funny Louisiana-themed political comic strip that made its debut in 1996, in the Times of Acadiana, and ran in New Orleans’&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/&#34;&gt;Gambit Weekly&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from 1999 to 2010. “Suspect Device” famously pulled no punches: In 1998, editor Harris Meyer resigned from the Times of Acadiana, when the paper’s publisher refused to run one of Mr. Peters’ strips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suspect Device” was recognized with awards from the Press Club of New Orleans and the Association of Alternative Newsweeklies, and in 2004 was anthologized in “&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=r18Or31mODcC&amp;amp;pg=PT95&amp;amp;dq=greg+peters+attitude+2&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=ih78UY3HG8iWqQHx7YFw&amp;amp;ved=0CC8Q6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=greg%20peters%20attitude%202&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Attitude 2: The New Subversive Alternative Cartoonists&lt;/a&gt;.” Mr. Peters’ work was displayed in exhibitions in conjunction with the book at New York City’s Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters was “one of the few alternative weekly political cartoonists whose mission is to skewer local and state politicians,&#34; anthology editor Ted Rall told Gambit’s Scott Jordan in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestofneworleans.com/gambit/unusual-suspect/Content?oid=1243221&#34;&gt;a 2004 profile of Mr. Peters&lt;/a&gt;. &#34;One would think that there would be such a cartoonist, or several, in every major city, but there just aren&#39;t,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Coupled with an over-the-top clip-art style and incredibly distinct cartooning personality, Greg&#39;s strip is everything that his readers and editors can hope for.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peters’ distinctive style involved the use of stock clip art images, arranged and annotated with wry, extensive text to skewer public figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;The clip art thing was always a punk staple,&#34; Mr. Peters told Jordan. &#34;Like the cut-out letters and clip art that Jamie Reid, the Sex Pistols designer, did using Queen Elizabeth with the safety clip through her cheek picture. They&#39;re very much out of the DIY ethos. And the attitude simply of baseline mistrust for authority, and the demand that you be shown, not told.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Peters is survived by his parents, Reg and Kay Peters of Lafayette; his partner, Eileen Loh; his former wife, Saundra Scarce; and his two sons, Wilder, 12, and Magnus, 10. Plans for a memorial service in the New Orleans area are pending.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leveesnotwar.org/in-memoriam-greg-peters-suspect-device-artist-and-blogger-father-friend/&#34;&gt;Levees Not War&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and obituaries</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-facebook-and-obituaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-facebook-and-obituaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More often than not, I am hearing about the death of friends or family through Facebook. I suppose this isn&amp;#39;t surprising; after all, I hear about babies born on the same site. Local newspapers are too slow or too local or publish too infrequently to be a source for family news. The Facebook wall makes as good a place as any to share condolences and to make plans for funerals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the news:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huffington Post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/07/death-facebook-dead-profiles_n_2245397.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Death on Facebook Now Common&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/help/contact/305593649477238&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Memorialization Request&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://abcnews.go.com/Technology/story?id=2384990&amp;amp;page=1#.UcdV3T6KKVc&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;ABC News on MyDeathSpace&lt;/a&gt;, 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huffington Post,&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/13/mydeathspace-death-facebook-social-media_n_2296496.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;On MyDeathSpace, Morbidly Curious Unpack Deaths, Profiles Of People They Never Knew&lt;/a&gt;, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Engelbart (1925-2013) - inventor of interactive computing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Douglas Engelbart has died at the age of 88.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/04/technology/douglas-c-engelbart-inventor-of-the-computer-mouse-dies-at-88.html?pagewanted=all&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;New York Times obit from John Markoff:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Douglas C. Engelbart, a visionary scientist whose singular epiphany in 1950 about technology’s potential to expand human intelligence led to a host of inventions — among them the computer mouse — that became the basis for both the Internet and the modern personal computer, died on Tuesday at his home in Atherton, Calif. He was 88.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engelbart was known for this 1968 (!) demo of interactive computing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/yJDv-zdhzMY?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story goes that while in World War II stationed on an island he read the Vannevar Bush work &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1945/07/as-we-may-think/3881/&#34;&gt;As We May Think&lt;/a&gt;&#34;, and it became the foundation for his work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retraction watch: Joe Paterno</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-22-retraction-watch-joe-paterno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-22-retraction-watch-joe-paterno/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note to self: never ever report anyone is dead. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/mgoblog/status/160963802345652224&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;MGoBlog&lt;/a&gt;, via Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Penn State football coach Joe Paterno died January 22, 2012, of complications from lung cancer treatment. He was 85. Hours before, his death was prematurely announced by multiple news services, prompting retractions and apologies from those organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbssports.com/collegefootball/story/16960572&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;CBSSports.com extends apology to Paterno family:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Saturday night, CBSSports.com published an unsubstantiated report that former Penn State coach Joe Paterno had died. That mistake was the result of a failure to verify the original report. CBSSports.com holds itself to high journalistic standards, and in this circumstance tonight, we fell well short of those expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://knightnews.com/2012/01/onward-state-managing-editor-resigns-joe-paterno-death-report-retraction/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Onward State Managing Editor Resigns After Paterno Death Report&lt;/a&gt;, Knight News:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twitter account that first reported former Penn State coach Joe Paterno died just posted an update linking to a letter of resignation from its managing editor, Devon Edwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the normally reputable national CBS Sports outlet picked up the student news source’s story, the now-retracted report of Paterno’s death went national.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside Breaking News:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.breakingnews.com/post/16271185670/the-paterno-story-what-went-wrong&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Paterno story: What went wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our editor noted that CBS Sports — a trusted source —&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/early-lead/post/joe-paterno-reports-start-internet-firestorm/2012/01/21/gIQAJPUNHQ_blog.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;Paterno’s death around 9pm ET. The CBS Sports headline and story was based, seemingly, on erroneous reporting by the Penn State student publication ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onwardstate.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Onward State&lt;/a&gt;.’ The original CBS Sports obituary didn’t directly attribute the student paper.&amp;#0160; The Huffington Post followed with a&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitpic.com/8a4wyv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SB Nation:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sbnation.com/ncaa-football/2012/1/22/2724607/explaining-the-reports-of-joe-paternos-passing-and-an-apology&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Explaining The Reports Of Joe Paterno&amp;#39;s Passing And An Apology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before publishing, we waited for multiple reports from national outlets. The reports spread to numerous trusted sources, sparking our own decision to publish a post as a result. It was based not on our own reporting, but on the reporting of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://storify.com/jeffsonderman/false-reports-of-joe-paterno-s-death&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jeff Sonderman has a chronicle on Storify of the false reports and retractions&lt;/a&gt;. Many in the news media waited for the AP report before running a story, and thus they were spared the need to reverse themselves. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pennlive.com/midstate/index.ssf/2012/01/joe_paterno_is_very_sick_but_c.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Penn Live has the family&amp;#39;s reaction&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Paterno is not dead.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s about as blunt as it gets, as sources close to the Paterno family say that the family is tremendously upset with&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eye-on-collegefootball.blogs.cbssports.com/mcc/blogs/entry/24156338/34497800&#34;&gt;CBS Sports&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfoxphilly.com/dpp/sports/penn_state/reports%3A-joe-paterno-dies-at-age-of-85-012112&#34;&gt;other news media&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;who have erroneously reported Paterno&amp;#39;s passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, though, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20563737,00.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;People Magazine still has an obituary online&lt;/a&gt;, citing the CBS Sports article as its source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this post is a nod to the weblog &lt;a href=&#34;http://retractionwatch.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks retractions in the scientific literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Jobs, 1955-2011; Apple cofounder, visionary, creative genius</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-05-steve-jobs-1955-2011-apple-cofounder-visionary-creative-genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 23:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-05-steve-jobs-1955-2011-apple-cofounder-visionary-creative-genius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/stevejobs&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs has died&lt;/a&gt; at the age of 56, after a long fight with cancer. Details are everywhere on the net. The Telegraph&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/steve-jobs/8809997/Steve-Jobs-dies-live-blog.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs dies: live blog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; is doing a credible job of tracking down stories, quotes, remembrances and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;main&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your thoughts, memories, and condolences, please email&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rememberingsteve@apple.com&#34;&gt;rememberingsteve@apple.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Faye Amo (1954-2011), high school French teacher</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MARQUETTE – Faye M. Amo, age 57, of 425 West Ridge Street, Marquette,
entered eternal life Wednesday evening, July 13, 2011, at her home
in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula
Home Health and Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born March 23, 1954 in Lima, Ohio, a daughter of Stephen J. and
Ethel (Salidas) Catel, Faye was raised in Ishpeming and graduated
from the Ishpeming High School as salutatorian of her class. From
her days in grade school, Faye held the desire to become a teacher.
She enrolled at Northern Michigan University, where she received
her baccalaureate degree summa cum laude (with highest honor) with
a double major in French and English. She continued at Northern,
obtaining a double masters degree in English and French in 1977 and
later studied at the University of the Sorbonne in Paris where she
earned highest honors in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye’s
lifelong dream of becoming a teacher began with her first teaching
assignment at the Ishpeming High School in 1977. In 1979, she started
teaching French at the Marquette Senior High School, a career that
would span 31 years. Teaching French was her passion in life and
she loved all her students and they loved her. Affectionately known
as Madame Amo, she was the consummate professional teacher, one who
truly cared about her students and was dedicated to their education
and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not enough that the
students learned the French language, she felt they needed to
experience what “French” meant. Heading the French Club at Marquette
Senior High School, Faye planned numerous trips for club members
to big city museums to view French art exhibits, eat at French
eateries, and learn about French culture. Over the years, several
trips were taken to Chicago and to France in her mission to educate.
These memorable events were always anticipated by Faye and greeted
with enthusiasm by her students. For a number of years, she served
as class advisor, particularly enjoying building and decorating
floats for homecoming and decorating the gym for junior prom
activities. Throughout her life, Faye maintained an untiring interest
in the students at MSHS, often asking parents about their children,
even through the children may never have been her students and she
kept in regular contact with students who were now living adult
lives, with families of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition
to her affiliations at MSHS as foreign language department head for
several years, class advisor for the MSHS graduating class of 2008,
and serving on numerous parent-teacher committees, Faye was also a
member of the Greek Orthodox Church of the Assumption and the Ladies
Philoptochos Society, and active in civic committees such as the
American Association of University Women and the Marquette
Beautification Committee. In her leisure, Faye loved walking her
dog, Mario, for the 13 years of his life, bicycling, running – even
participating in marathons in Detroit and France, and riding in her
boat on beautiful Lake Superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faye is
survived by her husband, John; her cherished son, Bret; two sisters,
Stephanie (Bob) Trumm and Jayme (Rick) Iknoiah both of California;
her mother-in-law, Leone Amo of Ironwood; brothers-in-law, Tom Amo
of Philadelphia, PA, Jim (Brooke) Amo of Livonia, and Ken Amo of
Ft Worth, TX; and several nieces and nephews. Faye was preceded in
death by her father, the honorable judge, Stephen J. Catel, her
mother, Ethel Catel; brother-in-law, Andrew Walton; and father-in-law,
John M. Amo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family will receive friends
at the Swanson-Lundquist Funeral Home on Sunday from 4:00 pm until
7:00 pm. Trisagion will be held at 6:00 pm. The Funeral Liturgy
will be held on Monday, July 18, at 11:00 am at the Greek Orthodox
Church of the Assumption with Rev. Tom Michalos officiating. Burial
will be made in the Park Cemetery. Pallbearers will be Jimmy Pedakis,
Lou Roumanis, Paul Andronis, Paul Wainio, Gary Shaffer, and Craig
Cox. Memorials may be directed to the Greek Orthodox Church of the
Assumption, 235 W. Ridge Street, Marquette, MI 49855 or to the Faye
Amo Scholarship Fund, Wells Fargo Bank, 101 W. Washington Street,
Marquette, MI 49855. Condolences may be expressed online at
www.swansonlundquistfuneralhome.com Adieu Madame Amo. Repose en
paix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Gil Scott-Heron (1949-2011), American musician and poet</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-27-obituary-gil-scott-heron-1948-2011-american-musician-and-poet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 23:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-27-obituary-gil-scott-heron-1948-2011-american-musician-and-poet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gil Scott-Heron (b. April 1, 1949; d. May 27, 2011) was a poet and musician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538ec6086d970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538ec6086d970b&#34; alt=&#34;6t&#34; title=&#34;6t&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538ec6086d970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obituaries: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/therecord/2011/05/27/136731274/gil-scott-heron-poet-and-musician-has-died&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;NPR, by Daoud Tyler-Ameen&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gil_Scott-Heron&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2011/05/27/us/AP-US-Obit-Gil-Scott-Heron.html&#34;&gt;Associated Press / New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/music_blog/2011/05/gil-scott-heron-dies.html&#34;&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/a&gt; written by Randall Roberts for the blog Pop and Hiss&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Last year the New Yorker published a reverent but heartbreaking profile of Scott-Heron by Alec Wilkinson.  Written after Scott-Heron had recorded &#34;I&#39;m New Here&#34; but after he had relapsed and was smoking crack openly in front of the reporter, the story traced his rise, his fall and his influence.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some music of his, linked here to Youtube clips so that I can have them in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGaRtqrlGy8&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Revolution Will Not Be Televised&lt;/a&gt;, 1970.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PtBy_ppG4hY&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Whitey&#39;s On The Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_b2F-XX0Ol0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Bottle&lt;/a&gt;, 1974, from &lt;em&gt;Winter In America&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b54rB64fXY4&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;We Almost Lost Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, live 1990 performance; about the Fermi power plant near Monroe, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhoSampled has a list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whosampled.com/artist/Gil%20Scott-Heron/&#34;&gt;artists who sampled Gil Scott-Heron&lt;/a&gt; in their work.  
&lt;p&gt;Compilations of information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gilscottheron.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;GilScottHeron.com&lt;/a&gt; - fan site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around the middle seventies when I first heard this brazen, young black man&#39;s voice. He was angry! We were angry! I was angry! Angry over the fact that it was a few years ago that they had just taken from us our black shining Prince. He was mad. We were mad. I was mad! Mad over the fact that our struggle for freedom had come to a screeching halt. He was loud! Loud and determined to be heard. And I heard him. I heard him loud and clear. I heard him when he said &#34;The Revolution Will Not Be Televised&#34;. I heard him when he said &#34;No Knock On My Brothers&#39; Head&#34;. I heard him when he was saying that the spirit of Brother Malcolm will flourish in him as it has in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gilscottheron.net/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;GilScottHeron.net &lt;/a&gt;- official site - includes his song &lt;a href=&#34;http://gilscottheron.net/album&#34;&gt;&#34;I&#39;m New Here&#34;&lt;/a&gt; from his album of the same name on XL Recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;314&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/eV_astp3BjM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jemimahknight.com/2011/05/28/crystallization-of-news-online-gil-scott-heron/&#34;&gt;Jemimah Knight&#39;s account of the evening spent confirming the news&lt;/a&gt; gives links to all sources along the way, noting how the net having been given some news starts to search for confirmation that the news is true.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Searches on Google under “news” are not showing any pages at five past three. It’s Gil Scott-Heron. You really do want to be sure before you write this up as a news source. No matter who crows about who was first on the web to break a story, trust is the currency. Trust and accuracy so, I am not surprised that the mainstream houses are not publishing yet. (No offence intended for the original tweet)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: David E. Davis Jr., 80; dean of automotive journalists</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-obituary-david-e-davis-jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-obituary-david-e-davis-jr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David E. Davis, Jr.&lt;/strong&gt; (b.&amp;#0160;November 7, 1930,&amp;#0160;Burnside, Kentucky; d.&amp;#0160;March 27, 2011, Ann Arbor, Michigan) was the founder of&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Automobile Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;and a long time&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Car and Driver&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;editor. His distinctive voice defined modern automotive journalism. He is survived by a&amp;#0160;wife, Jeannie, a daughter, and two sons, many friends, and a generation of automotive writers and car lovers. Services are pending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memorials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rumors.automobilemag.com/automobile-magazine-founder-david-davis-jr-dies-80-36613.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Automobile Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Davis was a lifelong car enthusiast&amp;#0160;who worked in all corners of the industry, from racing to advertising to editorial and publishing. He was well-regarded in the industry for the profound impact his work had on many modern car journalists, not to mention readers.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eddie Alterman for &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.caranddriver.com/david-e-davis-jr-1930%E2%80%932011/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Car and Driver&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;#0160;He was a champion of the automotive good life, and he lived it right to the very end. I hope he forgives me for using his sign-off, but:&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Freedom and Whiskey!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura K. Cowan:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2editor.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/rest-in-peace-david-e-davis-jr/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Rest in Peace David E. Davis, Jr.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;&amp;quot;He refused to use the subjunctive case in his writing, because he hated the way it sounded.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autoblog.com/2011/03/27/david-e-davis-jr-dean-of-automotive-journalism-dead-at-80/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Autoblog&lt;/a&gt;: Ever eloquent, where others might simply inquire &amp;quot;How are you?&amp;quot;, Davis was known for asking colleagues and friends &amp;quot;Is your life a rich tapestry?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jalopnik.com/#!5786191/david-e-davis-auto-buff-book-pioneer-dead-at-80&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jalopnik&lt;/a&gt;: Davis had a long and full career in the automotive world, starting as a racing driver and car salesmen and leading to a position as a copy writer for&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Road &amp;amp; Track&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;before becoming a writer for&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Car and Driver&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ur.umich.edu/0304/May10_04/26.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;University Record, 2004&lt;/a&gt;, on the occasion of his spring commencement address. &amp;quot;In 1955, at age 24, he flipped his race car upside down during a national championship in California. He lost his left eyelid, the bridge of his nose, the roof of his mouth and all but a half-dozen of his teeth.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Farrago &amp;quot;The Truth About Cars&amp;quot; video interview, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thetruthaboutcars.com/2009/09/david-e-davis-fired-for-truth-telling-wants-jean-jennings-dead/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Fired for Truth Telling&lt;/a&gt;, 2009. &amp;quot;The “fun” starts at about 11:00 in, where the former&amp;#0160;&lt;em&gt;Car and Driver&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;Editor reveals that Ziff-Davis fired him for not apologizing to Blaupunkt for dissing their products.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti&amp;#39;s other vehicle is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.automobilemag.com/green/reviews/0808_aata_gillig_hybrid_electric_bus/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;half million dollar hybrid that runs on biodiesel&lt;/a&gt;, of which Automobile Magazine says they were &amp;quot;most impressed by the hybrid bus&amp;#39;s braking power&amp;quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>