<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Obituaries on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/obituaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Obituaries on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/obituaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Doc&#34; title=&#34;Doc&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb07fd7066970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961. During his tenure, Lew served as department head from 1971 to 1975, taught Anatomy, Physiology and Parasitology, and in 1980 received a contract from the National Park Service to study parasites at Isle Royale. He retired in 1996 after 35 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew was a member of St. Michael Catholic Church and Marquette Rotary Club. He is survived by his wife, Kathy Peters of Marquette; children, Raymond (Velquis) Peters of Indianapolis, IN, Matthew (Elizabeth) Peters of Austin, TX, Dan (Jennifer) Peters of Tallahassee, FL, Edward (Deborah Fisch) Vielmetti of Ann Arbor, MI, Stephen (Paula) Vielmetti of Milwaukee, WI and Anne (Douglas) Moody of Vancouver, WA; grandchildren, Nicolette &amp;amp; Elizabeth Peters, Zack and Ava Peters, Garrett, Bryson &amp;amp; Reese Peters, Saul and Jonathan Vielmetti, Marshall, Nathan, Sophia and Zevon Vielmetti, Graham and Spencer Moody; sister, Robyn (David) Messner of Jensen Beach, FL; numerous nieces &amp;amp; nephews; and special family friend&#39;s, Tim Glover and his family. He was preceded in death by his parents, first wife, Oneita &#34;Beth&#34; Peters and a brother, Edward Peters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lew&#39;s family would like to thank the staff of Brookridge Heights and Lake Superior Hospice for the wonderful care they provided. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A memorial service will be held on Monday, March 9, 2015 at 3:00 p.m. at the Canale-Tonella Funeral Home with Deacon David Adler officiating. Visitation will be held from 1:00 p.m. until the time of the service in the funeral home. Inurnment will take place at Park Cemetery. In lieu of flowers, memorials can be directed to the Biology Department at NMU in care of the NMU Foundation or the Lake Superior Land Conservancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canale-Tonella Funeral Home is assisting the family where memories may be shared at canalefuneral.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Tom Fourner, WWII veteran, June 27, 1925 - November 7, 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 11:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fournier, Thomas James 6/27/1925 - 11/7/2014 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/Tom_Fournier&#34;&gt;Tom Fournier&lt;/a&gt; died peacefully with family by his side on November 7, 2014. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom was born on June 27, 1925 in Detroit, MI, to Christopher and Alice Fournier. He joined the Navy to fight in World War II and fought in the D-Day landing on Omaha Beach. After the war, Tom returned home to marry the love of his life, Joan, on June 1, 1946. Tom was proud of his wartime service and of the many accomplishments in his life including pursuing his doctoral degree in counseling. He loved to write stories about the many people he met; he loved to go camping; he loved to cook especially desserts. Tom was outgoing and made many friends in and around Ann Arbor, his beloved home town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom is survived by his eight children Julie Bloomfield, MaryAlice Galloway (Dennis), Tom Fournier, Jr. (Betty), Tim Fournier (Chris), Gay Marie Fournier (Rod Kroes), Amy Fournier, Joe Fournier (Molly), and Steve Fournier. His family legacy includes 14 grandchildren and 5 delightful great-grandchildren. A funeral liturgy honoring Tom&#39;s life will be held at St. Thomas the Apostle Church (530 Elizabeth St, Ann Arbor 48014) on Thursday, November 13, at 10:00 a.m. with family visitation at 9:00 a.m. In lieu of flowers, donations may be made to the Humane Society of Huron Valley or the VA Ann Arbor Healthcare System. Please visit www.muehligannarbor.com to leave the family your condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the daily birth and death</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the bitterest criticisms I have heard of late of what is left of our local media&#39;s coverage of town is their inability to function as a simple daily log of births and deaths. When a prominent local citizen dies, you expect a proper story told of their life. This is a service to friends and neighbors to get them to the b funeral on time, and it&#39;s an opportunity to reflect on a life well lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries have traditionally clipped obits in the service of local historians and genealogists to help the info seeker. From time to time I have posted or reprinted obits here, and Arborwiki collects them as well, unevenly but diligently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would you have if your collection had every obituary printed for a city, carefully indexed and cross referenced? The big challenge I can imagine is disambiguation, making sure that you can tell the many people apart who share a name and a home town. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>