<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Obituaries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/obituaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Obituaries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/obituaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters (April 10, 1932 - March 4, 2015)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 20:19:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-04-obituary-dr-lewis-ernest-peters-april-10-1932-march-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Lewis Ernest Peters, 82, of Marquette, died peacefully Wednesday morning, March 4, 2015, at Brookridge Heights Memory Care while under the care of Lake Superior Hospice.
He was born April 10, 1932, in Evanston, Illinois, a son of the late Lewis Ernest and Evelyn (Tehle) Peters. Lew married Katherine Kay Vielmetti in 1980 at the Marygrove Retreat Center in Garden, Michigan. He joined the faculty of the Biology Department at Northern Michigan University in 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: John Gall, 1925-2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</guid>
      <description>Gall, John C. 9/18/1925 - 12/15/2014 Walker, MN John C. Gall, Jr., beloved husband, father, pediatrician, scholar and author, passed away with his wife by his side Dec. 15, 2014, in Walker, MN, from natural causes. He was 89. John was born on September 18, 1925 in Washington, D.C. and grew up near Upperville, VA. In 1945 he was drafted into the Army Air Corps and sent to Germany, where he served as a medic in the Allied army of occupation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Tom Fourner, WWII veteran, June 27, 1925 - November 7, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 11:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-09-obituary-tom-fourner-wwii-veteran-june-27-1925-november-7-2014/</guid>
      <description>Fournier, Thomas James 6/27/1925 - 11/7/2014 Tom Fournier died peacefully with family by his side on November 7, 2014. Tom was born on June 27, 1925 in Detroit, MI, to Christopher and Alice Fournier. He joined the Navy to fight in World War II and fought in the D-Day landing on Omaha Beach. After the war, Tom returned home to marry the love of his life, Joan, on June 1, 1946.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the daily birth and death</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-the-daily-birth-and-death/</guid>
      <description>One of the bitterest criticisms I have heard of late of what is left of our local media&#39;s coverage of town is their inability to function as a simple daily log of births and deaths. When a prominent local citizen dies, you expect a proper story told of their life. This is a service to friends and neighbors to get them to the b funeral on time, and it&#39;s an opportunity to reflect on a life well lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Alfio Vielmetti (1911-2008)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-16-remembering-alfio-vielmetti-1911-2008/</guid>
      <description>This eulogy was read for my great-uncle Alfio (Auch) by his nephew Zorba. Alfio Vielmetti died in 2008 at the age of 96. I think of him when I am out on my walks, and I miss him when I wish I had someone like him to talk to about city council.
AUCH
My uncle Alfio lived a life centered on family and community, with lessons learned hard in early years, and applied for a very long lifetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: James Doyle, Lower Burns Park resident whose home was rehabbed by community groups in 2006</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</guid>
      <description>Mr. Jim Doyle, a long time Lower Burns Park resident, passed away late last month at the Grand Rapids VA. Mr. Doyle had lived at 1023 Granger Ave. for over 50 years. He served in the Philippines on General MacArthur&#39;s staff during the war. After the war, Mr. Doyle returned to Ann Arbor where after the passing of his parents, he spent the majority of his adult life taking care of his younger brother who was severely disabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and obituaries, part 2</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-18-facebook-and-obituaries-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-18-facebook-and-obituaries-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Facebook seems to be the place where I find out about deaths in people&#39;s families. It&#39;s a little jarring sometimes to have a newsfeed of cat video, advertisement, funny meme, obituary, cat video etc. It certainly makes me want to read down far enough in my feed that I haven&#39;t missed anything.
For all that Facebook is good at capturing people&#39;s thoughtfulness in the moment, it&#39;s a lousy place to publish anything enduring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Greg Peters, 50; Louisiana political cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 23:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-02-obituary-greg-peters/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;An obituary for Greg Peters is in Gambit, a New Orleans publication that he contributed political cartoons to. I knew him from high school in Marquette (from debate and High School Bowl) and hadn&#39;t stayed in touch for years, so this was a bit of a shock.
 
Bottom, from left: Tom Baldini (coach), me (alternate), Greg Peters, Joel White, Kerry Johnson, Mike Coyne, David Goldsmith (host). &#34;Nothing you learn is ever wasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and obituaries</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-facebook-and-obituaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-15-facebook-and-obituaries/</guid>
      <description>More often than not, I am hearing about the death of friends or family through Facebook. I suppose this isn&amp;#39;t surprising; after all, I hear about babies born on the same site. Local newspapers are too slow or too local or publish too infrequently to be a source for family news. The Facebook wall makes as good a place as any to share condolences and to make plans for funerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Engelbart (1925-2013) - inventor of interactive computing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-03-douglas-engelbart-1925-2013-inventor-of-interactive-computing/</guid>
      <description>Douglas Engelbart has died at the age of 88.
New York Times obit from John Markoff:
 Douglas C. Engelbart, a visionary scientist whose singular epiphany in 1950 about technology’s potential to expand human intelligence led to a host of inventions — among them the computer mouse — that became the basis for both the Internet and the modern personal computer, died on Tuesday at his home in Atherton, Calif. He was 88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retraction watch: Joe Paterno</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-22-retraction-watch-joe-paterno/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-01-22-retraction-watch-joe-paterno/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: never ever report anyone is dead. (MGoBlog, via Twitter)
UPDATE: Penn State football coach Joe Paterno died January 22, 2012, of complications from lung cancer treatment. He was 85. Hours before, his death was prematurely announced by multiple news services, prompting retractions and apologies from those organizations.
CBSSports.com extends apology to Paterno family:

 Earlier Saturday night, CBSSports.com published an unsubstantiated report that former Penn State coach Joe Paterno had died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Jobs, 1955-2011; Apple cofounder, visionary, creative genius</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-05-steve-jobs-1955-2011-apple-cofounder-visionary-creative-genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 23:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-10-05-steve-jobs-1955-2011-apple-cofounder-visionary-creative-genius/</guid>
      <description>Steve Jobs has died at the age of 56, after a long fight with cancer. Details are everywhere on the net. The Telegraph&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Steve Jobs dies: live blog&amp;quot; is doing a credible job of tracking down stories, quotes, remembrances and the like.
If you would like to share your thoughts, memories, and condolences, please email&amp;#0160;rememberingsteve@apple.com&amp;#0160;.
  &amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Faye Amo (1954-2011), high school French teacher</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-07-14-obituary-faye-amo-1954-2011-high-school-french-teacher/</guid>
      <description>MARQUETTE – Faye M. Amo, age 57, of 425 West Ridge Street, Marquette, entered eternal life Wednesday evening, July 13, 2011, at her home in the loving care of her family and the caregivers of Upper Peninsula Home Health and Hospice.
Born March 23, 1954 in Lima, Ohio, a daughter of Stephen J. and Ethel (Salidas) Catel, Faye was raised in Ishpeming and graduated from the Ishpeming High School as salutatorian of her class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Gil Scott-Heron (1949-2011), American musician and poet</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-27-obituary-gil-scott-heron-1948-2011-american-musician-and-poet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 23:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-27-obituary-gil-scott-heron-1948-2011-american-musician-and-poet/</guid>
      <description>Gil Scott-Heron (b. April 1, 1949; d. May 27, 2011) was a poet and musician.
 Obituaries: NPR, by Daoud Tyler-Ameen; Wikipedia; Associated Press / New York Times.
Los Angeles Times written by Randall Roberts for the blog Pop and Hiss:  Last year the New Yorker published a reverent but heartbreaking profile of Scott-Heron by Alec Wilkinson. Written after Scott-Heron had recorded &#34;I&#39;m New Here&#34; but after he had relapsed and was smoking crack openly in front of the reporter, the story traced his rise, his fall and his influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: David E. Davis Jr., 80; dean of automotive journalists</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-obituary-david-e-davis-jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-28-obituary-david-e-davis-jr/</guid>
      <description>David E. Davis, Jr. (b.&amp;#0160;November 7, 1930,&amp;#0160;Burnside, Kentucky; d.&amp;#0160;March 27, 2011, Ann Arbor, Michigan) was the founder of&amp;#0160;Automobile Magazine&amp;#0160;and a long time&amp;#0160;Car and Driver&amp;#0160;editor. His distinctive voice defined modern automotive journalism. He is survived by a&amp;#0160;wife, Jeannie, a daughter, and two sons, many friends, and a generation of automotive writers and car lovers. Services are pending.
Memorials:
Automobile Magazine: Davis was a lifelong car enthusiast&amp;#0160;who worked in all corners of the industry, from racing to advertising to editorial and publishing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Bob Frost (1952-2011), U of Michigan School of Information professor and great-grandson of poet Robert Frost</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-obituary-bob-frost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-27-obituary-bob-frost/</guid>
      <description>Robert L. &amp;quot;Bob&amp;quot; Frost (1952 - March 2011) was a professor at the University of Michigan School of Information. He&amp;#0160;received his Ph.D. in history from the University of Wisconsin in 1983 and joined the University of Michigan faculty in 2000. Frost was the great-grandson of poet Robert Frost, and established the&amp;#0160;Frost Open Access Fund&amp;#0160;with royalties from his great-grandfather&amp;#39;s works to&amp;#0160;support faculty and student projects related to open access to information. He is survived by his wife&amp;#0160;Margaret Hedstrom; relations, colleagues, current and former students and many friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Jeff Lamb, photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Lamb (January 16, 1949 - March 22, 2011) was a photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula. He is survived by his wife, Leyla Lau-Lamb, his dog, Sonny, and other relations and many friends.&amp;#0160;There will be a celebration of Jeff&amp;#39;s life at Hathaway&amp;#39;s Hideaway, 310 S. Ashley, Ann Arbor, on Saturday, April 9th beginning at 4:00 p.m. In lieu of flowers, donations to&amp;#0160;The Advocacy Department of the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. David Aberdeen, former Burns Park Elementary principal, obituary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 02:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</guid>
      <description>original from annarbor.com, hyperlinks mine
 F. David Aberdeen
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;addThis&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_AddThis&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt; var addthis_pub = &amp;amp;quot;legacycomobituaries&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_brand = &amp;amp;quot;Legacy.com&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_options = &amp;amp;quot;favorites, delicious, reddit, google, facebook, digg, twitter, yahoobkm, myspace, bebo&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_header_color = &amp;amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;amp;quot;; var addthis_header_background = &amp;amp;quot;#546F82&amp;amp;quot;;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;javascript:void(0);&amp;quot; onmouseout=&amp;quot;addthis_close();&amp;quot; onmouseover=&amp;quot;return addthis_open(this, &amp;amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;, &amp;amp;quot;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;amp;pid=133524746&amp;amp;quot;, &amp;amp;quot;F. Aberdeen Death Notice: F. Aberdeen’s Obituary by the AnnArbor.com.&amp;amp;quot;);&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Share&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;obitEmail&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary-email.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;amp;pid=133524746&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_EmailObituaryLink&amp;quot;&amp;gt;E-mail&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;viewSignGuestBook&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://www.legacy.com/gb2/default.aspx?bookid=3762524876042&amp;amp;amp;cid=full&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_VisitGuestBookLink&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Visit Guest Book&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;obitText&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; hspace=&amp;quot;10&amp;quot; lgyorigname=&amp;quot;0003443845-01-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Kim, former third grade teacher at Burns Park Elementary School, passed away on Sunday, Sept. 20, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-26-alice-kim-former-third-grade-teacher-at-burns-park-elementary-school-passed-away-on-sunday-sept-20-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-09-26-alice-kim-former-third-grade-teacher-at-burns-park-elementary-school-passed-away-on-sunday-sept-20-2/</guid>
      <description>from the AnnArbor.com obituaries:
Mrs. Alice Kim passed away on Sunday September 20, 2009. She was a third grade teacher at Burns Park Elementary School in Ann Arbor, MI for many years. She dedicated her life to her profession because she loved children and teaching. She is survived by her daughters and husband. She will be greatly missed by all of the people she taught, worked with, and loved. A private family funeral is planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walter Cronkite as seen by Johnny Carson, 1981</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-18-walter-cronkite-as-seen-by-johnny-carson-1981/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 01:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-18-walter-cronkite-as-seen-by-johnny-carson-1981/</guid>
      <description>Johnny Carson&#39;s interpretation of Cronkite&#39;s last newscast, from 1981.
)
Cronkite died today at the age of 92; here is the CBS News account of his career with the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eulogy for Alfio (Auch) Vielmetti</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-eulogy-for-alfi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 21:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-eulogy-for-alfi/</guid>
      <description>My cousin Zorba wrote a eulogy for my great uncle Auch, who died last week at the age of 96. The whole thing is a bit too much to share right now, but there was one paragraph that really spoke to me about the sort of family I come from (and perhaps some insight into who I am)  In his later years Auch did a lot of walking. I mean a LOT of walking, some of it right below us when the weather was bad, and I am convinced that his amblings had a lot to do with the length of his stay with us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>