<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ferguson Missouri on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ferguson-missouri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ferguson Missouri on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:09:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/ferguson-missouri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No fly zone over Ferguson affects airport traffic at Lambert-St Louis Airport</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-25-no-fly-zone-over-ferguson-affects-airport-traffic-at-lambert-st-louis-airport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-25-no-fly-zone-over-ferguson-affects-airport-traffic-at-lambert-st-louis-airport/</guid>
      <description>November 25, 2014, midnight. FAA has issued TFR affecting inbound flights. Airport is still open. Does not impact departures.
&amp;mdash; Lambert-STL Airport (@flystl) November 25, 2014 
FAA TFR, NOTAM : 4/0271 Location : FERGUSON, MO, Tuesday, November 25, 2014 UTC. Not for navigation.

Flightstats shows that traffic is being diverted from the airport.

The FAA has issued a TFR over #Ferguson. But unlike last time, commercial flights are diverting away from @flystl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FergusonCCM : Watching the Ferguson, MO City Council meeting of September 9, 2014</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-watching-the-ferguson-mo-city-council-meeting-on-fergusonccm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 08:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-11-watching-the-ferguson-mo-city-council-meeting-on-fergusonccm/</guid>
      <description>Some selected accounts here give some flavor of the meeting; I wasn&#39;t watching it end to end, but there was a lot of traffic on the Twitter octothorpe #FergusonCCM that was notable.
New York Times: &#34;Outrage and Calls for Change Follow Ferguson Officials Into Council Meeting&#34;
 FERGUSON, Mo. — The first Ferguson City Council meeting since the police killing of Michael Brown one month ago erupted on Tuesday into an outpouring of grievances — accusations of racism, police harassment and government incompetence — as hundreds of residents made angry appeals for change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of Ferguson, Missouri via the St Louis Localwiki</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-21-making-sense-of-ferguson-missouri-via-the-st-louis-localwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 20:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-21-making-sense-of-ferguson-missouri-via-the-st-louis-localwiki/</guid>
      <description>The St Louis, Missouri Localwiki - http://localwiki.net/st-louis - was mostly empty when the events in Ferguson, MO started on August 9, 2014 with the death of 18 year old student Michael Brown. As with any event where there&#39;s a lot that&#39;s going on in an unfamiliar area, I was drawn to making some sense of what was happening. This has been especially true when the coverage on the #ferguson hashtag overwhelmed my Twitter feed, which had been usually quiet at night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 13, 2014: Live feeds from Ferguson, MO</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-13-august-13-2014-live-from-ferguson-mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 21:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-13-august-13-2014-live-from-ferguson-mo/</guid>
      <description>August 13, 2014: The events in Ferguson, Missouri continue to be tense. This is a developing situation.
2020 CST approx: LRAD noisemakers deployed. All live feeds appear to have gone down.
Live on the scene with Twitter photos and Vine videos is Antonio French, a St Louis alderman; he&#39;s been there since the start and is a trusted local voice.
Video feed, live: The Real Alex Jones. Jones is a 9/11 truther and a conspiracy theorist; as of 2035 CST his feed is broadcasting in front of the QT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to unrest in Ferguson, MO via Twitter, police and fire scanner, Hot 104.1, KTVI TV</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-10-listening-to-unrest-in-ferguson-mo-via-st-ann-mo-police-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 22:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-10-listening-to-unrest-in-ferguson-mo-via-st-ann-mo-police-scanner/</guid>
      <description>August 10-11, 2014: It&#39;s a tense night in Ferguson, MO after last night&#39;s shooting of 18 year old Michael Brown.
News account from the St Louis Post Dispatch, with photos: Violence breaks out near site of vigil for teen killed by police.
 FERGUSON • A day of protests and vigils Sunday for an unarmed black teenager who was shot to death by a Ferguson police officer erupted Sunday night with confrontations, looting and gunshots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferguson, Missouri police shoot unarmed student Michael Brown, 18</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-09-ferguson-missouri-police-shoot-unarmed-student-michael-brown-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 22:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-08-09-ferguson-missouri-police-shoot-unarmed-student-michael-brown-18/</guid>
      <description>Who: Michael Brown, age 18.
What: Shot by Ferguson, Missouri police.
When: Brown was walking, unarmed, at 2:15 p.m. on Saturday, August 19, 2014.
Where: Ferguson, MO is 20 minutes northwest of St. Louis, MO.
Why: Unknown. The unnamed officer has been put on paid leave, and the St. Louis County, MO Police will investigate.
Media:
KMOV 4, St Louis. Heavy police presence in Ferguson after fatal officer-involved shooting.
 According to Stark, there are at least 100 police cars and numerous officers armed with M-16&#39;s in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>