<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:44:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>github on the very small screen is not much fun</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-30-github-on-the-very-small-screen-is-not-much-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-30-github-on-the-very-small-screen-is-not-much-fun/</guid>
      <description>Github is not much fun on a very small screen.
Octodroid does a competent job of letting you add comments to issues and scrolling through issues. It isn&#39;t so wonderful if you have gone to some trouble to categorize issues by milestone.
None of the github Android clients I have give any access to the github wiki.
Mostly the difficult part is that I had a well worked out workflow that moved open issues or if my inbox and into github, and the small screen simply does not make that a smooth process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some new apps for my Android phone</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-02-some-new-apps-for-my-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 17:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-02-some-new-apps-for-my-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>I organize lunch on Thursdays every week, and I ask my lunch group a question so that people can say a few words after they introduce themselves. This week the food was at Taco King (yummy) and the question was about new apps for people&#39;s phones that they added, or apps that they uninstalled. It was a good way to get some insight into the new parts of the net that are explored only through apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octodroid is a Github client for Android</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-octodroid-is-a-github-client-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 14:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-24-octodroid-is-a-github-client-for-android/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m using Github as a personal issue tracker, still using it in fact for a whole year. It says that I&#39;ve crossed 1200+ things off my todo lists and still have 70+ left to go. Unlike &#34;inbox zero&#34;, I&#39;m resigned to the notion that my todo list will hover somewhere between 60 and 90 things to do at any time.
inbox zero just means that my todo list is full</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evernote (for Android) as a reminder system</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-evernote-for-android-as-a-reminder-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-evernote-for-android-as-a-reminder-system/</guid>
      <description>I have a fickle relationship with reminder systems. Usually the drill is to discover something new, vigorously dump everything I can possibly think into it, and then slowly but surely get disillusioned with it as time goes on. The smell of a new system is seductive, and when something new comes along there&amp;#39;s a tendency to look at its good side and to focus on the bad parts of whatever you were using before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TuneIn: listen to broadcast radio from all over the world</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-10-tunein-listen-to-broadcast-radio-from-all-over-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m fond of TuneIn, a free service that lets you tune in to radio broadcasts from all over the world. I used it last night to listen to Pacific Coast League AAA baseball, and I&amp;#39;ve previously tuned in hockey games, news stations from far-away places when there&amp;#39;s breaking news, and the occasional music channel.
One of the remarkable things about TuneIn is that they have program schedules for the stations they are following, and so you can get real time updates for what&amp;#39;s playing now and who&amp;#39;s playing whom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vine for Android finally arrives</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-03-vine-for-android-finally-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 10:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-03-vine-for-android-finally-arrives/</guid>
      <description>Vine is a versatile short-form video capture application for iPhone and now for Android. It lets you grab 6 second short videos, like the one embedded below, and post them easily from your phone or tablet.
Get Vine for Android from the Google Play store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being partially online is worse than either being online or being offline</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-being-partially-online-is-worse-than-either-being-online-or-being-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-being-partially-online-is-worse-than-either-being-online-or-being-offline/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s nothing more frustrating to me than being almost but not quite on the Internet, as I discovered today when going to a cafe (unnamed, but linked) which advertised free wifi. My connections were slow and unreliable and frustrating to use. It looks like you&#39;re online but any applications that depend on always-on Internet for their well being work out badly.
The best reaction that I have for this state of interrupted connectivity is to go offline and write in my little notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two sleep tracker applications for Android: SleepBot and SleepTime</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-two-sleep-tracker-applications-for-android-sleepbot-and-sleeptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-24-two-sleep-tracker-applications-for-android-sleepbot-and-sleeptime/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m going to try to review two different applications for Android that are designed to track your sleeping habits and improve your ability to wake up on time.
Both SleepBot (http://mysleepbot.com/) and SleepTime (http://www.azumio.com/apps/sleep-time/) have the same basic strategy. You put your phone under your pillow and go to sleep. The phone&#39;s accelerometer notices your tossing and turning or your deeply quiet snoozing, and keeps track of same overnight. When it comes to be time to wake up, they look for a time window when you&#39;re not in deep sleep in order to maximize the chance that you wake up refreshed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>