<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Closed Captioning on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/closed-captioning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Closed Captioning on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/closed-captioning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers from CTN regarding City of Ann Arbor closed captioning</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 09:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-02-answers-from-ctn-regarding-city-of-ann-arbor-closed-captioning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Answers to questions sent to Greg McDonald, CTN manager, regarding closed captioning at on City of Ann Arbor&#39;s Community Television Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are you providing closed captioning?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Commission on Disability Issues made a request to add captions to their meetings to increase meeting accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is providing the closed captioning for CTN?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ScreenLine, L.L.C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much is the size of the contract, and for how long does it run?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not have a contract with the company, we’re in a trial period and they’ll be invoicing us each time we use their service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where are the individuals who are doing the closed captioning based? Are they on-site, or off-site?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off-site, based in Grand Ledge, Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When was the decision made to add closed captioning to the Disability Commission?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Disability Commission request for closed caption services was approved as part of the FY2015 budget discussion at the Feb. 25, 2014 Cable Commission meeting.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there considerations of adding closed captioning for City Council meetings?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding would have to be identified in order for closed captioning services to be provided for City Council or other Board and Commission meetings cablecast by CTN.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has changed about the technology to make closed captioning feasible now when it wasn&#39;t before?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology/equipment has improved and is a little less expensive today than when last researched in 2008. The closed caption service costs are about the same. The May 27, 2014 Cable Commission meeting includes (about 6:30 minute mark) discussion about the service and equipment  &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2govtv.pegcentral.com/player.php?video=507268f61855facce4fbff749ad0ad94&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the transcripts from the closed captioning available as well?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have no transcripts from the closed captions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One last question: what does one hour of closed-captioned video cost, under your current arrangement with Screenline? Is there a list price, and did we get a discount? I listened to the Cable Commission discussion you linked to (thanks for that) but was no wiser as to the hourly rate from that discussion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost is $100/hr and each meeting will require a minimum of 1hr of set-up/prep time but that could vary/increase depending upon the agenda.  As far as I know, we have not been given a discount, however ScreenLine has been very helpful as we were getting the technical part of the system set-up and did not charge us for any of their time during that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>