<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Botany on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/botany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Botany on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 23:25:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/botany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of a deep freeze on the emerald ash borer</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-the-impact-of-a-deep-freeze-on-the-emerald-ash-borer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 23:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-the-impact-of-a-deep-freeze-on-the-emerald-ash-borer/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s bitter cold in the Ann Arbor area and throughout the country; temperatures have been below zero most of the last two days. One of the things we&#39;re looking for a silver lining in super cold weather is its impact on bugs, especially invasive species like the emerald ash borer that are not used to unusual weather. A story in the The Gazette (Cedar Rapids Iowa) has a description of the effects of extreme cold on these destructive beetles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post-storm mushroom 5/5</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-06-post-storm-mushroom-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 14:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-06-06-post-storm-mushroom-55/</guid>
      <description>post-storm mushroom 5/5, originally uploaded by Edward Vielmetti. Big storms came through town and dumped somewhere between 2 and 4 inches of rain in the neighborhood. A morning walk showed a lot of mushrooms that came out including these unknown varieties growing on a dead (or partly dead) tree.
Posted by Edward Vielmetti from Flickr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the violets growing in my yard make me happy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-the-violets-growing-in-my-yard-make-me-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 19:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-05-02-the-violets-growing-in-my-yard-make-me-happy/</guid>
      <description>They are nothing special, really, just ordinary lawn violets.&amp;#0160; I love them, and I love it when they come out in the spring time.&amp;#0160; When they appear I have warm memories of my great aunt Gail Clark who kept violets at home and who was named after the plant.
Candied violets are said to be very easy - dip the violet flower in egg white and then in sugar.
More reading, of course:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woody plants - identifying the trees of Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</guid>
      <description>Every year the U of Michigan teaches a Woody Plants class.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t take it when I was in school, but my sister did, and it&amp;#39;s one of these legendary courses that people remember for a long time.
Here&amp;#39;s the links and notes I could find easily.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s prompted by the Ann Arbor Chronicle&amp;#39;s story about the city of Ann Arbor tree inventory going on now, which I hope will yield a precise map of where all of the public juneberry trees are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first frost in Ann Arbor MI 2008 - cover your tomatoes! - warnings</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-first-frost-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 14:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-03-first-frost-in/</guid>
      <description>Cover your tomatoes!
Here&#39;s this spring&#39;s suggestion list for how to protect your tomatoes from frost.&amp;nbsp; More suggestions welcomed.
First frost warnings for 2008 follow; I got this message via the Emergency Email Network (free).
 MIZ069-070-075-076-082-083-
041200-
/O.NEW.KDTX.FR.Y.0003.081004T0600Z-081004T1200Z/
OAKLAND-MACOMB-WASHTENAW-WAYNE-LENAWEE-MONROE-
INCLUDING THE CITIES OF.PONTIAC.WARREN.ANN ARBOR.
DETROIT.ADRIAN.MONROE
1214 PM EDT FRI OCT 3 2008
FROST ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 2 AM TO 8 AM EDT SATURDAY.
THE NATL WEATHER SVC IN DETROIT/PONTIAC HAS ISSUED A</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get rid of Japanese Knotweed</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-get-rid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 11:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-30-how-to-get-rid/</guid>
      <description>We have a patch of land that should be doing something productive but instead is growing Japanese Knotweed.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;d like to fix that.
The simple description of how to deal with it seems to be to smother the affected area (using tarps or old carpets) and to do container gardening on top of that ground cover.&amp;nbsp; (ref about.com)
It&#39;s time to think about it now, because I know that come May, it&#39;ll be growing with wild abandon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plant tomatoes upside down (so that you can move them out of the way of frost)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-28-how-to-plant-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 14:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-28-how-to-plant-to/</guid>
      <description>In the &#34;try this next year&#34; category, here are some designs for a planter for tomatoes where you put the tomato seedlings in a bucket and then hang the bucket upside down. Two advantages are obvious: one, that if there&#39;s frost, you can move the bucket out of the way, and two, you can grow in places where you don&#39;t have soil.
Three, I guess, is that you can plant something nice in the top of the pot and have it do double duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to protect tomatoes from frost</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-27-how-to-protect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 15:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-27-how-to-protect/</guid>
      <description>Frost warnings for Ann Arbor for tonight; that&#39;s kind of late.
In the spirit of gardeners everywhere, here&#39;s some collected recommendations for dealing with frost damage in your garden.
From Zimbabwe and Farm Radio International:
 Protect Tomatoes from Frost By Livai Matarirano, Zimbabawe
You can grow tomatoes even in cold weather. A farmer in Zimbabwe, Mr. Francis Handwa, uses cooking oil or milk bottles filled with water to keep tomato plants warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan Morel Map 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-25-michigan-morel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 21:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-25-michigan-morel/</guid>
      <description>You don&#39;t really think I&#39;m going to tell you where to pick morels, do you? Even my mom won&#39;t tell me where she gets hers.
What I can share is some set of things that people are tracking for timing for when morels appear, and forums where this stuff is being discussed by experts.
There is a terrific list of morel mushroom information carefully collected by The Great Morel; lots to read, if you want to know more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>