<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ann-arbor-farmers-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Farmers Market on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 16:00:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/ann-arbor-farmers-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2015 Farmers Market report</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-august-farmers-market-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 16:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-august-farmers-market-report/</guid>
      <description>At Ann Arbor Farmers Market:
Red Haven peaches 🍑, potatoes 🍠, kale, green onions, tomatoes, red peppers, and a cherry snow cone for my shopping companion.
(Testing to see how the emoji comes out; I didn&amp;rsquo;t see a kale emoji.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>food coop notes for July 18, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 14:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-18-food-coop-notes/</guid>
      <description>Some notes over a cup of coffee and some cold roast chicken. I need to mix up my menu selections at the coop more so that I can remember what I was writing by what I ate; I usually eat the same thing!
Peter Honeyman and Lynn Chamberlain were here at the coop, doing the NY Times crossword. (Saturday crossword in 36:05, a mid-day triumph.)
At Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market: cherries, parsley, kale, potatoes, dill, tomatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Farmers Market report for June 27, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 12:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-27-ann-arbor-farmers-market-report-for-june-27-2009/</guid>
      <description>mostly pulled from twitter, but also from some field reporting from your fearless market reporter.
The Farmer&amp;#39;s Marketer (Kim Bayer) notes
&amp;quot;Committee forming to determine if year round indoor farmers market viable in downtown Ann Arbor.&amp;quot; Open House 7.8.09. 3:30-7pm. Eaton Bldg.
I don&amp;#39;t have a URL to point to for this one for more details but you could ask Kim.
Jeff McCabe is on a misson to create &amp;quot;as many hoop houses in our area as these efforts can muster&amp;quot;; he has resources to support two of them to be built this fall, contact him for the application due July 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s at the Ann Arbor Farmer&#39;s Market, March 21, 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-whats-at-the-ann-arbor-farmers-market-may-21-2009/</guid>
      <description>Molly is publishing market lists; here&amp;#39;s last week&amp;#39;s.&amp;#0160; I don&amp;#39;t yet have a vendor list that goes with it.
March 21, 2009!&amp;#0160;
  Apples  Baked goods  Beef  Beet greens  Beets  Bison  Biscotti  Cider  Cupcakes  Delicious chocolate cookies  Cultivated mushrooms  Coffee (including hand-pulled espresso!)  Dulce du leche  Eggs  Honey  Jams &amp;amp; jellies  Kale  Lamb  Maple Syrup  Onions  Popcorn  Potatoes  Delicate salad greens  Radishes  Spinach  Tamales  Winter squash   +&amp;#0160;a&amp;#0160;delightful selection of crafts, plants, and flowers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>