<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 18:16:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from a construction project</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 18:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-27-notes-from-a-construction-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An old bicycle wheel makes a good pulley wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old modem, of any sort, can be repurposed by attaching a single RJ-11 cord to both ends of it; you now have a loop, and the RJ-11 threads through the bicycle wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An RS-232 cable should be thought of as a very strong wire rope with helpful screw connectors.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A transformer makes an excellent counterweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no piece of old electronic junk that doesn&amp;#39;t have some possible usefulness as a part of a kinetic sculpture, whether it works or not.&amp;#0160;Remember, kids, &lt;strong&gt;the connector is the artwork&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mindless mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-05-27-mindless-mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used this phrase in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/03/meaningless-indicators-of-progress.html&#34;&gt;meaningless indicators of progress&lt;/a&gt; post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other uses of it, just so I manage to put it in an appropriate context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronicle of Higher Education has a story called &lt;a href=&#34;http://chronicle.com/article/The-Art-of-Living-Mindfully/63292/?sid=at&#34;&gt;The Art of Living Mindfully&lt;/a&gt; on the work of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ellenlanger.com/&#34;&gt;Ellen Langer&lt;/a&gt;. Her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ellenlanger.com/blog/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is not frequent but it is thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
We have been explicitly and implicitly taught by our culture to be mindless. We have been taught absolutes when none really exist independent of context. When we think we know something absolutely, we have learned that it is reasonable never to question it, nor to pay attention to how it may be otherwise. Beliefs and behavior always make some kind of sense from the actor’s perspective or else the actor would have done otherwise. Blame suggests mindlessness on the part of the blamer who does not recognize this. We are not at fault for what we do not know just because someone else can see a way we could have known it.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1550775&#34;&gt;Just Breathe: Meditation as Organizational Slack&lt;/a&gt; is a paper by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/pub/kaisa-holloway-cripps/3/ba7/b62&#34;&gt;Kaisa G. Holloway Cripps&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#0160;Mostly a literature review, it looks at meditation inside an organization and identifies ways where it may be useful to engage human resources that are slack. &amp;#0160;The discussion reminds me of MBA consultants who work like dogs for months and then are periodically &amp;quot;on the beach&amp;quot; for a while when their gig is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly hit Buddhism when I look up this phrase, the parts of Buddhism that I haven&amp;#39;t lived close enough to that I appreciate all of the subtleties of the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;within&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;without&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;with&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mindfulness&lt;/strong&gt;,” he&amp;#0160;&lt;strong&gt;mindlessly&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#0160;chants. “Shut up just shut it up already,” ... (&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=J5PXLLQ5ADsC&amp;amp;dq=subject:fiction+mindless+mindfulness&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;source=gbs_navlinks_s&#34;&gt;Circle This Mountain&lt;/a&gt;, mercifully abbreviated by Google Books)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity, a collection</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-16-serendipity-a-collection-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some collected thoughts on serendipity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2005/06/serendipity_in_.html&#34;&gt;serendipity in book-finding&lt;/a&gt;: (via if:book)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;the pinpoint accuracy of computer-searches, leaves those of us lucky
enough to have spent time in library stacks, nostalgic for the
unexpected discovery of something we didn&amp;#39;t know we were looking for
but which just happened, serendipitously, to be on a nearby shelf.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/Lindsay/Writing/serendip.html&#34;&gt;Lindsay Marshall on serendipity:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;We are not, I believe, looking for tools to record our thoughts or to
provide them with structure. What we seek is something that leads us to
the unforeseen collisions, the copulations that lead to new thoughts,
new connections and yet more new meetings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/superpatron/2008/06/photo-credit-fr.html&#34;&gt;Moyra Davis on the problem of reading:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Both books are filled not only with Davey&amp;#39;s moody photos of bookshelves
in various states of disarray and transition but also with her thoughts
on the place of reading in a creative life, and the difficulty, in
managing the habit, of striking the right balance between purpose and
serendipity, and between work and pleasure. &amp;quot;&amp;#39;What to read?&amp;#39; is a
recurring dilemma in my life,&amp;quot; she admits in The Problem of Reading,
which has, among other images, a great close-up of her mother&amp;#39;s
annotations of Swann&amp;#39;s Way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chacocanyon.com/pointlookout/020925.shtml&#34;&gt;Rick Brenner on serendipity in project management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Serendipity in project management is rare,
in part, because we&amp;#39;re under too much pressure to see it. If we can
reduce the pressure, wonderful things happen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://catless.ncl.ac.uk/Lindsay/&#34;&gt;Lindsay Marshall&lt;/a&gt; for the original spur to this line of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>