<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Public Schools on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-public-schools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Public Schools on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:16:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-public-schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools superintendent Patricia Green resigns</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patricia Green, superintendent of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, has resigned effective 90 days from April 10, 2013. Her letter of resignation, which was distributed by electronic mail to AAPS parents, follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/2013/04/part-iv-my-commentary-on-superintendent.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ruth from A2 Schools Muse has insightful commentary.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 11, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues and AAPS Families:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last evening, I gave President Deb Mexicotte a letter in which I asked her to 
accept my resignation as Superintendent of Schools of the Ann Arbor Public 
Schools, effective 90 days from yesterday. I shared with her that I plan to 
retire during the summer after 43 years as a professional educator in public 
education. I have been blessed to have truly enjoyed my 43-year career and I 
thanked her and the Board for the opportunity to serve the Ann Arbor 
community during these past two years.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all my colleagues in Ann Arbor Public Schools, it has been a privilege to 
work with you and I wish you well as you continue to maintain the highest 
of standards for all of our children in the future. Ann Arbor is truly an 
outstanding school district with so many dedicated staff members who care 
enormously about children. Your commitment and dedication are beyond 
compare! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I retire, I hope to do some reflective writing about my many experiences 
in education, do some traveling, and reconnect with family and friends who I 
have neglected over the years!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to you all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patricia P. Green, Ph.D.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superintendent of Schools
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>