<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Public Schools on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-public-schools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Ann Arbor Public Schools on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 19:19:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-ann-arbor-public-schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools expects transportation disruption on Monday, 8 September 2014 because of aftereffects of Friday storms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-07-ann-arbor-public-schools-expects-transportation-disruption-on-monday-8-september-2014-because-of-aft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 19:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-09-07-ann-arbor-public-schools-expects-transportation-disruption-on-monday-8-september-2014-because-of-aft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANN ARBOR - Sunday, 7 September, 2014 - This letter was sent to all Ann Arbor Public Schools families and staff. The worst of the traffic will be in south Ann Arbor where there&#39;s detours on the Stone School bridge over I-94 and the Eisenhower bridge over over the Ann Arbor Railroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0655e14970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0655e14970c img-responsive&#34; style=&#34;width: 450px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-07 at 6.41.40 PM&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2014-09-07 at 6.41.40 PM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01b8d0655e14970c-450wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear AAPS Families and Staff,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to check in this evening to update you on our AAPS status regarding the numerous impacts of the storm that passed through our area on Friday evening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been monitoring our school buildings throughout the weekend, and are pleased to report that, at this time, all AAPS schools have power and are fully operational. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we also understand that a number of situations in Ann Arbor continue that may affect travel to and from schools tomorrow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many traffic lights across the area are still not working and the Eisenhower Bridge between S. Industrial Hwy. and Boardwalk has been closed since Friday night (two power line poles are leaning dangerously and so the bridge has been closed until DTE addresses this issue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This road closure along with the existing Stone School Rd. closure compounded by the various signal lights that are out across the community will make for a very busy and hectic Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please know that we expect delays in our bus service tomorrow morning that will continue until DTE completes these repairs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transportation will be re-routing buses to minimize the impact, and yet we anticipate delays in both bus and car travel to and from school tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we want to remind everyone that there are still areas throughout the community with active power lines down. These areas should be well-marked by now, but please be cautious and let&#39;s remind all our students to be very careful to stay clear of any areas that may have downed power lines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience as we all deal with the fallout from Friday night&#39;s storm that continues to impact our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeanice Swift
Superintendent&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Public Schools superintendent Patricia Green resigns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/2013-04-11-ann-arbor-public-school-superintendent-patricia-green-resigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patricia Green, superintendent of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, has resigned effective 90 days from April 10, 2013. Her letter of resignation, which was distributed by electronic mail to AAPS parents, follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2schoolsmuse.blogspot.com/2013/04/part-iv-my-commentary-on-superintendent.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ruth from A2 Schools Muse has insightful commentary.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 11, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues and AAPS Families:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last evening, I gave President Deb Mexicotte a letter in which I asked her to 
accept my resignation as Superintendent of Schools of the Ann Arbor Public 
Schools, effective 90 days from yesterday. I shared with her that I plan to 
retire during the summer after 43 years as a professional educator in public 
education. I have been blessed to have truly enjoyed my 43-year career and I 
thanked her and the Board for the opportunity to serve the Ann Arbor 
community during these past two years.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all my colleagues in Ann Arbor Public Schools, it has been a privilege to 
work with you and I wish you well as you continue to maintain the highest 
of standards for all of our children in the future. Ann Arbor is truly an 
outstanding school district with so many dedicated staff members who care 
enormously about children. Your commitment and dedication are beyond 
compare! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I retire, I hope to do some reflective writing about my many experiences 
in education, do some traveling, and reconnect with family and friends who I 
have neglected over the years!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to you all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patricia P. Green, Ph.D.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superintendent of Schools
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>