<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws Iot on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws-iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws Iot on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 13:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws-iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS IoT to Node-RED</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 13:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</guid>
      <description>Duong Dinh Cuong (on Github as cuongquay) has contributed a node for Node-RED that encapsulates the AWS IoT service and allows straightforward communication between the two systems over MQTT.
The node, node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub, includes support for the message-passing part of AWS IoT using MQTT, allowing you to open a channel to the IoT service and publish or subscribe to message topics. The result is easy integration between the two systems. As a part of this process, the node includes support for AWS certificates that have to be installed &amp;ldquo;just so&amp;rdquo; to allow AWS to trust Node-RED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platforms for the Internet of Things, 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</guid>
      <description>A discussion on one of the lists I follow covers the question of &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; support for the Internet of Things. Since consumer IoT is a kind of squooshy market right now with rapid changes in prices and no one obvious choice for what technology to adopt, it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile taking some kind of review of the landscape for 2015 and sort out what to watch for next year.
This is organized by vendor, and loosely grouped so that similar systems are next to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>