<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws-iot/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws-iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS IoT to Node-RED</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 13:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-11-aws-iot-to-node-red/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duong Dinh Cuong (on Github as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuongquay&#34;&gt;cuongquay&lt;/a&gt;) has contributed a node
for Node-RED that encapsulates the AWS IoT service and allows
straightforward communication between the two systems over MQTT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The node, node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub,
includes support for the message-passing
part of AWS IoT using MQTT, allowing you to open
a channel to the IoT service and publish or subscribe
to message topics. The result is easy integration between
the two systems. As a part of this process, the node
includes support for AWS certificates that have to be
installed &amp;ldquo;just so&amp;rdquo; to allow AWS to trust Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current release is 0.1.5 from today, October 11, 2016.
You can find it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuongquay/node-red-contrib-aws-iot&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;,
on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;,
and in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-aws-iot-hub&#34;&gt;Node-RED flows library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tested this with my airplane tracking code which publishes
from a Raspberry Pi to AWS IoT using mosquitto, and it all seems
to check out OK. A next step on my part is to port the whole
experience up from my Mac where a test instance is running up to
CoreOS, and also to document the AWS command line to generate
the correct certificates in the correct format with the correct
file names.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platforms for the Internet of Things, 2015 edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-17-iot-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A discussion on one of the lists I follow covers the question
of &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; support for the Internet of Things. Since consumer
IoT is a kind of squooshy market right now with rapid changes
in prices and no one obvious choice for what technology to adopt,
it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile taking some kind of review of the landscape for
2015 and sort out what to watch for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is organized by vendor, and loosely grouped so that similar
systems are next to each other. It&amp;rsquo;s a highly dimensional space, but
all elements have something in common: engineers are trying to
change how we interact with simple devices like light bulbs through
our hand-held phones, and no one has the full correct answer that&amp;rsquo;s
obviously right. Indeed it&amp;rsquo;s not clear at all that there is
a right answer for some of these controls; the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/internetofshit&#34;&gt;Internet of Shit twitter account&lt;/a&gt;
collects with some glee the number of devices that emphatically should
not be on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the platforms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon&lt;/em&gt; is hard to ignore. Many smaller cloud platforms are
built on top of its AWS computing platforms, and Amazon has
entered the fray with its AWS IoT service that offers a hosted
MQTT message server. In addition Amazon has the Echo product
that does voice recognition. Nearly impossible to ignore, Amazon
is a clear central player in the IoT consumer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; is a distant second in the IoT world, mostly because
the Google Compute Engine isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a compute
platform, and the Android phone isn&amp;rsquo;t the first choice for a top
end phone. Google does have the moxie to make it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Internet Thing&amp;rdquo;
be a self-driving car. The Nest thermostat is the most obvious
home point-of-entry for Google, and the platform and brand extension
to watch is more stuff that works with Nest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple&lt;/em&gt; has the phone to want, and the assistant (Siri) that people
have learned how to talk to to get things done. If the Internet of
Things is going to be controlled from an app, it&amp;rsquo;s an app that&amp;rsquo;s going
to run on an Apple phone, and you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to talk to it.
Less clear is Apple&amp;rsquo;s in-home device hub strategy - the AppleTV never
really has had that open platform feel to attract the first-mover developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft&lt;/em&gt; would dearly love to play in this world, but Windows 10
on ARM and the Raspberry Pi is a disappointment, and &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; is mostly
defined by problems too big for Excel. The Microsoft cloud platform,
Azure, mostly seems to be used by organizations that treat it as
a second or third data center, or who are locked in to Azure for
business and partnership reasons. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Cortana is capable, but
hardly anyone has Windows phones to talk with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IBM&lt;/em&gt; is the wild card here. Their Bluemix hosted platform service is
interesting if unusual and not really aimed at the consumer space. A
very interesting Node-RED project has extended IBM influence into
the Raspberry Pi and Bluetooth BLE sensor space, but it feels like
an interesting technology play and not a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, to major players with hardware. &amp;ldquo;How many engineers does it
take to change a lightbulb?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philips&lt;/em&gt; has the Hue line of home products, mostly lighting focused.
There was a hue and cry about the Philips decision to disable support
for some compatible products that did not have explicit partnership
agreements in place, and the nature of the complaining made it clear
that there&amp;rsquo;s an active hobbyist community around this product space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flex&lt;/em&gt; is the new player, with its recent acquisition of the
assets of Wink from the bankruptcy of Quirky.  Flex, formerly known
as Flextronics, is a large contract manufacturer, and it knows how
to build quite a few things; look for Wink&amp;rsquo;s technology to make its
way into a wider range of products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung&lt;/em&gt; and their SmartThings brand has enough market share to make
interesting efforts, but again to that point there&amp;rsquo;s no one breakout
product in their portfolio that brings that brand much to mind unless
you are using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest winner in the IoT space for this year and probably for
next year is an Internet tool with the unlikely name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ifttt.com&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;ldquo;If this, then that&amp;rdquo; is the level of control you get with IFTTT,
and surprisingly enough that&amp;rsquo;s enough to do all sorts of things -
mostly because IFTTT speaks just enough of the protocols of over 100
systems that you can glue together a recipe that does something
when something else happens even when the two vendors you are dealing
with have never heard of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interoperability is the bugaboo of Internet of Things systems development.
Many vendors want you to sign up to their big bear hug of a partnership
agreement and work solely within their ecosystem. Others have narrow
APIs and proprietary protocols that discourage casual reuse. Where
IFTTT fits in is as a universal connector kit that lets you explore
how parts fit together.  The IFTTT
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/recipes/collections/32-recipes-for-the-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;recipes for the Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt; captures some of the essence of what
can be done right now without much of a fuss if you have wide protocol
support, even if it&amp;rsquo;s only very simple support.
Many vendors in the &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things&amp;rdquo;
space could benefit from thorough understanding of simple connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>