<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Detroit on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/detroit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Detroit on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 23:58:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/detroit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DETROITography, a weblog of maps about Detroit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-detroitography-a-weblog-of-maps-about-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 23:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-11-detroitography-a-weblog-of-maps-about-detroit/</guid>
      <description>File under Detroit and maps -
From detroitography.com:  Maps and geography of Detroit – that’s what we are all about. We like to write about maps that other people make about the city as well as create our own maps of Detroit.
 This map (one of many on the site) shows the overlap of what people map out when they say they are from Detroit. The densest is the downtown region only; the most generous encompasses a 9-county region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packard Plant auction winner sends &#34;the most insane press release ever&#34;, bid cancelled by Wayne County</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-30-packard-plant-auction-winner-sends-the-most-insane-press-release-ever-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 08:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-30-packard-plant-auction-winner-sends-the-most-insane-press-release-ever-/</guid>
      <description>Detroit&#39;s Packard Plant recently went up for auction, and the winner is a group led by Texas physician Dr. Jill Van Horn with a bid of just over $6 million. The press release sent on the occasion was described as &#34;the most insane press release ever&#34;. Some news coverage and the full text the PR missive follow below.
UPDATE 10/30/13: The Wayne County Treasurer&#39;s Office has cancelled this bid, according to the Detroit Free Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE statement on power outage at beginning of 3d game of 2013 ALCS at Comerica Park in Detroit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-dte-statement-on-power-outage-at-beginning-of-3d-game-of-2013-alcs-at-comerica-park-in-detroit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-15-dte-statement-on-power-outage-at-beginning-of-3d-game-of-2013-alcs-at-comerica-park-in-detroit/</guid>
      <description>From DTE Energy:
DTE Energy addresses temporary lighting failure at Comerica Park DETROIT, Oct. 15, 2013 /PRNewswire/ -- DTE Energy&#39;s preliminary investigation of the temporary lighting failure that occurred at Comerica Park during Major League Baseball&#39;s American League Championship Series (ALCS), has found there was a cable failure in the area near the stadium, which caused the problem.
The lights in the stadium were out for approximately 20 minutes beginning at approximately 4:41 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Detroit &#34;Metro Times&#34; is up for sale</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-the-detroit-metro-times-is-up-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 07:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-28-the-detroit-metro-times-is-up-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>Originally seen on Deadline Detroit, my go-to place for quick hits on Detroit news - the Metro Times is up for sale. If you ever wanted to be in journalism now&#39;s your chance.
From the article -
 The company that owns the Metro Times told its Detroit staff this morning (August 26, 2013) the paper is for sale, throwing the future of the 33-year-old alternative weekly into doubt at a time of great uncertainty for print publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit, Michigan has filed for Chapter 9 bankruptcy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-18-detroit-has-filed-for-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 16:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-18-detroit-has-filed-for-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s all over the local news, but it&#39;s a national story as well: Detroit has filed for Chapter 9 bankruptcy.
New York Times: Detroit Files for Bankruptcy, July 18. &#34;Detroit, the cradle of America’s automobile industry and once the nation’s fourth-most-populous city, has filed for bankruptcy, an official said Thursday afternoon, the largest American city ever to take such a course.&#34;
Wall Street Journal: Detroit Files for Chapter 9 Bankruptcy, July 18.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>