<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 08:52:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>inbox 50, unread 500</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-04-16-inbox-50-unread-500/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 08:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2015/2015-04-16-inbox-50-unread-500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So if you don&#39;t read email every moment of every waking day, you get a bit behind. Apologies to my correspondents if I can&#39;t manage same-day responses every day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bee App, a multiplatform issue tracker client for Mac</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-bee-app-a-multiplatform-issue-tracker-client-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-bee-app-a-multiplatform-issue-tracker-client-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been tracking my personal todo list on Github for nearly two years now. When I &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/12/issue-tracker-a-github-project-for-personal-productivity.html&#34;&gt;first wrote up the experience&lt;/a&gt; I had just been using the standard web client for the system; since then I&#39;ve added &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/11/octodroid-is-a-github-client-for-android.html&#34;&gt;Octodroid&lt;/a&gt; as an Android client. So far so good, I&#39;ve closed more than 2300 issues since I started. Github&#39;s issues is a completely feature-filled issue management system, far and above overkill for a personal todo list, but useful and complete enough to manage routine tasking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: left;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-03 at 9.38.40 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-03 at 9.38.40 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new thing in my life (to go with the new laptop) is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neat.io/bee/&#34;&gt;Bee&lt;/a&gt; (@thebeeapp), a Mac native client that&#39;s a front end for several issue tracking systems. I have a free 30 day trial, after which the software looks like it could be reasonably priced if I were to use it all the time. Notably it&#39;s software-as-software, not software-as-a-service, so I&#39;d just buy it and not have to pay every month for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bee gives you a nice GUI for your issues, so that you can sift through the debris of what you thought you wanted to do and comment on, reassign, close, or edit those things. The net effect for me over a few hours of use was to flush out about two dozen things that had been obscured by my previous issue management regime that I was never going to do or that were totally overtaken by events. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;getting things done&#34; ritual speaks of a weekly review, where you once a week sort through all of the detritus that had landed on your todo list over the course of a week and make sense of it all. The ability to take on a review like that depends crucially on whether you can get everything that&#39;s on your plate into a single list that you can walk through methodically (and in some sensible order) so that you&#39;re not horribly fatigued by issue overload by the end. Perhaps it&#39;s the new app smell that makes it possible for me to do that anew, but I was really happy with Bee as a way to work through a review, and I&#39;m hopeful that it keeps giving me insights and inspiration as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>falling behind, slowly</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-29-falling-behind-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 10:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-29-falling-behind-slowly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My laptop has been in the shop for more than a week. I am not keeping up with correspondence as a result. I apparently had an efficient enough system that for a given hour of focus I could answer or log as much mail as came in. Now I can&#39;t, and there are not enough hours in the day to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse I have also rediscovered that I can write on this little device, and that blogging is about the right length for the small screen to compose. So even though I am not keeping up with private discourse, my public engagement with the tiny part of the net that reads blogs is going just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strong temptation is to head to the Apple store and buy something fast, fancy, shiny, waterproof, coffee proof, and with a solid keyboard. I don&#39;t know if that device exists. Until then the cup of coffee always goes to the far right of the small screen so I know where it is at all times and so I don&#39;t knock it over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>do next?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-27-do-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-09-27-do-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One algorithm for deciding what to do next is simply to identify
the item with the closest deadline and work on that. There is nothing
like a deadline to focus the mind, and it is better to get the items
that demand short term attention into the calendar and to allot the
time to tackle them. Bernie Galler described this approach to me once,
and it stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second approach is to put everything you might ever want to do
in a big pile and pick something at random from it to work on. I
use github issues to track my big pile of things to do, and alas
it does not have a random() function. Fortunately though there is
a Github API, and that combined with &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; and my &lt;code&gt;randomline&lt;/code&gt; script
are enough to approximate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third very reasonable approach is to ask someone what they would
like you to do; or even better yet anticipate what they would ask
and do it before they ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me, I have work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He sees you when you&#39;re sleeping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-05-06-he-sees-you-when-youre-sleeping-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 10:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-05-06-he-sees-you-when-youre-sleeping-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He sees you when you&#39;re sleeping &lt;br/&gt; 
  He knows when you&#39;re awake  &lt;br/&gt; 
  He knows if you&#39;ve been bad or good &lt;br/&gt;
  So be good for goodness sake &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The startup Buffer has a radical approach to transparency. Corporate minders watch your every move, on and off the clock, and the results of their nosy prying are available to all of your coworkers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inc.com/jeff-haden/inside-buffer-company-complete-transparency.html&#34;&gt;From Inc.&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We recently gave everyone at Buffer a Jawbone UP wristband. It allows you to automatically track your sleep, your daily steps, your nutrition, and a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;One of our key values at Buffer is to work smarter, not harder. Personal improvement is a big part of that, so giving employees a tool that can help improve their sleep patterns is a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;A few weeks in it&#39;s already had an incredible effect. Browsing everyone&#39;s sleep patterns and talking about how to get more deep sleep has an amazing effect on productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s good when companies give off a clear &#34;this is not for me&#34; signal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Personal Kanban with Boardthing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I change productivity tools from time to time. Here&#39;s a latest try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only two real rules with Personal Kanban:
1. Visualize your work
2. Limit your work-in-progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/07/personal-kanban-from-jim-benson-and-modus-cooperandi.html&#34;&gt;wrote about Personal Kanban before&lt;/a&gt; back in 2010, but I didn&#39;t try to put it into practice as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boardthing is an invention of Dave Gray. There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindmappingsoftwareblog.com/boardthing/&#34;&gt;review of Boardthing&lt;/a&gt; from Chuck Frey which goes into a few more details, but the short summary of it is that it&#39;s a suitable way to rearrange little rectangles on a board. The little rectangles each have some text or an image in them, and they can be nested so you can move them around in groups. There&#39;s really not much more than that, and it runs in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This infrastructure is enough to create a Personal Kanban board. Create little rectangles at minimum for &#34;Things to do&#34;, &#34;Doing&#34;, and &#34;Done&#34;, and type into the little rectangles to move them around until you figure out what to do, stop typing, and get something done. I recommend a &#34;Things not to do&#34; rectangle as an added productivity boost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this work in the long term? The system is pretty light weight, and it saves your state between sessions. I suppose if your page gets too cluttered you can start a new one that is more focused. Having a smallish screen forces you to limit your work in progress, which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Gray and Jim Benson have a set of approaches that should work well together, this is mostly written for the both of them as an introduction of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting things done includes deciding what not to do.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-14-getting-things-done-includes-deciding-what-not-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-04-14-getting-things-done-includes-deciding-what-not-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting things done includes deciding what not to do. In my case, it&#39;s a matter of going through my todo list and striking off the well-intentioned tasks from two or three months ago that took a moment to write and that would take hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m better off at accomplishing things when there are fewer undone things to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Janet Choi writes about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/articles/24875/the-art-of-the-done-list-harnessing-the-power-of-progress&#34;&gt;done list&lt;/a&gt; for 99u.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you do anything you consider useful, however small a win it may be, write it down on your done list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can lead to the purposeful behavior of writing something on your todo list just to cross it off and mark it done. The system I&#39;m using doesn&#39;t easily distinguish between the three states of &#34;did and then wrote it down&#34;, &#34;wrote it down and did it later&#34;, or &#34;wrote it down and decided not to do it later&#34;. But that&#39;s a quibble.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack, first impressions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-02-20-slack-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 09:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-02-20-slack-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Slack-logo&#34; title=&#34;Slack-logo&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b-120wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system has many familiar components. It feels like an IRC network, complete with a set of well thought out bots and useful integrations with development tools. Unlike most IRC nets, it comes with a rich set of web and native clients that make it feel like something that ordinary people could use and not just the ubergeeks. For the ubergeeks, it also has a very competent IRC client support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience of the system varies tremendously depending on who you have on your team. If they have somewhere else to talk, then you might never get the critical mass you need to have a real conversation online. About a third of the people I&#39;m inviting actually start to use the system, and most of those have some IRC channel time in their background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web client and the Android client for Slack are both very capably executed and feel like sound, solid pieces of engineering. It adds a lot of confidence to using the system to have such nice tools to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com/integrations&#34;&gt;integrations&lt;/a&gt; configured for RSS feeds, for Github (issues and commits), and for Google Hangouts. There&#39;s a rich API, or so it seems, and lots of other systems that have had integrations built for them. I have ambitions but no infrastructure yet to write my own code or better yet borrow other people&#39;s code to extend the system. I&#39;m not much more advanced yet than getting the &#34;hello world&#34; style post-to-Slack-from-the-command-line capability going, but it did work, so I have high hopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slack server I have set up is running on their free trial, which has a limited number of integration slots. I think that by cleverly enabling and disabling services that I can try enough of them to build up some experience with the system, but not necessarily run everything in production. I get 5 for free, and Github, Hangouts, RSS, Twitter, and the incoming webhook make up that 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to see what I&#39;ve built and join in, drop me a line and I can send you an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting work in progress vs. the endless todo list</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 10:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c&#34; alt=&#34;Github-activity-graph-illustration&#34; title=&#34;Github-activity-graph-illustration&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c-120wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using a todo system &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/12/issue-tracker-a-github-project-for-personal-productivity.html&#34;&gt;based on Github issues&lt;/a&gt; for the better part of a year. It&#39;s been an interesting exercise in trying to corral the things that aren&#39;t done yet but that need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started out, I dumped every last thing that I might do into the system, everything from major tasks to &#34;do laundry&#34; (which can seem like a major task at times). The count of undone things oscillated from 60 to 100 things to be done, which made it seem like an infinite list because it took too long to review the whole list and it was on 3 or 4 screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some reflection, I decided that the only way to make progress on this list was to dramatically prune it. That means taking some items off the list that I really do want to do eventually, it&#39;s just that I&#39;m not focusing on them now because every time I look at them on the list I say &#34;no&#34;. Crossing them off the list doesn&#39;t completely delete them, and when I need to revisit them I can reopen the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list is down to 30 now, and I&#39;m careful not to add more than that without crossing something else off the list. It still has a few lingering things that haven&#39;t been done for a long time, but I have had my teeth cleaned, and what&#39;s more I can read through the whole thing in one sitting and usually say &#34;yes&#34; to some next task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More reading: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.personalkanban.com/pk/primers/why-limit-your-wip-a-pk-info-series/&#34;&gt;Why limit your work in progress&lt;/a&gt;, Jim Benson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overtaken by events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-02-overtaken-by-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-02-overtaken-by-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thinning out my todo list for the new year to delete some of the oldest items, the ones that aren&#39;t particularly hard but they also haven&#39;t been done this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figure that if I need to do them, the opportunity will arise again, and it might be easier to get them done if they show up fresh at the top of the list rather than buried at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s humorous (or sad) is the items marked &#34;urgent&#34; that are more than a week old; clearly, simply marking something as urgent does not stand in for actually doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, new year&#39;s productivity !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Yup, thinning out the list is now a perpetual activity; I&#39;m trying to keep work in progress under about 30 tasks. There may be more to do in the world, you think? I can only keep track of so much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering that it&#39;s your happy birthday</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-07-08-remembering-that-its-your-happy-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 09:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2013/2013-07-08-remembering-that-its-your-happy-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Periodically I look at the sorts of tools that you can use to remember that it&amp;#39;s someone&amp;#39;s birthday. Here&amp;#39;s the current things that put birthday reminders in front of me every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910422a7a5970c-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Facebook-birthday-wish&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910422a7a5970c&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01910422a7a5970c-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Facebook-birthday-wish&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The 10,000 lb. gorilla of birthdays is Facebook, which offers a nice simple interface to send a one-line birthday greeting. You could visit Facebook daily just for birthdays and not much more, and be reasonably satisfied with the results. The site offers several convenient ways to send gifts via Starbucks, iTunes, and Target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The up and coming wannabe of birthdays is Google Plus, which puts birthday notifications on your Plus home screen. I&amp;#39;m not 100% certain where it gets its birthday information from - whether it pulls in details from you Google Contacts data, or if it&amp;#39;s just self-reported birthdays on your Google profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn has birthday alerts as well, but some people have &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.linkedin.com/questions/55441/stop-sending-say-congratulations-on-birthdays-or-a.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;complained&lt;/a&gt; that the reminders are annoying. There&amp;#39;s no apparent way to turn this feature off in LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.contapps.android&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Contacts +&lt;/a&gt; app running on my Android phone, and it reaches into your contact database and reminds you about people who have birthdays today. The handy thing about it is that new birthdays show up as notifications with a one-click to a screen that offers you lots of ways to contact someone, so that if you were to want to send someone a postcard (a few days late, alas) you could be ready for that task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still don&amp;#39;t have a great way to routinely get birthday postcards to people on time - that would take a level of daily or weekly commitment and organization that I&amp;#39;m not yet ready to take on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermemo, spaced repetition and time-structured randomness</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-06-06-supermemo-spaced-repetition-and-structured-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-06-06-supermemo-spaced-repetition-and-structured-randomness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eec7f78970b-pi&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 4&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eec7f78970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01538eec7f78970b-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve written about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/08/supermemo-repet.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Supermemo&lt;/a&gt; before, a system for focusing your attention on things that you have previously learned in such a way that you reinforce long term memory. Given a set of items which you were confident in at a stage in the past, identify a way to re-test yourself on that confidence. Space out those retest intervals so that you keep the learning from decaying into nothingness. Repetition is the very soul of the net, and if you are careful you can repeat at intervals that don&amp;#39;t overwhelm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New to me this week is a similar spaced repetition training tool focused on short term memory. Referred to as &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N-back&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;N-back&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (Wikipedia), it looks at turning the process of matching repetitive items in a sequence into a game, with higher scores if you can recall that e.g. 3 letters ago there was also an &amp;#39;x&amp;#39; in the string. The application &lt;a href=&#34;http://brainworkshop.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Brain Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;was created by Paul Hoskinson and lets you play with your current skills; I haven&amp;#39;t seen anyone render this into hardware a la the old game of &lt;strong&gt;Simon&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To turn the random noise of the world into patterns that you understand and can manipulate and recognize, you need to find the useful connections and build upon them somehow. You can&amp;#39;t just learn by remembering things out of context - it always helps to learn by doing. People love to make things into patterns, and an organized exploration of an otherwise random world can help you make connections which are key to understanding the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space I keep trying to explore is remembering the names of people, some of whom I know rather well by face, others who I know only by their work. The index into this space that lends itself to randomness is the birthday, which you can be pretty sure to capture less than 1% of the set of people every day. Alas, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.letsmovetothemoon.com/facebook-cheapens-birthdays/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Facebook has cheapened&lt;/a&gt; the opportunity for &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/12/how-to-remember-birthdays-ed44-edition.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;remembering someone&amp;#39;s birthday&lt;/a&gt; as a distinguishing mark, so the challenge is to use this somehow else; if I happen to remember your half birthday, it&amp;#39;s because I&amp;#39;m trying to remember and plan both forward and back 6 months. Even better if I send you a half-birthday postcard (to combine two unusual abilities). Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>daily aliquot of love</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-01-18-task-sandwich-activity-tracker-in-google-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2011/2011-01-18-task-sandwich-activity-tracker-in-google-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very brief writeup of a technique for doing online task management, in a world where there are so many social media channels that you need a spreadsheet to keep track of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software is Google Spreadsheet, used with a private sheet all for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the worksheet is a set of columns, with column headings indicating the piece of software, online system, or media channel that you are tracking; the rows are dated or time stamped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each cell has a brief summary of events, activities, or other goings-on for that channel at that time. &amp;quot;Birthday deals&amp;quot; is my notation from Facebook for Jan 5, 2011, noting that on that day I wished people a happy birthday by sending them the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Birthday_Deals&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki birthday deals page&lt;/a&gt; (my customary greeting card). Keep it short, down to a name, a keyword, a tag, or anything else minimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key technique is hyperlinking each of these (column header and activity cell) where possible, so that you can go back and re-animate your activity on a minimum notice. The syntax is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=hyperlink(URL,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is simple enough to make it not be a big deal to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The locus of activity moves. Rather than opening a new window, looking for page changes to the more frequent sites that you visit, and hoping mindlessly that there&amp;#39;s something new, the unit of online activity becomes working your way across the columns and methodically filling in each of them with a daily aliquot of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is getting the column headers right, so that you focus on the correct systems, and ignore the irrelevant ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I call it task sandwich? Darned if I know, that&amp;#39;s what got typed in.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alas, poor delicious, you knew us well</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-12-17-alas-poor-delicious-you-knew-us-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-12-17-alas-poor-delicious-you-knew-us-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2010/12/16/is-yahoo-shutting-down-del-icio-us/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt; is that delicious is going to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/bpm140/status/15473591558602752&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;axed&lt;/a&gt; by Yahoo.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, I bookmarked everything interesting that came across my path to delicious (back when it was del.icio.us). &amp;#0160;It was part of my routine, and a daily summary was posted through to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delicious was from the tags era of the Internet, where in addition to noting that a thing existed you could add your own tags to describe it. Sometimes these were straightforward tags, like the 1533 pages I marked as &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.delicious.com/vielmetti/annarbor&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;annarbor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. Others were idiosyncratic, like the 5 pages I marked as &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.delicious.com/vielmetti/attention-to-irrelevant-details&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;attention-to-irrelevant-details&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other, better ways to bookmark things so that lots of people see them. The facebook &amp;quot;like&amp;quot; button gets more page views without consuming any &lt;a href=&#34;http://elab.eserver.org/hfl0098.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;cognitive overhead&lt;/a&gt; about how to tag, whether to tag, and what you&amp;#39;ve tagged before. Actually writing about something is quite a bit better than just bookmarking it, because you get to be yourself for a little while and not just an automaton forwarding on links automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every bookmark I ever did on delicious, up until now, is archived for posterity here:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/delicious-20101216.htm&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/delicious-20101216.htm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;. As I review it, there really should have been more of them marked &amp;quot;attention to irrelevant details&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;s hours of reading, though some of it goes by fast because the site that was linked to has disappeared, leaving only the bookmark and whatever clipping I managed to care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;edit: now with more cognitive overhead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more delicious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les Orchard, &lt;a href=&#34;http://decafbad.com/blog/2010/12/19/let-a-million-bookmarks-bloom&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Let a million bookmarks bloom&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Use the web. Host your own, pay for it, or find someone who values your data.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hood,&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uniquehazards.tumblr.com/post/2377362882/we-can-save-delicious-but-probably-not-in-the-way-you&#34;&gt;We can save Delicious, but probably not in the way you think&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;The Delicious user community could organize to save the data themselves via a coordinated harvesting project.&amp;quot;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti is&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.delicious.com/vielmetti&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://www.delicious.com/vielmetti&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we can learn from procrastination : James Surowiecki The New Yorker</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-10-17-what-we-can-learn-from-procrastination-the-new-yorker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 18:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2010/2010-10-17-what-we-can-learn-from-procrastination-the-new-yorker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academics, who work for long periods in a self-directed fashion, may be especially prone to putting things off: surveys suggest that the vast majority of college students procrastinate, and articles in the literature of procrastination often allude to the author’s own problems with finishing the piece. (This article will be no exception.) But the academic buzz around the subject isn’t just a case of eggheads rationalizing their slothfulness. As various scholars argue in “The Thief of Time,” edited by Chrisoula Andreou and Mark D. White (Oxford; $65)—a collection of essays on procrastination, ranging from the resolutely theoretical to the surprisingly practical—the tendency raises fundamental philosophical and psychological issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/books/2010/10/11/101011crbo_books_surowiecki?currentPage=all&#34;&gt;www.newyorker.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I am reading this while procrastinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/03/time_management.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;precise instructions to myself&lt;/a&gt; in my journal in 1999, repeated in 2004, on how to avoid procrastination, under the guise of &amp;quot;time management&amp;quot;. This presumes, of course, that all you need to do is make a few rational decisions and buck up and buckle down to work, in the ignorance of all other possible motivations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A challenge in a world of infinite possibilities is that choosing to do anything means you are choosing not to do something else. This brings to mind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.personalkanban.com/pk/personal-kanban-101/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jim Benson&amp;#39;s Personal Kanban&lt;/a&gt;, which only has two rules at its core:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit your work in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sure cure for procrastination, then, is simply to not do something, rather than putting it off. Alas not all tasks can be discarded so easily.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>