<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/productivity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All watched over by machines</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-07-all-watched-over-by-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 23:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-07-all-watched-over-by-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, a detailed look at the way you spend time over
the course of a day online yields several fascinating conclusions.
As previously noted, &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Wakatime&lt;/span&gt; is the introspective tool of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gee, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time to look at Facebook, Twitter, and Gmail;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t you spending more of your productive time writing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll bet that if you put down the computer your day would be more productive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, #2 is the most interesting one. Of course time spent on Facebook,
Twitter, and Gmail is time spent writing, but it&amp;rsquo;s transactional writing -
short bursts of functional prose to negotiate a time, set up a plan,
make a clever comeback or otherwise do online chit-chat. The words are writing,
but there&amp;rsquo;s not a body of work that you can point to that&amp;rsquo;s of any size as
your opus from that hour plus spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productive is a very funny word when you&amp;rsquo;re being watched by a machine.
Some parts of the time are marked as &amp;ldquo;good time&amp;rdquo;, where you&amp;rsquo;re happy to
have an extra minute spent credited to a project or task. Not all time is
&amp;ldquo;good time&amp;rdquo;, though some of the non-good time is just as essential, just
measured differently. And then there&amp;rsquo;s the occasional glitch in the matrix
where time is credited or blamed on one thing but you could swear you were
doing something else at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent on task sometimes looks very small when all of these are taken into
account. Those 99 words you wrote for publication were edited down from 150,
and might be edited further down to 55. If you could precisely allocate all
of the time you spent on it it would include the musing and ruminations, but
that got chalked up to Gmail where it&amp;rsquo;s mixed in with the time spent deleting
mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to mix up inputs and outputs.
If your system measures inputs, you get ritualized behavior designed to
maximize time spent on task, no matter how the time is actually used.
Maximizing outputs would yield word counts and not minute counts. If you&amp;rsquo;re
slow and terse, there&amp;rsquo;s no help for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A random walk through the rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-28-a-random-walk-through-the-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:37:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-28-a-random-walk-through-the-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The evening&#39;s work can be roughly summed up as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generate a random item from my personal wiki that starts with &#39;A&#39;. Much of the time, that will be a person&#39;s name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comment on that person&#39;s weblog, if they have one, or otherwise get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Repeat until &#39;Z&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of doing this I came across an essay, otherwise unpublished, on &#34;The algorithm driven day&#34;. In reading through it I am not sure it needs to see the light of day just yet, but it does help me wonder what parts of our efforts are driven by randomness and which are put there by design and how on earth one might tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inbox 50, unread 500</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-16-inbox-50-unread-500/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 08:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-04-16-inbox-50-unread-500/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So if you don&#39;t read email every moment of every waking day, you get a bit behind. Apologies to my correspondents if I can&#39;t manage same-day responses every day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bee App, a multiplatform issue tracker client for Mac</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-bee-app-a-multiplatform-issue-tracker-client-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-the-bee-app-a-multiplatform-issue-tracker-client-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been tracking my personal todo list on Github for nearly two years now. When I &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/12/issue-tracker-a-github-project-for-personal-productivity.html&#34;&gt;first wrote up the experience&lt;/a&gt; I had just been using the standard web client for the system; since then I&#39;ve added &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/11/octodroid-is-a-github-client-for-android.html&#34;&gt;Octodroid&lt;/a&gt; as an Android client. So far so good, I&#39;ve closed more than 2300 issues since I started. Github&#39;s issues is a completely feature-filled issue management system, far and above overkill for a personal todo list, but useful and complete enough to manage routine tasking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: left;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-03 at 9.38.40 AM&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2014-10-03 at 9.38.40 AM&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01bb0791947f970d-320wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new thing in my life (to go with the new laptop) is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neat.io/bee/&#34;&gt;Bee&lt;/a&gt; (@thebeeapp), a Mac native client that&#39;s a front end for several issue tracking systems. I have a free 30 day trial, after which the software looks like it could be reasonably priced if I were to use it all the time. Notably it&#39;s software-as-software, not software-as-a-service, so I&#39;d just buy it and not have to pay every month for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bee gives you a nice GUI for your issues, so that you can sift through the debris of what you thought you wanted to do and comment on, reassign, close, or edit those things. The net effect for me over a few hours of use was to flush out about two dozen things that had been obscured by my previous issue management regime that I was never going to do or that were totally overtaken by events. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &#34;getting things done&#34; ritual speaks of a weekly review, where you once a week sort through all of the detritus that had landed on your todo list over the course of a week and make sense of it all. The ability to take on a review like that depends crucially on whether you can get everything that&#39;s on your plate into a single list that you can walk through methodically (and in some sensible order) so that you&#39;re not horribly fatigued by issue overload by the end. Perhaps it&#39;s the new app smell that makes it possible for me to do that anew, but I was really happy with Bee as a way to work through a review, and I&#39;m hopeful that it keeps giving me insights and inspiration as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>falling behind, slowly</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-falling-behind-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 10:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-29-falling-behind-slowly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My laptop has been in the shop for more than a week. I am not keeping up with correspondence as a result. I apparently had an efficient enough system that for a given hour of focus I could answer or log as much mail as came in. Now I can&#39;t, and there are not enough hours in the day to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse I have also rediscovered that I can write on this little device, and that blogging is about the right length for the small screen to compose. So even though I am not keeping up with private discourse, my public engagement with the tiny part of the net that reads blogs is going just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strong temptation is to head to the Apple store and buy something fast, fancy, shiny, waterproof, coffee proof, and with a solid keyboard. I don&#39;t know if that device exists. Until then the cup of coffee always goes to the far right of the small screen so I know where it is at all times and so I don&#39;t knock it over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>do next?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-do-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-27-do-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One algorithm for deciding what to do next is simply to identify
the item with the closest deadline and work on that. There is nothing
like a deadline to focus the mind, and it is better to get the items
that demand short term attention into the calendar and to allot the
time to tackle them. Bernie Galler described this approach to me once,
and it stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second approach is to put everything you might ever want to do
in a big pile and pick something at random from it to work on. I
use github issues to track my big pile of things to do, and alas
it does not have a random() function. Fortunately though there is
a Github API, and that combined with &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; and my &lt;code&gt;randomline&lt;/code&gt; script
are enough to approximate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third very reasonable approach is to ask someone what they would
like you to do; or even better yet anticipate what they would ask
and do it before they ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reminds me, I have work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines have a way of focusing the mind</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-01-deadlines-have-a-way-of-focusing-the-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 22:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-01-deadlines-have-a-way-of-focusing-the-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve given myself an arbitrary deadline; write until the battery runs out, and then plug in and don&#39;t use the computer again for the day. At the very least I will type faster when the timer ticks down to 0:04. (The phone still has power though.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He sees you when you&#39;re sleeping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-06-he-sees-you-when-youre-sleeping-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 10:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-06-he-sees-you-when-youre-sleeping-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He sees you when you&#39;re sleeping &lt;br/&gt; 
  He knows when you&#39;re awake  &lt;br/&gt; 
  He knows if you&#39;ve been bad or good &lt;br/&gt;
  So be good for goodness sake &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The startup Buffer has a radical approach to transparency. Corporate minders watch your every move, on and off the clock, and the results of their nosy prying are available to all of your coworkers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inc.com/jeff-haden/inside-buffer-company-complete-transparency.html&#34;&gt;From Inc.&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We recently gave everyone at Buffer a Jawbone UP wristband. It allows you to automatically track your sleep, your daily steps, your nutrition, and a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;One of our key values at Buffer is to work smarter, not harder. Personal improvement is a big part of that, so giving employees a tool that can help improve their sleep patterns is a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;A few weeks in it&#39;s already had an incredible effect. Browsing everyone&#39;s sleep patterns and talking about how to get more deep sleep has an amazing effect on productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s good when companies give off a clear &#34;this is not for me&#34; signal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Personal Kanban with Boardthing</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-05-05-doing-personal-kanban-with-boardthing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I change productivity tools from time to time. Here&#39;s a latest try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only two real rules with Personal Kanban:
1. Visualize your work
2. Limit your work-in-progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2010/07/personal-kanban-from-jim-benson-and-modus-cooperandi.html&#34;&gt;wrote about Personal Kanban before&lt;/a&gt; back in 2010, but I didn&#39;t try to put it into practice as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boardthing is an invention of Dave Gray. There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindmappingsoftwareblog.com/boardthing/&#34;&gt;review of Boardthing&lt;/a&gt; from Chuck Frey which goes into a few more details, but the short summary of it is that it&#39;s a suitable way to rearrange little rectangles on a board. The little rectangles each have some text or an image in them, and they can be nested so you can move them around in groups. There&#39;s really not much more than that, and it runs in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This infrastructure is enough to create a Personal Kanban board. Create little rectangles at minimum for &#34;Things to do&#34;, &#34;Doing&#34;, and &#34;Done&#34;, and type into the little rectangles to move them around until you figure out what to do, stop typing, and get something done. I recommend a &#34;Things not to do&#34; rectangle as an added productivity boost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this work in the long term? The system is pretty light weight, and it saves your state between sessions. I suppose if your page gets too cluttered you can start a new one that is more focused. Having a smallish screen forces you to limit your work in progress, which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Gray and Jim Benson have a set of approaches that should work well together, this is mostly written for the both of them as an introduction of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting things done includes deciding what not to do.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-getting-things-done-includes-deciding-what-not-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 13:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-14-getting-things-done-includes-deciding-what-not-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting things done includes deciding what not to do. In my case, it&#39;s a matter of going through my todo list and striking off the well-intentioned tasks from two or three months ago that took a moment to write and that would take hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m better off at accomplishing things when there are fewer undone things to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Janet Choi writes about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/articles/24875/the-art-of-the-done-list-harnessing-the-power-of-progress&#34;&gt;done list&lt;/a&gt; for 99u.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you do anything you consider useful, however small a win it may be, write it down on your done list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can lead to the purposeful behavior of writing something on your todo list just to cross it off and mark it done. The system I&#39;m using doesn&#39;t easily distinguish between the three states of &#34;did and then wrote it down&#34;, &#34;wrote it down and did it later&#34;, or &#34;wrote it down and decided not to do it later&#34;. But that&#39;s a quibble.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack, first impressions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-20-slack-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 09:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-20-slack-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Slack-logo&#34; title=&#34;Slack-logo&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a3fcc1a673970b-120wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system has many familiar components. It feels like an IRC network, complete with a set of well thought out bots and useful integrations with development tools. Unlike most IRC nets, it comes with a rich set of web and native clients that make it feel like something that ordinary people could use and not just the ubergeeks. For the ubergeeks, it also has a very competent IRC client support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience of the system varies tremendously depending on who you have on your team. If they have somewhere else to talk, then you might never get the critical mass you need to have a real conversation online. About a third of the people I&#39;m inviting actually start to use the system, and most of those have some IRC channel time in their background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web client and the Android client for Slack are both very capably executed and feel like sound, solid pieces of engineering. It adds a lot of confidence to using the system to have such nice tools to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.com/integrations&#34;&gt;integrations&lt;/a&gt; configured for RSS feeds, for Github (issues and commits), and for Google Hangouts. There&#39;s a rich API, or so it seems, and lots of other systems that have had integrations built for them. I have ambitions but no infrastructure yet to write my own code or better yet borrow other people&#39;s code to extend the system. I&#39;m not much more advanced yet than getting the &#34;hello world&#34; style post-to-Slack-from-the-command-line capability going, but it did work, so I have high hopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slack server I have set up is running on their free trial, which has a limited number of integration slots. I think that by cleverly enabling and disabling services that I can try enough of them to build up some experience with the system, but not necessarily run everything in production. I get 5 for free, and Github, Hangouts, RSS, Twitter, and the incoming webhook make up that 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to see what I&#39;ve built and join in, drop me a line and I can send you an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting work in progress vs. the endless todo list</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 10:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-14-limiting-work-in-progress-vs-the-endless-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c&#34; alt=&#34;Github-activity-graph-illustration&#34; title=&#34;Github-activity-graph-illustration&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef01a510e1ff93970c-120wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using a todo system &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2012/12/issue-tracker-a-github-project-for-personal-productivity.html&#34;&gt;based on Github issues&lt;/a&gt; for the better part of a year. It&#39;s been an interesting exercise in trying to corral the things that aren&#39;t done yet but that need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started out, I dumped every last thing that I might do into the system, everything from major tasks to &#34;do laundry&#34; (which can seem like a major task at times). The count of undone things oscillated from 60 to 100 things to be done, which made it seem like an infinite list because it took too long to review the whole list and it was on 3 or 4 screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some reflection, I decided that the only way to make progress on this list was to dramatically prune it. That means taking some items off the list that I really do want to do eventually, it&#39;s just that I&#39;m not focusing on them now because every time I look at them on the list I say &#34;no&#34;. Crossing them off the list doesn&#39;t completely delete them, and when I need to revisit them I can reopen the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list is down to 30 now, and I&#39;m careful not to add more than that without crossing something else off the list. It still has a few lingering things that haven&#39;t been done for a long time, but I have had my teeth cleaned, and what&#39;s more I can read through the whole thing in one sitting and usually say &#34;yes&#34; to some next task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More reading: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.personalkanban.com/pk/primers/why-limit-your-wip-a-pk-info-series/&#34;&gt;Why limit your work in progress&lt;/a&gt;, Jim Benson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still answering yesterday&#39;s email; also doing yesterday&#39;s todos</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-still-answering-yesterdays-email-also-doing-yesterdays-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-07-still-answering-yesterdays-email-also-doing-yesterdays-todos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a big fan of finite lists of things to do. It&#39;s hard to keep up with things that require an answer, and sometimes you need to let things slide until the next day. When you combine those two, you get &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/05/yesterbox-answer-yesterdays-email-today.html&#34;&gt;yesterbox&lt;/a&gt;. The basic idea is that you answer today&#39;s email tomorrow, so that you know when you get to the bottom of yesterday&#39;s mail you are really done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slight complication for this system for me is that I&#39;m also using a todo list which is supposed to capture everything I need to do. Alas, things go onto this list and stay there forever. How to reconcile the two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;m going to try, as best I can, is to deal with today&#39;s bright ideas about what I need to do but don&#39;t have time to do right now tomorrow. There will be a finite number of things to look at, and I can probably deal with some of them right away. I don&#39;t mean to kick the can down the road, but I also don&#39;t want to try to tackle everything I&#39;ve ever thought of doing all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired in part by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wallofvoodoo.net/&#34;&gt;Wall of Voodoo&lt;/a&gt; song &#34;Tomorrow&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll do it tomorrow / that seems like a pretty good idea to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/-eEfAGzgv18?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overtaken by events</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-overtaken-by-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-02-overtaken-by-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thinning out my todo list for the new year to delete some of the oldest items, the ones that aren&#39;t particularly hard but they also haven&#39;t been done this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figure that if I need to do them, the opportunity will arise again, and it might be easier to get them done if they show up fresh at the top of the list rather than buried at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s humorous (or sad) is the items marked &#34;urgent&#34; that are more than a week old; clearly, simply marking something as urgent does not stand in for actually doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, new year&#39;s productivity !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Yup, thinning out the list is now a perpetual activity; I&#39;m trying to keep work in progress under about 30 tasks. There may be more to do in the world, you think? I can only keep track of so much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness about what you&#39;re doing with OneTab</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-12-mindfulness-about-what-youre-doing-with-onetab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 15:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-12-mindfulness-about-what-youre-doing-with-onetab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.one-tab.com/&#34;&gt;OneTab&lt;/a&gt; (see: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2013/03/onetab-a-chrome-extension-to-reduce-system-memory-usage.html&#34;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;) to manage the tabs on my Chrome browser. It does a great job of sweeping a bunch of current state for open tabs onto a page, so that you can get a fresh start when a new project comes up and then restore the state of the old one. It also means that I have a lot more working memory on my old MacBook. All in all a big win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while the projects pile up, and I forget what I was doing but still don&#39;t know what to focus on. The mindfulness project then is to go methodically through each of the tabs, dealing with whatever is on that page and then closing the tab instead of saving it. This has been a good way to feel like I don&#39;t have an infinite set of half-done efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>