<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oxford England on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/oxford-england/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oxford England on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 11:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/oxford-england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Flood Network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-18-oxford-flood-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-18-oxford-flood-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Oxford Flood Network is making a flood detection network in
the UK, using low cost sensors and volunteers. They are sharing
their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oxfloodnet&#34;&gt;code on Github&lt;/a&gt; and their
results on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flood_network&#34;&gt;Flood_Network&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They encourage you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://flood.network/join&#34;&gt;join their effort&lt;/a&gt;,
and no high technology is necessary. The network incorporates
both readings from automated sensors (about £250) as well as
manual readings from gaugeboards or photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New as of December 2015 is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nominet.uk/iot-technology-powers-an-interactive-flood-map-and-sensor-network/&#34;&gt;interactive flood map&lt;/a&gt;.
A post from Nominet describes the effort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominet, in association with the Flood Network, is today launching an interactive, online map which visualises river and stream levels around Oxford. The map, showing how technology can be a part of flood defence systems anywhere, has been developed following a successful pilot project with the Oxford Flood Network. The project has been focused on exploring the potential of the Internet of Things (IoT) to create an extensive, localised, early-warning system for flood-prone areas for the first time in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is using TVWS (&amp;ldquo;TV white space&amp;rdquo;) as its wide area backhaul
network for these sensors for hard-to-reach devices that are outside
of the range of wifi. Cost-effective and reliable access to remote
small sensors is one of the tough spots in Internet of Things development,
it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see TVWS as a possible solution to this issue.
The other relevant technology for low-cost metro area networks for
sensors is Lorawan, more about which later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>