<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheese on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/cheese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cheese on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/recipes/cheese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac and Goat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/Mac-and-Goat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/Mac-and-Goat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/strong&gt; calls for goat cheese; we generally use a goat gouda or
a goat cheddar, both of which are usually available at the local
Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s. Feel free to substitute any hard cheese that melts
well in your recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dish also calls for rice pasta, but again feel free to substitute;
you&amp;rsquo;re aiming for something like a rotini which handles the sauce well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Take out a lasagna pan, which is
what you&amp;rsquo;re going to assemble the dish in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-and-goat:b7d41359d960c78f56dcc5a9d35b0ec6&#34;&gt;Mac and Goat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 lb. pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; lb. goat gouda, goat cheddar, or a nice aged gouda or cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large can crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bread crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;romano cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil water for pasta; cook a pound or so of your favorite pasta,
we use a rice rotini pasta in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shred the cheese fine in a food processor or with a hand grater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pasta is done, drain it, and then put about half of it
in the lasagna pan. Cover with about half of the cheese and half of
the tomatoes. Put the rest of the pasta in, then more tomatoes and
more cheese. Top with breadcrumbs and then sprinkle a little romano
cheese on top and a few pinches of nutmeg for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook 20-25 minutes, until the top is lightly browned and the
tomato sauce is bubbling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>