<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University Of Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/university-of-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University Of Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/university-of-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>U of Michigan to announce &#34;historic event&#34; at Michigan Stadium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</guid>
      <description>BREAKING: Special Event Press Conference today @ Noon (EDT). Historic event to be held at Michigan Stadium. #BigHouse
&amp;mdash; Michigan Tix Office (@umichtix) April 4, 2014 
The working assumption is that this is the long-rumored summer soccer game between Manchester United and Real Madrid in August. From Crain&#39;s Detroit:
 Global soccer powerhouses Manchester United — wearing its new Chevrolet-sponsored jerseys — and Real Madrid will square off at Michigan Stadium in Ann Arbor at 4 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who will replace MSC as U Michigan president?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</guid>
      <description>MGoBlog has a tremendously entertaining and informative guide to handicapping the race to replace Mary Sue Coleman as University of Michigan president. The article calls out the University of Virginia&#39;s Teresa Sullivan (ex UM provost), Oberlin&#39;s Marvin Krislov (ex UM general counsel), and Rutgers&#39;s Nancy Cantor (ex UM provost) as the top three picks. Of the three Cantor seems to be least likely, since she just took a position at Rutgers in January 2014 having left Syracuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500&#43; University of Michigan faculty protest &#34;Administrative Services Transformation&#34; project in open letter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-23-500-university-of-michigan-faculty-protest-administrative-services-transformation-project-in-open-le/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 13:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-23-500-university-of-michigan-faculty-protest-administrative-services-transformation-project-in-open-le/</guid>
      <description>&#34;An Open Letter to President Coleman and Provost Pollack&#34;, published on um-openletter.eecs.umich.edu/ - from the lead paragraph:
 We, the undersigned faculty of the University of Michigan, support your intent to realign administrative expenses relative to revenues. However we collectively reject the proposed Administrative Services Transformation (AST) project. We respectfully offer an alternative approach to AST, which we call Unit- Centric Services (UCS). We believe that the AST approach is inherently flawed because its focus is on reducing administrative costs without taking into account the concurrent reduction in faculty and staff productivity, collaborative academic culture, and the unique needs of heterogeneous academic units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-bbum-at-the-poster-wall-near-the-fishbowl-university-of-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-bbum-at-the-poster-wall-near-the-fishbowl-university-of-michigan/</guid>
      <description>I saw this today at the poster wall near the Fishbowl on the University of Michigan central campus. The #BBUM hashtag has been trending for a couple of days now. It stands for &#34;Being Black at the University of Michigan&#34;, and it&#39;s part of a brilliant campaign organized by the Black Student Union that shows no signs of stopping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) Fifth Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 20:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>I went with S and J to the University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) on the UM North Campus in the basement of the Duderstadt Center. They were celebrating their fifth anniversary with cupcakes and a Mario tournament. The boys had a chance to play games, and I had a chance to talk to David S. Carter (aka superman@umich.edu) about the collection. Here are some notes.
There are about 5000 games in the collection, and about half of them are donated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan increases 2013-2014 tuition 1.1% for in-state, 3.2% for out of state</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-university-of-michigan-increases-2013-2014-tuition-11-for-in-state-32-for-out-of-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-university-of-michigan-increases-2013-2014-tuition-11-for-in-state-32-for-out-of-state/</guid>
      <description>AnnArbor.com has the story. In-state tuition is now $13,142, and out of state tuition is a hefty&amp;#0160;$40,392. The total U of Michigan budget is&amp;#0160;$1.72 billion.
&amp;#0160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furry Wolverine mascot, circa 1983</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-furry-wolverine-mascot-circa-1983/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 16:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-furry-wolverine-mascot-circa-1983/</guid>
      <description>From Michigan Today, v20 n5, 1989:

There&amp;#39;s a reason that the University of Michigan doesn&amp;#39;t have a mascot. Read more about Michigan mascots from James David Dickson in Michigan Today, June 16, 2011&amp;#0160;and beware of furries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2, North Dakota 0 (2011 NCAA Frozen Four semifinal hockey)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-07-michigan-2-north-dakota-0-2011-ncaa-frozen-four-semifinal-hockey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 23:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-07-michigan-2-north-dakota-0-2011-ncaa-frozen-four-semifinal-hockey/</guid>
      <description>Michigan defeated North Dakota 2-0 tonight in NCAA Frozen Four hockey. I watched on ESPN3. Recap: MGoBlue.com, &amp;quot;Going for 10! U-M Blanks No. 1 North Dakota to Reach NCAA Final&amp;quot;.
Box score: ESPN.
   Next game is Saturday night, 7:00 pm. &amp;#0160;vs. the University of Minnesota-Duluth Bulldogs. UMD beat Notre Dame 4-3 to advance to the finals.
Edward Vielmetti writes about sports, sometimes, and sings along with the band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Quad Community Open House, Thursday March 31, 2011, 3p-6p</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-30-north-quad-community-open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 22:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-30-north-quad-community-open-house/</guid>
      <description>From the news release:
 This fall, students moved into the first U-M residence hall to open in more than 40 years. Throughout the first semester, the academic programs that are part of this new community moved in. Today, in addition to 450 residents, North Quad is home to the School of Information, the LSA Departments of Screen Arts and Cultures and Communication Studies, the Sweetland Center for Writing, the Global Scholars Program, the Language Resource Center and the Max Kade House.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>