<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University Of Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/university-of-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University Of Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/university-of-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>U of Michigan to announce &#34;historic event&#34; at Michigan Stadium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 10:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-04-04-u-of-michigan-to-announce-historic-event-at-michigan-stadium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: Special Event Press Conference today @ Noon (EDT). Historic event to be held at Michigan Stadium. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23BigHouse&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#BigHouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Michigan Tix Office (@umichtix) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/umichtix/statuses/452084506975952896&#34;&gt;April 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working assumption is that this is the long-rumored summer soccer game between Manchester United and Real Madrid in August. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crainsdetroit.com/article/20140403/NEWS/140409938/soccer-headed-to-big-house-manchester-united-real-madrid-to-play-in&#34;&gt;Crain&#39;s Detroit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Global soccer powerhouses Manchester United — wearing its new Chevrolet-sponsored jerseys — and Real Madrid will square off at Michigan Stadium in Ann Arbor at 4 p.m. Aug. 2, two sources with direct knowledge of the situation told Crain’s this week.
  The University of Michigan has scheduled a press conference for noon Friday to announce the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23mufc&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#mufc&lt;/a&gt; face Real Madrid in the International Champions Cup, presented by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChevroletFC&#34;&gt;@ChevroletFC&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23mutour&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#mutour&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/6bTkIaqdoJ&#34;&gt;http://t.co/6bTkIaqdoJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/3DVqUwFD8q&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3DVqUwFD8q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Manchester United (@ManUtd) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ManUtd/statuses/452113689621966848&#34;&gt;April 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who will replace MSC as U Michigan president?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-%E2%80%93-odds-university-michigan%E2%80%99s-next-president&#34;&gt;MGoBlog has a tremendously entertaining and informative guide&lt;/a&gt; to handicapping the race to replace Mary Sue Coleman as University of Michigan president. The article calls out the University of Virginia&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virginia.edu/president/biography.html&#34;&gt;Teresa Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM provost), Oberlin&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://new.oberlin.edu/office/president/about.dot&#34;&gt;Marvin Krislov&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM general counsel), and Rutgers&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://syr.edu/chancellorcantor/&#34;&gt;Nancy Cantor&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM provost) as the top three picks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the three Cantor seems to be least likely, since she just took a position at Rutgers in January 2014 having left Syracuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field is a lot longer - MGoBlog gives current UM Athletic Director David Brandon a 350-1 chance at getting the nod. The commenters are even less enthusiastic: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dave Brandon entering the presidency with zero academic administration experience, much less zero experience in the academy... Disaster. Dismantle the Diag, mothball the libraries, send everyone home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: It turns out MGoBlog is triply entertaining; there&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-%E2%80%93-odds-university-michigan%E2%80%99s-next-president-part-ii&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-part-3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; to the race to replace series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So now we all sit back and wait. If there is going to be a a permanent President named to start by the fall, we should hear the name in the next few months. If I hear any names start to surface, I&#39;ll certainly tap out the fourth installment of the Diary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MGoBlog refers to David Jesse&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freep.com/article/20140105/NEWS05/301050063/university-of-michigan-presidential-search-mary-sue-coleman-secret-board-of-regents&#34;&gt;Freep article&lt;/a&gt; with more about how the search has been very secretive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500&#43; University of Michigan faculty protest &#34;Administrative Services Transformation&#34; project in open letter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-23-500-university-of-michigan-faculty-protest-administrative-services-transformation-project-in-open-le/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 13:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-23-500-university-of-michigan-faculty-protest-administrative-services-transformation-project-in-open-le/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#34;An Open Letter to President Coleman and Provost Pollack&#34;, published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://um-openletter.eecs.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;um-openletter.eecs.umich.edu/&lt;/a&gt; - from the lead paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We, the undersigned faculty of the University of Michigan, support your intent to realign administrative expenses relative to revenues. However we collectively reject the proposed Administrative Services Transformation (AST) project. We respectfully offer an alternative approach to AST, which we call Unit- Centric Services (UCS). We believe that the AST approach is inherently flawed because its focus is on reducing administrative costs without taking into account the concurrent reduction in faculty and staff productivity, collaborative academic culture, and the unique needs of heterogeneous academic units. In contrast, UCS&#39;s focus is on productivity and intra-unit efficiencies. Higher productivity translates into higher revenues relative to expenses, even though expenses may, but do not need to, be higher. The unique cultures and modes of operation of different units are facilitated by staff that retain corporate knowledge of local processes. Conversely, AST is a top-down program that eliminates the ability to retain corporate knowledge and leverage the unit-culture experiences of some 300 support staff while limiting their contributions to a series of transactional tasks in a call center. The inevitable result is to tax the faculty with numerous clerical tasks, thereby reducing their accessibility to students and their productivity as scholars and researchers. In contrast, the premise of UCS is to develop a strategic plan aimed at improving productivity at the unit level (school/college and/or department), with plans developed with full participation by the faculty, staff and administrators in that unit, and in tune with the particular academic culture and practices of that unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the document is signed by 594 faculty members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, one of the things that the University would need to centralize to avoid public displays of dissent is the control of web sites and the domain name system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also noted by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2013/11/23/um-faculty-petition/&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michigandaily.com/news/university-administrators-address-concerns-shared-services-center&#34;&gt;Michigan Daily&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;University administrators apologized to concerned department chairs Thursday about the lack of communication and clarity in their decision-making process about the center, which is expected to cut costs by $5 to 6 million by consolidating human-resource and finance services to a centralized location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also previously, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insidehighered.com/news/2013/11/21/u-michigan-tries-save-money-staff-costs-meets-faculty-opposition&#34;&gt;Inside Higher Ed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nineteen department chairs in the College of Literature, Science and the Arts -- the largest college on campus -- wrote a Nov. 1 letter to senior administrators protesting an “air of secrecy” around the effort and raising concerns that longtime staffers, particularly lower-income women, would be hurt by the changes, either because of layoffs or pay cuts.
  In response, senior Michigan officials wrote a Nov. 14 letter acknowledging they were “not sensitive or consultative enough in the planning and communication of this initiative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-bbum-at-the-poster-wall-near-the-fishbowl-university-of-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 20:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-20-bbum-at-the-poster-wall-near-the-fishbowl-university-of-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this today at the poster wall near the Fishbowl on the University of Michigan central campus. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://tchat.io/rooms/bbum&#34;&gt;#BBUM&lt;/a&gt; hashtag has been trending for a couple of days now. It stands for &#34;Being Black at the University of Michigan&#34;, and it&#39;s part of a brilliant campaign organized by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theblackstudentunion.com/&#34;&gt;Black Student Union&lt;/a&gt; that shows no signs of stopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0167b6f0970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0167b6f0970b&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; alt=&#34;2013-11-20 17.22.13&#34; title=&#34;2013-11-20 17.22.13&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0167b6f0970b-600wi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive (CVGA) Fifth Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 20:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-16-university-of-michigan-computer-and-video-game-archive-cvga-fifth-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34;  style=&#34;float: right;&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0136b662970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0136b662970c img-responsive&#34; alt=&#34;Aael-cvga-300x225&#34; title=&#34;Aael-cvga-300x225&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef019b0136b662970c-800wi&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I went with S and J to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lib.umich.edu/computer-video-game-archive&#34;&gt;University of Michigan Computer and Video Game Archive&lt;/a&gt; (CVGA) on the UM North Campus in the basement of the Duderstadt Center. They were celebrating their fifth anniversary with cupcakes and a Mario tournament. The boys had a chance to play games, and I had a chance to talk to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lib.umich.edu/users/superman&#34;&gt;David S. Carter&lt;/a&gt; (aka superman@umich.edu) about the collection. Here are some notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are about 5000 games in the collection, and about half of them are donated. An annual collection budget of about $13,000 buys new games and the occasional old console from eBay. The archive has a near complete collection of US consoles, and Dave said they are looking to expand their international coverage. One of their latest acquisitions was a DVD system that plays only one title. The archive would like to improve its collection of handheld games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge of the next five years is with digital rights management (DRM). The DRM systems envisioned would lock a game to a particular piece of console hardware, making it impossible to have used games and very hard for a library to add a title to a collection. For network-delivered games like Steam it&#39;s equally hard for the library to spend $10 on a license, when licenses negotiated by libraries for things like electronic versions of journals are usually for much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave said the archive was pretty much where they want to be after 5 years. He knew they were on the right track when they got space in the library even before they had a budget. The challenge of next five years is less collection building and more about building connections across campus and around the world to other research collections. He compared the collection to early film and video collections, now standard at all research libraries, but once considered a novelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other comparable collections are at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cah.utexas.edu/projects/videogamearchive/index.php&#34;&gt;University of Texas at Austin&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href=&#34;http://library.stanford.edu/news/2013/03/stanford-libraries-preserves-historical-software-collection-federal-agency&#34;&gt;Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. Public libraries so not tend to have research collections, preferring to  either use video games strictly for events or to have a circulating collection where you check out current games like any other video or music media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Dave about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/historicalsoftware&#34;&gt;Internet Archive&#39;s online gaming collection&lt;/a&gt;, and especially about the role of emulation in preserving games. He told me that emulation does not preserve original game play, especially the ergonomics of controllers. Playing on original game hardware with original video hardware gives you an accurate rendition of original game play experience. (Besides, you can&#39;t play &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirlyn.lib.umich.edu/Record/005840579&#34;&gt;Duck Hunt&lt;/a&gt; without an old fashioned TV because the game depends on sensing the scan lines on the TV.) Some old games are very hard to enjoy on original hardware and the limitations of the controls, not the game itself, are what trips up your enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan increases 2013-2014 tuition 1.1% for in-state, 3.2% for out of state</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-university-of-michigan-increases-2013-2014-tuition-11-for-in-state-32-for-out-of-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-21-university-of-michigan-increases-2013-2014-tuition-11-for-in-state-32-for-out-of-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AnnArbor.com &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/news/university-of-michigan-raises-in-state-tuition-11-and-adopts-172b-general-fund-budget/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;has the story&lt;/a&gt;. In-state tuition is now $13,142, and out of state tuition is a hefty&amp;#0160;$40,392. The total U of Michigan budget is&amp;#0160;$1.72 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furry Wolverine mascot, circa 1983</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-furry-wolverine-mascot-circa-1983/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 16:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-18-furry-wolverine-mascot-circa-1983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Michigan Today, v20 n5, 1989:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e893a2ed0970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 30&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e893a2ed0970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e893a2ed0970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 30&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a reason that the University of Michigan doesn&amp;#39;t have a mascot. Read more about Michigan mascots from &lt;a href=&#34;http://michigantoday.umich.edu/2011/06/story.php?id=8003&amp;amp;tr=y&amp;amp;auid=8513677&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;James David Dickson in Michigan Today, June 16, 2011&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;and beware of furries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan 2, North Dakota 0 (2011 NCAA Frozen Four semifinal hockey)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-07-michigan-2-north-dakota-0-2011-ncaa-frozen-four-semifinal-hockey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 23:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-04-07-michigan-2-north-dakota-0-2011-ncaa-frozen-four-semifinal-hockey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michigan defeated North Dakota 2-0 tonight in NCAA Frozen Four hockey. I watched on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.espn3.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;ESPN3&lt;/a&gt;. Recap: MGoBlue.com, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mgoblue.com/sports/m-hockey/recaps/040711aaa.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Going for 10! U-M Blanks No. 1 North Dakota to Reach NCAA Final&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Box score: &lt;a href=&#34;http://scores.espn.go.com/ncaa/hockey/boxscore?gameId=310407155&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;ESPN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;storyNav&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;fb-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3d1f5ae970b-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Espn3-michigan-north-dakota-frozen-four-semifinal-2011&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3d1f5ae970b&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0147e3d1f5ae970b-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Espn3-michigan-north-dakota-frozen-four-semifinal-2011&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Next game is Saturday night, 7:00 pm. &amp;#0160;vs. the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umdbulldogs.com/teams-mens-hockey.php&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;University of Minnesota-Duluth Bulldogs&lt;/a&gt;. UMD beat Notre Dame 4-3 to advance to the finals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti writes about sports, sometimes, and sings along with the band.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Quad Community Open House, Thursday March 31, 2011, 3p-6p</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-30-north-quad-community-open-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 22:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-30-north-quad-community-open-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vpcomm.umich.edu/email/northquad/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;news release&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fall, students moved into the first U-M residence hall to open in more than 40 years. Throughout the first semester, the academic programs that are part of this new community moved in. Today, in addition to 450 residents, North Quad is home to the School of Information, the LSA Departments of Screen Arts and Cultures and Communication Studies, the Sweetland Center for Writing, the Global Scholars Program, the Language Resource Center and the Max Kade House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87211cae970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen shot 2011-03-30 at 10.14.42 PM&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87211cae970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef014e87211cae970d-500wi&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2011-03-30 at 10.14.42 PM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edward Vielmetti lived at Bursley Hall, Max Kade House (briefly), Alice Lloyd, and Joint House at the University of Michigan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>