<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University Of Michigan on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/university-of-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University Of Michigan on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:31:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/university-of-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Who will replace MSC as U Michigan president?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-01-23-who-will-replace-msc-as-u-michigan-president/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-%E2%80%93-odds-university-michigan%E2%80%99s-next-president&#34;&gt;MGoBlog has a tremendously entertaining and informative guide&lt;/a&gt; to handicapping the race to replace Mary Sue Coleman as University of Michigan president. The article calls out the University of Virginia&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virginia.edu/president/biography.html&#34;&gt;Teresa Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM provost), Oberlin&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://new.oberlin.edu/office/president/about.dot&#34;&gt;Marvin Krislov&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM general counsel), and Rutgers&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://syr.edu/chancellorcantor/&#34;&gt;Nancy Cantor&lt;/a&gt; (ex UM provost) as the top three picks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the three Cantor seems to be least likely, since she just took a position at Rutgers in January 2014 having left Syracuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field is a lot longer - MGoBlog gives current UM Athletic Director David Brandon a 350-1 chance at getting the nod. The commenters are even less enthusiastic: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dave Brandon entering the presidency with zero academic administration experience, much less zero experience in the academy... Disaster. Dismantle the Diag, mothball the libraries, send everyone home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: It turns out MGoBlog is triply entertaining; there&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-%E2%80%93-odds-university-michigan%E2%80%99s-next-president-part-ii&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mgoblog.com/diaries/race-replace-mary-sue-coleman-part-3&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; to the race to replace series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So now we all sit back and wait. If there is going to be a a permanent President named to start by the fall, we should hear the name in the next few months. If I hear any names start to surface, I&#39;ll certainly tap out the fourth installment of the Diary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MGoBlog refers to David Jesse&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freep.com/article/20140105/NEWS05/301050063/university-of-michigan-presidential-search-mary-sue-coleman-secret-board-of-regents&#34;&gt;Freep article&lt;/a&gt; with more about how the search has been very secretive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>