<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor City Council Community Television Network on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-council-community-television-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor City Council Community Television Network on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-city-council-community-television-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a public meeting with five windows open to the world -</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-10-16-watching-a-public-meeting-with-five-windows-open-to-the-world-a2council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor City Council holds meetings twice each month, which are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/meetingplace/Pages/TheMeetingPlace.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;streamed online through the city&amp;#39;s CTN network&lt;/a&gt;. I tuned in last night on my laptop to listen and watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was listening, I had a few other windows open on my computer. First and foremost, I had a twitter stream that I was watching for the #&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23a2council&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;a2council&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;hash tag; that caught commentary from a few other people who were watching at home, plus some reporters in the audience. The running cmmentary made it easier to follow what was going on, and it served as a back channel to help make sense of the proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The council was working from an agenda that&amp;#39;s in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Legistar system&lt;/a&gt;, and from time to time I&amp;#39;d go back to that to see what the text of an agenda item was, to look at supporting materials, and see the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor Chronicle does near-real-time news coverage as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/category/civic-news-ticker/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Civic News Ticker&lt;/a&gt;, reporting out results from key votes and decisions during the meeting. This is brief coverage but important, and it sets the stage for their 10,000 word meeting reports that come out a week or so later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I had a window open to &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Arborwiki&lt;/a&gt;, which has a local encyclopedia of information about what is going on in the city and the surrounding area. As council considered various options, I looked up what Arborwiki had to say about the current state of affairs, and updated it as best I could to reflect the meeting results and the news that was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure that watching this multi-connected stream was different from the experience of being in the same room as council. You miss the non-verbal communications, the body language, the hallway conversations that take place during breaks, and all sorts of in-person nuance. But for what it was, I&amp;#39;m pretty happy with the experience. It felt like I was engaged with the meeting and could have a sense that I was part of the civic process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor City Council meetings now simulcast online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-ann-arbor-city-council-meetings-now-simulcast-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/citycouncil/Pages/Home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor City Council&lt;/a&gt; meetings are now simulcast online, which is handy if you don&amp;#39;t get local CTN cable service. &amp;#0160;This link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://a2docs.org/assets/files/2011/03/21/a2govtvcrawl.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;goes to an experimental setup which also tracks the Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23aacitycouncil&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;#aacitycouncil&lt;/a&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a2gov.org/government/city_administration/communicationsoffice/ctn/meetingplace/Pages/TheMeetingPlace.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;CTN Meetingplace&lt;/a&gt; page now hosts the current broadcast (both live and delayed) for CTN Channel 16. Meetings are held the first and third Monday nights of the month starting at 7:00 p.m., unless they aren&amp;#39;t for some reason like a holiday. There is a meeting today, May 23, 2011, which is a continuation of budget-related issues that were left unresolved at the May 16, 2011 meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Legistar at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a2gov.legistar.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;http://a2gov.legistar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for the calendar and agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Agendas can and do change up until the last moment, and it&amp;#39;s impossible to know ahead of time whether your topic of burning interest will be addressed at any given meeting. Watching online, and ensuring that you have a person who is tracking your issue close enough to city hall to get to council chambers, can be an alternative to sitting in the pews every other Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>