<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Give And Take on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/books/give-and-take/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Give And Take on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/books/give-and-take/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Grant, Give and Take; on being &#34;otherish&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</guid>
      <description>A brief review of Give and Take, which I checked out from the Ann Arbor District Library.
Grant writes about a number of people he calls givers, who are generous to a fault when sharing their time and expertise, even when there is not a sure bet that the generosity will be repaid. He contrasts this with the matchers, who always keep track of favors, and the takers who seek to exploit every circumstance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocity, give and take a little bit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 16:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading&amp;#0160;Adam Grant&amp;#39;s book&amp;#0160;Give and Take&amp;#0160;(aadl). &amp;#0160;Look in the March 31 NY Times Magazine for a preview, featuring a quote from the U of Michigan&amp;#39;s Jerry Davis. At the moment I&amp;#39;m&amp;#0160;33d on a list of 53 holds at the library for the book; if you&amp;#39;re generous, and have finished your copy, please lend it to me!
The table of contents and blurb, from the AADL catalog:
 Good returns: the dangers and rewards of giving more than you get -- The peacock and the panda: how givers, takers, and matchers build networks -- The ripple effect: collaboration and the dynamics of giving and taking credit -- Finding the diamond in the rough: the fact and fiction of recognizing potential -- The power of powerless communication: how to be modest and influence people -- The art of motivation maintenance: why some givers burn out but others are on fire -- Chump change: overcoming the doormat effect -- The scrooge shift: why a soccer team, a fingerprint, and a name can tilt us in the other direction -- Out of the shadows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</guid>
      <description>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.

Bright idea? Write it down, photograph it, transcribe it, then (and only then) post to the network.
It&#39;s OK to wait quite a long time between initial idea and eventual posting. This also works for blog postings, or at least it should. Twitter happens to make it easy to do in one step for short posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>