<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/adam-grant/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/adam-grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Grant, Give and Take; on being &#34;otherish&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 23:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-10-adam-grant-give-and-take/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief review of Give and Take, which I checked out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1427997&#34;&gt;from the Ann Arbor District Library.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant writes about a number of people he calls givers, who are generous to a fault when sharing their time and expertise, even when there is not a sure bet that the generosity will be repaid. He contrasts this with the matchers, who always keep track of favors, and the takers who seek to exploit every circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant likes givers, but recognizes that sometimes people give too much and never manage to get things in return. These selfless people tend to burn out when too many things go opposite to their interests. He opens up the opportunity to recognize a newly coined word &#34;otherish&#34; - an opposite of selfish where you consider both your interests and the others interests simultaneously. &#34;Otherish&#34; people are looking for win-win situations, as opposed to selfless people who end up in win-lose setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#34;Givers are overrepresented at the top, as well as at the bottom, of most success measures.&#34; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/printer_friendly.cfm?articleid=3224&#34;&gt;interview with Adam Grant&lt;/a&gt; about the book is a 25 minute version which touches on several more high points of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocity, give and take a little bit</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 16:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-18-reciprocity-give-and-take-a-little-bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m looking forward to reading&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.giveandtake.com/Home/AdamGrant&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Adam Grant&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; book&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aadl.org/catalog/record/1427997&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Give and Take&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(aadl). &amp;#0160;Look in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/magazine/is-giving-the-secret-to-getting-ahead.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;March 31 NY Times Magazine for a preview&lt;/a&gt;, featuring a quote from the U of Michigan&amp;#39;s Jerry Davis. At the moment I&amp;#39;m&amp;#0160;33d on a list of 53 holds at the library for the book; if you&amp;#39;re generous, and have finished your copy, please lend it to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table of contents and blurb, from the AADL catalog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good returns: the dangers and rewards of giving more than you get -- The peacock and the panda: how givers, takers, and matchers build networks -- The ripple effect: collaboration and the dynamics of giving and taking credit -- Finding the diamond in the rough: the fact and fiction of recognizing potential -- The power of powerless communication: how to be modest and influence people -- The art of motivation maintenance: why some givers burn out but others are on fire -- Chump change: overcoming the doormat effect -- The scrooge shift: why a soccer team, a fingerprint, and a name can tilt us in the other direction -- Out of the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using his own cutting-edge research as a professor at Wharton Business School, Adam Grant shows how helping others can lead to greater personal success. He demonstrates how smart givers avoid becoming doormats, and why this kind of success has the power to transform not just individuals and groups, but entire organisations and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m particularly intrigued by the notion that there&amp;#39;s a distinction that creates &amp;quot;smart givers&amp;quot; that win some unspecified game through a generous strategy that pays off for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-03-28-a-slow-moving-version-of-twitter-always-hand-write-your-tweets-before-sending-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A slow moving version of Twitter: always hand write your tweets before sending them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Slow-moving-version-of-twitter&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017d4257b39c970c-600wi&#34; alt=&#34;Slow-moving-version-of-twitter&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bright idea? Write it down, photograph it, transcribe it, then (and only then) post to the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s OK to wait quite a long time between initial idea and eventual posting. This also works for blog postings, or at least it should. Twitter happens to make it easy to do in one step for short posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will lunch work on Thursday at a new place? (A2B3 lost its regular restaurant, Eastern Accents, and we&#39;re meeting at Conor O&#39;Neill&#39;s instead.) Caroline is manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you want to have stored up so that you can respond quickly to something new after having already thought through it at leisure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is the drawing? (Very.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you focus on something long enough to make it worthwhile to construct a lengthy effort to assemble media to support it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marginalia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Grant&#39;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.giveandtake.com/Home/AdamGrant&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Give and Take&lt;/a&gt;. Jerry Davis is interviewed. Look in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/magazine/is-giving-the-secret-to-getting-ahead.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;March 31 NY Times Magazine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest it at the Ann Arbor District Library once I get online. It&#39;s too hard to fill out the suggestion form from my teeny tiny phone screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry Michalski suggesting a similar piece on &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2012/10/plodding-and-bursting/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;bursting vs plodding&lt;/a&gt;&#34; and the benefits of each, written by Steve Pavlina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m listening to electronica by Valdis Krebs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F85186702&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterword&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I think Buddha is one line of work.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>