<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food And Drink Juneberry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/food-and-drink-juneberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food And Drink Juneberry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 22:14:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/food-and-drink-juneberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>seven random (food) facts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008-10-27-seven-random-food-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 22:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008-10-27-seven-random-food-facts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4obsessions.blogspot.com/2008/10/7-random-food-facts.html&#34;&gt;Inspired by Kate from Four Obsessions, here are seven food-related things to share.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; From an early age I was taught what was good to eat in the north woods and how to find it.&amp;#0160; If you&amp;#39;re walking with me and suddenly I dive into the bushes and come up with a handful of berries, you&amp;#39;ll understand.&amp;#0160; Locally this means that the first day of &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/search?q=ann+arbor+blueberries&#34;&gt;blueberry&lt;/a&gt;, raspberry, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/juneberry/&#34;&gt;juneberry&lt;/a&gt;, and strawberry season are holidays, and I employ a small army of berry-picking advance scouts to keep me informed of when opening day is and how conditions are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.&amp;#0160; When I was a kid we made cookies out of acorns once.&amp;#0160; It took a long time to gather them, and a lot of work to process them, and when they finally got into the oven somehow (mysteriously) they got scorched.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve never had the need to repeat that experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.&amp;#0160; The first complicated recipe I tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://amasci.com/amateur/sciamdx.html&#34;&gt;sauce Bearnaise, using a recipe from Scientific American&amp;#39;s The Amateur Scientist (1979 Dec, pg 178; 1981 Jan, pg 164).&amp;#0160;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160; It turned out pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4.&amp;#0160; After having had &lt;a href=&#34;http://williamtozier.com/slurry/2008/09/16/winter-squash-caramel&#34;&gt;sweet dumpling squash&lt;/a&gt;, I can&amp;#39;t go back to ever eating acorn squash again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5.&amp;#0160; We are vegetarians at home, but I&amp;#39;m a confirmed omnivore, and so you&amp;#39;ll see restaurant reviews of meat dishes but only vegetarian recipes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m bad at doing recipes because I hardly ever measure anything anymore - mostly I spice things by eye and smell, and as often as not the recipes I end up with are a description of what I did this one time with the food on hand and not instructions for what to go buy.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;m sure that there&amp;#39;s some recipe vocabulary in some language that I&amp;#39;m missing which could make them better, other than &amp;quot;cook until it smells good&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;7.&amp;#0160; I&amp;#39;ve taken to blogging recipes in part because it&amp;#39;s a convenient way to look them up the next time I need to cook them, since I don&amp;#39;t always know which cookbook on our shelf has the recipe on the menu plan for the week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tag: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ourfounder.typepad.com/leblog/2007/10/jimmy-wales-gro.html&#34;&gt;Jim Benson (e.g. &amp;quot;stir-fried wikipedia with pimentoes&amp;quot;)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kitchenchick.com/2008/02/paczki-day-tomo.html&#34;&gt;KitchenChick (my reliable source for Paczki Day information)&lt;/a&gt;, and The Cottage Smallholder (who &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cottagesmallholder.com/?p=855&#34;&gt;got tagged already&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>