<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Obituaries on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-obituaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Obituaries on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/ann-arbor-obituaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: James Doyle, Lower Burns Park resident whose home was rehabbed by community groups in 2006</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 09:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2014/2014-03-06-obituary-james-doyle-lower-burns-park-resident-whose-home-was-rehabbed-by-community-groups-in-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jim Doyle, a long time Lower Burns Park resident, passed away late last month at the Grand Rapids VA.  Mr. Doyle had lived at 1023 Granger Ave. for over 50 years. He served in the Philippines on General MacArthur&#39;s staff during the war.  After the war, Mr. Doyle returned to Ann Arbor where after the passing of his parents, he spent the majority of his adult life taking care of his younger brother who was severely disabled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you may remember Mr. Doyle from the efforts to &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20060727194215/http://www.ewashtenaw.org/news/2006/doyle_home.html/Assets/aa_news_james_doyle.pdf&#34;&gt;refurbish his house&lt;/a&gt; by Veteran groups back in 2006.  Mr. Doyle was a friendly man who always had a smile on his face and a penchant for whole milk and chocolate candy bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Graydon Krapohl for the information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. David Aberdeen, former Burns Park Elementary principal, obituary</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 02:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2009/2009-09-30-f-david-aberdeen-former-burns-park-elementary-principal-obituary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;span class=&#34;ObitsTile&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile&#34; style=&#34;min-width: 200px; display: inline-block; width: 615px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34; id=&#34;obitDetails&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34; id=&#34;obitHeader&#34;&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;original from &lt;a href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=133524746&#34;&gt;annarbor.com&lt;/a&gt;, hyperlinks mine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
                F. David Aberdeen
                
              &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;addThis&#34;&gt;
                &lt;span id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_AddThis&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt; var addthis_pub = &amp;quot;legacycomobituaries&amp;quot;; var addthis_brand = &amp;quot;Legacy.com&amp;quot;; var addthis_options = &amp;quot;favorites, delicious, reddit, google, facebook, digg, twitter, yahoobkm, myspace, bebo&amp;quot;; var addthis_header_color = &amp;quot;#FFFFFF&amp;quot;; var addthis_header_background = &amp;quot;#546F82&amp;quot;;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;javascript:void(0);&#34; onmouseout=&#34;addthis_close();&#34; onmouseover=&#34;return addthis_open(this, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;pid=133524746&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;F. Aberdeen Death Notice: F. Aberdeen’s Obituary by the AnnArbor.com.&amp;quot;);&#34;&gt;Share&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;a class=&#34;obitEmail&#34; href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary-email.aspx?n=f-david-aberdeen&amp;amp;pid=133524746&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_EmailObituaryLink&#34;&gt;E-mail&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;a class=&#34;viewSignGuestBook&#34; href=&#34;http://www.legacy.com/gb2/default.aspx?bookid=3762524876042&amp;amp;cid=full&#34; id=&#34;ctl00_ctl00_ContentPlaceHolder1_ContentPlaceHolder1_ObituaryTile_VisitGuestBookLink&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visit Guest Book&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div id=&#34;obitText&#34;&gt;
              
              &lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; lgyorigname=&#34;0003443845-01-1.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://mi-cache.legacy.com/legacy/images/Cobrands/AnnArbor/Photos/09272009_0003443845_1.jpg&#34; vspace=&#34;4&#34; /&gt;Aberdeen, F. David &lt;p&gt;
Age 79, died September 23 2009. Born on July 10, 1930 in Detroit, MI
the only child of Albert Frank Aberdeen and Leona Winifred Cozzens
Aberdeen. In 1961, David married Virginia Ray Ackley of Oakdale
California. They were married 36 years when she predeceased him in
1997. Together they had two sons, David Hall and John Stuart. David
spent his first 8 years in Detroit before moving to Portage Lake, where
he graduated from Pinckney High School in 1948. He attended Albion
College in his freshman year before transferring to the University of
Michigan. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1952 and then
earned a Masters degree in education from the University of Michigan in
1954. He began his long public school career in Chicago, where he
taught elementary school for five years, as well as night classes in
English as a Second Language. He then returned to Ann Arbor where he
would spend the rest of his professional career working for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Ann%20Arbor%20Public%20Schools&#34;&gt;Ann
Arbor Public Schools&lt;/a&gt;. He worked first as an elementary school teacher
and later as an administrator, at different times serving as Deputy
Superintendent and principal of &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Thurston_Elementary_School&#34;&gt;Thurston&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Burns_Park_Elementary_School&#34;&gt;Burns Park&lt;/a&gt; elementary
schools. An early advocate of equal opportunity for all students, he
spent a year with the Mott Foundation in Flint, after which he obtained
his Ph.D. from the University of Michigan in 1969. After retiring from
Burns Park in 1988, he continued to work for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Ann_Arbor_Administrators_Association&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor
Administrators Association&lt;/a&gt; until earlier this year. He also served on
the board of the Pinckey Community Schools Alumni Association, chairing
the scholarship committee. He chose the perfect profession as it
allowed him to express his lifelong passion for teaching and learning.
In 1988 the Michigan State Senate passed a concurrent resolution (No.
672) offering tribute to honor David&amp;#39;s contributions to public
education. Along with his family, his other great loves were music,
literature and the arts. Possessing an uncanny ability to remember the
lyrics to any song he was unbeatable at &amp;quot;Name that Tune&amp;quot;. His love of
words was reflected in his unique writings, his large collection of
books and his ability to quote from almost any poem, book or movie.
David was never a stranger in any group - if he met you, he was your
friend. He is survived by his two sons, David Hall Aberdeen of San
Francisco California, and John Stuart Aberdeen of Arlington
Massachusetts, and a host of friends, colleagues and former students. A
memorial will be held at 10 a.m. Saturday, October 3rd, in the Ballroom
of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Michigan_League&#34;&gt;Michigan League&lt;/a&gt;, 911 N. University Avenue in Ann Arbor. David
was a lifelong advocate of public education and to honor him donations
in his memory may be made to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/AAPSEF&#34;&gt;Ann Arbor Public Schools Educational
Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://aapsef.org/&#34;&gt;http://aapsef.org/&lt;/a&gt;)
             &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>