<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 11:34:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Need: A login and registration system for a free WiFi network</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-26-need-a-login-and-registration-system-for-a-free-wifi-network-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 11:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-26-need-a-login-and-registration-system-for-a-free-wifi-network-/</guid>
      <description>A note from Steve Pierce regarding a request for ideas and code to help people log into a free WiFi mesh network. Contact him for details at bottom.
 HDL.com and volunteers have deployed a free WiFi network in SE Michigan over the last 5 years. With over 1,000 access points deployed and 650,000 unique devices connected, Wireless Ypsi and companion networks such as Detroit Enabled are averaging over 2,500 users per day, making it one of the largest free WiFi networks in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 22, 2008: Brewster Kahle in Ann Arbor, MI at the John Seely Brown Symposium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-october-22-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 12:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-14-october-22-2008/</guid>
      <description>Brewster&#39;s coming to town to talk at the U.
Official announcement from the school of information
Brewster gave me a mug from Thinking Machines back in the WAIS days, I&#39;m looking forward to the visit.
More details:
Wed, Oct 22, 3:00 - 5:30
Live Webcast - http://si.umich.edu/jsb
Submit your questions via e-mail.
Or attend in person:
Biomed Science Research Bldg Auditorium
(corner of Huron and Glen in Ann Arbor)
A leading proponent of open access to all knowledge will consider the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#atlgas: real time reporting on gasoline availability in Atlanta, using Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-atlgas-real-tim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 15:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-atlgas-real-tim/</guid>
      <description>For a bunch of reasons which I don&#39;t completely understand, there are gasoline shortages in the Atlanta area.
The net is responding by using the #atlgas tag on Twitter to coordinate real time information about the location and availability of gasoline.&amp;nbsp; To look at it the easiest way is through the twitter search for #atlgas.&amp;nbsp; Some recent examples -
 wheelmom: #atlgas BP at I-85 and Clairmont. $4.39(!) Barely a wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage density in petabytes per shipping container</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-25-storage-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-25-storage-density/</guid>
      <description>One way to get high density storage without creating building-wide cooling issues is to move your computing and storage facilities into a container which can be housed out of the building.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;m looking at specs for some various systems to do this, optimized for storage density, to see what the expectations might be for what you&#39;d get in &amp;quot;petabytes per container&amp;quot;.
The answer appears to be &amp;quot;about one petabyte per six linear feet of container&amp;quot;, or put another way, &amp;quot;about one petabyte per ten cubic meters of containerized storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury in Retrograde, The Reverse Engineers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-25-mercury-in-retr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 09:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-25-mercury-in-retr-1/</guid>
      <description>For any of you who run Yahoo Groups, it&amp;#39;s well known that Yahoo has problems when Mercury is retrograde.
The Reverse Engineers have a song &amp;quot;Mercury in Retrograde&amp;quot; that&amp;#39;s a $0.99 download from Amazon.
The lyrics match the problem.
Mercury in Retrograde
Lyrics by Charles Cote, Daniel Cote, William Cote It travels round the sun
Six times to our one
What no one else can see
Is plain as day to me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop backpacks - summary of recommendations</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-01-laptop-backpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 09:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-01-laptop-backpack/</guid>
      <description>I recently sent out an email query to the a2b3 mailing list about backpacks suitable for laptops.&amp;nbsp; In the interests of not keeping useful information in my inbox, here&#39;s a summary of sorts.
The list, in no particular order, with some amount of incomplete information:
Land&#39;s End: the pack I have has a label, don&#39;t know the name of it in their catalog.&amp;nbsp; It&#39;s nice.&amp;nbsp; The Land&#39;s End backpack page has more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service as a service</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-29-service-as-a-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 22:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-29-service-as-a-se/</guid>
      <description>After a small set of discussions today with people I won&#39;t blog about, here&#39;s some ideas from people I don&#39;t know using a phrase I thought I might have made up: &#34;service as a service&#34;.
James Urquhart&#39;s &#34;The Wisdom of Clouds&#34; on Service as a Service Market Explored:

Real quick, David Linthicum has a cool post on the move in the market from human-oriented SaaS (Software as a Service) to systems oriented SaaS--perhaps better named &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kilowatts per terabyte, or terabytes per kilowatt: a measure of storage energy efficiency</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-26-kilowatts-per-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 10:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-26-kilowatts-per-t/</guid>
      <description>A measure of the efficiency of data storage; the equivalent would be W/GB (watts per gigabyte).
The range measured below is 0.4 TB/KW (RAM) to 500 TB/KW (Blu-ray disks), with a corresponding range in access speed and update times.
Some estimates or measures:
If you are using solid state memory (no disk; just memory, configured as disk) from Texas Memory Systems, expect to have 2.5 KW/TB, or 0.4 TB/KW:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WaterWatch, Advanced Hydrologic Prediction Service - US flood and rain maps and predictions</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-13-waterwatch-adva/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-13-waterwatch-adva/</guid>
      <description>WaterWatch is a US Geological Survey online product that gives consolidated river level and flood stage information across the US. The graphic is from 12 June 2008 showing the floods across the midwestern US.
 

A similar set of data (not precisely the same, but overlapping) is kept by the National Weather Service, as part of their Advanced Hydrologic Prediction Service. This has a whole set of comprehensive rainfall measures, which are as useful in drought condition monitoring as they are in flood monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE power outages persist in Oakland County, MI after storm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-dte-power-outag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 10:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-dte-power-outag/</guid>
      <description>The Detroit News has some reporting on the DTE power outages across the Detroit metro region.

The company serves Metro Detroit, home to about 136,000 of the homes and businesses still without power. More than two-thirds of those -- 95,000 -- are in Oakland County, where frustrations are running high as schools and businesses remained closed and families flocked to hotels for temporary shelter. Since Sunday night, an estimated 600,000 people in Michigan have been affected by the outages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reification is an ontological imperative</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-19-reification-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-05-19-reification-is/</guid>
      <description>Reification is an ontological imperative.
I think that this might be some deep statement about the semantic web, but it&#39;s so deep that I really don&#39;t understand it.
Reification in this sense appears to have something to do with taking abstract concepts and making them concrete, turning ad hoc heuristics into code, writing down a set of things into a list so that it can be machine processed and sorted, and otherwise taking thoughts and ideas and turning them into bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo Alumni Association</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-12-yahoo-alumni-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 20:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-02-12-yahoo-alumni-as/</guid>
      <description>Quite a few people got laid off at Yahoo today; reports are trickling in from Twitter.  UPDATED: This hit techmeme; adding a few details throughout.  CNET reports 1000 (but &amp;ldquo;no details&amp;rdquo;).  &amp;ldquo;We are aligning resources to support our big bets: starting points, must buy, and open,&amp;rdquo; a Yahoo spokeswoman said. That refers to Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s new mission of being the most popular starting place for people on the Internet and the most popular advertising platform, as well as the company&amp;rsquo;s focus on opening up Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s network to third-party publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>