<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Radio on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Radio on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:39:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ann-arbor-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Geek tour: WCBN-FM control room, Wednesday, November 14, 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-11-13-geek-tour-wcbn-fm-control-room-wednesday-november-14-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a2geeks is hosting a tour of the WCBN-FM control room on Wednesday, November 14, 2012. Tours start at 5:30p, 6:30p, and 7:30p, and you should &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2geektour5control.eventbrite.com/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;RSVP for your space&lt;/a&gt;. (I&amp;#39;ll be at the 5:30pm tour.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wcbn.org&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;WCBN&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing student-run radio station at the University of Michigan, founded in 1972 and broadcasting from the basement of the Student Activities Building. Listen live to WCBN at 88.3 FM (all the way to the left on your dial) or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wcbn.org/listen.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. You might need to go online to enjoy it if you live outside the transmission area - this map from the FCC shows an approximate radius of where the station can best be enjoyed, though I&amp;#39;m sure I&amp;#39;ve heard it from further away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Map credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://transition.fcc.gov/fcc-bin/fmq?call=WCBN&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;FCC station database for WCBN-FM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;asset-img-link&#34; href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee51306e9970d-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Picture 92&#34; class=&#34;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee51306e9970d&#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef017ee51306e9970d-600wi&#34; style=&#34;width: 600px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; title=&#34;Picture 92&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area FM radio, scanning left to right on your radio dial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/2011-11-17-ann-arbor-area-fm-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A band scan from Ann Arbor, with notes especially on how to get ahold of the station if you like the tunes being played. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is incomplete, because you can always have a better radio with a better antenna that can pick out one more low power station at the edge of its range. It&#39;s also incomplete, because it only points to stations I&#39;m likely to listen to, and because it&#39;s starting at the left edge of the dial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;88.3 FM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wcbn.org&#34;&gt;WCBN-FM Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt; is the University of Michigan student radio station; the studio line is +1 734 763 3500. Your chance of getting your request played on air is excellent during one of the many freeform shows. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wcbn.org/listen.html&#34;&gt;Listen live online to WCBN&lt;/a&gt;, or point your terrestrial antenna towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wcbn.org/facilities.html&#34;&gt;WCBN transmitter&lt;/a&gt; located at the top of the Dennison Building on the University of Michigan campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;89.1 FM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wemu.org&#34;&gt;WEMU-FM Ypsilanti&lt;/a&gt; is the Eastern Michigan University National Public Radio affiliate, playing news, jazz, and blues. The studio line is +1 734 487 8936. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wemump3.emich.edu:8000/broadband.mp3.m3u&#34;&gt;Listen live online to WEMU&lt;/a&gt;, or point your terrestrial antenna towards the transmitter located off LeForge Road to the north of the EMU campus. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wemu.org/term/local&#34;&gt;WEMU&#39;s local news bureau&lt;/a&gt; reports community news. Twitter: @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WEMU891&#34;&gt;WEMU891&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;89.9 FM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbc.ca/windsor/&#34;&gt;CBC Radio 2 Windsor&lt;/a&gt; broadcasts from Detroit&#39;s neighbor to the south, Windsor Ontario. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbc.ca/video/radio-popup.html#networkKey=cbc_radio_2&amp;amp;programKey=eastern&#34;&gt;Listen live online to CBC Radio 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;90.5 FM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wkar.org/90.5/&#34;&gt;WKAR-FM East Lansing&lt;/a&gt; is the NPR affiliate for Michigan State University, with classical music programming. The transmitter is located in Ingham County, and you&#39;ll need to point your antenna to pick up signals from the northwest of Ann Arbor. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wkar.org/stream/fm.pls&#34;&gt;Listen live online to WKAR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;91.7 FM. &lt;a href=&#34;http://michiganradio.org&#34;&gt;WUOM-FM Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt; is Michigan Radio, the University of Michigan National Public Radio affiliate, featuring news and talk programming. WUOM runs BBC programming overnight. &lt;a href=&#34;http://pod.michiganradio.org/player/listen_now.php&#34;&gt;Listen live online to WUOM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mike O&#39;Connor, Chris Dzombak, Jessica Webster, Tamar Charney, Tex, arwulf arwulf, Erika Sherman, The Electrifying Mojo, Lucy Ann Lance, Jessica Webster, and a number of other people I haven&#39;t mentioned yet for their contributions and encouragement for this document and to Ann Arbor area radio.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Gears, NPR project adding staff for Rustbelt local coverage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 00:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/2010-08-11-changing-gears-npr-project-adding-staff-for-rustbelt-local-coverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Award-winning journalists from public media, the Web and newspapers are now part of the Changing Gears team.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.changinggears.info/2010/08/04/journalists-named-to-changing-gears-team/#more-258&#34;&gt;www.changinggears.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Public Radio launching local coverage out of Cleveland, Ann Arbor, and Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>