<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Detroit Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/detroit-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Detroit Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/detroit-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy: Greystone Jazz rescue</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 11:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-detroit-sound-conservancy-greystone-jazz-rescue/</guid>
      <description>The Detroit Sound Conservancy went to the vacant Book Building in Detroit on July 7, 2015 to salvage the collection of the defunct Graystone International Jazz Museum. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice writeup in MLive, Graystone jazz artifacts, forgotten in Detroit skyscraper, now being preserved. Photographer Doug Coombe went along to document the effort with a photo set on Facebook.
 &amp;ldquo;We knew that things were bad,&amp;rdquo; said DSC&amp;rsquo;s Founder and President Carleton Gholz about the neglected collection, but Gholz didn&amp;rsquo;t know how bad until he discovered many of the former museum&amp;rsquo;s records were broken and strewn across the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Cass, the distinguished Senator of Michigan, is the Great Michigander.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-11-general-cass-the-distinguished-senator-of-michigan-is-the-great-michigander-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 00:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-02-11-general-cass-the-distinguished-senator-of-michigan-is-the-great-michigander-/</guid>
      <description>The quote is from the 1853&amp;#0160;White, red, black, sketches of American society in the United States, by F. and T. Pulszky (p. 87). &amp;#0160;The word shows up in Victor Hugo&amp;#39;s 1866&amp;#0160;Les travailleurs de la mer&amp;#0160;as &amp;quot;le grand Michigantier&amp;quot;, also referring to Cass.
In&amp;#0160;Off-hand takings; or, Crayon sketches of the noticeable men of our age By George Washington Bungay (1854) we have this anecdote, of an encounter between Lewis Cass of Michigan and John Parker Hale of New Hampshire, attributed to an interaction in 1848.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1920s Detroit newsreels from the Detroit News online</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-1920s-detroit-n/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-11-1920s-detroit-n/</guid>
      <description>via the Detroit Area Libraries Network:

From the WSULS News Blog: “Because of a six month extension to an Institute of Library and Museum Services grant, the Wayne State University Library System and the Walter P. Reuther Library just finished adding around 20,000 images and over 400 videos to the Virtual Motor City photo collection, an online resource already containing digitized images from the Detroit News Collection, a photojournalistic resource held at the Reuther Library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>