<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Buffalo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/buffalo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Buffalo on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 16:29:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/buffalo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Buffalo stew</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-blueberry-buffa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 16:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-blueberry-buffa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cookingdebauchery.com/cooking_debauchery/2006/09/blueberrybuffal.html&#34;&gt;Blueberry buffalo stew&lt;/a&gt; from Cooking Debauchery, via merathena on LJ:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The blueberries melt into the stock producing the most delectable, mahogany colored broth and a fragrance the fills the house with the scents of fall. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re vegetarians at home, so this is going to have to be someone else&#39;s potluck dish.  There&#39;s buffalo raised in Michigan at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sprikfarms.com/&#34;&gt;Sprik Farms&lt;/a&gt; near Grand Rapids, and at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tmzfarm.com/&#34;&gt;TMZ Farm&lt;/a&gt; near Pinckney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blueberry-Buffalo Stew&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 ½ - 2 pounds buffalo, beef, or lamb stew meat&lt;br /&gt;
1 cup blueberries&lt;br /&gt;
4 cups chicken or beef stock&lt;br /&gt;
2 tablespoons canola oil (or bacon drippings)&lt;br /&gt;
1 ½ tablespoons honey&lt;br /&gt;
3 tablespoons dry sherry (optional)&lt;br /&gt;
1/8 teaspoon cayenne pepper (optional)&lt;br /&gt;
Salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut the meat into one inch chunks and season lightly with salt and pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat a large Dutch oven or stew pot.  Drizzle in oil or bacon dripping to coat the bottom.  Working in batches, brown the meat well on all sides.  Add oil as necessary.  Do not over crowd the pan.  Remove browned meat to a clean dish and cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the meat is browned, return it all to the pan with any juices that have accumulated on the plate.  Add stock and bring to a boil.  Lower the heat and skim off any froth that has collected on the surface until the broth is clear.  Add the blueberries, honey, sherry, and cayenne pepper and bring back to a boil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simmer for 2 hours or until the meat is very tender and the broth has reduced.  Stir occasionally.  This helps to break up the blueberries and incorporate them into the liquid.  By the end of the cooking time the blueberries should be completely incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve with crusty bread and salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More blueberry buffalo recipes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gourmet.com/recipes/diaryofafoodie/2007/01/buffalo_tenderloin_cranberry_blueberry_sauce&#34;&gt;Buffalo tenderloin with cranberry blueberry sauce&lt;/a&gt;, from Gourmet magazine&#39;s &#34;Diary of a Foodie&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;A href=&#34;http://kitchenparade.com/2006/09/buffalo-ragout.php&#34;&gt;Buffalo Ragout with dried blueberries&lt;/a&gt;, from Kitchen Parade, adapted from The Food Journal of Lewis &amp; Clark by Mary Gunderson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and not quite the same:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twoboredneighbors.com/FreeRecipes.htm&#34;&gt;Blueberry buffalo wings&lt;/a&gt; using a blueberry based BBQ sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>