<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roos Roast on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/roos-roast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roos Roast on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:05:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/roos-roast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Coffee and Wifi, Roos Roast Wednesday edition</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-22-daily-coffee-wifi-roos-roast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Roos, an espresso over ice with a little half and half and a hard
boiled egg. It&amp;rsquo;s a very compact breakfast. The espresso is served in
an appropriately sized glass mug and tastes like the strongest little
iced latte you will ever have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Mac, run &amp;lsquo;boot2docker upgrade&amp;rsquo;. That gets me up to current 1.7.1
revision of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Edwards-MacBook-Air:~ emv$ docker version
Client version: 1.7.1
Client API version: 1.19
Go version (client): go1.4.2
Git commit (client): 786b29d
OS/Arch (client): darwin/amd64
Server version: 1.7.1
Server API version: 1.19
Go version (server): go1.4.2
Git commit (server): 786b29d
OS/Arch (server): linux/amd64
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue that 1.7.1 resolves for me is certificate support - if I
understand the bug right, the Docker daemon was creating a key for
each interface it had, but not all of the interfaces were up at key
init time. The fix was to move DHCP init earlier in the start sequence
so that everything was initialized by the time key creation took place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Docker team is trying to improve code quality by having their
code base pass the &lt;code&gt;golint&lt;/code&gt; test. The open issue,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/pull/14784&#34;&gt;fix golint errors/warnings #14784&lt;/a&gt;,
has attracted a swarm of contributors, and a lot of them have
proposed changes that don&amp;rsquo;t pass the automated tests. The build
farm is managed with Jenkins, and you can see the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.dockerproject.org/&#34;&gt;status of every build of Docker&lt;/a&gt; on their
dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a full lintable codebase is a great goal. The challenge comes when
the suggested changes by lint send you in the direction of making an
incompatible change to some interface that has the &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; name but that
people were relying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps importantly for the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that currently
all of these tests are done on x86 platforms (Linux and Windows) and there
isn&amp;rsquo;t an official automated build on ARM. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;Docker distribution from Hypriot&lt;/a&gt; as my
baseline for working on the Raspberry Pi, with good success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction on I-75 at 13 Mile Road! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theoaklandpress.com/general-news/20150715/traffic-delays-expected-for-6-weeks-on-i-75-and-13-mile-during-mdot-project&#34;&gt;Expect major delays&lt;/a&gt; at this
project in Madison Heights. From the Oakland Press&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the construction project, there will be lane closures on both I-75 and 13 Mile Road in Madison Heights, said Diane Cross, a spokeswoman for the Michigan Department of Transportation, which is doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(insert map here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the alternative routes look any good, allow extra time for travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components of the postcard project are coming together. So far I have little
pieces that put and get addresses from a database, resize pictures to the
correct size, and generate test and live cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I lob a single thoughtful card out every time I have an espresso, there
will be some steady stream of cards going out. Next piece of the checklist is
pulling a report showing which cards are in flight and which ones just arrived
so that I can schedule followups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key bits of sending cards is that your recipient doesn&amp;rsquo;t get them
right away. That gives you a chance to refine your thinking and contemplate
what you have to say when you do follow up when they do get it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>