<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newberry Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/newberry-michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newberry Michigan on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 17:19:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/cities/newberry-michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Duck Lake Fire, north of Newberry MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-25-duck-lake-fire-north-of-newberry-mi/</guid>
      <description>Some sources for information on the Duck Lake Fire, which started on Wednesday, May 23, 2012 and is burning rapidly in Luce County, north of Newberry, MI. The fire is dangerous and has caused evacuations; if you are reading this and you are in the area, seek authoritative and current information from official sources.
The fire brings to mind the 2007 Sleeper Lake Fire&amp;#0160;which burned over 18,000 acres in Luce County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeper Lake Fire mushroom hunting near Newberry, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-sleeper-lake-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 14:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-12-sleeper-lake-fi/</guid>
      <description>Last year there was a fire near Sleeper Lake in Newberry, MI in the UP; when I wrote about it, I collected fire maps of the Sleeper Lake area showing where the fire lines were. That fire is out now, but that page where I had those maps is still getting a steady stream of page views. So, I have to ask, why?
The other popular seasonal page is my annual Michigan morel map, which I pull an excerpt from the morel progression sightings map and highlight the appearance of these tasty mushrooms in the Michigan woods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>