<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discardia on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/discardia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Discardia on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/discardia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2011 discardia notes</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-summer-2011-discardia-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-23-summer-2011-discardia-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discardia is a quarterly holiday where we decide to let go of some things around us in order to make way to do things for the new season. It&amp;#39;s a modern invention of Dinah Sanders, who writes about it at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.discardia.com&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;discardia.com&lt;/a&gt;. The season runs from the solstice or equinox to the following new moon. For summer 2011, the dates are June 21 through July 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my kids, Lego is the part of their existence which most calls out for straightforward decisionmaking to create order amidst the chaos. Before you can do a rebuild of a model that you already have, you need to find all of the impossibly tiny scattered pieces that make it up. A multipart storage box container is a great way to occupy a small boy&amp;#39;s hour cleaning and sorting, because only when you have all of the yellow pieces together do you find the tiny Lego-sized firefighters accessories. Once you get down to the level that you can find the tiny black fireman&amp;#39;s axe, the small child is content to build with it rather than agitate to buy more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books are my bane of accumulation existence, to the point where deciding what to do with them takes more energy than actually reading them. We have used Paperback Swap to maintain a steady state of inventory and still get new reading materials, and Books By Chance to dispose of surplus. Fortunately, the Lego situation (q.v.) is under control enough that I have reclaimed one bookshelf, which is being carefully curated as best I can to contain the collection that I would keep if it were my only shelf of books. Every decision to add to it means there&amp;#39;s a corresponding decision to remove a book, and that keeps the shelf from accumulating dust and ennui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The element of my life that absorbs more time than it should is the Internet, especially the Internet of flitting around from site to site trying to decide that someone has written something new worth writing. My self control is weak for shiny new things, but what I have discovered is that I can replace self control with ritual sometimes, and a ritual of writing on a specific topic for a specific person rather than reading aimlessly repays the time. I don&amp;#39;t know yet how to cure a ritual addiction to being online, though Paul Jones&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;no email&amp;quot; project points to one way to discard a portion of the online existence while staying connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Dinah Sanders for the &amp;quot;decide and do&amp;quot; theme for this season&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;Discardia&lt;/a&gt;. John Weise and Stephanie Bentley run &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.booksbychance.com/&#34;&gt;Books By Chance&lt;/a&gt;, a consignment used bookstore which helps deal with my book surplus. Duane Collicott&amp;#39;s Bricks for Brains provides an annual Lego surplus at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/03/brick-bash-lego-2011.html&#34;&gt;Brick Bash&lt;/a&gt;. Reach &lt;a href=&#34;http://ibiblio.org/pjones/blog/&#34;&gt;Paul Jones&lt;/a&gt; by any of a thousand online systems, all except email. LEGO is a registered trademark owned by the LEGO Group, and don&amp;#39;t you forget it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for midsummer 2010: paperback swap</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-discardia-for-midsummer-2010-paperback-swap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-13-discardia-for-midsummer-2010-paperback-swap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge is to get rid of some set of books that have accumulated, while simultaneously fulfilling the need to always have some kind of new reading in the house. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new (to me) way to do this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paperbackswap.com&#34;&gt;Paperback Swap&lt;/a&gt;, a system which works as a trading board for books. &amp;#0160;You are entitled to books in the proportion that you send books to others, and every book you request is free to you. &amp;#0160;The catch is that you pay postage for the books you send to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of the sender-pays structure, many of the books listed are lightweight and cheap to mail. There&amp;#39;s some calculus in people&amp;#39;s minds that probably says &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m willing to pay the cost of shipping to get rid of this.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can imagine a lot of other things that could work the same way, looking especially for items that have relatively high value compared to weight, but where you might accumulate unwanted and unused items over time that have more swap value than use value. &amp;#0160;It looks like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swap-bot.com/&#34;&gt;Swap-bot&lt;/a&gt; fills some of that need for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/&#34;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;-class homemade items.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.discardia.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discardia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; from Dinah Sanders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia runs 20 Mar 2010 - 14 Apr 2010</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-discardia-runs-20-mar-2010-14-apr-2010-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-03-20-discardia-runs-20-mar-2010-14-apr-2010-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The season of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;discardia&lt;/a&gt; is upon us again. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s time to unsubscribe from mailing lists, take out the trash, empty out your pockets, weigh your inbox and reduce its weight, clean out the cupboards and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also time for me to stop even pretending that I can follow everything that have at one time been interested in and let some things that fascinate me slip by the wayside for a while, so that in some future I can come back to them and be surprised by how much progress has been made since I was gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My one purchase for this discardia season is going to be a digital scale, so that I can give a number to just how much crud I have sitting in front of me and measure the progress of removing it. &amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;heave ho,&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for spring 2009</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-discardia-for-spring-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-21-discardia-for-spring-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;Discardia&lt;/a&gt; is a four times a year holiday that celebrates letting go, getting rid of, and removing unneeded things from your life.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s one of my favorite modern holidays, one of those repeated reminders that there are sometimes things that you have gathered into your life that need to be scattered around instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority one is a book purge; I&amp;#39;ll be filling up a few bags with books to get out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority two is an internet purge, looking at the online services that absorb time (and money some times) and seeing which ones I can do without.&amp;#0160; This means that every single email that comes into the inbox for the next few days gets the query &amp;quot;how do I get rid of this&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority three is a kitchen purge, looking at the emergency cupboard for the food that will never be eaten by us and should be donated, and looking for spare utensils and containers that could go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Properly done, this is a year round effort, the sort of effort that has a box in your house that is the designated spot to send things off to the Reuse Center or some other organized recycling process.&amp;#0160; With two kids around the house the natural tendency is towards unmitigated clutter, but there&amp;#39;s some way to counteract that.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discardia for winter 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-21-discardia-for-winter-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 12:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-21-discardia-for-winter-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;Discardia&lt;/a&gt; is a four times a year holiday that celebrates letting go, getting rid of, and removing unneeded things from your life.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s one of my favorite modern holidays, one of those repeated reminders that there are sometimes things that you have gathered into your life that need to be scattered around instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority one is a book purge; I&amp;#39;ll be filling up a few bags with books to get out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority two is an internet purge, looking at the online services that absorb time (and money some times) and seeing which ones I can do without.&amp;#0160; This means that every single email that comes into the inbox for the next few days gets the query &amp;quot;how do I get rid of this&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Properly done, this is a year round effort, the sort of effort that has a box in your house that is the designated spot to send things off to the Reuse Center or some other organized recycling process.&amp;#0160; With two kids around the house the natural tendency is towards unmitigated clutter, but there&amp;#39;s some way to counteract that.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2008 Discardia, 22-29 September 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-fall-2008-disca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 01:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-28-fall-2008-disca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/&#34;&gt;Dinah&lt;/a&gt; made up a holiday called 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;Discardia&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/metagrrrl/2002/12/a_new_holiday_d.html&#34;&gt;She wrote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve decided to invent a new holiday called Discardia. It takes place
in the time between the Solstices &amp;amp; Equinoxes and their following
new moons. Discardia is celebrated by getting rid of stuff and ideas
and habits you no longer need. On the Discardian new moon you don&#39;t
buy anything or bring anything into your home and enjoy the fact that
you have enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend&#39;s project is emptying out bits of the garage that have accumulated reusable leftovers from the summer&#39;s kitchen project.&amp;nbsp; We took a couple of windows to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Reuse_Center&#34;&gt;Reuse Center on S. Industrial&lt;/a&gt; which gladly took them, and there&#39;s more in the garage that looks like it should go before the first frost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In thinking about how to identify the things that need to go, I&#39;m back to notes I wrote about seiri.&amp;nbsp; The approach here is to use red tags to identify things that don&#39;t belong, and then to systematically remove the things that don&#39;t belong so that no red tags are left and no new red tags appear.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/edward-vielmetti/48871860/&#34;&gt;The most interesting thing I&#39;ve written about seiri &lt;/a&gt;was written on paper, so you can see the scan.&amp;nbsp; I want to go back and do the red tag thing online in some clever way.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discardia: 20 Jun 2008 - 2 Jul 2008</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-19-discardia-20-ju/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 14:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-19-discardia-20-ju/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metagrrrl.com/discardia/&#34;&gt;What is Discardia?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Discardia is celebrated by getting rid of stuff and ideas you no longer need. It&#39;s about letting go, abdicating from obligation and guilt, being true to the self you are now. Discardia is the time to get rid of things that no longer add value to your life, shed bad habits, let go of emotional baggage and generally lighten your load. - Dinah Sanders
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discardia was the theme of today&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/a2b3&#34;&gt;a2b3&lt;/a&gt; Thursday lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked of family emptying years of accumulation as their inheritances, including removing acres of scrap metal from a farm, organizing two day long estate sales, auctioning old books off by the case, and dealing with the environmental impact of 200 old tires.  Some of that meant quite a bit of money and some family bonding time; others of it was stories of incredible hassles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balancing that, of course, was the urge to collect, whether it be &lt;a href=&#34;http://potifos.com/fraud/&#34;&gt;Nigerian fraud email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;A href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/edward-vielmetti/349434750/in/pool-fairydoors&#34;&gt;fairy door drawing from your kids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/catalog/superpatron&#34;&gt;books you&#39;ve read or would like to read&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/vielmetti/annarbor&#34;&gt;web pages about Ann Arbor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2004/05/my_quadrille_no.html&#34;&gt;handwritten notebooks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cscs.umich.edu/~crshalizi/notebooks/&#34;&gt;online notebooks&lt;/a&gt;, or any of the things in the physical world.  Physical world stuff - tools, two-by-four remnants, scrap metal, pig-themed trinkets, fish-themed trinkets, books, books, more books, paper (sorted or unsorted) take up a lot more space, but the online things occupy your brain too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you doing for discardia?  We&#39;ve been emptying kitchen cupboards of unused pans - one piece that&#39;s on its way out is a broiling pan (Not Much Use In A Vegetarian Household).&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>