<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food And Drink Garlic Mustard on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/food-and-drink-garlic-mustard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food And Drink Garlic Mustard on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/food-and-drink-garlic-mustard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Mustard in Michigan (via MSU IPM)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-garlic-mustard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-garlic-mustard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipm.msu.edu/garlicmustard.htm&#34;&gt;Garlic Mustard in Michigan&lt;/a&gt;, a report and information from Michigan State University:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Garlic mustard is an exotic invasive plant from Europe that invades woodland habitats in North America and impacts forest biodiversity. In some woodlands, dense stands of garlic mustard in the spring threaten showy spring blooming ephemerals like spring beauty, trilliums and trout lilies. Other research points toward potentially negative impacts on timber species and forest health. Many land managers consider it to be one of the most potentially harmful and difficult to control invasive plants in the region.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It&#39;s time to pull garlic mustard again, which is a sure sign of spring.  Our yard has a little bit, not too bad, and certainly not as bad as it was a few years ago before we realized just what we had that was growing so vigorously.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2007/04/where_else_can_.html&#34;&gt;Last year at this time&lt;/a&gt; I recounted a tale of where to go for a walk in the woods, and the story of the celebration of the garlic mustard recipe of the year.  (in summary, bleah.)  As a reminder:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
So I made it and tasted it. Not particularly good, and I&#39;m still dealing with the tummy ache. Perhaps someone else has a better recipe, or I picked it too late in the season, or it really just doesn&#39;t taste that good? I will admit to not adding the vinegar (or, as Allen Bailey suggested, lemon juice) which might have been the problem. Next time, I&#39;ll also cook the greens in a change or two of water first, which should also draw off some of the bitterness.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you have an awesome garlic mustard recipe - or, if you know a source for a supply of pygmy goats that will eat the stuff - pls. note in the comments.
&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>