<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systemantics on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/books/systemantics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systemantics on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/books/systemantics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: John Gall, 1925-2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/2014-12-15-john-gall-obituary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gall, John C. 9/18/1925 - 12/15/2014 Walker, MN John C. Gall, Jr.,
beloved husband, father, pediatrician, scholar and author, passed
away with his wife by his side Dec. 15, 2014, in Walker, MN, from
natural causes. He was 89. John was born on September 18, 1925 in
Washington, D.C. and grew up near Upperville, VA. In 1945 he was
drafted into the Army Air Corps and sent to Germany, where he served
as a medic in the Allied army of occupation. During his tour of
duty he attended the Nuremberg trials, which kindled in him a
lifelong passion to heal the afflicted and promote justice. Upon
returning home he furthered his education, graduating from Yale and
George Washington University Medical School. He was a postdoctorate
fellow at the Mayo Clinic, where he was dubbed &amp;ldquo;the best pediatric
diagnostician [they had] ever seen!&amp;rdquo; In addition he earned a
certification in Human Genetics and completed 7 years of therapy
training. Dr. Gall began his medical career as a researcher at the
University of Virginia, followed by a 3-year stint at the Geisinger
Clinic in Danville, PA. He next went into private practice in Miles
City, MT, but was soon invited to teach at the University of Michigan
Medical School in Ann Arbor, MI. There he also served as head of
the Plymouth State Home, where he did research partially funded by
the Kennedy family foundation, and named and described several
syndromes of the developmentally disabled . In addition he established
a long-running private pediatric practice of 38 years. During this
period he developed a special appreciation for, and an enduring
interest in, the importance of nonverbal communication between very
young children and their parents. This led him to expand his practice
to include support and education classes, in which he was aided by
his late wife, Beth, and then by his wife Carol. Their observations
and anecdotes are included in Elegant Parenting, written with wife,
Beth; in Dancing with Elves written by John, and with wife Carol
he wrote Hit by a Low-Flying Goose. John&amp;rsquo;s best known book is System
Antics, later published under the title The Systems Bible, a humorous
but insightful study of the problems and pitfalls that afflict every
type of system that human beings create-whether mechanical, economic,
corporate, aeronautical, legal, linguistic, religious, medical or
electronic. It was first published in 1976 by the New York
Times/Quadrangle Press and has been translated (officially or
unofficially) into at least 14 languages. He lectured widely
throughout the United States and was interviewed by the Voice of
America on nuclear proliferation issues after its publication. John
and Carol were both invited to speak in London in 2012 to a group
of CEOs and other executives from around the world and John was
introduced as &amp;ldquo;The Grandfather of Systems Theory.&amp;rdquo; He retired to
Walker, MN, in 2001 in search of privacy and uninterrupted time,
which he used to write seven other books, including a novel, First
Queen, plus books and video books on parenting and the art of
pediatric practice. He was very proud that the great Swiss psychiatrist,
Alice Miller, who introduced the world to the subject of child
sexual abuse, endorsed his work before she died. His work has also
been endorsed by others too numerous to name, but including such
luminaries as the head of the Dept. of Psychology at Cambridge,
University, who forwarded his material to several British social
service agencies. In the late 1990s John helped to write the National
Pediatric Nurse Practitioner Exam in Washington D.C several years
running. More recently he was invited to Washington D.C. by a
government psychiatrist and consulted with this man on the development
of psychological profiles of moles (double agents). He also spoke
at a symposium at Princeton University entitled &amp;ldquo;Children under the
Shadow of War.&amp;rdquo; The group included scholars from around the world,
and filmmakers who had photographed kidnapped children who had been
conscripted into war and forced to commit atrocities. It was John&amp;rsquo;s
job to deliver the final speech, summarizing and tying together all
of the presentations. This was the only lecture open to the public.
John gave a moving presentation that left not a dry eye in the
audience. In the final months of his life, John continued to think
and write actively on a wide range of subjects. Most recently he
completed a 4th edition of Systemantics and contributed, with other
international scholars, to a book on Panarchy, due to be published
in 2015. John was preceded in death by his first wife, Beth, and
three step-grandsons, Michael Nelson, and Franklin and Alexander
Sawvel. His is survived by his wife, Carol, brothers Dr. Joseph
Gall (Diane Dwyer) and Howard, sons Duane (Valerie) and David
(Suzette), step-sons Steven (Sarah) and Terrell (Eleanor) Nelson,
and grandchildren Izzie, Nathan, Sebastian, and Simone, plus
step-grandchildren Anthony, Cody, Alaya, Nicole, and Branden Nelson.
A private family ceremony will be held in the Episcopal Church in
Upperville, VA, in the late spring.  -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more at:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=173778701#sthash.HpdH8buv.dpuf&#34;&gt;http://obits.mlive.com/obituaries/annarbor/obituary.aspx?pid=173778701#sthash.HpdH8buv.dpuf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>