<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker Raspberry Pi on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/docker-raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker Raspberry Pi on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:50:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/docker-raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 1.7.0 issues: problems with Mac and boot2docker, ARM, Ubuntu, and disk size of images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-26-docker-170-issues-problems-with-mac-and-boot2docker-arm-and-disk-size-of-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:50:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-26-docker-170-issues-problems-with-mac-and-boot2docker-arm-and-disk-size-of-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker 1.7.0 has been released into the wild. Every .0 release of software should be expected to have some issues, no matter how good the QA and automated test process. Here&#39;s what to expect if you&#39;re getting Docker 1.7.0 up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;boot2docker on Mac&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Mac, with boot2docker: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boot2docker/boot2docker/issues/938&#34;&gt;Docker certs not valid with 1.7 upgrade&lt;/a&gt; is issue 938 on boot2docker. The symptom is a message like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An error occurred trying to connect: Get https://192.168.59.103:2376/v1.19/containers/json: x509: certificate is valid for 127.0.0.1, 10.0.2.15, not 192.168.59.103&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and restarting docker on the VM with &lt;code&gt;boot2docker ssh sudo /etc/init.d/docker restart&lt;/code&gt; fixes it, at least temporarily. Read through the issue on github to see the full diagnosis - as best I understand it, eth1 is not up when certificates are generated, hence the cert not valid error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Raspberry Pi or any other ARM system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a Raspberry Pi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14184&#34;&gt;Docker 1.7 on RaspberryPI : &#34;socket operation on non-socket&#34;&lt;/a&gt; is issue 14184 on docker. The symptom is a message like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[tki@anzu ~]$ docker start redis
  Error response from daemon: Cannot start container redis: socket operation on non-socket
  Error: failed to start containers: [redis]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The error flushed out a whole set of people running Docker on ARM on a variety of platforms, all having similar issues. If you&#39;re running a Scaleway C1, ODROID C1, ODROID XU3-Lite, Utilite Pro, Cubox 4x4, and all flavors of Raspberry Pi or Pi 2 you&#39;ll see this. &#34;When using --net host the container starts&#34; is the report, but port forwarding fails to work in that case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ubuntu: problems with statically compiled Docker binaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14035&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 15.04 vivid can not start docker 1.7.0&lt;/a&gt;, docker issue 14035. The relevant bits of the error message are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ERRO[0000] Udev sync is not supported. This will lead to unexpected behavior, data loss and errors. For more information, see https://docs.docker.com/reference/commandline/cli/#daemon-storage-driver-option &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;ERRO[0000] [graphdriver] prior storage driver &#34;devicemapper&#34; failed: driver not supported &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;FATA[0000] Error starting daemon: error initializing graphdriver: driver not supported &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a long discussion, culminating in &lt;code&gt;In the end, removing /var/lib/docker/devicemapper/ will fix the issue&lt;/code&gt;, but people are also rolling back to 1.6.2. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ubuntu on x86: large file sizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report that &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.docker.com/t/docker-1-7-0-is-using-huge-amount-of-disk-space/2046&#34;&gt;Docker 1.7.0 is using huge amounts of disk space&lt;/a&gt; appears on the Docker forum, item 2046. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/docker/issues/14204&#34;&gt;Pulling image fills disk/image size is huge, version 1.7.0&lt;/a&gt; is issue 14204 on Docker. Not much insight into this one yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a few notes from Dockercon 2015, as seen via Twitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-24-a-few-notes-from-dockercon-2015-as-seen-via-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 13:27:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-06-24-a-few-notes-from-dockercon-2015-as-seen-via-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The annual conference for Docker, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;Dockercon&lt;/a&gt;, has been going on. A few highlights from the event as seen through Twitter - I was not there to attend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker is real on the Raspberry Pi through support for the ARM processor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Awesome live demo of Docker on a Raspberry Pi by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Quintus23M&#34;&gt;@Quintus23M&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dockercon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#dockercon&lt;/a&gt; closing keynote. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/DJfBtpcYws&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DJfBtpcYws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bridget Kromhout (@bridgetkromhout) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bridgetkromhout/status/613495958089785344&#34;&gt;June 23, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details from the presenter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/dockercon2015/&#34;&gt;Hypriot-Demo and challenge at DockerCon 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker&#39;s plumbing is being spun out as &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.docker.com/2015/06/runc/&#34;&gt;runC&lt;/a&gt;. The new infrastructure supports migration of containers from one server to another, illustrated through a Quake III demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;QuakeIII in a container, migrated seamlessly from Singapore to Amsterdam to London using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/runc?src=hash&#34;&gt;#runc&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dockercon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#dockercon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/no3c0G1MDY&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/no3c0G1MDY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Paul V. Novarese (@pvnovarese) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pvnovarese/status/613499654219526144&#34;&gt;June 24, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more highlights, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2015/06/22/everything-announced-at-dockercon-2015/&#34;&gt;Venturebeat roundup of Dockercon 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Node-RED on a Raspberry Pi with Docker and Hypriot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 02:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/2015-05-23-running-node-red-on-a-raspberry-pi-with-docker-and-hypriot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal for the week was to empty out my inbox sufficiently that I would be able to make progress on some programming tasks that are hard to do when there&#39;s distractions. The inbox got all the way down to zero, and that meant that there was a chunk of evening time suitable for hacking. Happy to report that the result of this is Node-RED running on a Raspberry Pi under Docker on top of Hypriot. A word of explanation of how this all works in detail is too much, but here&#39;s where I got the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device/&#34;&gt;Hypriot&#39;s gettting started guide&lt;/a&gt; brings you up to speed on getting Docker running on your ARM device (e.g. your Raspberry Pi). They have bootable images that you can download and burn to SD card, and from there you load up applications from Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypriot has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/hypriot/talk&#34;&gt;chat window&lt;/a&gt; on Gitter, so you can pop in and there will be occasionally people to assist. Best to do things European time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/&#34;&gt;DockerHub&lt;/a&gt; is a one stop shop for packaged applications. When you&#39;re running on the Pi, you&#39;ll want to seek out versions with &#39;rpi&#39; or &#39;arm&#39; in their names as they have likely been adapted for that system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up pulling Niel Eyde&#39;s Raspberry Pi versions of Node-RED from DockerHub as &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/u/nieleyde/rpi-nodered/&#34;&gt;nieleyde/rpi-nodered&lt;/a&gt;. It has all sorts of interesting modules that I had not previously built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is at 0.10.6 at this writing. Its &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodered.org/docs/hardware/raspberrypi.html&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi support&lt;/a&gt; includes hardware support using &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiringpi.com/&#34;&gt;WiringPi&lt;/a&gt; to access the GPIO pins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node-RED currently supports Node.JS 0.10. Node.JS and IO.JS have &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdtimes.com/node-js-and-io-js-to-merge-under-node-js-foundation/&#34;&gt;merged forces&lt;/a&gt; after a fork, which means hopefully development will start to be sane again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all said I am not sure I have everything I need yet but as a leap forward it&#39;s pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>