<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bo Biafra on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bo-biafra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bo Biafra on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:59:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/bo-biafra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unrest in the streets of Columbus and East Lansing after Michigan State beats Ohio State to win Big 10 football</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-unrest-in-the-streets-of-columbus-and-east-lansing-after-michigan-state-beats-ohio-state-to-win-big-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-12-08-unrest-in-the-streets-of-columbus-and-east-lansing-after-michigan-state-beats-ohio-state-to-win-big-/</guid>
      <description>Both Columbus, Ohio and East Lansing, Michigan are reporting unrest in the streets after the football victory by the Spartans over the Buckeyes.
To listen in:
 Columbus Ohio Police Dispatch Ingham County Michigan Public Safety  I&#39;m looking for news stories from both areas. Twitter is moving fastest; it&#39;s hard to tell stories straight from the scanner.
East Lansing From East Lansing, a series of couch fires, reported on by the State News and the Detroit News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bo Biafra: &#34;the invisible paw of the International Wolverine Conspiracy has taken down Tressel&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-30-tressel-dead-schembechlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 21:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-30-tressel-dead-schembechlers/</guid>
      <description>The Columbus Dispatch broke the news this morning that Jim Tressel has resigned as head football coach at Ohio State University. A Sports Illustrated cover story details troubles with Tressel&amp;#39;s leadership of the program, culminating in an NCAA investigation.
For balanced reporting from Columbus about the football program I always turn to Bo Biafra, front man for the Columbus based punk band the Dead Schembechlers. Biafra knows the story with the Wolverines; it&amp;#39;s best to have a &amp;quot;holy rivalry&amp;quot; with Michigan, and thus every problem in Columbus with the program gets blamed on the &amp;quot;New Wolverine Order&amp;quot;, the &amp;quot;International Wolverine Conspiracy&amp;quot;, or the &amp;quot;Mainstream Michigan Media&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>