<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About This Weblog on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/about-this-weblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About This Weblog on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:26:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/about-this-weblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The next major change for this weblog is converting over comments to Disqus</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-the-next-major-change-for-this-weblog-is-converting-over-comments-to-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-21-the-next-major-change-for-this-weblog-is-converting-over-comments-to-disqus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not ready to take it on yet, but my next plan here is to port
the 2000+ comments that I have on this blog over to Disqus, and
start using that instead of Typepad Comments. Expect that to happen
in the next month or so. I think all I need is a practice session on
a small blog to make sure I get the steps right, and a fast network
connection to make sure the switch happens quickly when I upload the 
new comment stream into Disqus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I understand it it&#39;s a one-way switch with no turning back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://help.typepad.com/disqus.html&#34;&gt;Setting Up Disqus Commenting&lt;/a&gt; is the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new responsive design for this weblog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-20-a-new-responsive-design-for-this-weblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 22:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-03-20-a-new-responsive-design-for-this-weblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the good folks at Typepad, I now have a
responsive design for this blog. Their new &#34;Snap&#34;
theme gives you one design that works well on devices
of various sizes. I&#39;m liking it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing that I want to tweak is the design of
the &#34;blockquote&#34; font size and weight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Blockquote is here in bold, whereas I&#39;d prefer to make
  it quite a bit less bold since I don&#39;t use it so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A somewhat trickier problem is that I&#39;m using &#34;Markdown&#34;
as my composition tool within Typepad instead of HTML,
and that works only somewhat well with the new automated
summary system. If I use Markdown punctuation in the first
paragraph or so of the text it shows up as punctuation rather
than HTML rendered text in the summary body on the home page.
That&#39;s a minor enough issue and one easy enough to fix if I
had to that I&#39;m letting that slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://everything.typepad.com/blog/2014/03/new-for-beta-users-a-responsive-design.html&#34;&gt;Snap responsive theme&lt;/a&gt; announcement on Typepad.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>