<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/aventura/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/aventura/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2015 food inspections for Washtenaw County</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-22-august-2015-food-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-22-august-2015-food-inspections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every month the Washtenaw County Health Department releases reports from a previous month&amp;rsquo;s
inspections of restaurants in the county. Restaurants are typically inspected twice a year.
The inspector looks to see that the state Food Code is enforced, with a particular eye
towards identifying violations that result in increased risk to the public of food-borne illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayne Eaker has put together a searchable and browsable database of these inspections,
which is online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&#34;&gt;food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com&lt;/a&gt; . Here are some highlights
and lowlights from the August 2015 report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 restaurants and food service establishments had &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/?f[0]=field_inspection_date%3A2015&amp;amp;f[1]=field_inspection_date%3A2015-08&amp;amp;f[2]=field_count_total%3A%5B0%20TO%200%5D&#34;&gt;zero violations in August 2015&lt;/a&gt;. Among those perfect scores:
Zingerman&amp;rsquo;s Next Door, Earthen Jar, BTB Cantina on South U,
Little Porky&amp;rsquo;s in Whitmore Lake, World of Beers,
Classic Pizza in Dexter, and Sweetwaters on Plymouth Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yee Siang Dumplings at 4837 Washtenaw received
a total of 17 violations.
At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-08-21-yee-siang-dumplings&#34;&gt;August 21, 2015 inspection&lt;/a&gt;
the issues identifed included
&amp;ldquo;unsafe cooling methods&amp;rdquo;,
a dirty meat slicer and meat grinder,
and no soap at the rear employee hand sink.
&amp;ldquo;NO ONE IN THIS STORE HAS ANY KNOWLEDGE OF FOOD SAFETY AND HOW TO IMPLEMENT THE FOOD CODE IN THEIR OPERATION.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony Sacco&amp;rsquo;s on W Eisenhower Pkwy
had 19 violations
in their &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-08-05-tony-saccos&#34;&gt;August 5, 2015 inspection&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;ldquo;OBSERVED LIVE ANTS AND NUMEROUS SMALL FLIES IN THE AREAS SURROUNDING THE FLOOR DRAIN IN THE WAITSTATION.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grange Kitchen and Bar was dinged for
&amp;ldquo;OBSERVED UNLABELED MASON JARS OF DUCK BLOOD IN CHEST FREEZER IN KITCHEN.&amp;rdquo;
Their &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-08-27-grange-kitchen-bar&#34;&gt;August 27, 2015 inspection&lt;/a&gt;
recorded a total of 8 violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aventura at 216 East Washington received a total of 7 violations
in their &lt;a href=&#34;http://food-inspections.annarbortelegraph.com/2015-08-18-aventura&#34;&gt;August 18, 2015 inspection&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;ldquo;OBSERVED SEVERAL EMPLOYEES IN BAR AREA HANDLE RTE FOOD WITH BARE HANDS&amp;rdquo; was noted, as well as
a practice of re-labeling datemarked foods to extend their shelf life.
&amp;ldquo;EMPLOYEE STATED THAT IT IS COMMON PRACTICE FOR KITCHEN STAFF TO SMELL OR TASTE FOOD PRODUCTS WHEN THEY ARE ON THEIR LAST DAY OF SALE AND RE-DATE FOOD FOR ANOTHER 5 DAYS IF THEY THINK THE FOOD IS STILL GOOD. THIS PRACTICE MUST BE CEASED IMMEDIATELY.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the whole list and see how your favorites did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>