<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How To on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How To on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 22:42:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to mount your smart phone on a tripod, by Roger Rayle</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-23-how-to-mount-your-smart-phone-on-a-tripod-by-roger-rayle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 22:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-23-how-to-mount-your-smart-phone-on-a-tripod-by-roger-rayle/</guid>
      <description>Roger Rayle (@wguru) gets the credit for this slide deck, which shows you how to adapt an automotive aftermarket phone mount as a holder for that phone in a tripod.
  Tripod Mount for Smart Phone  from wguru</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing machine has a hose leak? How to repair it.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</guid>
      <description>There are a couple of good sites for information about do-it-yourself washing machine repair. Ours had a leak, which I think I traced to a tiny hole in the low-pressure drain hose that was fixable with a pipe tape that the good folks at Stadium Hardware helped me find. Let&amp;#39;s hope the repair holds!
I used the Family Handyman&amp;#39;s How To Repair a Leaking Washing Machine&amp;#0160;as my guide. The pinhole sized leak was in the middle of the low-pressure drain hose, where a rusty piece of bracket had wedged itself against the hose and slowly caused it to get a pinhole sized hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link blogging, from pinboard?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-07-link-blogging-from-pinboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 16:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-01-07-link-blogging-from-pinboard/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time this blog featured (?) a daily link dump from delicious. It was completely automated, so that once a day something got dumped in. I don&amp;#39;t know if anyone read it except search engines, but it was a handy way to replicate some content.
There must be a way to do this from pinboard, which is what I am using now, but I don&amp;#39;t see a one-click from the pinboard FAQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emptying out my inbox into my blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-21-emptying-out-my-inbox-into-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 23:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-12-21-emptying-out-my-inbox-into-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>Every so often the inbox is full and the blog is empty; this is an attempt to remedy that.
How to do an introduction online.&amp;#0160; X, meet Y; Y, meet X.&amp;#0160; X is notable for a1, a2, a3; Y is notable for b1, b2, b3.&amp;#0160; You have a mutual interest in c1, c2, c3; you should connect.&amp;#0160; There are several of those pending.
How to make the best of not responding to mail promptly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do before you lose your wallet</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-30-what-to-do-befo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-30-what-to-do-befo/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Be prepared.&#34;
from &#39;bill says this&#39;:

But here&#39;s some critical information to limit the damage in case this happens to you or someone you know. As everyone always advises, cancel your credit cards immediately, but the key is having the toll free numbers and your card numbers handy so you know whom to call. Keep those where you can find them easily. File a police report immediately in the jurisdiction where it was stolen, this proves to credit providers you were diligent, and is a first step toward an investigation (if there ever is one).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>