<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ann Arbor Food And Drink Sandwiches on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-food-and-drink-sandwiches/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ann Arbor Food And Drink Sandwiches on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 13:35:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/ann-arbor-food-and-drink-sandwiches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this blog</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 13:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-04-there-is-a-serious-lack-of-sandwich-reporting-on-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And, if I am able to rectify the situation, I will &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarbor.com/business-review/long-awaited-subway-on-the-corner-of-packard-and-platt-opens/?cmpid=NL_DH_topicbox_headline&#34;&gt;share my profits with Jordan Miller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I agree! There is a serious lack of sandwich reporting on this website. I, for one, love sandwiches. What if all the pet stories were sandwich stories instead? Everyone isn&#39;t into pets, but who doesn&#39;t like sandwiches? Not anyone I want living in my town. PS if [redacted] puts this advice into action, I expect a share of what is sure to be a tremendous surge in profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For who does not love sandwiches? They are compact, and amiable, and easy to pack for lunch. If you have a generous lunch budget, you have have someone else make you a sandwich of wide variety on the spot and enjoy it at your leisure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous sandwich coverage here and elsewhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/eat-well-at-any-deli-by-making-your-own-sandwich-1/&#34;&gt;Eat well at any deli by making your own sandwich&lt;/a&gt;, written for AnnArbor.com; please excuse the random punctuation marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annarbor.com/vielmetti/monday-lunch-links-fried-egg-sandwich/&#34;&gt;Fried egg sandwich&lt;/a&gt;, also written for AnnArbor.com; please excuse the lack of photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2011/06/lack-of-discretion-is-the-better-part-of-twitter.html&#34;&gt;Lack of discretion is the better part of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, on this blog: &#34;Your indiscretions make up for the rest of us who are content to describe where we are eating a sandwich.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>