<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Urban Chickens on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/urban-chickens/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Urban Chickens on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 20:46:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/urban-chickens/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban chicken rescue for the Minneapolis, MN area</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-21-urban-chicken-rescue-for-the-minneapolis-mn-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 20:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-21-urban-chicken-rescue-for-the-minneapolis-mn-area/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about the practice of keeping urban chickens. Inevitably some of those chickens will be abandoned by their owners. To the rescue: Chicken Run Rescue (&amp;ldquo;Foster Care for Fowl&amp;rdquo;) of Minneapolis, MN, which will take in forelorn fowl and place them in new homes.
This 2009 video is from Minnesota Public Radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban chickens in Grand Rapids, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-16-urban-chickens-in-grand-rapids-mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-16-urban-chickens-in-grand-rapids-mi/</guid>
      <description>The Michigan Radio account&amp;#0160;details the opposition:  But not everyone agrees. A representative of large scale chicken farms has warned the city of the risk of disease. And the Kent County Health Department also opposes backyard chickens.  The Editorial from the Grand Rapids Press is careful not to take a side on the question.
 Grand Rapids is considering joining the trend. The city’s proposal will be up for a public hearing July 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lost chicken hatcheries of Iowa City, IA</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-14-the-lost-chicken-hatcheries-of-iowa-city-ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 10:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-07-14-the-lost-chicken-hatcheries-of-iowa-city-ia/</guid>
      <description>Copied in its entirety from the Iowa, City IA city government web page in their &#34;Public Art&#34; section.
King-Littrell-Palmer Chicken Hatchery
Irving King, head of the University of Iowa Department of Literature, had an unusual sideline for an English professor: raising chickens. In 1918, King started a hatchery as a hobby on the south side of Jackson Avenue. Eventually, the hatchery occupied several wood structures from Sheridan Avenue to Ralston Creek between the alley and Rundell Street.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>