<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Waffle on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/waffle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Waffle on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 23:55:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/waffle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Github Issues and Waffle.io as a personal kanban board</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-github-waffle-kanban-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 23:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-22-github-waffle-kanban-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Github issues to track my personal todo list for quite some
time now, and since November I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Waffle.io to help that process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waffle in this use is a view of a series of queues in my todo list. Most everything
that I&amp;rsquo;m not doing now lives in the &amp;ldquo;backlog&amp;rdquo; queue, which I try to keep to
less than 100 just to keep myself sane. (At more than 100 there&amp;rsquo;s usually a lot
of duplicates; at less than 100 I&amp;rsquo;m probably not acknowledging that there&amp;rsquo;s
something to be done). The &amp;ldquo;Ready&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;In Progress&amp;rdquo; queues hold no more than
5 tasks apiece, since I want to keep everything in that state visible on
the screen. Finally the &amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo; queue reflects how much work there is that
actually got accomplished over the last week, and I&amp;rsquo;d love to say that was
hovering at about 50 tasks a week though right now it&amp;rsquo;s only at 34.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github issues are more than capable of handling a personal todo list - indeed
it has a lot of features that if you tried to use all of them you&amp;rsquo;d quickly
find that too much of your time was perfecting your lists and not enough
time was spent doing things. So the challenge is coming up with a simple
configuration of the system that doesn&amp;rsquo;t ignore what might be done, but that
focuses on what really needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspriation for all of this is Jim Benson&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Personal Kanban&amp;rdquo;, and his
observation that really the task simplifies down to two rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit work in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is merely commentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Now I get to drag task 3568, &amp;ldquo;Write up use of Waffle for Vacuum blog&amp;rdquo;, into the
&amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo; category, which is kinetically very satisfactory.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github-based kanban boards: Zenhub, Waffle, Huboard, Blossom et al</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-24-github-based-kanban-boards-zenhub-waffle-huboard-blossom-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-24-github-based-kanban-boards-zenhub-waffle-huboard-blossom-et-al/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A kanban board is simply a two-dimensional view of a series of work queues.
By moving a piece of work from one column to another, you update its status.
This gives you a quick way to visualize your current priorities, as well
as making it very clear when one or more of your queues are too full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using Github issues as a personal issue tracker for a while,
using its milestones feature to track categories. This has been mostly
a one-dimensional exercise of managing very long lists, or shorter lists.
It&#39;s been cumbersome to use either labels or milestones to handle the quick
need to say to yourself &#34;I&#39;m going to focus on this now&#34; without the issue
sinking back quickly into a mile-long undifferentiated list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter a whole series of Github add-ons that all add a similar feature, the kanban-style
column view. I&#39;ll list them here with any experience I currently have using
them. My best bet is that at some point Github absorbs one of these and makes 
it its own, but that is tempered by the realization that Github issues really
isn&#39;t changing much as a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zenhub, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zenhub.io/&#34;&gt;zenhub.io&lt;/a&gt;. This is a Google Chrome plugin, which gives you a kanban-style view of your issues. It only works in Chrome. I tried it, but didn&#39;t see an easy way to configure which columns referred to which labels, and after a few tries gave up on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waffle, &lt;a href=&#34;https://waffle.io/&#34;&gt;waffle.io&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment this is what I&#39;m using. You authenticate to it with Github, and then it displays your issues. Free (for now), they are advertising that it will be $7/mo for private repos, which is what I currently pay for all of the rest of Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huboard, &lt;a href=&#34;https://huboard.com&#34;&gt;huboard.com&lt;/a&gt;. Free for open source repos or $7/mo/user for private repos. 14 day free trial. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blossom, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blossom.io&#34;&gt;blossom.io&lt;/a&gt;. No free plan, 14 day trial, minimum is a 5 user plan at $22/mo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Task Tub, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tasktub.com/&#34;&gt;tasktub.com&lt;/a&gt;. Company page does not load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SweepBoard, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sweepboard.com/&#34;&gt;sweepboard.com&lt;/a&gt;. Free for open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started finding these sorts of things, I didn&#39;t really realize that it was a whole category of products. Most of them have some other features beyond the kanban to add to Github as a project management tool. I don&#39;t think there&#39;s a category winner, but if you are interested in visualizing your work and taking your todo list beyond the simple long list this is a useful set of tools to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>