<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Kaminski on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-kaminski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peter Kaminski on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 12:23:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-kaminski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquity, focus, and isolation as success factors for Internet socialiability</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-27-ubiquity-focus-and-isolation-as-success-factors-for-internet-socialiability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 12:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-27-ubiquity-focus-and-isolation-as-success-factors-for-internet-socialiability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Pete Kaminski suggests (on a private &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com&#34; rel=&#34;homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Facebook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; forum) that there are two reasons that Facebook has taken a big chunk of our online social time - &amp;quot;ubiquity&amp;quot;, which is the character of providing global communications at scale, and &amp;quot;focus&amp;quot;, which is the ability to narrow your personal interest discussions down to a small set of topics. For all of its other charms, Facebook provides both of those, imperfectly of course but well enough that it can serve as a does-everything social platform for lots of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to ubiquity and focus, I&amp;#39;d like to suggest a third axis of utility for social media - &amp;quot;isolation&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;s the notion that you can go somewhere online and do something special that&amp;#39;s unlike anything else on the net, and that because of this the rules that have accreted over time about expected behavior are different.&lt;br id=&#34;.reactRoot[217].[1][2][1]{comment575633445785640_575968315752153}.0.[1].0.[1].0.[0].[0][2].0.[1]&#34; /&gt;&lt;br id=&#34;.reactRoot[217].[1][2][1]{comment575633445785640_575968315752153}.0.[1].0.[1].0.[0].[0][2].0.[2]&#34; /&gt;As an example, I have an account on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinterest.com/&#34; rel=&#34;homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Pinterest&#34;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; that I use nearly exclusively for collecting maps. I don&amp;#39;t follow all of my friends there, and I don&amp;#39;t expect that people will follow me just because they are my friends. Similarly, a few friends have Plurk accounts in a little circle where no one expects that anyone else will read what they write and where there is a decided element of silliness that would not play on Facebook.&lt;br id=&#34;.reactRoot[217].[1][2][1]{comment575633445785640_575968315752153}.0.[1].0.[1].0.[0].[0][2].0.[4]&#34; /&gt;&lt;br id=&#34;.reactRoot[217].[1][2][1]{comment575633445785640_575968315752153}.0.[1].0.[1].0.[0].[0][2].0.[5]&#34; /&gt;I think we all need a little corner of the net to call our own. Facebook ranks very low on the isolation scale and so it will not appeal to those who are looking for a quiet corner to express themselves. A lightly trafficked wiki, your own blog, or the carefully walled off corner of an interest-specific forum can all have that isolation factor that lets us be sociable but not to the entire world all at once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>