<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Kaminski on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-kaminski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peter Kaminski on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 12:23:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/peter-kaminski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquity, focus, and isolation as success factors for Internet socialiability</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-27-ubiquity-focus-and-isolation-as-success-factors-for-internet-socialiability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 12:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-27-ubiquity-focus-and-isolation-as-success-factors-for-internet-socialiability/</guid>
      <description>My friend Pete Kaminski suggests (on a private Facebook forum) that there are two reasons that Facebook has taken a big chunk of our online social time - &amp;quot;ubiquity&amp;quot;, which is the character of providing global communications at scale, and &amp;quot;focus&amp;quot;, which is the ability to narrow your personal interest discussions down to a small set of topics. For all of its other charms, Facebook provides both of those, imperfectly of course but well enough that it can serve as a does-everything social platform for lots of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknowledge management</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-10-unknowledge-management/</guid>
      <description>From The Unknowledge Pattern Language, on Nooron:
 Unknowledge Patterns describe ways of talking about that which is unknown. For example, the discovery of the periodic table of the elements created a pattern of information about what we didn&amp;#39;t know about the elements, until we &amp;quot;filled in the blanks.&amp;quot; These &amp;quot;named voids&amp;quot; in our knowledge were powerful attractors, and shaped the discourse of science. Are there other ways of naming voids which shape our discovery?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>