<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 22:31:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How did I meet you? How do I know you?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-how-did-i-meet-you-how-do-i-know-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 22:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-08-how-did-i-meet-you-how-do-i-know-you/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve been thinking a lot about how I keep track of people who I&amp;#39;ve met over the years. Systems like Facebook try to do that for you (hey! you&amp;#39;re friends with!) but they neglect to capture some critical information.
The most salient points for me about connecting or reconnecting with someone usually revolve around the circumstances of how we first met, the reasons that there&amp;#39;s still some ongoing connection, and the particular details of the last meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mental rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 21:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a great use of the term in an LA Magazine review of &amp;quot;Run Lola Run&amp;quot;:
Lola tosses her red phone up in the air and instantly goes through her mental Rolodex of possibilities. Faces flash on the screen. She decides to hit up her banker father and darts out of the house. Credits: the &amp;quot;mental rolodex&amp;quot; term is one I heard first from&amp;#0160;Terry Bean, who used it at an LA2M presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>supermemo and morning coffee ritual memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</guid>
      <description>An important piece of having coffee in the morning is making it part of a routine. If you&#39;re predictable in your habits, you start to see the same people in the same space at the same time, and you get to be something of a regular.
If you&#39;re careful, and switch your morning allegiances from time to time but still visit the old haunts often enough, you can be what passes for a regular long after you stopped coming every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>