<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sdr on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/sdr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sdr on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/sdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SDR.HU to listen to AM radio sports</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-23-sdr-hu-am-dx-baseball-and-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-23-sdr-hu-am-dx-baseball-and-football/</guid>
      <description>The Cubs won the pennant, and the Buckeyes lost to Penn State. I was able to listen to the radio calls of both of these through recievers connected to sdr.hu.
The Cubs radio call was from WMVP-AM, ESPN Chicago 1000. I had some practice listening to them through the Farmington Hills, MI SDR run by KB8SPI. That system is a KiwiSDR with a PA0RDT Mini-Whip, and it tunes from 0-30 Mhz including all of the longwave (broadcast AM) band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sdr.hu and the emergence of lots of small wideband SDR receivers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-sdr-hu-small-public-sdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-10-sdr-hu-small-public-sdr/</guid>
      <description>sdr.hu is the home base for OpenWebRX, a remote spectrum monitoring system written by Andras HA7ILM.
The system is designed to allow OpenWebRX servers, running on RTL-SDR or HackRF hardware, to share their radio spectrum and allow remote tuning of the available radio bandwidth. A typical installation will allow up to four remote listeners to independently tune in, and the tuning filters allow the listener to independently control the bandwidth of the receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area APRS network status, January 2016</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-14-aprs-network-status/</guid>
      <description>APRS is the &amp;ldquo;Automatic Position Reporting Service&amp;rdquo;, a system for sharing information about the position of participating amateur radio stations. Clients transmit position reports on 144.39 Mhz; digipeaters repeat these reports to other monitoring stations; and various IGate sites monitor transmissions and send their findings to aprs.fi which collects worldwide data.
In recent memory there has been an APRS digipeater in Chelsea, Michigan with wide area coverage, good enough to pick up travellers on I-94 west of Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave New N8SBE to speak at ARROW on Software Defined Radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-01-13-dave-new-n8sbe-sdr-at-arrow/</guid>
      <description>Dave New N8SBE will be speaking at the January 2016 meeting of the ARROW radio club on the topic of Software Defined Radio.
He will present an introduction to GNU Radio and the GNU Radio Companion visual programming environment, and the HackRF One Software Defined Transceiver from Great Scott Gadgets.
The demo will include a disucssion of receiver and transmitter flow graphs, as well as resources to learn more about digital signal processing using the HackRF One and GNU Radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CubicSDR, a cross-platform software defined radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-30-cubicsdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 17:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-30-cubicsdr/</guid>
      <description>CubicSDR is a software defined radio system for Mac, Linux, and Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s at version 0.1.4-beta as of August 28, 2015, and you can download the binaries from https://github.com/cjcliffe/CubicSDR/releases/tag/0.1.4 or the source code from Github at https://github.com/cjcliffe/CubicSDR .
My point of comparison for software defined radio is GQRX. When you put CubicSDR on the screen it has a very pretty waterfall display and relatively easy to sort out mouse commands, but it&amp;rsquo;s lacking some of the fancier controls that a more mature program like GQRX has accumulated over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sudo port upgrade outdated</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-30-sudo-port-upgrade-outdated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-30-sudo-port-upgrade-outdated/</guid>
      <description>Macports is a system for bringing 3d party software to the Mac under some kind of organized control. Rather than randomly downloading binaries or sources, you pick from a wide variety of software that&amp;rsquo;s already been ported with all of its dependencies carefully noted.
The process of bringing lots of software online inevitably means that when one system gets updated there are ripple effects up the stack until the software you had been using stops working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Radio Havana Cuba via a shortwave software defined radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-radio-havana-cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 22:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-24-radio-havana-cuba/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m listening to Radio Havana Cuba via a shortwave listening post set up with a software defined radio. The system, Great Lakes Listening Post, has four separate radios covering the 80, 40, 30, and 20 meter bands, all fed into the WebSDR software from PA3FWM. It&amp;rsquo;s located in Michigan, and thus approximates the radio reception I&amp;rsquo;d get from my own receiver.
R Havana Cuba is a good station to listen to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a dipole antenna for your SDR tuner stick from an old set of headphones</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:50:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-05-29-building-a-dipole-antenna-for-your-sdr-tuner-stick-from-an-old-set-of-headphones/</guid>
      <description>Some notes before I try to do the build.
The parts I have or know I can get: cheap earbud headphones, NooElec NESDR Mini 2 SDR tuner stick with whip antenna, Nokia 635 phone, antenna from an older NESDR Mini SDR tuner stick.
Parts I need: a short adapter cable that provides antenna in for the SDR stick as a headphone jack socket.
The SDR tuner comes with an antenna, but I want to replace it with a dipole - especially one cut to have a center point for FM broadcast on 88.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plane spotting; some quick notes on a new software-defined radio setup</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 18:50:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-03-30-plane-spotting-some-quick-notes-on-a-new-software-defined-radio-setup/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years ago, I got one of the first-generation RTL-SDR USB software defined radio units. These inexpensive devices are originally designed as TV tuners, but clever radio hackers figured out how to turn them into software-defined radios that tune to a broad spectrum of radio.
After some experimental use I managed to cook the original unit which in its death throes no longer listened. The vendor (Nooelec) generously offered a modest discount on my next purchase, so I took them up on the 2d generation unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>decoding radio digital modes without a radio, using WebSDR and fldigi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 02:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-09-decoding-radio-digital-modes-without-a-radio-using-websdr-and-fldigi/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in decoding radio digital modes without actually having a radio. The idea is that by using a web-based software defined radio (to tune in the signals) and the fldigi program (to decode the signals) that I should be able to &amp;ldquo;listen&amp;rdquo; to digital modes and start to explore the digital parts of the amateur and broadcast radio bands.

I think I have all of the components, but I have yet to be able to get everything to work as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the W8UM net looks like in software defined radio</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-what-the-w8um-net-looks-like-in-software-defined-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-02-what-the-w8um-net-looks-like-in-software-defined-radio/</guid>
      <description>A sample screen grab from tonight&amp;#39;s W8UM net on 145.23. Please note that the radio I&amp;#39;m using looks like it&amp;#39;s out of tune a little bit, since I&amp;#39;m actually listening here on 145.217.
 
It was a good clear strong signal (the red/yellow line), even with the not very good antenna I have; it should be, since the transmitter is only about a mile from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software defined radio (SDR) for Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-20-software-defined-radio-sdr-for-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 23:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-04-20-software-defined-radio-sdr-for-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;ve started looking into software defined radio for Mac OS X. The goal is to take a cheap USB stick, plug it in to the Mac, and have it connect to software that will decode radio signals.
So far there&amp;#39;s nothing obvious that&amp;#39;s packaged as a single collection of software plus hardware, but that&amp;#39;s not surprising.
My best notes to date are from Pinboard&amp;#39;s t:sdr tag, which looks like it has a few dozen people sharing links.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>