<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Cisler on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/steve-cisler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steve Cisler on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 23:52:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/steve-cisler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking inventory of old Github projects</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-12-taking-inventory-of-old-github-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 23:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-12-taking-inventory-of-old-github-projects/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Octopress has given me a chance to look through some of my old Github repositories and re-assess what&#39;s there and how to improve on them. This is more like a wish list than an actual set of directions, and it reflects how much the world has moved since I first signed up for a github account.
 aadl-amazon-linky and superpatron. Both of these are interfaces to the Ann Arbor District Library catalog, which has a very accessible programming interface with things like RSS feeds for catalog searches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year without the internet (as suggested by my son)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-20-my-year-without-the-internet-as-suggested-by-my-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 20:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-10-20-my-year-without-the-internet-as-suggested-by-my-son/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;When you retire,&amp;quot; he says, &amp;quot;you should go offline for a whole year.&amp;quot;
The idea is to sell all of your computers, turn in your cell phone, and generally shun any computer technology. Perhaps you&amp;#39;ll still write, but it will be longhand or on a typewriter. If there&amp;#39;s a phone call to be made, you&amp;#39;ll have to be there to receive it, since there is no answering machine. No Twitter, no Facebook, no blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>