<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Outages on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/power-outages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Outages on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 14:40:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/power-outages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating a power grid with RTDS</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-simulating-a-power-grid-with-rtds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 14:40:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-24-simulating-a-power-grid-with-rtds/</guid>
      <description>Noted as an example of &#34;how do they do that&#34;
 The RTDS simulates any user-defined electrical system with models of complex electrical components, such as transmission lines, generators and transformers. The components can be precisely defined to match your equipment characteristics. Through real-time simulation, your relay or control equipment is tested in closed-loop mode, acting on the simulated system as it would in the actual installation.
 Kinetrics has a page on RTDS describing how it&#39;s used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power outage map outage at Emera and Central Maine Power (Maine electrical utilities)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-power-outage-map-outage-at-emera-and-central-maine-power-maine-electrical-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 17:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-11-02-power-outage-map-outage-at-emera-and-central-maine-power-maine-electrical-utilities/</guid>
      <description>November 2, 2014, 5:04 p.m. EST (Ann Arbor, MI): The state of Maine is being hit by winter storms, with more than 1 inch an hour falling across parts of the state. This has led to widespread power outages, as well as outages of the power outage maps provided by Emera and by Central Maine Power, two utility companies that serve the state.

Emera&#39;s live outage map is throwing an error at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe storms of October 2, 2014 hit the Dallas-Fort Worth area; Oncor power outage map shows the storm track</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-severe-storms-of-october-2-2014-hit-the-dallas-fort-worth-area-oncor-power-outage-map-shows-the-stor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 09:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-10-03-severe-storms-of-october-2-2014-hit-the-dallas-fort-worth-area-oncor-power-outage-map-shows-the-stor/</guid>
      <description>The Dallas-Fort Worth area was hit by severe storms the evening of October 2, 2014. The Dallas Morning News live blog details the impact, with more than 250,000 people without power.
This outage map from about 7:00 p.m. that evening shows the extent of the damage.

My power outage tracker page is a good early warning of problems with the power grid. By looking at what web pages people are clicking through on, I can see where the troubles are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Components for a $100 solar charging system?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-06-components-for-a-100-solar-charging-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 14:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-09-06-components-for-a-100-solar-charging-system/</guid>
      <description>The challenge I put to myself is to spend not more than $100 and get a functioning solar powered charging station. The alternate name is a &#34;camping power supply&#34; for off-the-grid operations.
Breaking down the components it looks like this would be a combination of the following:
Solar panel. Estimate as a start that you want to generate 40 watts of power at peak times, using a panel that&#39;s small enough and portable enough that you can move it to where there&#39;s the best sun, but not necessarily so portable that you&#39;re carrying it with you in your backpack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 July 2014 Ann Arbor widespread power interruptions, 800 pm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-16-16-july-2014-ann-arbor-widespread-power-interruptions-800-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-07-16-16-july-2014-ann-arbor-widespread-power-interruptions-800-pm/</guid>
      <description>Multiple people around Ann Arbor Michigan reported power blips at about 8 pm Wednesday 16 July 2014. Detailed explanation of the incident is unavailable at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The internet of power outages</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-power-outages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 19:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-06-27-the-internet-of-power-outages/</guid>
      <description>The single most popular page on this web site is the power outage tracking map collection page. It has static copies of samples of power outage maps from utilities around the country, and it gets bunches of hits every single time there&#39;s bad weather - to the extent that I can pretty much tell where there&#39;s bad weather by the outbound clicks on the page.
The page, however, is not fed with live data; it only has static instances of previous maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sawnee EMC (north of Atlanta, GA) power outage map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-11-sawnee-emc-has-a-new-power-outage-map-including-a-map-optimized-for-mobile-access-sawnee-emc-serves-electrical-cust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 14:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-11-sawnee-emc-has-a-new-power-outage-map-including-a-map-optimized-for-mobile-access-sawnee-emc-serves-electrical-cust/</guid>
      <description>Sawnee EMC has a recently new power outage map, including a map optimized for mobile access. The press release they issued back in November 2013 has a lot more details.
Sawnee EMC serves electrical customers in portions of Forsyth, Fulton, Dawson, Lumpkin, Cherokee, Hall, &amp;amp; Gwinnett counties, in an area north of Atlanta, Georgia.

The Atlanta area is expecting severe weather and ice the week of February 12, 2014, according to the Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 5, 2014: Philadelphia area power outages due to ice storm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-05-february-5-2014-philadelphia-area-power-outages-due-to-ice-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-02-05-february-5-2014-philadelphia-area-power-outages-due-to-ice-storm/</guid>
      <description>February 5, 2014: More than 623,000 customers were without power in the service area covered by PECO (Philadelphia, PA area) at the peak of an ice storm on Wednesday. This is the second worst storm that the company has reported, right behind Hurricane Sandy.

The PECO power outage map does not go into lots of detail on the map, but it does list individual communities and their outage status in county by county detail pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many power outages are there in the nation?</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-08-how-many-power-outages-are-there-in-the-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-08-how-many-power-outages-are-there-in-the-nation/</guid>
      <description>The world of power outage maps is a very fragmented one, with what looks like dozens of designs and systems and no apparent standardization. There&#39;s no way that I know to get a USA-wide power outage map without going to all 50 states worth of utilities and piecing together incompatible maps. Some places - like Lansing, Michigan&#39;s BWL, don&#39;t have maps, making customer communication difficult.
If you can&#39;t map the whole nation, the next best thing is to count the number of outages nationwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor area closings for Monday, 18 November 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 09:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-11-18-ann-arbor-area-closings-for-monday-18-november-2013/</guid>
      <description>High winds took down trees and knocked out power to thousands in Washtenaw County the night of 17 November 2013, and the next morning a number of schools and government offices closed because of lack of power.
From various sources including email and twitter; this is surely incomplete.
Ann Arbor Public Schools: Tappan and King are closed today due to power outages at both schools. Tonight&#39;s Listen and Learn at Tappan will be rescheduled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power outage and explosions at U Cal Berkeley campus, 30 September 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-30-power-outage-and-explosions-at-u-cal-berkeley-campus-30-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 22:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-30-power-outage-and-explosions-at-u-cal-berkeley-campus-30-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>The Daily Cal reports that power went out on the U Cal Berkeley campus at 4:45 p.m. local time on 30 September 2013, and that subsequently an explosion on campus at about 6:40 p.m. injured an unknown number of people. The report includes a striking photo of a manhole on fire. The campus has been evacuated.
The Berkeley scanner has live audio from the area; at this writing, there were over 140 people monitoring it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro North power outage</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-09-27-metro-north-power-outage/</guid>
      <description>A power outage on a 138,000 volt line that provides power to Metro North trains in New York has snarled commutes from Connecticut to New York City and has also affected Amtrak service in the busy New York - Boston corridor. Work is underway to put in a temporary fix by diverting power from surrounding businesses and neighborhoods. A backup feeder line was offline, and full service restoration may take weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 years ago: the great blackout of 2003</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-10-years-ago-the-great-blackout-of-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 16:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-08-14-10-years-ago-the-great-blackout-of-2003/</guid>
      <description>Ten years ago, the power went out.
It&#39;s not unusual for the power to go out, but as always when it happens, you wonder if it&#39;s just you or if it&#39;s happening to everyone. Who better to know whether things are happening everywhere than your favorite systems administrator? So I called Dave Langhorst, and he reported the grim truth: power is out across a wide area, not just here, and his office phone was only working because of a battery backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota power outages follow the storms of June 21-22, 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-minnesota-power-outages-follow-the-storms-of-june-21-22-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 15:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-23-minnesota-power-outages-follow-the-storms-of-june-21-22-2013/</guid>
      <description>WHOA! RT @kare11: Yikes!! @jenyoung18: Take a look at the power outage map. @XcelEnergyMN #ouch #kare11wx pic.twitter.com/XGfhy380pU #minnesota
&amp;mdash; Chris (@Annie_CAS) June 22, 2013  The Minneapolis, MN area saw severe storms on Thursday June 20, 2013 and Friday June 21, 2013. This led to widespread power outages, with a total of more than half a million subscribers affected.
The power outage map from Xcel Energy would be the normal reference point for storm analysis, but they have had so much traffic to the page that the power outage map is behaving intermittently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the power is out, Lineman Barn&#39;s Facebook page heats up</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-26-when-the-power-is-out-lineman-barns-facebook-page-heats-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 22:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-12-26-when-the-power-is-out-lineman-barns-facebook-page-heats-up/</guid>
      <description>Lineman Barn has a page on Facebook. They say about themselves
  Established in 2003 to bring pride and recognition to the trade, Lineman Barn is the First Choice of Linemen and their families for custom shirts, hats, decals, gifts, JOBS and Lineman Safety News.  Part of the news that gets circulated is information about power outages, in the form of calls for linemen to work at utility companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumers Energy announces new power outage map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-16-consumers-energy-announces-new-power-outage-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 11:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-16-consumers-energy-announces-new-power-outage-map/</guid>
      <description>The new Consumers Energy Power Outage map is at&amp;#0160;http://www.consumersenergy.com/outagemap. Here&amp;#39;s a map with the service territory marked - there are no outages to speak of on the map right now. The page automatically switches to a mobile web view if you are coming from a smart mobile device (IOS and Android; not so much Blackberry). There are three views: one for individual detailed outages, one at a city level, and one at a county level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIPA Style - Long Island Power Authority version of &#34;Gangnam Style&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-16-lipa-style-long-island-power-authority-version-of-gangnam-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 10:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-16-lipa-style-long-island-power-authority-version-of-gangnam-style/</guid>
      <description>Via Viral Viral Videos:
 Long Island hit music station 106.1 BLI ... made this genius Long Island Power Authority spoof of the KPop mega hit with their own relevant lyrics, all pertaining to the recent mass power outages due to hurricane Sandy. Naturally, the music video is instantly going viral!
&amp;#0160;
  Add this to your list of parodies of this hit - my other favorite is &amp;quot;Klingon Style&amp;quot;, and my younger son was singing along to &amp;quot;Mitt Romney Style&amp;quot; the other day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy: power outage tracking and mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-02-huricane-sandy-power-outage-tracking-and-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 10:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-11-02-huricane-sandy-power-outage-tracking-and-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Hurricane Sandy hit the US East Coast earlier this week, knocking out power to more than 8 million subscribers. The damage to the infrastructure was so severe that it&amp;#39;s expected to take more than a week to bring service back.
Here are a few of the better projects online to track the progress of service restoration.
NY Times
The New York Times is tracking power outages and restoration for the Con Edison service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 700 million lose power in India in second day of grid failures</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-31-over-700-million-lose-power-in-india-in-second-day-of-grid-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-07-31-over-700-million-lose-power-in-india-in-second-day-of-grid-failures/</guid>
      <description>After writing about power problems that affected thousands of homes, it&amp;#39;s hard to imagine a problem that would take out 700 million subscribers. But that&amp;#39;s just the problem facing India, which has seen failures of its transmission grid in two days straight - the biggest power outage ever.
Some sources for more information:
The Guardian, UK. &amp;quot;Power cuts plunge 20 of India&amp;#39;s 28 states into darkness as energy suppliers fail to meet growing demand&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Outage Mapping</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-10-power-outage-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 11:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2012/2012-05-10-power-outage-mapping/</guid>
      <description>One of my most popular posts on this blog - especially in times of widespread severe weather - is a list of power outage maps that are available for utility companies across the nation and across the world.
There&amp;#39;s a lot of talk about a &amp;quot;smart grid&amp;quot;, and how improvements in technology will lead to more reliable power and other innovations in energy delivery. But the truth of the matter is that sometimes the power does go out, and it&amp;#39;s not always obvious why it did or when the systems will be back online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power outage information from DTE Energy on your Android phone</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-power-outage-information-from-dte-energy-on-your-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-29-power-outage-information-from-dte-energy-on-your-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>This news release follows an earlier notice of an iPhone app, also available on the app store. For outage information from your browser, go to the DTE Energy outage map.
News Release Issued: November 28, 2011 3:00 PM EST
DTE Energy Introduces a New Android App to Get Outage Information DETROIT, Nov. 28, 2011 /PRNewswire/ --&amp;#0160;DTE Energy has introduced a new interactive mobile Android application (app) for customers to access a variety of up-to-the-minute information, including outage information from their smartphones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the San Diego power blackout with FNET</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-25-mapping-the-san-diego-power-blackout-with-fnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 22:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-11-25-mapping-the-san-diego-power-blackout-with-fnet/</guid>
      <description>via geospatial.blogs.com
Geoff Zeiss has a note on the University of Tennessee Power Information Technology Laboratory and its network of power sensors. FNET&amp;#0160;is
 a low-cost, quickly deployable GPS-synchronized wide-area frequency measurement network. High dynamic accuracy Frequency Disturbance Recorders (FDRs) are used to measure the frequency, phase angle, and voltage of the power system at ordinary 120 V outlets. The measurement data are continuously transmitted via the Internet to the FNET servers hosted at the University of Tennessee and&amp;#0160;Virginia Tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined East Coast power outage tracking map</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-07-combined-east-coast-power-outage-tracking-map-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 13:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-07-combined-east-coast-power-outage-tracking-map-/</guid>
      <description>One of the hardest parts of tracking large storms is figuring out the damage to the power infrastructure as the storms roll through. You can get a good grasp on how bad a storm is by how much the power goes out, but each power company&amp;#39;s outage site is different, and there has been no straightforward multi-state combined view.
The 2011 hurricane season crisis map from Google&amp;#0160;has the first large scale version of a multi-utility outage map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE Energy has new iPhone app for outage reporting and tracking</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-07-dte-energy-has-new-iphone-app-for-outage-reporting-and-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 12:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-09-07-dte-energy-has-new-iphone-app-for-outage-reporting-and-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Press release follows, unedited. Download from the Apple iTunes App store; this screen shot is from that source. The application was developed by RIIS in Southfield.
 DTE Energy Introduces New iPhone App to Get Real-Time Outage Information DETROIT, Sept. 7, 2011 /PRNewswire/ -- DTE Energy has introduced a new interactive iPhone application (app) for customers to access a variety of up-to-the-minute information, including real-time outage information from their mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTE power outage map for May 23, 2011, 11:00 p.m.</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-dte-power-outage-map-for-may-23-2011-1100-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 23:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-23-dte-power-outage-map-for-may-23-2011-1100-pm/</guid>
      <description>This DTE power outage map shows the storm paths through the area for the storms of May 23, 2011 pretty clearly. Note the track along Michigan Avenue and then heading a bit to the north via the Davison; you&amp;#39;re looking for when individual purple dots turn to green, yellow, orange and then red.

 Map: DTE Energy, as of 11:03 p.m. ET May 23, 2011; data may be more than 15 minutes old.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>