<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jeff-lamb/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/jeff-lamb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Jeff Lamb, photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-03-25-obituary-jeff-lamb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeff Lamb&lt;/strong&gt; (January 16, 1949 - March 22, 2011) was a photographer of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelenau Peninsula. He is survived by his wife, Leyla Lau-Lamb, his dog, Sonny, and other relations and many friends.&amp;#0160;There will be a celebration of Jeff&amp;#39;s life at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Hathaway&amp;#39;s_Hideaway&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Hathaway&amp;#39;s Hideaway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 310 S. Ashley, Ann Arbor, on Saturday, April 9th beginning at 4:00 p.m. In lieu of flowers, donations to&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prcno.org/programs/advocacy.php&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;The Advocacy Department of the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elsewhere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark O&amp;#39;Brien:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://randomphoto.blogspot.com/2011/03/remembering-jeff-lamb.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Remembering Jeff Lamb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michigan in Pictures: &lt;a href=&#34;http://michpics.wordpress.com/2011/03/23/remembering-jeff-lamb&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Remembering Jeff Lamb&lt;/a&gt;, and sharing Jeff&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fej/sets/72157594264195900/show/with/1464861534/ &#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Leelenau slideshow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLAFemmes:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nolafemmes.com/2011/03/23/jeff-lamb/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jeff Lamb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flickr:&amp;#0160;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/fej/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Jeff Lamb&amp;#39;s photostream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obituary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lamb, Robert Jeffrey &amp;quot;Jeff&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Ffej&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Honey Bunny&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;January 16, 1949 - March 22, 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff was born in Oberlin, Ohio, and shortly afterward his family moved to Ann Arbor, Michigan. He attended public schools in Ann Arbor and earned a Master of Landscape Architecture degree from the University of Michigan. In 1978, Jeff moved to New Orleans, Louisiana, a city he loved dearly until the day he died. It was there that he met his loving wife, Leyla, who was visiting New Orleans from Hannover, Germany. Jeff and Leyla were married in Ann Arbor in 1986 and lived there happily until his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff was a professional photographer whose extraordinary photographs of New Orleans, Detroit, Ann Arbor and the Leelanau Peninsula will stand the test of time. He showed his love for New Orleans by documenting the architecture of the city and worked closely with the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans. After Jeff moved back to Ann Arbor, he continued his photography career and established many professional contacts throughout the world. His work has been influential, especially after Hurricane Katrina devastated New Orleans and destroyed many of the homes of which Jeff had taken photographs. He established deep connections with other photographers in New Orleans and made many close friends there through Facebook.&amp;#0160;Jeff also photographed historic homes in Ann Arbor and was instrumental in trying to save the Ann Arbor Seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff was preceded in death by his parents, Jane and Robert Lamb; and sister, Susan. He is survived by his wife, Leyla Lau-Lamb; his dog, Sonny; a cousin, David (Susan) Emmett of Howell, Michigan; nephew, Bryan Emmett (Shawnee); niece, Kelin Emmett; and many friends around the world who miss him terribly. He was one of a kind. There will be a celebration of Jeff&amp;#39;s life at Hathaway&amp;#39;s Hideaway, 310 S. Ashley, Ann Arbor, on April 9th beginning at 4:00 p.m. In lieu of flowers, donations may be made in Jeff&amp;#39;s name to The Advocacy Department of the Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans, 923 Tchoupitoulas St., New Orleans, LA 70130.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>