<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taco King on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/taco-king/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taco King on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/annarbor/taco-king/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Taco King</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-taco-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-05-25-taco-king/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The back story on Taco King is that the a2b3 group was here for lunch
once about two years ago on the same day that the kitchen was being inspected
by the state - and that day the restaurant closed voluntarily
to deal with some of its problems on the spot rather than
face sanction. We haven&amp;rsquo;t been back as a group, but I wanted to
check out the place to see what I was missing and if anything
had obviously changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspection if you want to see it is on a2docs, as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2docs.aadl.org/view/389&#34;&gt;World Call Shop (Taco King) inspections, October 2 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure it could be a good place to bring a large group for
lunch again, if you live with the
understanding that not every circumstance is perfect, and some
delicious food comes out of kitchens that are not perfectly clean.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much reading of restaurant inspections to know that
it&amp;rsquo;s rare to get a perfect score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the down side, loud nonsense television is playing on the TV set.
Ads for title loans, and the show is the People&amp;rsquo;s Court.
It&amp;rsquo;s a noisy background that makes it less fun to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The verdict: it was a bit more expensive than I remembered,
even though I had the special. The food was OK but not exceptional;
in particular, the lengua taco was not worth the $1.00 upcharge
on the daily special, I am a fan of tongue but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t
as articulate as I might expect it to be. And further I think I
was charged $1.25 for a drink that was labelled $0.99 on the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little things, always! And perhaps the little reasons not to bring a big group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>