<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Memory on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/coffee-memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coffee Memory on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:31:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.com/categories/coffee-memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>supermemo and morning coffee ritual memory</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.com/post/2008/2008-04-23-supermemo-and-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An important piece of having coffee in the morning is making it part of a routine.  If you&#39;re predictable in your habits, you start to see the same people in the same space at the same time, and you get to be something of a regular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re careful, and switch your morning allegiances from time to time but still visit the old haunts often enough, you can be what passes for a regular long after you stopped coming every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How often, then, do you need to show up for people to remember you?  For that I turn to structured repetition, and the power of priming memory periodically to strengthen it.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.supermemo.com&#34;&gt;Supermemo&lt;/a&gt;, a software package for memory improvement, has a nice paper on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.supermemo.com/articles/paper.htm&#34;&gt;using Supermemo without a computer&lt;/a&gt;, which specifies a pattern of repetitions and intervals to get details into memory.  The table of intervals specified says that you review materials at this pace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 days, 7 days, 12 days, 20 days, 1 month, 2 months, 3 months, 5 months, 9 months, 16 months, 2 years, 4 years, 6 years, 11 years, 18 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which suggests that a well-timed practice of showing up at a cafe, introducing yourself to everyone, learning their names, and them coming back at precisely timed intervals to repeat the process would be enough to make you a regular in no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>