<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/comments/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/comments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Verge turns off comments</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-the-verge-turns-off-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 15:20:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-06-the-verge-turns-off-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of course you never read the comments, but you might read the commentary on the comments. Here&#39;s The Verge&#39;s decision to turn off comments on its stories for the summer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And sometimes it gets too intense. What we&#39;ve found lately is that the tone of our comments (and some of our commenters) is getting a little too aggressive and negative — a change that feels like it started with GamerGate and has steadily gotten worse ever since. It&#39;s hard for us to do our best work in that environment, and it&#39;s even harder for our staff to hang out with our audience and build the relationships that led to us having a great community in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/6/8901115/were-turning-comments-off-for-a-bit&#34;&gt;We&#39;re turning comments off for a bit: Get ready for a chill summer&lt;/a&gt; in The Verge, July 6 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2015/06/never-read-the-comments.html&#34;&gt;Never read the comments&lt;/a&gt;, 2015; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/vacuum/2008/03/marquette-minin.html&#34;&gt;Marquette Mining Journal removes reader comments from newspaper web site&lt;/a&gt;, 2008. Also: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2013-09/why-were-shutting-our-comments&#34;&gt;WHY WE&#39;RE SHUTTING OFF OUR COMMENTS&lt;/a&gt;, Popular Science, 2013; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbsnews.com/news/cbsnewscom-turns-off-comments-on-obama-stories/&#34;&gt;CBSNews.com Turns Off Comments on Obama Stories&lt;/a&gt;, 2007; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.outsidethebeltway.com/washington_post_blog_shuts_off_comments/&#34;&gt;Washington Post Blog Shuts Off Comments&lt;/a&gt;, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never read the comments</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-29-never-read-the-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 10:07:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-29-never-read-the-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your comments excluded, of course, dear reader, though there are
more posts here than comments by people on those posts. The reference
is to the interminable slog of newspaper comments which place a
long stream of dreck at the end of that carefully edited story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss the days of carefully considered letters to the editor -
when you could count on not every letter getting published, when
you were limited to a certain number of words, and when if you were
wildly off-topic your words might never see the light of day. An
editor would pick a selection of letters to run, and some wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
make the cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishers who have well-edited work up front shouldn&amp;rsquo;t diminish
the impact of their work by giving the great unwashed Internet
access to their platform to post whatever the heck they please. It
detracts from the work to have unedited commentary on it posted so
close to the original. At a minimum any comments should be held for
approval before being posted, just so that the balance of power
tips over to the editor and not to the drooling, mouth-breathing
commentariat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>