<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kai Petainen on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/kai-petainen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kai Petainen on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 01:22:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/kai-petainen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor Library Lot exit problems on New Years Eve 2013</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-01-ann-arbor-library-lot-exit-problems-on-new-years-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 01:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2014/2014-01-01-ann-arbor-library-lot-exit-problems-on-new-years-eve/</guid>
      <description>Kai Petainen writes that the downtown &#34;Library Lot&#34; parking structure so full on New Years Eve that when everyone went to leave it at once, the lines were so long that people&#39;s paid tickets ran out of time. This caused additional delays of up to 45 minutes on exit and confusion as people had to turn around to re-pay.
I have heard of previous times where other unattended structures (notably Liberty Square) have had similar problems with the prepaid ticket system in busy events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huron River: May 25, 2011 flooding</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-05-26-huron-river-may-2011-flood/</guid>
      <description>The river is high. Will it flood? That&amp;#39;s a very good question to ask in the morning before a storm; and the answer today turned out to be yes. Roads were inundated, Lake Barracuda emerged from its stormwater geyser, Depot Street filled with water, Mullholland Creek popped a manhole cover, and S. Main Street near Michigan Stadium filled. West Park&amp;#39;s new water features get a workout.
Basements have taken on water, and the full extent of storm damage is unknown yet until we get the May 26 predicted rains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>