<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lifehacks on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/lifehacks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lifehacks on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 17:39:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/lifehacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evernote (for Android) as a reminder system</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-evernote-for-android-as-a-reminder-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-06-16-evernote-for-android-as-a-reminder-system/</guid>
      <description>I have a fickle relationship with reminder systems. Usually the drill is to discover something new, vigorously dump everything I can possibly think into it, and then slowly but surely get disillusioned with it as time goes on. The smell of a new system is seductive, and when something new comes along there&amp;#39;s a tendency to look at its good side and to focus on the bad parts of whatever you were using before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yesterbox: answer yesterday&#39;s email, today</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-27-yesterbox-answer-yesterdays-email-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-05-27-yesterbox-answer-yesterdays-email-today/</guid>
      <description>Yesterbox is a technique from Zappo&amp;#39;s CEO Tony Hseih that redefines the task of email management. Rather than aim for an &amp;quot;inbox zero&amp;quot; for today&amp;#39;s email (a never-ending task), he calls for answering today&amp;#39;s mail tomorrow, and yesterday&amp;#39;s mail today. Every message gets a one day delay unless it&amp;#39;s so urgent that has to be dealt with right away.
The biggest problem with &amp;quot;inbox zero&amp;quot; is that it&amp;#39;s impossible to be caught up for any length of time, since you need to be always on the alert for new messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack of discretion is the better part of Twitter</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-lack-of-discretion-is-the-better-part-of-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-06-14-lack-of-discretion-is-the-better-part-of-twitter/</guid>
      <description>The input box on Twitter is very small, the user interface works on a cell phone, and it all feels so much like you are having a small intimate conversation with a few confidants. Something horrible is said and you and perhaps the world realize that this thing is not just a harmless lark.&amp;#0160;
Twitter is a global communications infrastructure, with short meaningful names that replace carrier-assigned numbers for text and picture messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>clean your dishwasher with the breakfast drink of astronauts</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-16-clean-your-dishwasher-with-the-breakfast-drink-of-astronauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 23:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-16-clean-your-dishwasher-with-the-breakfast-drink-of-astronauts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s a cheaper way to clean a dishwasher than to put heavily marketed, sugary &amp;ldquo;breakfast drink&amp;rdquo; powder into it. Tang is citric acid and sweetener and artificial flavor that tastes like moon rocks.
The dishwasher is cleaner, though, which is a good thing.
Other suggestions for cleaners include vinegar, straight citric acid, borax, and baking soda. None of those have the astronaut cachet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cayenne in your socks</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-14-cayenne-in-your-socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-12-14-cayenne-in-your-socks/</guid>
      <description>An old, old recipe to keep your feet warm: sprinkle cayenne in your socks. &amp;#0160;
 The powdered capsicum slightly dusted in the socks of persons subject to cold feet will generally prove a salutary means of overpowering that unpleasant sensation. (The American Dispensatory, 1823)
 Not recommended to keep your fingers warm.
An illustrated example, from The Cooper Family: Warm feet in the snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story of mad-stone (W. R. Sanner, Fort Worth, TX, 1886)</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-12-the-story-of-madstone-w-r-sanner-fort-worth-tx-1886/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 10:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-03-12-the-story-of-madstone-w-r-sanner-fort-worth-tx-1886/</guid>
      <description>pulled from text at an online newspaper clippings archive
THE COURIER
ALEX A. WALL, Editor and Proprietor
Vernon, Alabama
Friday, December 24, 1886
 THE STORY OF MAD-STONE
[Fort Worth (Texas), December 4th - Cor. New York Mail and Express]
Miss May Bartlett was bitten yesterday by a dog which, from all
indications, is mad. A mad-stone owned by W. R. Sanner, of this city,
has been applied and adhered several times, drawing out the poison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brain, v5 (beta) for Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-20-the-brain-v5-beta-for-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 21:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-11-20-the-brain-v5-beta-for-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time a long time ago I used The Brain, an innovative and distinctive mind and idea mapping tool.&amp;#0160; I hit a wall at some point in my use of it, switched my desktop to a platform that it didn&amp;#39;t support, and unfocused from it.
There&amp;#39;s now a copy of The Brain for the Mac, and I pulled it down this afternoon to help someone work on a presentation where they need to make sense of a whole semester&amp;#39;s worth of interconnected ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>top 10 delicous tags, unusual delicious tags</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-30-top-10-delicous-tags-unusual-delicious-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 23:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-30-top-10-delicous-tags-unusual-delicious-tags/</guid>
      <description>inspired by britta, here is a list of my top 10 tags on delicious, annotated.
michigan - lots of links from around the state
annarbor - lots of links from around town
library - links from and about libraries from around the world
blog - these are primarily the &amp;quot;about&amp;quot; pages of blogs
superpatron - it would be convienent if these were auto-summarized for my superpatron blog
google - an exhaustive tour of the google archipelago</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>noe web disease</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-25-noe-web-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-07-25-noe-web-disease/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a bit of science fiction I&#39;d like to read -
The time is the future, but the near future, within reach - perhaps 2012. The hero has some kind of cognitive deficit that&#39;s progressive, so that they are slowly losing their ability to reason. (Think Flowers for Algernon, for instance.)
The twist is that the nature of the loss of thinking is that they are fine in person and in everything they normally do, but that they are unable to effectively use search engines any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The notebooks of Cosma Shalizi</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-19-the-notebooks-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 11:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-19-the-notebooks-o/</guid>
      <description>Since 1994, Cosma Shalizi has been keeping track of what he is reading and what he is interested in in his notebooks online.
 Burned all my notebooks What good are notebooks If they won&#39;t help me survive?  The colophon is worth quoting in full, though you&#39;ll need to go to the original to get all of the hyperlinks.
 These notebooks began in September 1994 as a set of key-words for Usenet filtering; I don&amp;rsquo;t remember why I started to elaborate them, but I did, and put them online on 3 October 1994.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to self: 15 minutes of attention</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-note-to-self-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 18:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-03-04-note-to-self-15/</guid>
      <description>If you could pay attention to just one thing over the next 15 minutes, what would it be?  The list of categories of potential things to be alert to is too long, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to sort through them to find the right type of thing. Don&amp;rsquo;t start by reviewing the list, because the list is too long to review without making that the one solitary task.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>