<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Checklist on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/checklist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Checklist on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/checklist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Levenshtein distance for approximate match</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 16:11:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-17-levenshtein-distance-for-approximate-match/</guid>
      <description>The problem, simply stated, is that of typoes and inconsistent spelling and pluraliziation. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a collection of text that you want to annotate with some metadata, like categories and tags. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside ahead of time exactly which tags you want to use, but you want to catch through some test or lint step that you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong by typing &amp;ldquo;apples&amp;rdquo; into a field that really has &amp;ldquo;apple&amp;rdquo; most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checklists, eptitude, how to get things right - Atul Gawande</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-04-checklists-eptitude-how-to-get-things-right-atul-gawande/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2010/2010-02-04-checklists-eptitude-how-to-get-things-right-atul-gawande/</guid>
      <description>The Checklist Manifesto; review in the New York Times.

THE CHECKLIST MANIFESTOHow to Get Things RightAtul Gawande
Excerpt from Freakonomics review
 Even more interesting are the stories about Walmart’s response to Hurricane Katrina, and the real reason why David Lee Roth used to demand that there be a bowl of M&amp;amp;M’s with all the brown ones removed in his dressing room backstage. Times Online review
The surgeon-author was on the track of what might be described as a classic magic bullet — a low-tech way in a high-tech, expensive world in which lives might be saved and costs reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twelve things to update when you get a new job</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-29-twelve-things-to-update-when-you-get-a-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-06-29-twelve-things-to-update-when-you-get-a-new-job/</guid>
      <description>A checklist for Monday.
1.&amp;#0160; Blog.&amp;#0160; Put a new photo in the sidebar, and update &amp;quot;about me&amp;quot; page.
2.&amp;#0160; Twitter.&amp;#0160; New mini-bio, new photo, update the link as appropriate.
3.&amp;#0160; Arborwiki. edit the Edward Vielmetti page; that will be the &amp;quot;about me&amp;quot; link.
4.&amp;#0160; LinkedIn.&amp;#0160; Create the new position, new title.&amp;#0160; Get a recommendation.
5.&amp;#0160; Facebook.&amp;#0160; Make some clever remark, update photo, bio.
6.&amp;#0160; Google profile.&amp;#0160; Google is probably keeping track of something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>community organizer&#39;s checklist: weekly lunch meeting</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 11:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-12-04-community-organizers-checklist-weekly-lunch-meeting/</guid>
      <description>A checklist of things to do for the weekly lunch.
1.&amp;#0160; Day of the week: Mo - Tu - We - Th - Fri
2.&amp;#0160; Frequency: Every - First - Second - Third - Fourth - Last - Even - Odd
3.&amp;#0160; Location: Fixed (Eastern Accents) - Floating - Alternate (Ypsilanti TBD)
4.&amp;#0160; Holiday schedule: Skip - Alternate Day (Weds or Fri) - Alternate Week 5.&amp;#0160; Summer schedule: Skip - Alternate Time - Alternate Location (Ypsilanti TBD)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>