<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dug Song on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dug-song/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dug Song on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/dug-song/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>mitmproxy</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-mitmproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 02:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-31-mitmproxy/</guid>
      <description>In his An internet x-ray machine for the masses, Paul Ohm writes a lucid introduction to mitmproxy, a man-in-the-middle proxy server that allows you to get between your browser and the Internet and poke at (and change) the traffic going between the two.
http://mitmproxy.org is the home of mitmproxy. It&amp;rsquo;s the work of Aldo Cortesi and a cast of hundreds of contributors on github at https://github.com/mitmproxy/mitmproxy . I used the OS X binary distribution from the download page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dug Song&#39;s letter to the Ann Arbor News endorsing Kirk Westphal, annotated</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-dug-songs-letter-to-the-ann-arbor-news-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 23:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-10-27-dug-songs-letter-to-the-ann-arbor-news-annotated/</guid>
      <description>Dug Song wrote a letter to the editor of the Ann Arbor News which was published on Sunday, 27 October 2013. It is annotated here with the hyperlinks to a variety of sources for further reading. The letter includes a political endorsement.
  While I deeply appreciate city council&#39;s dedication to a balanced budget and basic services, we cannot simply save our way to success. Post-Pfizer, Ann Arbor must increase its tax base by supporting a strong and diversified economy of high-growth, high tech companies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>