<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/etrakit/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/etrakit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of the city, Ann Arbor, fall 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-14-the-state-of-the-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-10-14-the-state-of-the-city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A perspective on Ann Arbor area local government, as seen from fall 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top level view is that local units of government are struggling
with their technology investments, having a difficult time keeping
them working, and are unwilling or unable to commit to any sort of
&amp;ldquo;open data&amp;rdquo; initiatives as a result of their difficulties with basic
operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples will illustrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City of Ann Arbor keeps track of a wide range of planning and
permit documents through a vendor system called eTrakit. This system
was down for more than a week in September, and still occasionally
crashes in response to a query. There is no general purpose &amp;ldquo;open data&amp;rdquo;
query to get access to the system, though the city does publish a
&amp;ldquo;permits under review&amp;rdquo; feed on its open data catalog that has a small
subset of the available data. Attachments in the system were recently
taken offline after unredacted credit card numbers were discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City of Ann Arbor meeting agendas and minutes and documents are locked up
in a vendor-provided Legistar system, which is so difficult to use that
many boards and commissions don&amp;rsquo;t even bother to publish their minutes
through that system. Meeting agendas are often delayed in publication,
and there is no method available to search across the whole system for
documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ann Arbor City Clerk keeps track of FOIA requests across the city
and publishes a &amp;ldquo;database&amp;rdquo; of requests. As is all too typical for
municipal government, this &amp;ldquo;database&amp;rdquo; is published as a PDF file, not
as plain text in some format that can be easily parsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City Liquor License Review Committee routinely evaluates applications
for new permits to serve or manufacture alcohol. These applications
are not published as part of the agenda for that committee or for
Ann Arbor City Council&amp;rsquo;s online system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would go on, but the City Council meeting is tonight, and I&amp;rsquo;m
preparing something for public commentary (probably to add to the
discussion only after the decisions have been made).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>