<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House And Home How To on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/house-and-home-how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in House And Home How To on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/house-and-home-how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing machine has a hose leak? How to repair it.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2012/2012-06-06-washing-machine-hose-leak-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of good sites for information about do-it-yourself washing machine repair. Ours had a leak, which I think I traced to a tiny hole in the low-pressure drain hose that was fixable with a pipe tape that the good folks at Stadium Hardware helped me find. Let&amp;#39;s hope the repair holds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.familyhandyman.com/DIY-Projects/Home-Repair/Appliance-Repair/how-to-repair-a-leaking-washing-machine/View-All&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Family Handyman&amp;#39;s How To Repair a Leaking Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;as my guide. The pinhole sized leak was in the middle of the low-pressure drain hose, where a rusty piece of bracket had wedged itself against the hose and slowly caused it to get a pinhole sized hole. The repair was made with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.duckbrand.com/Products/diy-products/diy-specialties/self-fusing-repair-tape.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Duck Brand Wrap-Fix Tape&lt;/a&gt;, a self-fusing silicone tape that says it&amp;#39;s good to 100 PSI.&amp;#0160;And &lt;a href=&#34;http://arborwiki.org/city/Stadium_Hardware&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Stadium Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#0160;(Arborwiki link) is a marvelous store, with helpful folks and a seemingly infinite supply of parts for every hardware need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#39;s just hope the repair holds! The next step, if it doesn&amp;#39;t, is to replace that hose entirely. Repair Clinic has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.repairclinic.com/GE-Washing-Machine-Hose-Tube-Or-Fittings-Parts?z=100&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;about 70 different GE washing machine hose parts available&lt;/a&gt;; I haven&amp;#39;t yet identified the exact part.&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the repair for the high-pressure supply hose would be very different, as noted in the comment below. The Family Handyman guide referenced above suggests getting a metallic no-burst supply hose &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluidmaster.com/washing-machine-connectors.html/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;similar to this one from Fluidmaster&lt;/a&gt; to replace any worn, corroded, or leaky supply hoses. Supply lines run at much higher pressure than drain lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>