<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 22:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/categories/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The world spider catalog, version 9.0. American Museum of Natural History</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-05-the-world-spide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 22:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-10-05-the-world-spide/</guid>
      <description>Platnick, N. I. 2008. The world spider catalog, version 9.0. American Museum of Natural &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; History, online at http://research.amnh.org/entomology/spiders/catalog/index.html
The World Spider Catalog is a thorough catalog of the scientific literature regarding spiders, with a special attention paid to classification and taxonomy.&amp;nbsp; The organization of the entries is hierarchically determined; hence synonymies at the &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; generic level are indicated under the family (and cross-referenced under the appropriate &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; generic) listings, but affected species are listed separately only if there are significant &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; references to them in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin spider, Araneus trifolium</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-29-pumpkin-spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 23:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-29-pumpkin-spider/</guid>
      <description>From my inbox:
My name is Sarah and I’m 12. I live in Ann Arbor. Recently, my family found a spider with a body about 3&amp;frasl;4 an inch in diameter and with legs it was bigger than a quarter. It is so huge! It is living in a big web between my house and some bushes. The web is made up of circles and the spider is only there during evening and night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very rare southern black widow spider bite in Michigan</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-very-rare-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 23:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-22-very-rare-south/</guid>
      <description>Brad Gregory of Belding, MI (about 30 miles NE of Grand Rapids, MI) was bitten by a southern black widow spider (Latrodectus mactans Fabricius) on September 7, 2008.&amp;nbsp; The spider was found inside a Maytag dishwasher that his grandparents had purchased at Home Depot two weeks earlier.&amp;nbsp; He was treated at Spectrum Health System&#39;s Blodgett Hospital in East Grand Rapids, which had the antivenin on hand.
The best news article on this is from the Greenville, MI Daily News, which also includes a picture of Brad holding the spider in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pictures of Michigan Spiders</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-pictures-of-mic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 21:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-09-08-pictures-of-mic/</guid>
      <description>As a part of a continuing series on Michigan spiders, here are some images.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ve identified them as best I can with Latin and common names.&amp;nbsp; I&#39;ll be adding to this from time to time to make it as complete as I can; the end of this post has some more sources.
Jumping spiders &amp;quot;Jumping Spider&amp;quot; by Hamilton Images; all rights reserved, used with permission

This jumping spider was photographed in Rockwood, MI in the Lake Erie Metropark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern Michigan spiders (and other inverts): the Backyard Arthropod Project from Atlantic Mine, MI</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-27-northern-michig/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-06-27-northern-michig/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a long while, you run across something so wonderful you have to share.
I have been tracking hits to the Google search Michigan spiders, ever since an odd combination of page text about automated web browsing tools unearthed a bunch of folks trying to identify the spiders crawling across their day lilies.
Today&#39;s search logs turned up this amazing resource, the The Backyard Arthropod Project
A Field Guide to the North Side of Old Mill Hill, Atlantic Mine, MI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>