<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prabal Dutta on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/prabal-dutta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prabal Dutta on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/prabal-dutta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuter North and South</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-07-20-commuter-north-and-south/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bus labeled &amp;ldquo;TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t take that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kayakers in bright yellow kayaks on the Huron River under the bridge on Fuller Road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be too much to ask to have wifi actually on the blue bus, or
is it more reasonable to expect that people have cell data coverage
everywhere and that wifi on the bus is for long haul buses like Megabus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that with Hugo I can have a reasonably complete local blogging
environment completely independent of having Internet access, so long as I have
my computer with me. On the other hand doing live-blogging from a phone is
not possible, not that it ever really was very practical with any previous setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your UMARC shack access code is &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Achievement unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The todo list right now for the shack is very short - &amp;ldquo;get in&amp;rdquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m
in I should have a longer list. There is a lot of gear in that room
to get familiar with, not least of which is HF equipment with tunable
and movable antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2013/06/twitter-marius-eriksen-finagle/&#34;&gt;Why Twitter Has More Freedom To Innovate Than Google&lt;/a&gt; is a 2013 Wired Magazine writeup.
Prominently featured are Marius Eriksen, Niels Provos, and Peter Honeyman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the early aughts, when Eriksen was an undergrad at
Michigan, studying computer science under a professor and lovable
eccentric named Peter Honeyman. Known as “Dr. Honey” among the
undergrads and PhD students at his Center for Information Technology
Integration, Honeyman was famous for making assignments without
really making assignments. “He would develop a particular obsession,
and he would give you random hints about it, but he wouldn’t actually
tell you what to do,” Eriksen remembers. “You would end up collaborating
with people on whatever it was, in this freeform way, without much
direction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to one of Peter&amp;rsquo;s current students. Evan is looking at ways to
direct RF energy at devices to make them fail in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan are working on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://it.slashdot.org/story/15/06/30/1917207/stanford-starts-the-secure-internet-of-things-project&#34;&gt;Secure Internet of Things Project (slashdot)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford, Berkeley, and the University of Michigan have now started
the Secure Internet of Things Project, which aims to promote security
and transparency for IoT devices. They hope to unite regulators,
researchers, and manufacturers to ensure nascent internet-connected
tech is developed in a way that respects customer privacy and choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web site has more details at &lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu&#34;&gt;http://iot.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the presentations at the Secure Internet of Things Project Retreat
in Half Moon Bay on June 5, 2015 was this by U of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s Prabal Dutta,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://iot.stanford.edu/retreat15/sitp15-swhw.pdf&#34;&gt;State of the Field: Hardware and Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(embed deck here, if I can)
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LP0965 Antenna is a Log Periodic PCB directional antenna, at 5-6dBi Gain.
The design is from Kent Britain WA5VJB, and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wa5vjb.com/pcb-pdfs/LP8565.pdf&#34;&gt;data sheet for the antenna&lt;/a&gt; describes its
utility for signals from 850 Mhz to 6500 Mhz. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://wa5vjb.com&#34;&gt;http://wa5vjb.com&lt;/a&gt; for more
circuit board antennas for use for hobby, wifi, microwave and cellular use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic jam on Fuller on the return trip, backed up all the way to the river.
It took about 15 minutes to get through because of construction on westbound
Fuller taking traffic to one lane. It would have been faster to take the Route 1
AAATA bus via Pontiac Trail, even though it would have been a considerable detour,
or to walk to Plymouth Road and take the 2 in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a fire at the Michigan League this afternoon. No sign of any issues
as I pass by this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question when taking Commuter South is always where to get off the bus. Today
I&amp;rsquo;ll take it all the way to the end of its route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>