<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Botany Juneberry on tracker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/botany-juneberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Botany Juneberry on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:39:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/botany-juneberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Woody plants - identifying the trees of Michigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009-02-17-woody-plants-identifying-the-trees-of-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year the U of Michigan teaches a Woody Plants class.&amp;#0160; I didn&amp;#39;t take it when I was in school, but my sister did, and it&amp;#39;s one of these legendary courses that people remember for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the links and notes I could find easily.&amp;#0160; It&amp;#39;s prompted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://annarborchronicle.com/2009/02/13/where-are-ann-arbors-trees/&#34;&gt;the Ann Arbor Chronicle&amp;#39;s story about the city of Ann Arbor tree inventory going on now,&lt;/a&gt; which I hope will yield a precise map of where all of the public juneberry trees are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Course listing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snre.umich.edu/node/349&#34;&gt;NRE 436: Woody Plants Biology and Identification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0in 0in 0pt 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#34;#000000&#34; face=&#34;Times New Roman&#34; size=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Woody
Plants is an intensive field- and lecture-based learning experience, in
which you will learn to identify 160 trees, shrub and vine species that
are important in Michigan environments. You will learn about their
taxonomy, distribution, habitat associations, and biogeographic history
and how to identify them in their leafless winter condition. The lab
component consists of weekly field trips in the Ann Arbor area, which
include riparian and floodplain habitats, glacial lakes, moraines,
bogs, fens and mesic forests. The lectures cover elementary aspects of
plant identification, taxonomy and ecology; however, the broader themes
include biogeographic history and the assembly of Michigan plant
communities, both before and after major glaciations, ecological
specializiation, and impacts of global warming and other anthropogenic
environmental changes.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://http://sitemaker.umich.edu/woodyplants/home&#34;&gt;Woody Plants - Sitemaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;The required textbook for Woody Plants is &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Michigan Trees&lt;/span&gt;
by Burt V. Barnes and Warren H. Wagner. The authors taught the Woody
Plants class from 1965 to 2005 and know their topic well. The books are
available at Shaman Drum bookshop on 311 State Street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snre.umich.edu/profile/bvb&#34;&gt;Burt Barnes home page&lt;/a&gt; at SNRE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;Undergraduate and graduate teaching in forest ecology; landscape
ecology; natural history, and identification of Woody Plants. Research
focuses on the theory and application of the landscape ecosystem
approach. Studies emphasize spatial mapping of landscape ecosystems as
the basis for conserving and managing ecosystems at multiple scales.
Research on diversity of ecosystems and biota in upland, riverine, and
wetland ecosystems. Specific areas include genetic and systematic
studies of aspen species (genus &lt;em&gt;Populus&lt;/em&gt;), worldwide and comparative studies of east Asian and North American forests and species of the temperate zone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=Mc0YAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=michigan+trees&amp;amp;ei=rhGbSeCiDZicMq685KEP#PPP3,M1&#34;&gt;An early edition of Michigan Trees, in 1913, as seen on Google Books&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_sectionwrap&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line book_title_line&#34;&gt;Michigan Trees: A Handbook of the Native and Most Important Introduced Species&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;By Charles Herbert Otis&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Edition: 2&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Published by The Regents, 1913&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Original from Harvard University&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;Digitized Apr 11, 2008&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;bookinfo_section_line&#34;&gt;246 pages&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>