<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/blueberries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blueberries on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:47:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/recipes/blueberries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 Dexter Blueberry Farm season starts July 18</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-2013-dexter-blueberry-farm-season-starts-july-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-07-17-2013-dexter-blueberry-farm-season-starts-july-18/</guid>
      <description>From a news release by the Dexter Blueberry Farm: The Dexter Blueberry Farm will open earlier than planned. We will open July 18 2013.
The early berries are ready, Blue-Ray, Blue-Crop and Northland varieties. Blue-Ray and Blue-Crop berries tend to be larger and slightly tart. The picking will be good. The Jersey will begin in another 10 days.
The price for blueberries is $1.75/lb. Mon-Sat: 8:00am-7:30 pm Sunday: Noon-6:00 pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 u-pick blueberry report for the Dexter Blueberry Farm</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-14-2009-upick-blueberry-report-for-the-dexter-blueberry-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-07-14-2009-upick-blueberry-report-for-the-dexter-blueberry-farm/</guid>
      <description>first u-pick blueberries in the area from dexter blueberry farm; here&amp;#39;s the email they sent out. &amp;#0160;you will want to go to their web site and join their mailing list if you want to get more.
blueberries arrive. &amp;#0160;
the web site says &amp;quot;The price of berries /lb. is $1.60/lb&amp;quot;. &amp;#0160;this compares with $40 for 10# at the Ann Arbor Farmers Market. &amp;#0160;
&amp;ndash;
dexterblueberry.com
Early picking opportunity.
We will open for you to pick blueberries starting&amp;#0160;Friday July 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to freeze berries</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-24-how-to-freeze-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-24-how-to-freeze-b/</guid>
      <description>Wash, drain, then spread in a single layer on a cookie sheet.&amp;nbsp; Freeze until solid and then use a spatula to carefully scrape them (whole) into freezer bags or tubs.
Label, carefully.&amp;nbsp; &amp;quot;Beans, do not open until February&amp;quot;.&amp;nbsp; So that when it&#39;s February, you&#39;ll have something to look forward to, and so that the fridge monsters don&#39;t eat them before then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Buffalo stew</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-blueberry-buffa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 16:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-04-blueberry-buffa/</guid>
      <description>Blueberry buffalo stew from Cooking Debauchery, via merathena on LJ:

The blueberries melt into the stock producing the most delectable, mahogany colored broth and a fragrance the fills the house with the scents of fall. 
We&#39;re vegetarians at home, so this is going to have to be someone else&#39;s potluck dish. There&#39;s buffalo raised in Michigan at Sprik Farms near Grand Rapids, and at TMZ Farm near Pinckney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim Johnson, poet laureate of Duluth, MN; In The Blueberry Bucket</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-03-jim-johnson-poe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2008/2008-08-03-jim-johnson-poe/</guid>
      <description>Jim Johnson is the 2008-2010 poet laureate of Duluth, Minnesota. From a profile of Jim Johnson by writer Cheryl Reitan in the mnartists.org site:
 JIM JOHNSON, THE RECENTLY CHOSEN 2008-2010 DULUTH POET LAUREATE, writes poetry that is cut from the cloth of his Finnish roots. While much of his work recalls the lives of Finnish settlers in northern Minnesota, the message is universal. It is the quintessentially American story of the immigrant experience and of families, hunger, nature, and hard work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>