<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/code/wakatime/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/code/wakatime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All watched over by machines</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-07-all-watched-over-by-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 23:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-07-all-watched-over-by-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, a detailed look at the way you spend time over
the course of a day online yields several fascinating conclusions.
As previously noted, &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;Wakatime&lt;/span&gt; is the introspective tool of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gee, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time to look at Facebook, Twitter, and Gmail;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t you spending more of your productive time writing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll bet that if you put down the computer your day would be more productive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, #2 is the most interesting one. Of course time spent on Facebook,
Twitter, and Gmail is time spent writing, but it&amp;rsquo;s transactional writing -
short bursts of functional prose to negotiate a time, set up a plan,
make a clever comeback or otherwise do online chit-chat. The words are writing,
but there&amp;rsquo;s not a body of work that you can point to that&amp;rsquo;s of any size as
your opus from that hour plus spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productive is a very funny word when you&amp;rsquo;re being watched by a machine.
Some parts of the time are marked as &amp;ldquo;good time&amp;rdquo;, where you&amp;rsquo;re happy to
have an extra minute spent credited to a project or task. Not all time is
&amp;ldquo;good time&amp;rdquo;, though some of the non-good time is just as essential, just
measured differently. And then there&amp;rsquo;s the occasional glitch in the matrix
where time is credited or blamed on one thing but you could swear you were
doing something else at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time spent on task sometimes looks very small when all of these are taken into
account. Those 99 words you wrote for publication were edited down from 150,
and might be edited further down to 55. If you could precisely allocate all
of the time you spent on it it would include the musing and ruminations, but
that got chalked up to Gmail where it&amp;rsquo;s mixed in with the time spent deleting
mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to mix up inputs and outputs.
If your system measures inputs, you get ritualized behavior designed to
maximize time spent on task, no matter how the time is actually used.
Maximizing outputs would yield word counts and not minute counts. If you&amp;rsquo;re
slow and terse, there&amp;rsquo;s no help for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wakatime, an automatic time tracker for programmers</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-05-wakatime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 23:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-05-wakatime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wakatime tracks your time if you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer. It does this by
integrating into your favorite text editor (including vim) and your
favorite source code maintainence system (including Github) and then
matching time spent editing with checkins into your system. It collects
stats behind the scenes and turns everything into a shiny dashboard.
&amp;ldquo;Fitbit for programmers&amp;rdquo; is the tag line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That which is measured, improves. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if wakatime will improve
your writing, or your coding, or your general state of mind. What I do
know is that manually tracking your time is a pain, and that anything
you can do to manage to keep things running in your time accounting
system that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of manual labor is very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, of course, is that you generally don&amp;rsquo;t spend all of your
time inside a text editor. (But maybe you should! Just think how much
more productive you&amp;rsquo;d be.) Wakatime can be set up to also track you
in Chrome and pinpoint just how many hours per day get
absorbed by Twitter or Gmail or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I know myself, this is going to be a temporary enthusiasm. My
experience with the whole &amp;ldquo;quanitifed self&amp;rdquo; world is to know that
some months in the summer, my normal step count is well over 10000,
and that in the winter time it&amp;rsquo;s well under 10000, just because of
Michigan&amp;rsquo;s grey February. Benchmarking time spent sometimes makes you
work more mindfully, and sometimes just recognizes immutable human
issues that no amount of mechanical impetus will change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>