<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amy Ingram on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/people/amy-ingram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amy Ingram on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/people/amy-ingram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Your new robo-assistant, Amy Ingram</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-robo-assistant-xdotai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-08-04-robo-assistant-xdotai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, computers are making people easier and easier to use.
(David Tempkin, In Formation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://x.ai?rf=8o4arg&#34;&gt;x.ai&lt;/a&gt; has a new service in development, an automated
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;personal assistant&lt;/span&gt;
that helps you schedule meetings. You give it - or I should
say &amp;ldquo;her&amp;rdquo;, because the bot&amp;rsquo;s name is &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #bfffff;&#34;&gt;Amy Ingram&lt;/span&gt; -
you give Amy your calendar and some simple instructions, and &amp;ldquo;she&amp;rdquo;
manages the correspondence with the person you&amp;rsquo;re trying to meet
with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service is very new, so new that it&amp;rsquo;s the subject of breathless
enthusiasm about how wonderful it works in media accounts. Suddenly
people who never have had a personal assistant work for them get
access to an automaton who behaves like a well trained and inhumanly
efficient personal scheduler, and they get excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what is a personal assistant anyway but a carefully programmed
&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #ffffbf;&#34;&gt;protocol droid&lt;/span&gt;,
something who knows the expressions that are used
to work your way onto someone&amp;rsquo;s calendar. Having been trained with
the likes of Siri, we collectively know how useful it is to have a bot
teach us how to ask questions in an easy to parse, formalized way.
x.ai&amp;rsquo;s Amy invokes all of our ritual behavior when it comes to understanding
how to deal with the gatekeepers to the powerful and busy, and wraps
that up in an algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally I&amp;rsquo;ve signed up to be on the beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some press coverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/248707&#34;&gt;Human + A.I. = Your Business Future&lt;/a&gt;,
Entrepreneur, July 23 2015 from Nir Eyal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I get a response from Mindy, Tim, or Amy, I have no idea if
it was a human or machine that sent the message on their behalf.
With an assistants-as-app, the distinction between who&amp;rsquo;s doing the
messaging isn&amp;rsquo;t always clear — sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a bot and sometimes
it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WNYC, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wnyc.org/story/latest-productivity-digital-personal-assistant-named-amy/&#34;&gt;Say Hello to Amy, Your Plucky Digital Personal Assistant&lt;/a&gt;. November 26, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode, we test out a new breed of personal assistant.
Her, or its, name is Amy Ingram. She&amp;rsquo;s plucky, tenacious, and loves
arranging meetings. In contrast to Apple&amp;rsquo;s Siri, Google Now or
Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Cortana, Amy is specialized on one thing and one thing
only: scheduling. A new and increasingly common type of software,
Amy isn&amp;rsquo;t a program you download, or an app you install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/amyingramnyc&#34;&gt;Amy Ingram&lt;/a&gt;, LinkedIn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful Meeting Scheduling Personal Assistant with excellent
communication and follow-through skills. Demonstrates exceptional
interpersonal skills and high level of confidentiality. Extremely
well-organized, methodical and efficient. Ability to multi-task and
work well in an always changing, fast-paced environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Insider, Lara O&amp;rsquo;Reilly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/review-of-amy-ingram-the-virtual-personal-assistant-from-xai-2015-7&#34;&gt;I hired a virtual PA for a week and it&amp;rsquo;s made me a far more organized person than I ever was before&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there on in, organizing meetings became a breeze. Those who
didn&amp;rsquo;t know me too well didn&amp;rsquo;t question the fact that I was adding
Amy into our conversations. Those who did were just as incredulous
as Chris. One contact responded: &amp;ldquo;Well if I’d known you had people
I would have got my people to speak to your people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>