<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morel on tracker</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/morel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Morel on tracker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 08:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/morel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan morel festivals for 2009, and how to find morels</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-25-michigan-morel-festivals-for-2009-and-how-to-find-morels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2009/2009-04-25-michigan-morel-festivals-for-2009-and-how-to-find-morels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0472032747?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=superpatron-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0472032747&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img  alt=&#34;How-to-find-morels-0472032747&#34; class=&#34;at-xid-6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0115705275e7970b &#34; src=&#34;http://vielmetti.typepad.com/.a/6a00d8341c4f1a53ef0115705275e7970b-800wi&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;&#34; title=&#34;How-to-find-morels-0472032747&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; My search logs are starting to show hits for morel season, so it&#39;s time to put this year&#39;s post together.&amp;nbsp; The early reports from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://morelmushroomhunting.com/morel_progression_sightings_map.htm&#34;&gt;morel progression sightings map show a few isolated dots in southern Michigan&lt;/a&gt;, as of April 22 2009, but typically May is morel month, when and where the May apples are in good form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a list of some morel festivals in the state; if I have missed any, please let me know so that next year&#39;s list can be better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mesick-mushroomfest.org/&#34;&gt;Make your plans for May 8th –10th, 2009 for our
“Golden Anniversary”&amp;nbsp; 50th Annual Mesick Mushroom Festival.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Mesick is on M-115 NW of Cadillac; they helpfully sell &#34;spore bags&#34; to pickers so that when you go out in the woods looking for morels you can seed new crops for future years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mesick-mushroomfest.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.morelfest.com/&#34;&gt;49th Annual National Morel Mushroom Festival: Boyne City, Michigan&amp;nbsp;May 14 through 17 2009&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Brochure (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.morelfest.com/attachments/File/2009_brochure.pdf&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;), and the site has the song, the Mushroomer&#39;s Waltz (mp3), which tells you precisely what sorts of locations are good to go picking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The University of Michigan Press has a book -&lt;span class=&#34;h1&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.press.umich.edu/titleDetailDesc.do?id=318052&#34;&gt;How to Find Morels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Helvetica;&#34;&gt;, by Milan Pelouch, recipes by Lila Pelouch&lt;/span&gt; - which tells all:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;blockquote&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 40px;&#34;&gt;While many morel fans remain tight lipped about their favorite subject, in &lt;span class=&#34;ltblue&#34;&gt;How to Find Morels&lt;/span&gt;
author Milan Pelouch freely shares everything he&#39;s learned during his
years of morel hunting. The book covers all aspects of finding and
eating morels: identification of true and false morels; what to wear
(and not to wear) and take with you on mushroom hunts; when to search
for morels; the best places to look for them; cleaning and preservation
methods; and, of course, delicious recipes using morels in dozens of
different dishes, from soups to entrées. Although the author&#39;s
preferred hunting area is northern Michigan, his tips can be used in
any location in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want Scientific Research to go with your morels, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springerlink.com/content/7247581354685p6p/&#34;&gt;doi:10.1007/BF02858213&lt;/a&gt;, a touching account from a Harvard lad fresh to the Michigan woods published as Morchellamania in Michigan, Economic Botany, Volume 33, Number 1 / January, 1979. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any day you can go for a walk in the woods is a good day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>