<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Lambda for Python with &#34;Chalice&#34;</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-13-aws-lambda-with-chalice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2016/2016-10-13-aws-lambda-with-chalice/</guid>
      <description>Chalice is a microframework for Python for AWS Lambda, similar in spirit to Flask. What does that even mean?
A framework is a set of libraries and coding conventions that makes development in a specific language for a specific task easier. That usually involves making some simplifying assumptions about the task you are trying to solve, and embedding those assumptions in your code so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to spell out quite as much detail to get a task done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN scaling</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-12-16-openvpn-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Previously: OpenVPN in a container
Also previously: Split tunnels considered harmful
I have this running in a staging environment and a test environment; it properly isolates OpenVPN from the underlying operating system, and seems to do the right thing performing rather well. However, its biggest limitation is that it runs on a single host &amp;amp; thus provides neither high availability in the case of Amazon funkiness nor scalability to handle lots of clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DynamoDB downtime, Sunday am, September 20, 2015</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-09-20-aws-dynamodb-downtime-sunday-am/</guid>
      <description>A distributed system is one in which the failure of a computer you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed can render your own computer unusable. Leslie Lamport, 1987
 Amazon Web Services DynamoDB experienced downtime in the N Virginia availability zone early Sunday morning, September 20, 2015. As a result, a number of other AWS services inside N Virginia that depend on DynamoDB also had downtime. Companies and organizations that built services on top of those systems who didn&amp;rsquo;t have geographic load balancing were having problems as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>