<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rolodex on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</title>
    <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/rolodex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rolodex on Vacuum weblog from Edward Vielmetti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:37:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vielmetti.github.io/keyphrases/rolodex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A random walk through the rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-28-a-random-walk-through-the-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:37:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2015/2015-06-28-a-random-walk-through-the-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>The evening&#39;s work can be roughly summed up as
 Generate a random item from my personal wiki that starts with &#39;A&#39;. Much of the time, that will be a person&#39;s name.
 Comment on that person&#39;s weblog, if they have one, or otherwise get in touch.
 Repeat until &#39;Z&#39;.
  In the course of doing this I came across an essay, otherwise unpublished, on &#34;The algorithm driven day&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>graph-structured rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-15-graph-structured-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 19:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2013/2013-01-15-graph-structured-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>Facebook announced a new search tool today that lets you search through your &amp;quot;social graph&amp;quot;. Techmeme&amp;#39;s front page has plenty of commentary.
I wrote myself this unpublished note about it a few years ago, which looks pretty much spot-on now:
 For each person in your rolodex, draw a little graph of how they are related to others. There might be a few or there might be a dozen links you&amp;#39;d want to make explicit, and each link would have a name so the edges of the graph are also labeled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mental rolodex</title>
      <link>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 21:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vielmetti.github.io/post/2011/2011-12-17-associative-memory-and-the-mental-rolodex/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s a great use of the term in an LA Magazine review of &amp;quot;Run Lola Run&amp;quot;:
Lola tosses her red phone up in the air and instantly goes through her mental Rolodex of possibilities. Faces flash on the screen. She decides to hit up her banker father and darts out of the house. Credits: the &amp;quot;mental rolodex&amp;quot; term is one I heard first from&amp;#0160;Terry Bean, who used it at an LA2M presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>